1
00:00:52,970 --> 00:00:55,304
(MOTHER): I knew it would come out right
in the end!

2
00:00:55,389 --> 00:00:58,641
My dear, dear Lydia!
She will be married.

3
00:00:59,476 --> 00:01:02,812
My good, kind brother!
I knew how it would be.

4
00:01:02,896 --> 00:01:05,064
I knew he would manage everything!

5
00:01:05,649 --> 00:01:09,902
Oh, but the clothes! And of course
she must be married from Longbourn.

6
00:01:09,987 --> 00:01:13,239
This is all nonsense
about her being married from Cheapside!

7
00:01:13,323 --> 00:01:16,951
She must be married in Longbourn church,
where her friends can see her.

8
00:01:17,035 --> 00:01:19,245
That is not possible. You must see that.

9
00:01:19,997 --> 00:01:22,623
I do not see that!
Why should I see that?

10
00:01:22,708 --> 00:01:23,958
Why should that be?

11
00:01:24,042 --> 00:01:26,878
She's been living
with Mr Wickham in London.

12
00:01:26,962 --> 00:01:29,338
If she were to arrive
home unmarried still...

13
00:01:29,423 --> 00:01:34,427
I suppose it must be, if you put it
like that! But it is all very vexing.

14
00:01:34,511 --> 00:01:39,348
Your uncle has been most highhanded!
Why should he take so much upon him?

15
00:01:39,433 --> 00:01:42,518
Mamma, we're greatly
indebted to Mr Gardiner.

16
00:01:42,603 --> 00:01:46,397
He must have laid out a great deal
of money to pay off Mr Wickham's debts.

17
00:01:47,357 --> 00:01:50,485
- More than we can ever repay.
- Why should he not?

18
00:01:50,569 --> 00:01:52,820
Who else should lay out money,
but her uncle?

19
00:01:52,905 --> 00:01:53,905
Mother!

20
00:01:53,989 --> 00:01:56,574
Oh, well! I am so happy!

21
00:01:56,658 --> 00:01:59,494
A daughter married.
And only just sixteen.

22
00:02:00,370 --> 00:02:03,539
"Mrs Wickham". Oh, how well that sounds!

23
00:02:04,333 --> 00:02:06,167
Oh, but the wedding clothes!

24
00:02:06,251 --> 00:02:09,879
Lizzy, go down to your father
and ask how much he will give her.

25
00:02:12,716 --> 00:02:15,301
(MOTHER): Oh, Jane,
as soon as I am dressed

26
00:02:15,385 --> 00:02:18,137
I shall go to Meryton
and tell my sister Philips!

27
00:02:18,222 --> 00:02:19,972
(MOTHER): Ring the bell for Hill!

28
00:02:20,057 --> 00:02:24,101
An airing will do me
a great deal of good, I'm sure.

29
00:02:24,269 --> 00:02:29,482
(MOTHER): And I shall call on Lady Lucas
and Mrs Long. Oh, Jane!

30
00:02:29,566 --> 00:02:30,608
Papa.

31
00:02:30,692 --> 00:02:33,778
(MOTHER): Jane,
it's such wonderful news!

32
00:02:34,196 --> 00:02:39,408
(MOTHER): Oh, where is Hill?
Oh, Hill, have you heard the good news?

33
00:02:40,035 --> 00:02:41,244
Shut the door, Lizzy.

34
00:02:42,162 --> 00:02:45,248
(MOTHER): And you shall have
a bowl of punch to make merry at...

35
00:02:50,504 --> 00:02:53,756
Someone, at least,
finds pleasure in these events.

36
00:02:54,967 --> 00:03:01,556
But considering what we thought only
a few hours ago, it's not so bad, is it?

37
00:03:05,018 --> 00:03:07,562
Do you think my uncle
paid out much money?

38
00:03:07,646 --> 00:03:08,855
I do.

39
00:03:08,939 --> 00:03:13,442
Wickham's a fool if he takes her
with a farthing less than 1 0,000 pounds.

40
00:03:14,653 --> 00:03:16,195
1 0,000 pounds!

41
00:03:18,282 --> 00:03:22,535
Heaven forbid!
How is half such a sum to be repaid?

42
00:03:22,619 --> 00:03:24,579
I wish I had laid by an annual sum

43
00:03:24,663 --> 00:03:27,874
to bribe worthless young men
to marry my daughters,

44
00:03:27,958 --> 00:03:30,001
but I have not, I confess.

45
00:03:30,794 --> 00:03:36,090
The reason was, of course,
that I intended to father a son.

46
00:03:36,633 --> 00:03:41,137
The son would inherit the estate,
no part of which would be entailed away,

47
00:03:41,221 --> 00:03:44,849
so providing for my widow
and any other children.

48
00:03:45,976 --> 00:03:49,687
By the time we had abandoned hope
of producing an heir,

49
00:03:49,771 --> 00:03:52,148
it seemed a little late to begin saving.

50
00:03:52,232 --> 00:03:55,318
You could not have
foreseen this, father.

51
00:03:55,402 --> 00:03:58,237
I should have taken
better care of you all.

52
00:03:58,322 --> 00:04:00,114
The satisfaction of prevailing upon

53
00:04:00,198 --> 00:04:03,451
one of the most worthless
young men in Britain,

54
00:04:03,535 --> 00:04:05,995
might then have
rested in its proper place.

55
00:04:06,747 --> 00:04:08,080
As it is, the thing is done

56
00:04:08,165 --> 00:04:11,375
with extraordinary little
inconvenience to myself.

57
00:04:11,877 --> 00:04:14,003
When you take into account
what I shall save

58
00:04:14,087 --> 00:04:16,130
on Lydia's board and pocket allowance,

59
00:04:16,214 --> 00:04:19,091
I am scarcely ten pounds
a year worse off.

60
00:04:21,094 --> 00:04:23,846
I am heartily ashamed of myself, Lizzy.

61
00:04:25,140 --> 00:04:27,558
But don't despair, it will pass...

62
00:04:29,102 --> 00:04:31,979
..and no doubt
more quickly than it should.

63
00:04:59,132 --> 00:05:00,841
Where is everyone?

64
00:05:22,531 --> 00:05:27,201
Dearly beloved. We are gathered
here in the sight of God.

65
00:05:27,285 --> 00:05:28,703
(UNCLE): Mr Wickham is to resign

66
00:05:28,787 --> 00:05:31,747
from the Militia and go
into a northern regiment.

67
00:05:31,832 --> 00:05:34,250
Happily some of his former friends

68
00:05:34,334 --> 00:05:36,919
are willing to assist him
in purchasing a commission.

69
00:05:38,797 --> 00:05:40,840
I have written to
Colonel Forster to request

70
00:05:40,924 --> 00:05:44,593
that he will satisfy
Wickham's creditors in Brighton,

71
00:05:44,678 --> 00:05:46,137
for which I've pledged myself.

72
00:05:46,221 --> 00:05:52,852
"Perhaps you will be so good as to do
the same for his creditors in Meryton,"

73
00:05:52,936 --> 00:05:58,315
"of whom I enclose a list
according to his information."

74
00:06:00,193 --> 00:06:03,904
"I hope, at least, he has not
deceived us". Let us all hope so.

75
00:06:04,531 --> 00:06:05,948
"As soon as they are married,"

76
00:06:06,033 --> 00:06:09,785
"they will journey directly
to join his regiment in Newcastle,"

77
00:06:09,870 --> 00:06:14,290
"unless they are first
invited to Longbourn."

78
00:06:14,374 --> 00:06:18,210
Oh, yes, my dear Mr Bennet,
of course they must come here!

79
00:06:18,295 --> 00:06:23,716
I long to see my dear Lydia!
And dear Wickham, too, of course.

80
00:06:23,800 --> 00:06:26,093
But it is shocking that poor Lydia

81
00:06:26,178 --> 00:06:28,220
should have been
sent away from Brighton.

82
00:06:28,305 --> 00:06:30,765
Such a favourite among all the officers!

83
00:06:31,475 --> 00:06:35,352
There were several young men there
that she liked very much.

84
00:06:35,437 --> 00:06:37,897
They will miss her
as much as she will miss them.

85
00:06:37,981 --> 00:06:40,733
These northern officers
may not be so pleasant.

86
00:06:40,817 --> 00:06:43,652
Dear Mrs Bennet,
I'm sure our youngest daughter

87
00:06:43,737 --> 00:06:48,282
will find friends as silly
as she in Newcastle.

88
00:06:48,366 --> 00:06:51,869
She has a talent for making a spectacle
of herself wherever she goes.

89
00:06:51,953 --> 00:06:53,704
If they are to leave Brighton,

90
00:06:53,789 --> 00:06:56,749
they should come to Hertfordshire
and reside in the neighbourhood.

91
00:06:56,833 --> 00:07:00,127
Haye Park might do,
if the Gouldings would quit it.

92
00:07:00,587 --> 00:07:03,881
Or the great house at Stoke,
if the drawing-rooms were larger.

93
00:07:03,965 --> 00:07:09,011
- Or Purvis Lodge.
- Oh, no dear, not Purvis Lodge!

94
00:07:09,429 --> 00:07:11,764
The attics are dreadful!

95
00:07:11,848 --> 00:07:14,767
Mrs Bennet, before you take any,

96
00:07:14,851 --> 00:07:18,521
or all of these houses,
let us come to a right understanding.

97
00:07:18,605 --> 00:07:22,358
Into one house in the neighbourhood
they shall never have admittance.

98
00:07:22,442 --> 00:07:26,695
(FATHER): Mr and Mrs Wickham
will never be welcome to Longbourn.

99
00:07:45,632 --> 00:07:48,884
(LYDIA): Lord! It seems an age
since we were at Longbourn.

100
00:07:48,969 --> 00:07:51,345
Here you all are, just the same!

101
00:07:51,429 --> 00:07:55,307
My dear, dear Lydia, at last!

102
00:07:55,392 --> 00:08:00,104
Oh, I do believe you've grown!
Oh, how we have missed you.

103
00:08:00,188 --> 00:08:02,481
We've been far too
merry to miss any of you!

104
00:08:03,900 --> 00:08:08,487
Here we are! Haven't I caught myself
a handsome husband?

105
00:08:08,572 --> 00:08:13,534
Indeed you have, my love!
You are very welcome, sir.

106
00:08:13,869 --> 00:08:17,079
You are all goodness and kindness,
ma'am, as always.

107
00:08:17,372 --> 00:08:19,081
Oh, let me give you a kiss, then!

108
00:08:23,420 --> 00:08:25,254
Well, shall we go in?

109
00:08:31,011 --> 00:08:34,263
No, Jane. I take your place now.

110
00:08:34,347 --> 00:08:37,641
You must go lower,
because I am a married woman!

111
00:08:39,102 --> 00:08:40,603
"Mrs Wickham"!

112
00:08:42,647 --> 00:08:44,815
Lord, how droll that sounds!

113
00:09:04,711 --> 00:09:06,837
How do you like my husband, Lizzy?

114
00:09:06,922 --> 00:09:10,799
I believe you envy me.
Was he not a favourite of yours once?

115
00:09:11,343 --> 00:09:13,219
(LIZZY): Not at all.

116
00:09:13,303 --> 00:09:15,221
A pity we didn't all go to Brighton.

117
00:09:15,305 --> 00:09:18,182
I could have got
husbands for all my sisters!

118
00:09:18,266 --> 00:09:22,561
Thank you, but I don't particularly
like your way of getting husbands.

119
00:09:26,149 --> 00:09:29,151
Isn't my husband a fine horseman?

120
00:09:29,236 --> 00:09:33,155
Colonel Forster said he has as good
a seat as any officer in the regiment.

121
00:09:35,992 --> 00:09:38,118
I wished he could wear
his red coat at the wedding,

122
00:09:38,203 --> 00:09:41,121
and have a guard of honour,

123
00:09:41,206 --> 00:09:43,749
but the officers could not
be spared from duty.

124
00:09:43,833 --> 00:09:47,503
There was no one there
but my aunt and uncle and Mr Darcy.

125
00:09:47,921 --> 00:09:49,380
Mr Darcy?

126
00:09:51,341 --> 00:09:56,929
- (LIZZY): Mr Darcy was at your wedding?
- Oh, yes. Someone had to be groomsman.

127
00:09:57,013 --> 00:10:01,850
I had much rather it had been Denny
or one of our friends... Oh, Lord!

128
00:10:04,187 --> 00:10:05,562
Oh, Lord, I forgot.

129
00:10:05,647 --> 00:10:09,316
I wasn't to say a word!
And I promised them so faithfully.

130
00:10:10,068 --> 00:10:11,652
What'll Wickham say now?

131
00:10:13,029 --> 00:10:15,322
It was supposed to be a secret!

132
00:10:23,540 --> 00:10:24,957
(LIZZY): My dear Aunt, pray write

133
00:10:25,041 --> 00:10:28,419
and let me understand
how he should have been there.

134
00:10:28,503 --> 00:10:30,504
Unless you, too,
are bound in the secrecy

135
00:10:30,588 --> 00:10:33,215
which Lydia seems to think necessary.

136
00:10:33,675 --> 00:10:38,053
My dear niece, I must confess myself
surprised by your letter.

137
00:10:38,638 --> 00:10:41,265
If you are in ignorance
of the part that Mr Darcy

138
00:10:41,349 --> 00:10:43,225
played in bringing about the marriage,

139
00:10:43,310 --> 00:10:49,064
let me enlighten you at once.
Mr Darcy paid us an unexpected visit...

140
00:10:50,317 --> 00:10:54,445
..and so, my dear Lizzy,
Mr Darcy would brook no opposition.

141
00:10:54,529 --> 00:10:59,450
He insisted on doing everything himself
and bearing the entirety of the expense.

142
00:10:59,909 --> 00:11:03,162
Nothing was to be done
that he did not do himself.

143
00:11:03,663 --> 00:11:07,333
Your uncle, instead of being allowed
to be of use to his niece,

144
00:11:07,417 --> 00:11:09,793
had to accept having the credit of it.

145
00:11:09,878 --> 00:11:12,421
I must be allowed to insist on this.

146
00:11:13,381 --> 00:11:16,425
The fault is mine,
and so must the remedy be.

147
00:11:17,093 --> 00:11:18,385
It was through my mistaken pride

148
00:11:18,470 --> 00:11:21,805
that Mr Wickham's character
has not been made known.

149
00:11:23,141 --> 00:11:27,061
Had I not thought it beneath me
to lay my private actions open,

150
00:11:27,145 --> 00:11:30,356
his character would have been exposed.

151
00:11:30,815 --> 00:11:34,234
Mr Darcy, I really believe you take
too much upon yourself.

152
00:11:34,444 --> 00:11:36,487
I must insist on this, sir.

153
00:11:36,571 --> 00:11:40,115
I assure you that in this matter,
argument is fruitless.

154
00:11:40,200 --> 00:11:43,786
The responsibility is mine. I must
have it, sir. I shall not give way.

155
00:11:50,502 --> 00:11:52,086
My dear sister!

156
00:11:54,339 --> 00:11:56,548
I'm afraid I'm interrupting
your solitary reverie.

157
00:11:56,633 --> 00:11:58,300
You are, indeed.

158
00:11:58,927 --> 00:12:01,887
But it doesn't follow
that the interruption must be unwelcome.

159
00:12:01,971 --> 00:12:06,350
I should be sorry if it were.
You and I were always good friends.

160
00:12:08,103 --> 00:12:09,561
True.

161
00:12:10,313 --> 00:12:14,149
Then shall we take
a turn together, sister?

162
00:12:20,073 --> 00:12:23,283
I was surprised to see
Darcy in town last month.

163
00:12:23,368 --> 00:12:25,911
We passed each other several times.

164
00:12:26,830 --> 00:12:29,498
I wonder what he could be doing there.

165
00:12:30,041 --> 00:12:34,002
Perhaps preparing for the wedding...
with Miss de Bourgh.

166
00:12:34,587 --> 00:12:36,296
Yes. Yes, perhaps.

167
00:12:36,798 --> 00:12:39,675
Must have been something particular,
to take him there this time of year.

168
00:12:39,759 --> 00:12:41,176
Undoubtedly.

169
00:12:45,849 --> 00:12:48,600
Did you see him
while you were at Lambton?

170
00:12:48,685 --> 00:12:50,894
I understood
from the Gardiners that you had.

171
00:12:50,979 --> 00:12:53,522
Yes. He introduced us to his sister.

172
00:12:54,732 --> 00:12:57,860
- Did you like her?
- Yes, very much indeed.

173
00:12:58,361 --> 00:13:00,112
Well, I have heard
that she is uncommonly

174
00:13:00,196 --> 00:13:02,239
improved within this last year or two.

175
00:13:03,158 --> 00:13:05,576
When I last saw her,
she was not very promising.

176
00:13:06,369 --> 00:13:09,455
I'm glad you liked her.
I hope she'll turn out well.

177
00:13:09,539 --> 00:13:13,333
I dare say she will.
She has got over the most trying age.

178
00:13:15,503 --> 00:13:18,422
- Did you go by Kympton?
- I don't recollect...

179
00:13:18,506 --> 00:13:22,092
I mention it because it was the living
I should have had.

180
00:13:22,886 --> 00:13:25,721
How should you have
liked making sermons?

181
00:13:27,098 --> 00:13:29,057
Exceedingly well.

182
00:13:29,726 --> 00:13:31,185
I did hear that there was a time

183
00:13:31,269 --> 00:13:35,689
when sermon making was not
so palatable to you as at present.

184
00:13:35,773 --> 00:13:37,733
That you actually
declared your resolution

185
00:13:37,817 --> 00:13:41,361
of never taking orders
and were compensated accordingly.

186
00:13:42,071 --> 00:13:43,238
Well.

187
00:13:45,700 --> 00:13:49,286
Oh come, Mr Wickham,
we are brother and sister, you know.

188
00:13:49,746 --> 00:13:52,206
Let us not quarrel about the past.

189
00:14:20,360 --> 00:14:26,323
- Oh, Lydia, when shall we meet again?
- Not these two or three years, perhaps.

190
00:14:26,407 --> 00:14:30,661
Not these two or three years.
Oh, what shall I do?

191
00:14:31,120 --> 00:14:35,541
And Mr Bennet is so cruel as to refuse
to take us into the North Country!

192
00:14:35,625 --> 00:14:39,711
- I should refuse to go in any case.
- Hold your tongue, girl!

193
00:14:39,963 --> 00:14:43,382
Oh, Lydia!
You will write to me often, won't you?

194
00:14:43,466 --> 00:14:48,095
I don't know. We married women
don't have much time for writing.

195
00:14:48,179 --> 00:14:51,932
My sisters may write to me.
They will have nothing better to do.

196
00:14:52,016 --> 00:14:55,811
Oh, Lydia!
Mr Wickham, take care of my girl!

197
00:14:55,895 --> 00:14:58,689
I shall, ma'am,
to the very best of my ability.

198
00:14:58,773 --> 00:15:00,190
And thank you, ma'am, and to you, sir,

199
00:15:00,275 --> 00:15:03,735
for your continued
kindness and hospitality.

200
00:15:04,362 --> 00:15:07,197
And to you, my dear sisters-in-law.

201
00:15:07,282 --> 00:15:09,825
And now as dear to me
as sisters ever could be.

202
00:15:10,952 --> 00:15:13,161
But, the carriage awaits.

203
00:15:13,246 --> 00:15:16,456
Duty and honour call me to the North.
So, come, my dear!

204
00:15:22,505 --> 00:15:27,259
Let us say not farewell,
but as the French have it: Au revoir!

205
00:15:36,019 --> 00:15:38,854
He's as fine a fellow as ever I saw!

206
00:15:38,938 --> 00:15:42,149
He simpers and smirks,
and makes love to us all.

207
00:15:42,525 --> 00:15:44,610
I am prodigiously proud of him.

208
00:15:44,694 --> 00:15:49,364
I defy even Sir William Lucas
to produce such a son-in-law.

209
00:17:00,269 --> 00:17:03,897
(MRS PHILIPS): Sister!Sister!
Have you heard the news?

210
00:17:03,981 --> 00:17:06,441
Mr Bingley is coming
back to Netherfield,

211
00:17:06,526 --> 00:17:09,277
and the whole town is talking about it!

212
00:17:31,926 --> 00:17:35,929
I do assure you, this news
does not affect me, truly, Lizzy.

213
00:17:37,140 --> 00:17:41,643
I am glad of one thing.
That he doesn't bring any ladies.

214
00:17:42,520 --> 00:17:46,356
If it is merely a shooting party,
we shall not see him often.

215
00:17:46,983 --> 00:17:52,154
Not that I am afraid of myself... but
I dread other people's remarks, Lizzy.

216
00:17:52,238 --> 00:17:57,242
Then I shall venture none...
however sorely I am tempted.

217
00:17:59,454 --> 00:18:02,456
It is hard that the man
can't come to a house

218
00:18:02,540 --> 00:18:04,791
he's legally rented,
without raising all this speculation.

219
00:18:04,876 --> 00:18:06,918
That is just what I think.

220
00:18:07,670 --> 00:18:10,630
- Then we shall leave him to himself.
- Yes.

221
00:18:16,137 --> 00:18:18,013
Stop it, Lizzy.

222
00:18:21,517 --> 00:18:26,062
Three days he has been in the
neighbourhood, and still he shuns us!

223
00:18:26,522 --> 00:18:31,485
I say it's all your father's fault!
He would not do his duty and call,

224
00:18:31,569 --> 00:18:34,154
so you shall die old maids,

225
00:18:34,238 --> 00:18:38,116
and we shall be turned out by the
Collinses to starve in the hedgerows!

226
00:18:38,201 --> 00:18:42,788
You promised last year that if I went to
see him, he'd marry one of my daughters,

227
00:18:42,872 --> 00:18:44,664
but it all came to nothing.

228
00:18:44,749 --> 00:18:47,292
I won't be sent on
a fool's errand again!

229
00:18:49,253 --> 00:18:52,589
Mamma! Mamma, look!
I think he is coming!

230
00:18:58,930 --> 00:19:02,140
Is it really him? I believe it must be!

231
00:19:02,225 --> 00:19:04,976
He is come, Jane! He is come at last.

232
00:19:05,061 --> 00:19:07,979
Put on your blue gown.
No, stay where you are!

233
00:19:08,064 --> 00:19:09,314
(KITTY): Who's with him?

234
00:19:09,398 --> 00:19:12,692
I don't know, dear.
Some acquaintance, I suppose!

235
00:19:12,777 --> 00:19:15,195
It looks like that man
who used to be with him before.

236
00:19:15,279 --> 00:19:18,490
Mr... You know, that tall proud one.

237
00:19:20,243 --> 00:19:22,035
(MOTHER): Mr Darcy!

238
00:19:22,578 --> 00:19:23,912
I believe it is.

239
00:19:24,872 --> 00:19:29,334
Well, any friend of Mr Bingley's will
always be welcome here, to be sure.

240
00:19:29,418 --> 00:19:34,422
But I must say I hate the sight of him!
But I am determined to be civil.

241
00:19:35,049 --> 00:19:37,175
If only because the man
is a friend of Bingley's,

242
00:19:37,260 --> 00:19:40,720
but no more than civil.
Sit up straight, Jane!

243
00:19:40,847 --> 00:19:42,389
Pull your shoulders back.

244
00:19:42,473 --> 00:19:45,225
A man could go a long way
without seeing a figure like yours,

245
00:19:45,309 --> 00:19:47,561
if you'd make the most of it.

246
00:19:56,404 --> 00:19:59,239
Mr Bingley and Mr Darcy, ma'am.

247
00:20:04,787 --> 00:20:07,873
Mr Bingley, you are very, very welcome.

248
00:20:07,957 --> 00:20:09,708
How do you do, Mrs Bennet. I...

249
00:20:09,792 --> 00:20:14,129
It's far too long since you were here,
and very kind of you to call.

250
00:20:14,213 --> 00:20:15,922
Mr Bennet, of course, would have

251
00:20:16,007 --> 00:20:18,967
paid his addresses
before this, were it not...

252
00:20:19,051 --> 00:20:22,888
Well, here you are! I am delighted!

253
00:20:23,306 --> 00:20:26,558
And Mr Darcy, you are welcome, too.

254
00:20:33,983 --> 00:20:37,277
(MOTHER): We began to be afraid
you would never come back.

255
00:20:37,361 --> 00:20:39,279
People did say,
you meant to quit the place

256
00:20:39,363 --> 00:20:43,825
by Michaelmas,
but I hope that is not true.

257
00:20:43,993 --> 00:20:46,453
Ring the bell for tea, Kitty.

258
00:20:46,537 --> 00:20:49,789
A great many changes have taken place
since you went away.

259
00:20:49,874 --> 00:20:54,169
Miss Lucas is married.
And one of my own daughters!

260
00:20:54,462 --> 00:20:57,464
You've heard of it
or read it in the papers?

261
00:20:57,548 --> 00:20:58,590
Yes, indeed...

262
00:20:58,674 --> 00:21:00,592
It was not put in properly.

263
00:21:00,676 --> 00:21:04,387
It only said: "Lately, George Wickham,
Esq. to Miss Lydia Bennet",

264
00:21:04,472 --> 00:21:08,516
without a syllable said about
who her father was, or where she lived!

265
00:21:08,601 --> 00:21:11,686
Now they are gone to Newcastle,
and there they are to stay.

266
00:21:11,771 --> 00:21:13,438
I don't know how long.

267
00:21:13,522 --> 00:21:16,733
I expect you've heard
he's gone into the regulars.

268
00:21:17,526 --> 00:21:19,319
Thank Heaven he has some friends,

269
00:21:19,403 --> 00:21:22,447
though perhaps not as many
as he deserves!

270
00:21:24,408 --> 00:21:27,160
Do you mean to stay long
in the neighbourhood on this visit?

271
00:21:28,204 --> 00:21:31,122
Our plans are not yet firmly settled,

272
00:21:31,207 --> 00:21:35,585
but I hope,
I hope we shall stay some weeks.

273
00:21:37,672 --> 00:21:40,548
I hope very much
we shall stay a few weeks.

274
00:21:41,968 --> 00:21:43,343
At the very least.

275
00:21:43,427 --> 00:21:46,763
(MOTHER): When you've
killed your own birds,

276
00:21:46,847 --> 00:21:48,306
I beg you would come here and shoot

277
00:21:48,391 --> 00:21:50,809
as many as you please
on Mr Bennet's manor.

278
00:21:50,893 --> 00:21:54,396
I'm sure he'll be happy to oblige you!

279
00:21:56,065 --> 00:21:59,818
I suppose you may bring your friends,
if you will.

280
00:22:14,291 --> 00:22:17,585
(JANE): Now that this first meeting
is over, I feel at ease.

281
00:22:17,795 --> 00:22:18,920
Good!

282
00:22:19,547 --> 00:22:21,089
Now I know my own strength,

283
00:22:21,173 --> 00:22:24,426
and I shall never again
be embarrassed by his coming.

284
00:22:24,760 --> 00:22:30,223
We shall be able to meet now as...
common and indifferent acquaintances.

285
00:22:31,142 --> 00:22:35,270
Yes, very indifferent! Jane, take care.

286
00:22:36,731 --> 00:22:39,858
Don't think me to be
in any danger now, Lizzy.

287
00:22:39,942 --> 00:22:42,152
I think you are in very great danger

288
00:22:42,236 --> 00:22:45,321
of making him as much in love
with you as ever.

289
00:22:55,708 --> 00:22:58,835
You tell me now that
she was in London all those months?

290
00:22:58,919 --> 00:23:00,795
And you concealed it from me?

291
00:23:00,880 --> 00:23:03,923
Yes. I can offer no justification.

292
00:23:04,008 --> 00:23:05,884
It was an arrogant presumption,
based on a failure

293
00:23:05,968 --> 00:23:09,220
to recognise your true feelings
and Miss Bennet's.

294
00:23:12,016 --> 00:23:16,728
I should never have interfered. It was
wrong of me, Bingley, and I apologise.

295
00:23:17,438 --> 00:23:21,441
- You admit that you were in the wrong?
- Utterly and completely.

296
00:23:22,318 --> 00:23:24,486
Then... I have you blessing?

297
00:23:25,571 --> 00:23:27,572
Do you need my blessing?

298
00:23:28,074 --> 00:23:31,993
No. But I should like to know
I have it all the same.

299
00:23:32,536 --> 00:23:34,120
Then go to it.

300
00:23:51,514 --> 00:23:55,183
Bring me my horse at once. Quick, man!

301
00:24:04,944 --> 00:24:06,069
(MOTHER): Jane!

302
00:24:06,153 --> 00:24:08,738
Jane! Oh, my dear Jane!

303
00:24:10,366 --> 00:24:12,867
- Mamma, what's the matter?
- He is come!

304
00:24:12,952 --> 00:24:16,329
- Who is come?
- Mr Bingley, of course!

305
00:24:16,413 --> 00:24:21,709
Make haste, make haste, hurry down!
Oh, gracious, you are not half dressed!

306
00:24:21,794 --> 00:24:24,129
Hill! Hill!

307
00:24:24,213 --> 00:24:27,507
Oh, where is Hill?

308
00:24:30,594 --> 00:24:34,139
Never mind, Sarah. You must come to
Miss Bennet this moment!

309
00:24:34,223 --> 00:24:37,350
Come along and help her
on with her gown!

310
00:24:37,434 --> 00:24:38,810
Mamma! Mamma!

311
00:24:38,894 --> 00:24:42,939
Where is my new locket that Lydia
brought me? Mary, have you seen it?

312
00:24:43,023 --> 00:24:46,067
I shouldn't know it if I saw it.
I care nothing for such baubles.

313
00:24:46,152 --> 00:24:48,987
Oh, never mind your locket, girl!

314
00:24:49,071 --> 00:24:51,906
Jane, stir yourself.
He is here, he is here!

315
00:24:51,991 --> 00:24:56,077
We will be down as soon as we can.
Let Kitty go down, she is forwarder.

316
00:24:56,162 --> 00:25:00,874
Hang Kitty! What has she to do with it?
Jane, be quick!

317
00:25:00,958 --> 00:25:03,042
Where is your muslin dress?

318
00:25:03,127 --> 00:25:06,796
(MOTHER): Hill! Hill! Where is Hill?

319
00:25:15,306 --> 00:25:17,515
So Mr Darcy is gone to town?

320
00:25:17,600 --> 00:25:20,560
Yes, ma'am.
He left quite early this morning.

321
00:25:40,915 --> 00:25:42,957
What's the matter, mamma?

322
00:25:43,417 --> 00:25:45,668
Why do you keep winking at me?

323
00:25:46,629 --> 00:25:48,046
What am I to do?

324
00:25:48,130 --> 00:25:51,174
Wink at you?
Why should I wink at you, child?

325
00:25:51,258 --> 00:25:55,803
What a notion! Why should I be winking
at my own daughter, pray?

326
00:25:57,681 --> 00:25:59,849
But now you ask, it puts me in mind.

327
00:25:59,934 --> 00:26:03,436
I do have something
I would speak to you about.

328
00:26:04,647 --> 00:26:06,397
Come, come with me.

329
00:26:07,775 --> 00:26:09,567
And you, Mary. Come!

330
00:26:29,838 --> 00:26:31,506
Miss Elizabeth...

331
00:26:32,633 --> 00:26:34,968
(HILL): You're needed upstairs.

332
00:27:06,208 --> 00:27:09,961
Please let me go to Jane.
I promised I would stay with her.

333
00:27:10,045 --> 00:27:14,257
Stay where you are.
Five more minutes will do the trick.

334
00:27:35,654 --> 00:27:39,407
- Oh, I am so sorry.
- No. No, don't go, Lizzy.

335
00:27:41,618 --> 00:27:43,619
(BINGLEY WHISPERS SOMETHING INAUDIBLE)

336
00:27:52,463 --> 00:27:53,963
Well?

337
00:27:56,008 --> 00:27:57,383
Oh, Lizzy!

338
00:27:59,094 --> 00:28:02,138
I'm so happy! It is too much!

339
00:28:02,222 --> 00:28:05,641
It is too much!
Why can't everyone be as happy as I am?

340
00:28:07,936 --> 00:28:11,606
He loves me, Lizzy. He loves me!

341
00:28:11,690 --> 00:28:13,608
Of course he does!

342
00:28:13,692 --> 00:28:17,362
He told me he loved me all the time.
He didn't believe...

343
00:28:17,446 --> 00:28:21,324
I must tell mamma.
He is gone to papa already!

344
00:28:21,408 --> 00:28:26,537
Oh, Lizzy, could you believe
things would end in this happy way?

345
00:28:26,622 --> 00:28:30,583
- I could, and I do!
- I must go to my mother.

346
00:28:31,210 --> 00:28:32,585
Oh, Lizzy!

347
00:28:33,295 --> 00:28:37,173
To know I shall be giving such
pleasure to all my dear family!

348
00:28:37,800 --> 00:28:40,301
How shall I bear so much happiness?

349
00:29:00,406 --> 00:29:03,408
Come back tomorrow, sir,
if you can bear to.

350
00:29:03,492 --> 00:29:05,076
Come and shoot with me, if you will.

351
00:29:05,160 --> 00:29:09,122
There are few men
whose society I can tolerate well.

352
00:29:09,206 --> 00:29:11,207
I believe you may be one of them.

353
00:29:11,291 --> 00:29:13,668
Thank you, sir.
I shall be very happy to.

354
00:29:13,752 --> 00:29:16,504
Very well, very well.
Get along with you.

355
00:29:23,429 --> 00:29:25,513
Till tomorrow, then!

356
00:29:34,440 --> 00:29:39,986
Jane, congratulations.
You will be a very happy woman.

357
00:29:40,070 --> 00:29:41,779
Thank you, father.

358
00:29:42,906 --> 00:29:46,451
- I believe I shall.
- Well, well, you're a good girl.

359
00:29:46,535 --> 00:29:49,996
I've no doubt
you'll do very well together.

360
00:29:50,080 --> 00:29:54,000
You're each of you so complying
that nothing will ever be resolved on.

361
00:29:54,084 --> 00:29:55,168
Papa!

362
00:29:55,252 --> 00:29:57,253
So easy that
every servant will cheat you!

363
00:29:57,337 --> 00:29:58,337
No, indeed!

364
00:29:58,422 --> 00:30:01,716
So generous that
you will exceed your income.

365
00:30:01,800 --> 00:30:04,635
Exceed their income!
What are you talking about?

366
00:30:04,720 --> 00:30:08,431
Don't you know that
he has 5,000 a year?!

367
00:30:10,392 --> 00:30:14,770
Oh, my dear, dear Jane! I am so happy!

368
00:30:14,855 --> 00:30:16,856
Oh, I knew how it would be!

369
00:30:16,940 --> 00:30:20,067
I was sure you could not be
so beautiful for nothing.

370
00:30:20,152 --> 00:30:23,446
He is the handsomest
man that was ever seen!

371
00:30:30,954 --> 00:30:35,708
Oh, Lizzy.
If only I could see you as happy.

372
00:30:35,792 --> 00:30:39,670
If there were only
such another man for you.

373
00:30:39,755 --> 00:30:43,591
If you were to give me forty such men...

374
00:30:43,675 --> 00:30:46,636
..I could never be as happy as you.

375
00:30:46,720 --> 00:30:51,349
Till I have your goodness,
I can never have your happiness.

376
00:30:51,433 --> 00:30:56,187
But... perhaps if I have very good luck,

377
00:30:56,271 --> 00:30:59,232
I may in time meet
with another Mr Collins!

378
00:31:21,421 --> 00:31:25,633
Mamma, Lizzy, come and look!
The most enormous carriage has arrived.

379
00:31:31,348 --> 00:31:34,725
(LADY CATHERINE):
What an extremely small hall!

380
00:31:34,810 --> 00:31:36,769
(HILL): If you'll wait here,
your ladyship,

381
00:31:36,853 --> 00:31:38,563
I'll tell my mistress you're here.

382
00:31:38,647 --> 00:31:41,482
(LADY CATHERINE): No, I will not wait!

383
00:31:41,567 --> 00:31:45,152
(LADY CATHERINE): Where is she?
Is this the drawing-room?

384
00:31:46,697 --> 00:31:49,323
Lady Catherine de Bourgh.

385
00:32:08,093 --> 00:32:10,720
That lady, I suppose, is your mother.

386
00:32:11,888 --> 00:32:16,434
Yes, she is. Mamma,
this is Lady Catherine de Bourgh.

387
00:32:19,646 --> 00:32:22,815
And that, I suppose,
is one of your sisters.

388
00:32:22,899 --> 00:32:27,194
Yes, ma'am.
She is my youngest girl but one.

389
00:32:27,279 --> 00:32:29,196
My youngest of all is lately married.

390
00:32:30,157 --> 00:32:32,533
You have a very small park here.

391
00:32:34,703 --> 00:32:40,374
And this must be a most inconvenient
sitting-room for the evening in summer.

392
00:32:40,459 --> 00:32:43,461
Why, the windows are full west.

393
00:32:44,713 --> 00:32:50,301
Indeed, they are, your ladyship,
but we never sit in here after dinner.

394
00:32:50,385 --> 00:32:53,137
- We have...
- Miss Bennet.

395
00:32:54,431 --> 00:32:56,223
There seemed to be a prettyish kind of

396
00:32:56,308 --> 00:33:00,019
little wilderness on
one side of your lawn.

397
00:33:00,103 --> 00:33:03,189
I should be glad to take a turn in it...

398
00:33:03,273 --> 00:33:07,068
if you would favour me
with your company.

399
00:33:33,929 --> 00:33:39,058
You can be at no loss to understand
the reason for my journey, Miss Bennet.

400
00:33:39,142 --> 00:33:40,434
You are mistaken, madam.

401
00:33:40,519 --> 00:33:44,980
I'm quite unable to account
for the honour of seeing you here.

402
00:33:45,065 --> 00:33:49,777
Miss Bennet, you ought to know
I am not to be trifled with.

403
00:33:50,821 --> 00:33:55,199
But however insincere you choose to be,
you shall not find me so.

404
00:33:55,867 --> 00:34:00,246
A report of an alarming nature
reached me two days ago.

405
00:34:00,330 --> 00:34:05,459
I was told, not only that your sister
was to be most advantageously married,

406
00:34:05,544 --> 00:34:08,587
but that you, Miss Elizabeth Bennet,

407
00:34:08,672 --> 00:34:12,967
would be soon afterwards
united to my nephew Mr Darcy!

408
00:34:14,636 --> 00:34:17,847
Though I know it must be
a scandalous falsehood,

409
00:34:17,931 --> 00:34:20,725
I instantly resolved
on setting off for this place,

410
00:34:20,809 --> 00:34:23,185
to make my sentiments known to you.

411
00:34:23,270 --> 00:34:24,353
If you believed it to be impossible,

412
00:34:24,438 --> 00:34:28,107
I wonder what your ladyship
would propose by coming here?

413
00:34:28,191 --> 00:34:33,320
At once to insist upon having
such a report universally contradicted!

414
00:34:33,405 --> 00:34:36,490
Your coming to Longbourn
will be taken as a confirmation of it,

415
00:34:36,575 --> 00:34:37,950
if such a report exists.

416
00:34:38,034 --> 00:34:42,580
This is not to be borne. Miss Bennet,
I insist on being satisfied!

417
00:34:42,664 --> 00:34:45,458
Has my nephew made you
an offer of marriage?

418
00:34:45,542 --> 00:34:47,585
Your ladyship declared
it to be impossible.

419
00:34:47,669 --> 00:34:51,756
It ought to be so,
but your arts and allurements

420
00:34:51,840 --> 00:34:55,801
may have made him forget
what he owes to himself and the family.

421
00:34:55,886 --> 00:34:57,970
You may have drawn him in!

422
00:34:58,054 --> 00:35:01,015
If I had, I should be
the last to confess it.

423
00:35:01,725 --> 00:35:04,852
Miss Bennet, do you know who I am?

424
00:35:06,688 --> 00:35:10,149
I have not been accustomed
to such language as this.

425
00:35:11,026 --> 00:35:13,652
I am almost the nearest relation he has,

426
00:35:13,737 --> 00:35:17,156
and I am entitled to know
all his nearest concerns.

427
00:35:17,240 --> 00:35:18,949
But not to know mine,

428
00:35:19,034 --> 00:35:21,827
nor will such behaviour
as this induce me to be explicit.

429
00:35:21,912 --> 00:35:25,122
Let me be rightly understood.

430
00:35:25,207 --> 00:35:26,832
This match, to which you have

431
00:35:26,917 --> 00:35:30,628
the presumption to aspire,
can never take place.

432
00:35:30,712 --> 00:35:35,382
Mr Darcy is engaged to my daughter.
Now, what have you to say?

433
00:35:35,467 --> 00:35:37,635
Only this: that if he is so,

434
00:35:37,719 --> 00:35:41,472
you can have no reason
to suppose he'll make an offer to me.

435
00:35:41,640 --> 00:35:44,433
The engagement between them
is of a peculiar kind.

436
00:35:44,518 --> 00:35:47,978
From their infancy they have been
intended for each other.

437
00:35:48,063 --> 00:35:52,066
It was the favourite wish of his mother
as well as hers.

438
00:35:52,150 --> 00:35:55,861
While she was in her cradle,
we planned the union.

439
00:35:55,946 --> 00:35:59,365
And now to be prevented by the upstart

440
00:35:59,449 --> 00:36:02,660
pretensions of a young woman
without family,

441
00:36:02,744 --> 00:36:08,666
connections or fortune?
Is this to be endured? It shall not be!

442
00:36:08,750 --> 00:36:12,503
Your alliance would be a disgrace!

443
00:36:12,587 --> 00:36:16,006
Your name would never even be
mentioned by any of us.

444
00:36:16,341 --> 00:36:19,009
These would be heavy
misfortunes, indeed.

445
00:36:19,094 --> 00:36:23,472
Obstinate, headstrong girl!
I am ashamed of you.

446
00:36:24,641 --> 00:36:28,018
I have not been in the habit
of brooking disappointment!

447
00:36:28,103 --> 00:36:31,188
That will make your ladyship's
situation at present more pitiable,

448
00:36:31,273 --> 00:36:33,190
but it will have no effect on me.

449
00:36:33,275 --> 00:36:36,151
I will not be interrupted!

450
00:36:36,945 --> 00:36:39,613
If you were sensible,
you would not wish to quit

451
00:36:39,698 --> 00:36:42,366
the sphere in which
you have been brought up!

452
00:36:42,450 --> 00:36:44,660
Lady Catherine, in marrying your nephew

453
00:36:44,744 --> 00:36:48,539
I should not consider myself
as quitting that sphere.

454
00:36:48,623 --> 00:36:50,875
He's a gentleman,
I'm a gentleman's daughter.

455
00:36:50,959 --> 00:36:52,418
So far we are equal.

456
00:36:52,502 --> 00:36:55,713
But who was your mother?
Your uncles and aunts?

457
00:36:55,797 --> 00:36:58,549
Do not imagine me
ignorant of their condition.

458
00:36:58,633 --> 00:37:03,262
If your nephew does not object to my
connections, they can be nothing to you.

459
00:37:03,346 --> 00:37:07,683
Tell me once and for all,
are you engaged to him?

460
00:37:10,645 --> 00:37:12,313
I am not.

461
00:37:16,318 --> 00:37:20,404
And will you promise me never
to enter into such an engagement?

462
00:37:21,573 --> 00:37:23,574
I will make no promise of the kind,

463
00:37:23,658 --> 00:37:27,369
and I beg you not to
importune me any further on the subject.

464
00:37:27,454 --> 00:37:32,541
Not so hasty, if you please!
I have another objection.

465
00:37:32,626 --> 00:37:38,047
Your youngest sister's infamous
elopement. I know it all!

466
00:37:38,131 --> 00:37:42,051
Is such a girl to be
my nephew's sister-in-law?

467
00:37:42,135 --> 00:37:46,013
Are the shades of Pemberley
to be thus polluted?

468
00:37:46,097 --> 00:37:48,849
You can have nothing further to say.

469
00:37:48,934 --> 00:37:52,186
You have insulted me
by every possible method.

470
00:37:52,270 --> 00:37:54,730
I must beg to return to the house.

471
00:37:55,023 --> 00:38:00,778
You have no regard then,
for the honour and credit of my nephew?

472
00:38:01,529 --> 00:38:04,907
Unfeeling, selfish girl!

473
00:38:05,241 --> 00:38:08,035
You refuse to oblige me?

474
00:38:09,371 --> 00:38:14,375
You refuse the claims of duty,
honour, gratitude?

475
00:38:16,544 --> 00:38:22,216
You are determined to ruin him,
and make him the contempt of the world!

476
00:38:22,300 --> 00:38:26,220
I am only resolved to act in a manner
which will constitute my own happiness,

477
00:38:26,304 --> 00:38:29,223
without reference to you,
or to any person

478
00:38:29,307 --> 00:38:31,558
so wholly unconnected with me.

479
00:38:32,227 --> 00:38:35,229
And this is your final resolve?

480
00:38:37,148 --> 00:38:39,441
Very well. I shall know how to act!

481
00:38:49,035 --> 00:38:51,537
I take no leave of you, Miss Bennet.

482
00:38:51,621 --> 00:38:56,500
I send no compliments to your mother.
You deserve no such attention.

483
00:38:58,294 --> 00:39:02,756
I am most seriously displeased.
Drive on!

484
00:39:22,485 --> 00:39:25,446
Lizzy, Lizzy! I was going to look
for you. Come into my room.

485
00:39:32,454 --> 00:39:36,874
I received a letter this morning,
which has astonished me exceedingly.

486
00:39:36,958 --> 00:39:40,419
- From Mr Collins.
- What can he have to say?

487
00:39:40,503 --> 00:39:42,129
He begins with congratulations

488
00:39:42,213 --> 00:39:44,381
on the approaching nuptials
of my eldest daughter,

489
00:39:44,466 --> 00:39:46,300
but I shan't sport
with your intelligence

490
00:39:46,384 --> 00:39:49,219
by reading his remarks on that topic.

491
00:39:49,304 --> 00:39:51,597
Ah, yes. Here, here, here.

492
00:39:51,681 --> 00:39:54,266
"Your daughter Elizabeth,
it is presumed,"

493
00:39:54,350 --> 00:39:56,727
"will not long bear the name of Bennet,"

494
00:39:56,811 --> 00:40:01,899
"after her elder sister has resigned it,
and the chosen partner of her fate"

495
00:40:01,983 --> 00:40:03,484
"may be reasonably looked up to"

496
00:40:03,568 --> 00:40:06,695
"as one of the most
illustrious personages in the land."

497
00:40:07,822 --> 00:40:12,076
Can you guess who he means, Lizzy?
Now it comes out.

498
00:40:12,160 --> 00:40:15,120
"My motive for cautioning you
is as follows:"

499
00:40:15,205 --> 00:40:17,581
"his aunt, Lady Catherine de Bourgh,"

500
00:40:17,665 --> 00:40:21,001
"does not look on the match
with a friendly eye."

501
00:40:21,669 --> 00:40:26,381
Mr Darcy, you see, is the man.
Mr Darcy of all men!

502
00:40:27,926 --> 00:40:32,387
Who never looks at a woman except to see
a blemish! Are you not diverted?

503
00:40:32,722 --> 00:40:33,722
Yes.

504
00:40:33,807 --> 00:40:38,268
Mr Darcy, who probably never
looked at you in his life before!

505
00:40:38,353 --> 00:40:42,397
This is admirable! But Lizzy,
you look as if you didn't enjoy it.

506
00:40:43,525 --> 00:40:44,900
You're not going to be Missish now,

507
00:40:44,984 --> 00:40:47,611
and pretend to be affronted
by an idle report?

508
00:40:47,695 --> 00:40:51,532
Oh, no, I am excessively diverted.
It's all so strange.

509
00:40:51,616 --> 00:40:54,743
What said Lady Catherine de Bourgh?

510
00:40:54,828 --> 00:40:57,579
I suppose she came
to refuse her consent?

511
00:40:58,039 --> 00:40:59,665
What do we live for,

512
00:40:59,749 --> 00:41:04,128
but to make sport for our neighbours
and laugh at them in our turn?

513
00:41:05,588 --> 00:41:07,131
True, true.

514
00:41:16,724 --> 00:41:19,059
Mr Bingley and Mr Darcy, ma'am.

515
00:41:20,562 --> 00:41:23,147
- Good day to you!
- Mr Bingley.

516
00:41:25,859 --> 00:41:30,112
(BINGLEY): This is a fine day.
Should we perhaps all walk to Meryton?

517
00:41:37,453 --> 00:41:39,329
(KITTY): Lizzy!

518
00:41:39,414 --> 00:41:42,958
Do you mind if I run
to call on Maria Lucas?

519
00:41:43,042 --> 00:41:44,751
No, not at all.

520
00:41:59,475 --> 00:42:02,269
Mr Darcy.

521
00:42:02,353 --> 00:42:06,940
I can go no longer without thanking you
for your kindness to my poor sister.

522
00:42:07,817 --> 00:42:09,026
Ever since I have known of it,

523
00:42:09,110 --> 00:42:14,865
I've been most anxious
to tell you how grateful I am,

524
00:42:14,949 --> 00:42:17,201
for my family and for myself.

525
00:42:19,329 --> 00:42:23,749
You must not blame my aunt
for telling me. Lydia betrayed it first,

526
00:42:23,833 --> 00:42:26,960
and then I couldn't rest
till I knew everything.

527
00:42:27,420 --> 00:42:31,465
I know what trouble and what
mortification it must have cost you.

528
00:42:33,259 --> 00:42:37,596
Please let me say this,
please allow me to thank you,

529
00:42:37,680 --> 00:42:42,309
on behalf of all my family, since they
don't know to whom they are indebted.

530
00:42:44,687 --> 00:42:48,232
If you will thank me,
let it be for yourself alone.

531
00:42:48,316 --> 00:42:50,859
Your family owes me nothing.

532
00:42:50,944 --> 00:42:53,445
As much as I respect them,
I believe I thought only of you.

533
00:42:56,991 --> 00:42:58,575
You're too generous to trifle with me.

534
00:42:58,660 --> 00:43:01,912
If your feelings are what they were
last April, tell me so.

535
00:43:02,455 --> 00:43:05,457
My affections and wishes are unchanged.

536
00:43:06,793 --> 00:43:10,170
But one word from you will silence me
on this subject forever.

537
00:43:11,464 --> 00:43:13,674
Oh, my feelings...

538
00:43:13,758 --> 00:43:15,467
My feelings are...

539
00:43:16,427 --> 00:43:19,263
I am ashamed to remember
what I said then.

540
00:43:20,223 --> 00:43:22,432
My feelings are so different.

541
00:43:23,309 --> 00:43:27,479
In fact, they are quite the opposite.

542
00:43:41,160 --> 00:43:44,246
Lady Catherine told me
of her meeting with you.

543
00:43:44,706 --> 00:43:47,249
I may say that her disclosure
had quite the opposite effect

544
00:43:47,333 --> 00:43:48,709
to the one she had intended.

545
00:43:50,295 --> 00:43:51,670
It taught me to hope,
that I had scarcely

546
00:43:51,754 --> 00:43:54,298
ever allowed myself to hope before.

547
00:43:54,966 --> 00:43:58,969
Had you absolutely decided against me,
you would have acknowledged it openly.

548
00:43:59,053 --> 00:44:03,223
Yes, you know enough of my frankness
to believe me capable of that!

549
00:44:04,100 --> 00:44:06,310
After abusing you so to your face,

550
00:44:06,394 --> 00:44:09,354
I could have no scruple
in abusing you to all your relations.

551
00:44:09,439 --> 00:44:11,898
What did you say of me
that I did not deserve?

552
00:44:12,608 --> 00:44:14,526
My behaviour at the time
was unpardonable.

553
00:44:14,610 --> 00:44:17,195
I can hardly think of it
without abhorrence.

554
00:44:18,906 --> 00:44:21,658
Your reproof I shall never forget.

555
00:44:21,743 --> 00:44:25,829
"Had you behaved in a more
gentleman-like manner".

556
00:44:25,913 --> 00:44:28,332
How those words have tortured me!

557
00:44:28,416 --> 00:44:31,835
I had no idea of their being
taken such a way.

558
00:44:31,919 --> 00:44:33,003
I can easily believe it.

559
00:44:33,087 --> 00:44:36,089
You thought me devoid
of every proper feeling, I am sure.

560
00:44:36,924 --> 00:44:40,135
The turn of your countenance
I shall never forget.

561
00:44:40,595 --> 00:44:41,970
You said I could not have addressed you

562
00:44:42,055 --> 00:44:44,848
in any way that would
have induced you to accept me.

563
00:44:44,932 --> 00:44:47,809
Do not repeat what I said then!

564
00:44:48,853 --> 00:44:51,980
No, I have been a selfish
being all my life.

565
00:44:52,065 --> 00:44:53,690
As a child I was given good principles,

566
00:44:53,775 --> 00:44:56,985
but was left to follow them
in pride and conceit.

567
00:44:57,695 --> 00:45:00,739
And such I might still have been,
but for you.

568
00:45:02,200 --> 00:45:04,368
Dearest, loveliest Elizabeth!

569
00:45:15,546 --> 00:45:17,714
(JANE): Engaged to Mr Darcy!

570
00:45:19,050 --> 00:45:22,219
No, you are joking. It is impossible!

571
00:45:23,638 --> 00:45:25,847
This is a wretched beginning!

572
00:45:25,932 --> 00:45:29,226
If you don't believe me,
I'm sure no one else will.

573
00:45:29,644 --> 00:45:34,189
Indeed, I am in earnest.
He still loves me, and we are engaged.

574
00:45:35,149 --> 00:45:38,777
It can't be true.
I know how much you dislike him!

575
00:45:38,861 --> 00:45:41,780
No, it is all forgotten!

576
00:45:41,864 --> 00:45:45,242
Perhaps I didn't always love him
as well as I do now.

577
00:45:45,326 --> 00:45:49,121
But... in such cases as these
a good memory is unpardonable.

578
00:45:50,248 --> 00:45:52,624
Dearest Lizzy, do be serious.

579
00:45:53,751 --> 00:45:56,711
How long have you loved him?

580
00:45:56,796 --> 00:45:59,756
It's been coming on so gradually,
I hardly know.

581
00:46:01,676 --> 00:46:04,719
But I believe I must date it
from my first seeing

582
00:46:04,804 --> 00:46:06,972
his beautiful grounds at Pemberley!

583
00:46:08,307 --> 00:46:10,225
Lizzy!

584
00:46:12,895 --> 00:46:16,898
Are you out of your senses
to be accepting this man, Lizzy?

585
00:46:18,693 --> 00:46:20,986
Have you not always hated him?

586
00:46:21,863 --> 00:46:24,781
- Papa...
- I've given him my consent.

587
00:46:24,866 --> 00:46:29,411
He's the kind of man, indeed, to whom
I should never dare refuse anything.

588
00:46:30,746 --> 00:46:33,957
But let me advise you
to think the better of it.

589
00:46:34,041 --> 00:46:36,376
I know your disposition, Lizzy.

590
00:46:37,003 --> 00:46:39,963
My child, let me not have the grief

591
00:46:40,047 --> 00:46:43,800
of seeing you unable
to respect your partner in life.

592
00:46:45,011 --> 00:46:47,721
He is rich, but will he make you happy?

593
00:46:48,639 --> 00:46:51,683
Have you objections apart
from your belief in my indifference?

594
00:46:51,767 --> 00:46:56,021
None whatever. We all know him to be
a proud, unpleasant sort of man,

595
00:46:56,772 --> 00:46:59,524
but this would be nothing
if you really liked him.

596
00:47:00,526 --> 00:47:03,904
I do. I do like him.

597
00:47:05,490 --> 00:47:06,907
I love him.

598
00:47:08,659 --> 00:47:13,413
Indeed, he has no improper pride.
He is perfectly amiable.

599
00:47:14,874 --> 00:47:17,501
If you only knew his generous nature.

600
00:47:19,086 --> 00:47:21,796
I didn't always love him,

601
00:47:21,881 --> 00:47:24,341
but I love him now so very dearly.

602
00:47:26,302 --> 00:47:29,179
He is truly the best man
I have ever known.

603
00:47:32,934 --> 00:47:38,647
Well, my dear, if this be the case,
he deserves you.

604
00:47:40,399 --> 00:47:44,569
I could not have parted with you
to anyone less worthy, Lizzy.

605
00:47:53,204 --> 00:47:57,707
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here
in the sight of God,

606
00:47:57,792 --> 00:48:00,752
and in the face of this congregation,

607
00:48:00,836 --> 00:48:05,632
to join together this man
and this woman...

608
00:48:08,302 --> 00:48:12,889
..and this man and this woman

609
00:48:12,974 --> 00:48:17,310
in holy matrimony,
which is an honourable estate,

610
00:48:17,395 --> 00:48:21,314
instituted by God
in the time of man's innocency,

611
00:48:21,399 --> 00:48:27,237
signifying unto us the mystical union
that is between Christ and His church,

612
00:48:27,321 --> 00:48:32,409
and therefore is not by any
to be enterprised lightly, or wantonly,

613
00:48:32,493 --> 00:48:36,788
to satisfy man's
carnal lusts and appetites,

614
00:48:36,872 --> 00:48:42,377
but reverently, discreetly,
advisedly, soberly,

615
00:48:42,461 --> 00:48:44,212
and in the fear of God,

616
00:48:44,297 --> 00:48:48,133
duly considering the causes
for which matrimony was ordained.

617
00:48:49,093 --> 00:48:53,263
First, it was ordained
for the procreation of children.

618
00:48:55,850 --> 00:49:00,103
Secondly, as a remedy against sin,

619
00:49:00,187 --> 00:49:02,606
and to avoid fornication.

620
00:49:03,733 --> 00:49:05,317
Thirdly,

621
00:49:05,401 --> 00:49:11,114
for the mutual society, help and comfort
that the one ought to have of the other,

622
00:49:11,198 --> 00:49:15,118
both in prosperity and adversity,

623
00:49:15,202 --> 00:49:20,874
into which holy estate these persons
present come now to be joined.

624
00:50:12,426 --> 00:50:14,761
Three daughters married!

625
00:50:14,845 --> 00:50:18,264
Oh, Mr Bennet,
God has been very good to us!

626
00:50:18,349 --> 00:00:00,-001
Yes, so it would seem.

