1
00:01:07,651 --> 00:01:09,235
If you please, ma'am!

2
00:01:09,319 --> 00:01:13,030
There are two gentlemen and a lady
waiting upon you in the parlour.

3
00:01:13,115 --> 00:01:15,575
One of them is Mr Darcy.

4
00:01:18,162 --> 00:01:21,038
Thank you.
Tell them I shall come directly.

5
00:01:32,718 --> 00:01:34,010
Mr Darcy.

6
00:01:38,640 --> 00:01:40,558
I hope that you have not been
waiting long.

7
00:01:40,642 --> 00:01:42,018
Not at all.

8
00:01:43,061 --> 00:01:45,813
May I introduce my sister Georgiana?

9
00:01:52,112 --> 00:01:54,864
Georgiana,
this is Miss Elizabeth Bennet.

10
00:01:57,075 --> 00:01:58,618
How do you do?

11
00:01:58,744 --> 00:02:00,369
I'm very pleased
to meet you, Miss Darcy.

12
00:02:00,454 --> 00:02:03,247
- I've heard so much about you.
- And I about you.

13
00:02:03,499 --> 00:02:04,999
Mr Bingley is here with us,

14
00:02:05,083 --> 00:02:08,085
and very desirous to see you as well.
He insisted on accompanying us.

15
00:02:08,837 --> 00:02:10,463
May I summon him?

16
00:02:10,547 --> 00:02:13,549
Of course!
I should like to see him very much.

17
00:02:18,847 --> 00:02:23,434
I understand that you are fond of music,
and play very well.

18
00:02:23,519 --> 00:02:26,187
Oh, no. Not play very well.

19
00:02:26,647 --> 00:02:29,232
I mean, but I am very fond of music.

20
00:02:30,192 --> 00:02:32,735
I should dearly love to hear you
play and sing.

21
00:02:32,820 --> 00:02:35,238
My brother has told me
he has rarely heard anything

22
00:02:35,322 --> 00:02:37,490
that gave him more pleasure.

23
00:02:38,575 --> 00:02:39,992
Well, you shall.

24
00:02:40,077 --> 00:02:44,080
But I warn you, your brother
has grossly exaggerated my talents.

25
00:02:44,414 --> 00:02:46,791
No doubt for some mischievous reason.

26
00:02:46,875 --> 00:02:49,418
Oh, no. That could not be so.

27
00:02:49,962 --> 00:02:53,756
My brother never exaggerates.
He always tells the absolute truth.

28
00:02:54,383 --> 00:02:58,135
Except that sometimes I think
he is a little too kind to me.

29
00:02:58,762 --> 00:03:00,388
An ideal elder brother, then.

30
00:03:00,472 --> 00:03:04,141
Oh, yes! I couldn't imagine
a better or a kinder one.

31
00:03:05,769 --> 00:03:07,270
You make me feel quite envious.

32
00:03:07,354 --> 00:03:10,273
I have no brothers at all.
Only four sisters.

33
00:03:10,357 --> 00:03:12,984
I should have liked to have a sister.

34
00:03:14,653 --> 00:03:15,862
(BINGLEY): Miss Bennet!

35
00:03:15,946 --> 00:03:20,658
I was so delighted when Darcy told me
you were not five miles from Pemberley!

36
00:03:20,993 --> 00:03:22,535
How do you do?

37
00:03:23,120 --> 00:03:26,205
- I see you are well.
- Very well, thank you.

38
00:03:26,456 --> 00:03:29,166
Good, good, excellent! And your family?

39
00:03:29,626 --> 00:03:31,460
- Very well, sir.
- Yes?

40
00:03:33,714 --> 00:03:37,592
Pray, tell me. Are all your sisters
still at Longbourn?

41
00:03:38,260 --> 00:03:42,096
All except one.
My youngest sister is at Brighton.

42
00:03:42,180 --> 00:03:43,264
Ah.

43
00:03:46,518 --> 00:03:48,561
It seems too long...

44
00:03:49,605 --> 00:03:52,940
..it is too long, since I had
the pleasure of speaking to you.

45
00:03:53,025 --> 00:03:56,986
- It must be several months.
- It is above eight months at least.

46
00:03:57,696 --> 00:04:00,239
We have not met
since the 26th of November,

47
00:04:00,324 --> 00:04:02,491
when we were dancing together
at Netherfield.

48
00:04:02,951 --> 00:04:04,327
I think you must be right.

49
00:04:04,411 --> 00:04:08,247
I don't think I can remember
a happier time

50
00:04:08,332 --> 00:04:11,042
than those short months
I spent in Hertfordshire.

51
00:04:11,126 --> 00:04:15,338
Miss Bennet, my sister has a request
to make of you.

52
00:04:17,883 --> 00:04:22,595
Miss Bennet, my brother and I
would be honoured

53
00:04:22,679 --> 00:04:26,974
if you and your aunt and uncle would be
our guests at Pemberley for dinner.

54
00:04:28,310 --> 00:04:32,772
- Would tomorrow evening be convenient?
- Thank you, we shall be delighted.

55
00:04:34,191 --> 00:04:38,361
I can answer for Mr and Mrs Gardiner.
We have no fixed engagements.

56
00:04:38,487 --> 00:04:43,574
- And shall we hear you play?
- If you insist upon it, yes, you shall.

57
00:04:43,825 --> 00:04:46,202
(LIZZY PLAYS THE PIANO AND SINGS)

58
00:04:46,286 --> 00:04:49,622
("VOI, CHE SAPETE"
FROM "THE MARRIAGE OF FIGARO")

59
00:05:29,746 --> 00:05:31,622
Absolutely marvellous!

60
00:05:37,087 --> 00:05:40,673
Will you not play again?
You played that song so beautifully.

61
00:05:40,757 --> 00:05:43,718
Not very beautifully,
not faithfully at all.

62
00:05:44,261 --> 00:05:46,512
You must have seen
how I fudged and slurred my way

63
00:05:46,596 --> 00:05:48,931
through the difficult passages.

64
00:05:50,100 --> 00:05:53,853
- It's a beautiful instrument, though.
- My brother gave it to me.

65
00:05:53,937 --> 00:05:58,065
- He is so good. I don't deserve it.
- I am sure you do.

66
00:05:59,443 --> 00:06:03,404
Your brother thinks you do,
and as you know, he is never wrong.

67
00:06:07,868 --> 00:06:12,538
Now, it's your turn.
Oh, I absolutely insist!

68
00:06:12,622 --> 00:06:15,041
In front of all these people?

69
00:06:15,125 --> 00:06:17,793
I will play,
but please don't make me sing.

70
00:06:17,878 --> 00:06:18,961
If you like.

71
00:06:25,302 --> 00:06:28,679
Pray, Miss Eliza, are the Militia
still quartered at Meryton?

72
00:06:28,764 --> 00:06:31,640
No, they are encamped at Brighton
for the summer.

73
00:06:32,100 --> 00:06:34,935
That must be a great loss
for your family.

74
00:06:36,146 --> 00:06:39,023
We're enduring it
as best we can, Miss Bingley.

75
00:06:39,107 --> 00:06:41,317
I should have thought
one gentleman's absence

76
00:06:41,401 --> 00:06:43,944
might have caused particular pangs.

77
00:06:46,406 --> 00:06:48,657
I can't imagine who you mean.

78
00:06:48,950 --> 00:06:51,744
I understood that certain ladies
found the society

79
00:06:51,828 --> 00:06:54,580
of Mr Wickham curiously agreeable.

80
00:06:56,666 --> 00:06:59,919
I'm so sorry. I'm neglecting you.

81
00:07:00,003 --> 00:07:02,463
How can you play
with no one to turn the pages.

82
00:07:06,009 --> 00:07:07,635
There, allow me.

83
00:07:58,728 --> 00:08:01,689
(MISS BINGLEY): How very ill
Eliza Bennet looked this evening!

84
00:08:01,815 --> 00:08:05,818
I've never seen anyone so much altered
as she is since the winter.

85
00:08:05,902 --> 00:08:10,030
- Quite so, my dear.
- She is grown so brown and coarse.

86
00:08:10,115 --> 00:08:12,741
Louisa and I were agreeing
that we should hardly know her.

87
00:08:12,826 --> 00:08:14,994
What do you say, Mr Darcy?

88
00:08:15,620 --> 00:08:17,413
I noticed no great difference.

89
00:08:18,248 --> 00:08:20,124
She is, I suppose, a little tanned.

90
00:08:20,208 --> 00:08:23,252
Hardly surprising
when one travels in the summer.

91
00:08:23,336 --> 00:08:27,339
For my part, I must confess,
I never saw any beauty in her face.

92
00:08:27,674 --> 00:08:31,969
Her features are not at all handsome.
Her complexion has no brilliancy.

93
00:08:32,053 --> 00:08:34,847
Her teeth are tolerable, I suppose,

94
00:08:34,931 --> 00:08:37,308
but nothing out of the common way.

95
00:08:39,352 --> 00:08:43,772
And as for her eyes, which I have
sometimes heard called fine,

96
00:08:44,399 --> 00:08:47,109
I could never perceive anything
extraordinary in them.

97
00:08:49,362 --> 00:08:52,823
And in her air
there is a self-sufficiency

98
00:08:52,908 --> 00:08:55,618
without fashion,
which I find intolerable.

99
00:08:56,119 --> 00:08:57,119
I think...

100
00:08:57,204 --> 00:08:58,829
When we first knew her in Hertfordshire,

101
00:08:58,914 --> 00:09:02,249
how amazed we all were
to find her a reputed beauty!

102
00:09:02,834 --> 00:09:05,836
I particularly recall you, Mr Darcy,

103
00:09:05,921 --> 00:09:08,547
one night after they had been dining
at Netherfield,

104
00:09:08,632 --> 00:09:14,011
saying: "She a beauty?
I should as soon call her mother a wit!"

105
00:09:17,098 --> 00:09:19,683
(MISS BINGLEY): But afterwards
she seemed to improve on you.

106
00:09:20,477 --> 00:09:23,479
I even believe you thought her
rather pretty at one time.

107
00:09:24,689 --> 00:09:28,275
Yes, I did.
That was only when I first knew her.

108
00:09:28,860 --> 00:09:30,861
For many months now
I have considered her

109
00:09:30,946 --> 00:09:33,530
one of the handsomest women
of my acquaintance.

110
00:10:33,925 --> 00:10:35,843
No, no, the green one.

111
00:10:36,886 --> 00:10:38,554
Yes, that will do.

112
00:10:41,141 --> 00:10:43,225
Good. No, never mind that.

113
00:11:09,586 --> 00:11:12,713
If you please, ma'am.
The post's just come.

114
00:11:12,797 --> 00:11:14,089
Thank you, Hannah.

115
00:11:15,425 --> 00:11:17,843
A good girl, that. Very obliging.

116
00:11:19,262 --> 00:11:23,557
Two letters from Jane. At last!
I had been wondering why we hadn't...

117
00:11:24,434 --> 00:11:26,435
This one was misdirected at first.

118
00:11:26,519 --> 00:11:30,439
No wonder, for she wrote the direction
very ill, indeed!

119
00:11:31,941 --> 00:11:34,943
Would you be angry
if I beg you to postpone our outing?

120
00:11:35,028 --> 00:11:38,364
Not at all!
Of course you want to read your letters.

121
00:11:38,448 --> 00:11:42,284
We will walk to the church
and call back in an hour.

122
00:11:42,452 --> 00:11:44,620
Thank you, you're very kind!

123
00:12:01,805 --> 00:12:03,138
(JANE): My dearest Lizzy,

124
00:12:03,223 --> 00:12:06,558
I hope your journey has been
as delightful as you anticipated.

125
00:12:06,643 --> 00:12:09,937
We all miss you.
Our father most of all, I believe.

126
00:12:10,438 --> 00:12:12,398
I have hardly had time to write.

127
00:12:12,482 --> 00:12:15,150
My nephews and nieces
have taken almost every moment!

128
00:12:15,735 --> 00:12:18,112
But they are such dear children.

129
00:12:18,613 --> 00:12:22,616
Our mother indeed finds their exuberance
a little trying for her nerves.

130
00:12:23,952 --> 00:12:24,993
Mamma...

131
00:12:25,578 --> 00:12:29,790
She spends much of the day above stairs
in her room, or with Mrs Philips.

132
00:12:30,417 --> 00:12:33,127
Dearest Lizzy, since writing the above,

133
00:12:33,211 --> 00:12:37,256
something has occurred
of a most unexpected and serious nature.

134
00:12:38,299 --> 00:12:41,885
But I'm afraid of alarming you.
Be assured we are all well.

135
00:12:42,470 --> 00:12:45,222
What I have to say
relates to poor Lydia.

136
00:12:45,515 --> 00:12:46,682
Lydia!

137
00:12:49,144 --> 00:12:53,439
An express came at twelve last night,
just as we were all gone to bed.

138
00:12:56,901 --> 00:13:01,405
(MOTHER): Mr Bennet, what is it?
Are we to be murdered in our beds?

139
00:13:12,000 --> 00:13:14,543
(JANE): The letter
was from Colonel Forster,

140
00:13:14,627 --> 00:13:18,505
to inform us that Lydia was gone off
to Scotland with one of his officers.

141
00:13:19,257 --> 00:13:22,050
To own the truth... with Wickham.

142
00:13:23,470 --> 00:13:24,845
Oh, Lydia!

143
00:13:25,388 --> 00:13:29,349
Oh, Mr Bennet, we are all ruined!

144
00:13:30,185 --> 00:13:32,561
You will imagine our surprise and shock.

145
00:13:33,563 --> 00:13:37,274
To Kitty, however, it does not seem
so wholly unexpected.

146
00:13:40,111 --> 00:13:44,948
I am very, very sorry.
So imprudent a match on both sides!

147
00:13:45,783 --> 00:13:47,201
But I'm willing to hope the best,

148
00:13:47,285 --> 00:13:49,453
and that his character
has been misunderstood.

149
00:13:49,913 --> 00:13:51,997
I wish I could believe it.

150
00:13:55,001 --> 00:13:57,628
His choice is disinterested at least.

151
00:13:57,962 --> 00:14:00,672
He must know
that our father can give him nothing.

152
00:14:01,049 --> 00:14:05,177
Yes, that is true.
But how could he do this?

153
00:14:06,638 --> 00:14:08,764
She is silly enough for anything.

154
00:14:09,933 --> 00:14:12,017
But Wickham to love Lydia?

155
00:14:13,269 --> 00:14:15,229
Marry Lydia?

156
00:14:15,480 --> 00:14:18,690
There is one lady
I shall be very loath to part from.

157
00:14:24,989 --> 00:14:28,617
We expect them soon
returned from Gretna, man and wife.

158
00:14:29,619 --> 00:14:32,996
I must conclude. I cannot be away
from our poor mother long.

159
00:14:33,623 --> 00:14:36,500
I shall write again
as soon as I have news.

160
00:14:39,295 --> 00:14:43,924
My dearest Lizzy, I hardly know
what to write, but I have bad news!

161
00:14:45,009 --> 00:14:48,011
Imprudent as a marriage would be,
we now fear worse:

162
00:14:49,097 --> 00:14:51,265
That it has not taken place.

163
00:14:51,349 --> 00:14:54,476
That Wickham never intended
to marry Lydia at all!

164
00:14:54,561 --> 00:14:56,395
Great God, I knew it!

165
00:14:57,772 --> 00:14:59,231
I cannot think so ill of him.

166
00:14:59,315 --> 00:15:02,442
I can. Poor Lydia.

167
00:15:03,403 --> 00:15:05,320
Poor stupid girl!

168
00:15:08,116 --> 00:15:11,868
Colonel Forster said he feared
that Wickham was not to be trusted.

169
00:15:12,495 --> 00:15:15,330
(DARCY): She was then
but fifteen years old.

170
00:15:17,125 --> 00:15:18,584
They were traced as far as Clapham.

171
00:15:18,668 --> 00:15:22,129
Father has gone with Colonel Forster
to try to discover them.

172
00:15:23,631 --> 00:15:27,426
I cannot help but beg you all
to come here as soon as possible!

173
00:15:27,719 --> 00:15:30,512
Oh, yes! Where is my uncle?

174
00:15:35,685 --> 00:15:37,519
If you please, ma'am.

175
00:15:40,356 --> 00:15:41,398
Miss Bennet, I hope this...

176
00:15:41,482 --> 00:15:43,859
I beg your pardon.
I must find Mr Gardiner.

177
00:15:44,152 --> 00:15:48,697
- On business that cannot be delayed.
- Good God! What is the matter?

178
00:15:50,825 --> 00:15:53,493
Of course I will not detain you,
but let me go,

179
00:15:53,578 --> 00:15:56,038
or let the servant go
and fetch Mr and Mrs Gardiner.

180
00:15:56,205 --> 00:15:58,457
- You cannot go yourself.
- I must...

181
00:15:58,541 --> 00:16:02,127
Come. I insist.
This will be for the best. Hello there!

182
00:16:03,087 --> 00:16:05,464
Have Mr and Mrs Gardiner
fetched here at once.

183
00:16:05,548 --> 00:16:07,674
- They walked in the direction of...
- ..the church.

184
00:16:08,551 --> 00:16:10,802
Yes, sir, at once.

185
00:16:14,474 --> 00:16:16,141
You are not well.
May I not call a doctor?

186
00:16:16,225 --> 00:16:20,228
No. I am well. I am well.

187
00:16:21,564 --> 00:16:25,025
Is there nothing you can take
for your present relief?

188
00:16:25,652 --> 00:16:29,488
A glass of wine? Can I get you one?
Truly, you look very ill.

189
00:16:30,323 --> 00:16:34,618
No, I thank you. There is nothing
the matter with me. I am quite well.

190
00:16:35,870 --> 00:16:37,954
I am only distressed
by some dreadful news,

191
00:16:38,039 --> 00:16:40,415
which I have just received
from Longbourn.

192
00:16:45,713 --> 00:16:48,131
- I am sorry. Forgive me.
- No, no.

193
00:16:50,677 --> 00:16:54,721
I have just received a letter from Jane,
with such dreadful news.

194
00:16:55,765 --> 00:16:58,308
It cannot be concealed from anyone.

195
00:17:00,895 --> 00:17:04,690
My youngest sister
has left all her friends,

196
00:17:06,943 --> 00:17:08,318
has eloped,

197
00:17:10,363 --> 00:17:12,948
has thrown herself into the power...

198
00:17:13,991 --> 00:17:15,617
..of Mr Wickham.

199
00:17:18,579 --> 00:17:21,707
They have run away together
from Brighton.

200
00:17:21,791 --> 00:17:24,251
You know him too well to doubt the rest.

201
00:17:25,294 --> 00:17:28,630
She has no money, no connections,

202
00:17:29,632 --> 00:17:31,758
nothing that can tempt him.

203
00:17:34,929 --> 00:17:37,848
When I think
that I might have prevented it!

204
00:17:38,683 --> 00:17:40,684
I, who knew what he was!

205
00:17:41,811 --> 00:17:45,522
Had his character been known,
this could not have happened.

206
00:17:46,482 --> 00:17:48,608
But it is all too late now.

207
00:17:49,152 --> 00:17:52,320
I am grieved, indeed. Grieved, shocked.

208
00:17:54,574 --> 00:17:58,034
- But is it certain? Absolutely certain?
- Oh, yes.

209
00:17:58,870 --> 00:18:01,830
They left Brighton together
on Sunday night.

210
00:18:03,583 --> 00:18:06,835
They were traced as far as London,
but not beyond.

211
00:18:07,170 --> 00:18:09,838
They are certainly not gone to Scotland.

212
00:18:09,922 --> 00:18:12,674
What has been attempted to recover her?

213
00:18:13,134 --> 00:18:15,343
My father has gone to London.

214
00:18:15,720 --> 00:18:19,222
And Jane writes to beg my uncle's
immediate assistance.

215
00:18:20,516 --> 00:18:23,643
I hope that we shall leave
within half an hour.

216
00:18:23,811 --> 00:18:25,645
But what can be done?

217
00:18:25,855 --> 00:18:28,231
I know that nothing can be done.

218
00:18:30,651 --> 00:18:33,361
How is such a man to be worked on?

219
00:18:34,489 --> 00:18:37,032
How are they even to be discovered?

220
00:18:39,202 --> 00:18:41,411
I have not the smallest hope.

221
00:18:42,205 --> 00:18:46,208
She is lost forever,
and our whole family must partake

222
00:18:46,292 --> 00:18:48,335
of her ruin and disgrace.

223
00:18:54,258 --> 00:18:57,511
I'm afraid you have long been desiring
my absence.

224
00:19:00,306 --> 00:19:03,600
This unfortunate affair will, I fear,
prevent my sister

225
00:19:03,684 --> 00:19:07,354
from having the pleasure
of seeing you at Pemberley today.

226
00:19:07,730 --> 00:19:08,980
Oh, yes.

227
00:19:10,733 --> 00:19:14,486
Be so kind as to apologise for us
to Miss Darcy.

228
00:19:16,739 --> 00:19:20,033
Say that urgent business
calls us home immediately.

229
00:19:21,285 --> 00:19:23,161
And if you would be so kind...

230
00:19:23,246 --> 00:19:26,581
as to conceal the unhappy truth
as long as possible.

231
00:19:27,708 --> 00:19:30,168
I know that it cannot be long.

232
00:19:31,629 --> 00:19:34,089
You may be assured of my secrecy.

233
00:19:35,258 --> 00:19:39,135
But I have stayed too long.
I shall leave you now.

234
00:19:40,137 --> 00:19:42,097
Yes. Thank you.

235
00:19:47,562 --> 00:19:48,812
Goodbye.

236
00:20:00,408 --> 00:20:02,325
I shall never see him again.

237
00:20:11,836 --> 00:20:16,631
Even if what you say of Wickham is true,
I still cannot believe this of Lydia.

238
00:20:16,799 --> 00:20:19,175
Ever since the militia came to Meryton,

239
00:20:19,260 --> 00:20:22,762
there's been nothing
but love and officers in her head.

240
00:20:23,222 --> 00:20:25,223
We must not assume the worst.

241
00:20:25,308 --> 00:20:28,518
It may yet be
that this is all a misunderstanding.

242
00:20:28,603 --> 00:20:30,896
Or just a passing folly
that her friends can hush up

243
00:20:30,980 --> 00:20:33,523
and will in time be quite forgotten.

244
00:20:34,984 --> 00:20:37,819
- It is possible, Lizzy!
- Indeed it is.

245
00:20:38,154 --> 00:20:40,530
Why would any young man
form a design against a girl

246
00:20:40,615 --> 00:20:43,241
who is not unprotected or friendless,

247
00:20:43,743 --> 00:20:46,620
and who is staying
in the Colonel's family?

248
00:20:46,871 --> 00:20:51,166
Look at it in any way you like.
The temptation is not worth the risk.

249
00:20:53,169 --> 00:20:55,921
Not perhaps of risking his own interest.

250
00:20:56,255 --> 00:20:59,841
But I do believe him capable
of risking everything else!

251
00:21:20,696 --> 00:21:23,531
You are very quiet this evening,
Mr Darcy.

252
00:21:23,950 --> 00:21:27,619
I hope you're not pining for the loss
of Miss Eliza Bennet.

253
00:21:27,703 --> 00:21:28,870
What?

254
00:21:30,539 --> 00:21:31,873
Excuse me.

255
00:21:59,902 --> 00:22:05,573
(THE GARDINER CHILDREN): There she is!
Mamma, mamma! Did you bring us anything?

256
00:22:10,788 --> 00:22:14,958
- Lizzy! I am so glad to see you.
- Has anything been heard?

257
00:22:15,042 --> 00:22:18,420
Not yet, but now that our uncle
has come, I hope all will be well.

258
00:22:18,504 --> 00:22:20,088
Father left for town on Tuesday,

259
00:22:20,172 --> 00:22:23,258
and we've only heard
that he has arrived in safety.

260
00:22:23,884 --> 00:22:27,053
Mamma has been asking for you
every five minutes.

261
00:22:27,138 --> 00:22:30,098
- How is she?
- She has not yet left her room.

262
00:22:31,308 --> 00:22:33,018
And you look pale.

263
00:22:33,936 --> 00:22:36,730
Oh, Jane,
how much you must have gone through!

264
00:22:36,856 --> 00:22:39,941
I am so happy to see you, Lizzy. Come.

265
00:22:43,946 --> 00:22:44,988
Oh!

266
00:22:46,282 --> 00:22:47,657
Oh, Lizzy!

267
00:22:48,242 --> 00:22:49,659
Oh, brother!

268
00:22:50,578 --> 00:22:53,413
We are all ruined forever!

269
00:22:54,832 --> 00:22:58,251
If only Mr Bennet
had taken us all to Brighton,

270
00:22:58,335 --> 00:23:00,086
none of this would have happened!

271
00:23:00,629 --> 00:23:02,630
I blame those Forsters!

272
00:23:02,798 --> 00:23:06,426
I am sure there was some great neglect
on their part,

273
00:23:06,677 --> 00:23:10,180
for she is not the kind of girl
to do that sort of thing,

274
00:23:10,264 --> 00:23:12,640
if she had been properly looked after!

275
00:23:12,725 --> 00:23:15,977
- Mamma.
- And now here is Mr Bennet gone away.

276
00:23:16,395 --> 00:23:19,147
I know he will fight Wickham,
and then he will be killed,

277
00:23:19,231 --> 00:23:21,649
and then what is to become of us all?

278
00:23:22,735 --> 00:23:27,447
Those Collinses will turn us out
before he is cold in his grave!

279
00:23:28,407 --> 00:23:32,911
And if you are not kind to us, brother,
I don't know what we shall do!

280
00:23:32,995 --> 00:23:36,581
Sister, calm down.
Nothing dreadful will happen!

281
00:23:37,500 --> 00:23:41,795
I'll be in London tomorrow, and we will
consult as to what is to be done.

282
00:23:41,879 --> 00:23:43,755
Yes, yes, that is it!

283
00:23:43,839 --> 00:23:48,551
You must find them out, and if they be
not married, you must make them marry.

284
00:23:48,677 --> 00:23:51,387
Above all, keep Mr Bennet from fighting!

285
00:23:51,472 --> 00:23:54,265
Mamma, I am sure
he does not mean to fight.

286
00:23:54,350 --> 00:23:56,267
Oh yes, he does!

287
00:23:56,644 --> 00:24:01,022
And Wickham will kill him for sure,
unless you can prevent it, brother!

288
00:24:01,565 --> 00:24:04,609
You must tell him
what a dreadful state I'm in!

289
00:24:04,693 --> 00:24:08,321
How I have such
tremblings and flutterings.

290
00:24:09,865 --> 00:24:14,285
Such spasms in my side and pains
in my head and beatings at my heart,

291
00:24:14,370 --> 00:24:17,705
that I can get no rest
either night or day!

292
00:24:17,790 --> 00:24:19,707
Sister, calm yourself.

293
00:24:19,792 --> 00:24:23,545
And tell Lydia not to give
any directions about wedding clothes

294
00:24:23,629 --> 00:24:28,049
till she's seen me, for she does
not know which are the best warehouses!

295
00:24:57,913 --> 00:25:00,290
(MARY): This is the most
unfortunate affair,

296
00:25:00,374 --> 00:25:02,417
and will probably be much talked of.

297
00:25:02,501 --> 00:25:04,836
(LIZZY): Yes, thank you, Mary.

298
00:25:04,920 --> 00:25:07,213
I think we have all
apprehended that much.

299
00:25:07,298 --> 00:25:09,632
We must stem the tide of malice,

300
00:25:09,717 --> 00:25:14,429
and pour into each other's wounded
bosoms the balm of sisterly consolation.

301
00:25:15,264 --> 00:25:18,266
Mary, pass the potatoes
to your aunt Gardiner.

302
00:25:18,475 --> 00:25:21,686
- I beg your pardon?
- (KITTY): Never mind. I will.

303
00:25:22,563 --> 00:25:24,230
Thank you, Kitty.

304
00:25:25,065 --> 00:25:28,985
That's the first kind word I've had
from anyone since Lydia went away.

305
00:25:29,069 --> 00:25:32,614
It is most unfair, for I have not
done anything naughty!

306
00:25:33,407 --> 00:25:36,492
And I don't see that Lydia has done
anything dreadful either.

307
00:25:36,577 --> 00:25:40,163
- Kitty, please!
- Unhappy as the event must be

308
00:25:40,539 --> 00:25:43,291
for Lydia,
we must draw from it this useful lesson:

309
00:25:43,417 --> 00:25:46,628
that loss of virtue
in a female is irretrievable.

310
00:25:46,879 --> 00:25:49,505
My dear Mary, this is hardly helpful.

311
00:25:49,673 --> 00:25:53,718
For a woman's reputation
is no less brittle than it is beautiful.

312
00:25:53,802 --> 00:25:57,680
Therefore we cannot be too guarded
in our behaviour

313
00:25:58,098 --> 00:26:00,850
towards the undeserving
of the other sex.

314
00:26:01,101 --> 00:26:03,019
Yes... thank you, Mary.

315
00:26:20,996 --> 00:26:25,375
Now, Jane... tell me everything about it
that I have not already heard.

316
00:26:27,878 --> 00:26:30,129
What did Colonel Forster say?

317
00:26:30,798 --> 00:26:35,218
Had they no apprehension about anything
before the elopement took place?

318
00:26:35,302 --> 00:26:39,555
Colonel Forster did own he suspected
some partiality on Lydia's side,

319
00:26:40,182 --> 00:26:42,642
but nothing to give him any alarm.

320
00:26:43,852 --> 00:26:46,020
Lizzy, I feel I am to blame.

321
00:26:46,730 --> 00:26:50,066
I urged you not to make
Wickham's bad conduct known.

322
00:26:50,526 --> 00:26:52,902
Now poor Lydia is suffering for it.

323
00:26:52,987 --> 00:26:57,407
No one else suspected him for a moment.
I am, I am to blame!

324
00:26:57,825 --> 00:26:59,909
You are not to blame!

325
00:26:59,994 --> 00:27:04,205
No more than I, or Mr Darcy
or anyone else deceived by Wickham.

326
00:27:05,708 --> 00:27:09,961
You have nothing to blame yourself for.
Others are culpable, not you.

327
00:27:12,548 --> 00:27:16,301
She wrote a note for Mrs Forster
before she went away.

328
00:27:21,974 --> 00:27:26,811
"My dear Harriet, you will laugh
when you know where I am gone,"

329
00:27:27,313 --> 00:27:29,814
"and I can't help laughing myself
at your surprise

330
00:27:29,898 --> 00:27:32,775
"tomorrow morning,
as soon as I am missed."

331
00:27:34,236 --> 00:27:36,070
(LYDIA): I'm going to Gretna Green,

332
00:27:36,155 --> 00:27:39,282
and if you can't guess with who,
I'll think you a simpleton,

333
00:27:39,658 --> 00:27:42,076
for there is but one man
in the world I love.

334
00:27:43,120 --> 00:27:45,079
Don't send them word
at Longbourn of my going.

335
00:27:45,164 --> 00:27:46,956
It will make the surprise
all the greater,

336
00:27:47,041 --> 00:27:50,251
when I write to them
and sign my name Lydia Wickham!

337
00:27:50,794 --> 00:27:54,756
What a good joke it will be.
I can scarcely write for laughing!

338
00:27:59,011 --> 00:28:01,346
Thoughtless, thoughtless Lydia!

339
00:28:02,222 --> 00:28:05,099
What a letter to have written
at such a moment.

340
00:28:05,184 --> 00:28:07,435
But at least she believed
they were to be married,

341
00:28:07,519 --> 00:28:10,480
whatever he might persuade her
to afterwards.

342
00:28:11,357 --> 00:28:14,359
Our poor father!
How he must have felt it.

343
00:28:16,111 --> 00:28:18,363
I never saw anyone so shocked.

344
00:28:19,531 --> 00:28:21,741
He couldn't speak for ten minutes.

345
00:28:21,825 --> 00:28:25,078
Mother was in hysterics,
and the house was in confusion.

346
00:28:26,121 --> 00:28:29,248
Lady Lucas has been very kind,
offering her services.

347
00:28:31,293 --> 00:28:33,503
She had better had stayed home!

348
00:28:33,587 --> 00:28:36,422
Assistance is impossible,
and condolence insufferable.

349
00:28:36,507 --> 00:28:39,842
Let her triumph over us at a distance
and be satisfied!

350
00:28:39,927 --> 00:28:41,469
That is unkind.

351
00:28:43,889 --> 00:28:47,433
- I am sure she meant well.
- Yes, perhaps she did.

352
00:28:49,812 --> 00:28:53,856
I am sorry.
It's just that I can't help but be...

353
00:28:56,485 --> 00:28:57,819
Oh, Jane.

354
00:28:58,779 --> 00:29:00,571
Jane, do you not see

355
00:29:00,656 --> 00:29:05,243
that more things have been ruined by
this business than Lydia's reputation?

356
00:29:28,600 --> 00:29:32,019
I have stayed too long.
I shall leave you now.

357
00:29:36,817 --> 00:29:39,068
(THERE IS A KNOCK ON THE DOOR)

358
00:29:40,904 --> 00:29:42,363
Come in!

359
00:29:44,074 --> 00:29:46,742
I thought you would not be in bed yet.

360
00:29:56,920 --> 00:30:00,465
I have been thinking about
what you said this afternoon.

361
00:30:00,549 --> 00:30:04,302
That it is not only Lydia's reputation
that has been ruined.

362
00:30:05,637 --> 00:30:07,555
I was angry and upset.

363
00:30:08,390 --> 00:30:11,058
I should not have said it.
It does no good to dwell on it.

364
00:30:11,226 --> 00:30:13,853
You meant, I suppose, that you and I,

365
00:30:14,438 --> 00:30:18,649
and Mary and Kitty,
have been tainted by association.

366
00:30:20,360 --> 00:30:22,361
That our chances
of making a good marriage

367
00:30:22,446 --> 00:30:25,656
have been materially damaged
by Lydia's disgrace.

368
00:30:29,077 --> 00:30:33,372
The chances of any of us making
a good marriage were never very great.

369
00:30:33,957 --> 00:30:37,251
And now I should say,
they are non- existent.

370
00:30:39,087 --> 00:30:41,172
No one will solicit
our society after this.

371
00:30:41,256 --> 00:30:43,257
Mr Darcy made that very clear to me.

372
00:30:43,759 --> 00:30:45,092
Mr Darcy?

373
00:30:46,512 --> 00:30:48,596
Does he know our troubles?

374
00:30:51,934 --> 00:30:55,728
He happened upon me
a moment after I first read your letter.

375
00:30:57,439 --> 00:31:00,191
He was very kind,
very gentleman-like...

376
00:31:01,777 --> 00:31:06,572
..but he made it very clear he wanted
nothing more than to be out of my sight.

377
00:31:10,452 --> 00:31:13,371
He will not be
renewing his addresses to me.

378
00:31:13,872 --> 00:31:17,458
He'll make very sure his friend
doesn't renew his to you.

379
00:31:17,626 --> 00:31:20,253
I never expected
Mr Bingley would renew his addresses.

380
00:31:20,337 --> 00:31:22,630
I am quite reconciled to that.

381
00:31:23,715 --> 00:31:27,218
Surely you do not desire
Mr Darcy's attentions, do you?

382
00:31:28,136 --> 00:31:30,638
No, no. I never sought them.

383
00:31:32,140 --> 00:31:35,309
But you do think
he was intending to renew them?

384
00:31:35,811 --> 00:31:38,604
You think he is still in love with you?

385
00:31:38,689 --> 00:31:40,231
I don't know.

386
00:31:41,316 --> 00:31:43,985
I don't know what he was two days ago.

387
00:31:44,570 --> 00:31:46,654
All I know is that now he,

388
00:31:47,948 --> 00:31:52,201
or any other respectable man,
will want nothing to do with any of us.

389
00:31:54,830 --> 00:31:56,956
(MUSIC DROWNS ALL DIALOGUE)

390
00:32:13,223 --> 00:32:16,017
Lord! Look who's coming!

391
00:32:16,101 --> 00:32:18,936
- Who is it, Kitty?
- Mr Collins, of course.

392
00:32:19,479 --> 00:32:22,231
I'm not going to sit with him
for anyone!

393
00:32:34,286 --> 00:32:38,122
I had hoped to condole
with your poor father and your mother.

394
00:32:38,206 --> 00:32:42,960
Father is still in London, and mother is
not yet well enough to leave her room.

395
00:32:43,045 --> 00:32:45,755
Ah. Ah.

396
00:32:49,509 --> 00:32:53,471
I feel myself called on,
not only by our relationship,

397
00:32:53,555 --> 00:32:55,890
but by my situation as a clergyman,

398
00:32:55,974 --> 00:33:00,770
to condole with you all on the grievous
affliction you are now suffering under.

399
00:33:01,563 --> 00:33:03,105
Thank you, sir.

400
00:33:03,190 --> 00:33:04,565
It has often been said

401
00:33:04,650 --> 00:33:07,735
that a friend in need
is a friend, indeed, sir.

402
00:33:09,780 --> 00:33:10,905
Yes.

403
00:33:12,866 --> 00:33:15,326
Be assured, ladies,
that Mrs Collins and myself

404
00:33:15,410 --> 00:33:18,579
sincerely sympathise with you
in your distress,

405
00:33:18,664 --> 00:33:21,248
which must be of the bitterest kind,

406
00:33:21,625 --> 00:33:25,169
proceeding from a cause
which no time can remove.

407
00:33:25,253 --> 00:33:29,382
The death of your sister would have been
a blessing in comparison.

408
00:33:29,633 --> 00:33:34,095
And it is more to be lamented,
because there is reason to suppose,

409
00:33:35,055 --> 00:33:37,098
my dear Charlotte informs me,

410
00:33:37,182 --> 00:33:40,643
that this licentiousness of behaviour
in your sister

411
00:33:40,727 --> 00:33:43,938
has proceeded from a faulty degree
of indulgence,

412
00:33:44,731 --> 00:33:49,193
though I am inclined to think that
her disposition must be naturally bad.

413
00:33:49,444 --> 00:33:54,073
Now, howsoever that may be,
you are grievously to be pitied...

414
00:33:57,619 --> 00:33:59,954
We are very grateful, sir, for your...

415
00:34:00,038 --> 00:34:04,208
..in which opinion I am joined
by Lady Catherine de Bourgh

416
00:34:04,292 --> 00:34:08,045
and her daughter, to whom
I have related the affair in full.

417
00:34:08,338 --> 00:34:12,842
They agree with me in apprehending
that this false step in one sister

418
00:34:13,593 --> 00:34:17,471
must be injurious
to the fortunes of all the others.

419
00:34:17,973 --> 00:34:22,852
"For who", as Lady Catherine herself
condescendingly says,

420
00:34:23,311 --> 00:34:27,148
"will connect themselves
with such a family?"

421
00:34:33,113 --> 00:34:34,780
Who, indeed, sir.

422
00:34:36,992 --> 00:34:40,494
Now, perhaps,
in view of that consideration,

423
00:34:40,579 --> 00:34:43,873
you may feel it would be unwise
to stay any longer.

424
00:34:47,252 --> 00:34:49,712
Well, perhaps you are right.

425
00:34:49,796 --> 00:34:52,590
Yes, perhaps you are right,
cousin Elizabeth.

426
00:34:53,008 --> 00:34:56,427
I always feel that a clergyman
cannot be too careful.

427
00:34:57,345 --> 00:35:00,431
Especially one so fortunate as to enjoy

428
00:35:00,515 --> 00:35:03,851
the condescension
and patronage of Lady Catherine.

429
00:35:05,270 --> 00:35:08,731
Your thoughtfulness does you credit,
cousin Elizabeth.

430
00:35:13,153 --> 00:35:17,448
I am very, very sorry for you all!

431
00:35:32,088 --> 00:35:35,049
- Insufferable man!
- I suppose he means well.

432
00:35:35,133 --> 00:35:37,218
You suppose wrongly, Jane.

433
00:35:38,220 --> 00:35:40,304
His purpose was to enjoy our misfortunes

434
00:35:40,388 --> 00:35:42,640
and congratulate himself
on his own happy situation!

435
00:35:42,724 --> 00:35:45,851
I think it kind of him
to condole with us.

436
00:35:52,234 --> 00:35:53,609
Is he gone?

437
00:35:54,945 --> 00:35:56,070
Yes.

438
00:35:56,738 --> 00:35:58,656
- Good!
- Forever, with any luck.

439
00:35:59,074 --> 00:36:02,660
(KITTY): Here's aunt Philips!
She can tell us the news from Meryton.

440
00:36:02,744 --> 00:36:06,705
- I doubt there's much we care to hear.
- Mother will be pleased.

441
00:36:08,291 --> 00:36:11,126
Well, girls, here's a to-do.

442
00:36:11,878 --> 00:36:13,671
Does your mother still keep to her bed?

443
00:36:13,755 --> 00:36:16,090
No, but she keeps to her room.

444
00:36:16,341 --> 00:36:20,344
Well, well, the less the servants hear
the better, I dare say.

445
00:36:21,096 --> 00:36:23,347
Come, let me to her, Jane,

446
00:36:23,431 --> 00:36:26,100
though Heaven knows
I have no glad tidings for her.

447
00:36:29,354 --> 00:36:32,898
Every day I hear some new bad tale
of Mr Wickham!

448
00:36:32,983 --> 00:36:37,152
Oh, Mr Wickham,
that everybody praised to the skies!

449
00:36:37,237 --> 00:36:41,907
Mr Wickham, that half the town was mad
in love with. All the time a villain!

450
00:36:42,534 --> 00:36:45,828
A very demon from hell sent to ruin us!

451
00:36:47,289 --> 00:36:52,001
I have heard he's run up debts with
every reputable tradesman in the town.

452
00:36:52,085 --> 00:36:53,460
Oh, sister!

453
00:36:53,545 --> 00:36:56,881
- I have heard tales of gaming debts!
- Oh, sister!

454
00:36:56,965 --> 00:36:58,883
Of drunken routs,

455
00:36:58,967 --> 00:37:02,845
in which more things were broken
than heads and furniture, sister!

456
00:37:02,929 --> 00:37:04,597
Oh, sister, stop!

457
00:37:04,723 --> 00:37:08,225
Debauches, intrigues, seductions!

458
00:37:09,352 --> 00:37:11,312
They say there's hardly a tradesman
in the town

459
00:37:11,396 --> 00:37:13,147
whose daughters were not meddled with!

460
00:37:13,231 --> 00:37:16,942
Now he's meddling with our dearest girl.

461
00:37:17,319 --> 00:37:18,736
The foul fiend!

462
00:37:18,820 --> 00:37:21,822
He shall be discovered
and made to marry her!

463
00:37:24,701 --> 00:37:29,663
I have to say, sister, that I always
distrusted his appearance of goodness.

464
00:37:30,290 --> 00:37:34,293
Aye, sister, so did I,
and warned the girls!

465
00:37:34,544 --> 00:37:39,006
- Too smooth and plausible by half!
- But would anybody listen to me?

466
00:37:39,591 --> 00:37:42,134
And now we are all, all ruined!

467
00:37:42,928 --> 00:37:47,014
Oh, my poor girl. My poor, poor Lydia!

468
00:37:56,775 --> 00:37:59,985
When shall we travel into Hertfordshire,
my love?

469
00:38:00,195 --> 00:38:04,657
Come away from the window, dear.
When I have settled my business affairs.

470
00:38:05,492 --> 00:38:08,786
These things always take longer
than one thinks they will.

471
00:38:08,870 --> 00:38:12,331
- You're not unhappy, surely?
- Lord, no!

472
00:38:12,999 --> 00:38:15,459
Just that I can't wait to see
my mother's face!

473
00:38:15,543 --> 00:38:18,879
And my sisters'.
Kitty will be so envious!

474
00:38:19,589 --> 00:38:21,298
How I shall laugh!

475
00:38:22,467 --> 00:38:24,385
I hope we shall be married
from Longbourn.

476
00:38:24,469 --> 00:38:27,763
Then all my sisters will have to be
my bridesmaids.

477
00:38:29,557 --> 00:38:32,518
Oh, I do wish we could go out
into the town,

478
00:38:32,602 --> 00:38:35,020
and be seen at plays and assemblies.

479
00:38:35,105 --> 00:38:38,482
All in good time. Be patient, dear.

480
00:38:40,986 --> 00:38:43,570
Lord, it makes me want to
burst out laughing

481
00:38:44,322 --> 00:38:47,992
when I think that I have done
what none of my sisters has.

482
00:38:48,493 --> 00:38:50,828
And I the youngest of them all!

483
00:38:56,751 --> 00:38:59,920
Mother! Here is a letter
from my uncle Gardiner!

484
00:39:02,632 --> 00:39:05,592
- Father is coming home today!
- Does he bring Lydia?

485
00:39:05,677 --> 00:39:09,096
No. He and my uncle have not yet
discovered where she is.

486
00:39:09,472 --> 00:39:11,473
My uncle will continue
his enquiries alone.

487
00:39:11,558 --> 00:39:14,309
Coming home without poor Lydia?

488
00:39:14,394 --> 00:39:19,106
Who will fight Wickham and make him
marry her, if he comes away?

489
00:39:19,441 --> 00:39:22,276
Oh, Jane, Jane, what is to become of us?

490
00:39:22,944 --> 00:39:25,612
Oh, oh, fetch my smelling salts!

491
00:39:26,281 --> 00:39:29,074
I feel my faintness
coming upon me again!

492
00:39:39,127 --> 00:39:42,296
Not now, Jane. Not now, Lizzy.

493
00:40:19,000 --> 00:40:21,168
(MUSIC DROWNS ALL DIALOGUE)

494
00:40:43,858 --> 00:40:45,651
(DARCY): Mrs Younge.

495
00:40:51,199 --> 00:40:52,866
Should I go and get father?

496
00:40:52,951 --> 00:40:55,911
He has had nothing to eat
since he came home.

497
00:40:56,287 --> 00:40:59,039
Let me. You take mother her tea.

498
00:41:18,309 --> 00:41:19,726
Well, Jane.

499
00:41:20,979 --> 00:41:22,354
Elizabeth.

500
00:41:22,605 --> 00:41:24,064
Mary, Kitty.

501
00:41:27,402 --> 00:41:29,486
You look so tired, father.

502
00:41:29,779 --> 00:41:32,239
It must have been
a dreadful time for you.

503
00:41:32,323 --> 00:41:34,116
Say nothing of that.

504
00:41:34,576 --> 00:41:36,827
Who should suffer but myself?

505
00:41:37,245 --> 00:41:40,914
It has been my own doing,
and I ought to feel it.

506
00:41:41,416 --> 00:41:42,708
Oh, papa.

507
00:41:43,376 --> 00:41:46,003
You must not be so severe upon yourself.

508
00:41:46,629 --> 00:41:50,757
Let me, for once in my life,
feel how much I have been to blame.

509
00:41:51,718 --> 00:41:55,179
I am not afraid of being overpowered
by the impression.

510
00:41:55,263 --> 00:41:57,514
It will pass away soon enough.

511
00:42:00,101 --> 00:42:02,352
Do you still suppose them
to be in London, sir?

512
00:42:02,437 --> 00:42:06,190
Yes, where else can they be
so well concealed?

513
00:42:06,608 --> 00:42:09,151
Lydia always wanted to go to London!

514
00:42:10,612 --> 00:42:16,200
She is happy, then. And her residence
there will probably be of some duration.

515
00:42:18,912 --> 00:42:20,120
Lizzy.

516
00:42:20,622 --> 00:42:25,542
I bear you no ill-will for being
justified in your advice to me in May,

517
00:42:25,627 --> 00:42:30,964
which, considering the event,
shows some greatness of mind, I think.

518
00:42:33,384 --> 00:42:35,469
I must take mamma her tea.

519
00:42:37,263 --> 00:42:40,474
She still keeps her state
above stairs, does she?

520
00:42:41,100 --> 00:42:44,311
Good. It lends such an elegance
to our misfortune!

521
00:42:44,479 --> 00:42:48,941
Another time I'll do the same.
I'll sit in my library, in my nightcap

522
00:42:49,025 --> 00:42:52,778
and powdering gown,
and I'll give as much trouble as I can.

523
00:42:54,572 --> 00:42:57,699
Or perhaps I may defer it,
till Kitty runs away.

524
00:42:58,493 --> 00:43:00,494
I'm not going to run away.

525
00:43:00,578 --> 00:43:03,205
If I should go to Brighton,
I would behave better than Lydia.

526
00:43:03,331 --> 00:43:05,040
You go to Brighton?

527
00:43:05,124 --> 00:43:09,169
I wouldn't trust you as near it
as East Bourne. Not for fifty pounds!

528
00:43:09,712 --> 00:43:12,756
No, Kitty, I have at last
learnt to be cautious,

529
00:43:12,840 --> 00:43:14,758
and you will feel the effects of it.

530
00:43:15,009 --> 00:43:18,345
No officer is ever
to enter my house again.

531
00:43:19,138 --> 00:43:21,682
Or even to pass through the village!

532
00:43:21,808 --> 00:43:25,185
Balls will be absolutely prohibited,

533
00:43:25,270 --> 00:43:27,604
unless you stand up
with one of your sisters!

534
00:43:27,689 --> 00:43:30,399
And you are never to stir out of doors

535
00:43:30,483 --> 00:43:34,194
until having spent ten minutes
every day in a rational manner.

536
00:43:37,073 --> 00:43:41,034
Well, well, well,
don't make yourself unhappy, my dear.

537
00:43:41,202 --> 00:43:43,870
If you are a good girl
for the next ten years,

538
00:43:43,955 --> 00:43:46,915
I'll take you to a review
at the end of them.

539
00:44:15,987 --> 00:44:18,739
Oh, dearest,
shall we not go out tonight?

540
00:44:20,450 --> 00:44:22,701
Can we not go to the theatre?

541
00:44:24,579 --> 00:44:27,456
Lord! What in the world
is he doing here?

542
00:44:27,540 --> 00:44:28,665
What?

543
00:44:28,750 --> 00:44:31,960
- What a joke!
- Who is it?

544
00:44:32,295 --> 00:44:34,921
- You'll never guess!
- Who is it?

545
00:44:35,673 --> 00:44:37,257
Mr Darcy.

546
00:45:08,289 --> 00:45:09,998
(FATHER): Come in.

547
00:45:15,671 --> 00:45:17,297
Thank you, Hill.

548
00:45:32,021 --> 00:45:35,023
Hill, what is it?
Is Mrs Bennet asking for us?

549
00:45:35,108 --> 00:45:36,983
No, ma'am.

550
00:45:37,235 --> 00:45:40,570
I beg your pardon,
but did you know an express

551
00:45:40,655 --> 00:45:42,781
come for master from Mr Gardiner?

552
00:45:42,865 --> 00:45:46,660
- When did it come, Hill?
- Oh, about half an hour ago, ma'am.

553
00:46:12,854 --> 00:46:16,565
- Well, Lizzy?
- Papa, what news?

554
00:46:18,359 --> 00:46:22,112
- What news from my uncle?
- Yes, I've had a letter from him.

555
00:46:22,530 --> 00:46:27,242
- What news does it bring? Good or bad?
- What is there of good to be expected?

556
00:46:27,910 --> 00:46:30,787
Perhaps you would like
to read it yourself.

557
00:46:32,707 --> 00:46:36,543
Read it aloud, Lizzy.
I hardly know what to make of it myself.

558
00:46:37,545 --> 00:46:39,004
"My dear brother,

559
00:46:39,088 --> 00:46:42,466
at last I am able to send
tidings of my niece and Mr Wickham.

560
00:46:42,550 --> 00:46:45,844
- I have seen them..."
- It's as I hoped! They are married!

561
00:46:46,304 --> 00:46:50,891
"They are not married, nor can I find
there was any intention of being so,"

562
00:46:51,225 --> 00:46:53,643
"but if you will perform the engagements

563
00:46:53,728 --> 00:46:56,938
I have ventured to make for you,
they will before long."

564
00:46:57,023 --> 00:46:59,065
- What engagements?
- Read on.

565
00:47:00,401 --> 00:47:02,652
"All that is required is to
assure your daughter

566
00:47:02,737 --> 00:47:06,239
"her equal share of the 5,000 pounds
she will inherit,"

567
00:47:06,616 --> 00:47:10,577
"and also allow her, during your life,
1 00 pounds per annum."

568
00:47:11,662 --> 00:47:15,123
So little? What about Wickham's debts?

569
00:47:17,251 --> 00:47:18,502
Read on.

570
00:47:18,961 --> 00:47:22,297
"Mr Wickham's circumstances are
not so hopeless

571
00:47:22,381 --> 00:47:23,465
as they are generally believed to be."

572
00:47:23,549 --> 00:47:25,675
- There!
- Read on, Lizzy!

573
00:47:25,927 --> 00:47:28,011
"There will be some little money,

574
00:47:28,095 --> 00:47:32,265
"even when all his debts are discharged,
to settle on my niece."

575
00:47:34,185 --> 00:47:36,937
- I cannot believe it.
- Read on.

576
00:47:39,190 --> 00:47:42,567
"We've judged it best that my niece
should be married from this house.

577
00:47:42,652 --> 00:47:43,944
I hope you approve."

578
00:47:44,028 --> 00:47:46,655
Kitty will be disappointed
not to be a bridesmaid.

579
00:47:47,323 --> 00:47:48,949
"Send back your answer
as soon as you can,

580
00:47:49,033 --> 00:47:52,869
with the explicit financial settlement.
Yours," etc...

581
00:47:56,249 --> 00:47:59,125
How can it be possible
he will marry her for so little?

582
00:47:59,669 --> 00:48:02,379
He must not be undeserving,
as we thought.

583
00:48:02,463 --> 00:48:04,172
He must truly be in love with her,
I think.

584
00:48:04,257 --> 00:48:08,009
You think that, Jane,
if it gives you comfort.

585
00:48:08,719 --> 00:48:12,389
- Have you answered the letter?
- No, but I must - and soon.

586
00:48:17,353 --> 00:48:21,648
And they must marry.
Yet he is such a man.

587
00:48:21,732 --> 00:48:25,068
Yes, they must marry.
There's nothing else to be done.

588
00:48:25,152 --> 00:48:27,404
There are two things I want to know:

589
00:48:27,488 --> 00:48:31,491
One is, how much money your uncle
laid down to bring this about;

590
00:48:32,076 --> 00:48:35,996
and the other,
how am I ever to repay him?

591
00:48:42,837 --> 00:48:45,672
I wish I had never spoken of this
to Mr Darcy.

592
00:48:45,756 --> 00:48:48,717
Dear Lizzy,
please do not distress yourself.

593
00:48:48,801 --> 00:48:51,511
I'm sure Mr Darcy
will respect your confidence.

594
00:48:52,054 --> 00:48:56,391
I'm sure he will.
That is not what distresses me.

595
00:48:56,934 --> 00:48:59,019
- What, then?
- I don't know!

596
00:49:01,230 --> 00:49:04,566
How he must be congratulating himself
on his escape!

597
00:49:06,527 --> 00:49:10,363
- How he must despise me now.
- You never sought his love!

598
00:49:10,823 --> 00:49:13,366
Nor welcomed it when he offered it.

599
00:49:13,451 --> 00:49:17,495
If he has withdrawn his high opinion
of you, why should you care?

600
00:49:18,039 --> 00:49:19,539
I don't know!

601
00:49:20,750 --> 00:49:22,542
I can't explain it.

602
00:49:25,212 --> 00:49:28,131
I know I shall probably
never see him again.

603
00:49:30,092 --> 00:49:33,595
I cannot bear to think
that he is alive in the world...

604
00:49:34,972 --> 00:00:00,-001
..and thinking ill of me.

