1
00:01:13,323 --> 00:01:16,534
(LIZZY): You are the last man
whom I could ever marry!

2
00:01:16,618 --> 00:01:19,245
Do you think any consideration
would tempt me?

3
00:01:19,329 --> 00:01:21,247
Your arrogance, your conceit,

4
00:01:21,331 --> 00:01:24,167
and your selfish disdain
for the feelings of others!

5
00:01:24,251 --> 00:01:26,419
My opinion of you was
decided when I heard

6
00:01:26,503 --> 00:01:29,422
Mr Wickham's story
of your dealings with him.

7
00:01:29,506 --> 00:01:32,675
Well at least in that I
may defend myself.

8
00:01:33,302 --> 00:01:37,346
(DARCY): Could you expect me to rejoice
in the inferiority of your connections?

9
00:01:37,431 --> 00:01:39,640
To congratulate myself
on the hope of relations

10
00:01:39,725 --> 00:01:42,852
whose conditions in life
is so below my own?

11
00:01:44,313 --> 00:01:46,230
(LIZZY): You are mistaken, Mr Darcy.

12
00:01:46,690 --> 00:01:49,233
Your declaration merely spared me the

13
00:01:49,318 --> 00:01:51,527
concern I might have
felt in refusing you,

14
00:01:51,612 --> 00:01:54,697
had you behaved in a more
gentleman-like manner.

15
00:01:55,157 --> 00:01:57,992
(LADY CATHERINE): Who's
there, Fitzwilliam?

16
00:01:58,076 --> 00:02:01,996
- Darcy! We'd quite despaired of you!
- (LADY CATHERINE): Is that my nephew?

17
00:02:02,122 --> 00:02:06,584
(LADY CATHERINE): Where have you been?
Let him come in and explain himself!

18
00:02:06,668 --> 00:02:08,878
No. You will forgive me.

19
00:02:10,547 --> 00:02:12,673
You'll forgive me.

20
00:02:12,758 --> 00:02:14,884
Darcy, you are unwell?

21
00:02:14,968 --> 00:02:18,054
I'm very well, thank you, but I have a
pressing matter of business.

22
00:02:18,639 --> 00:02:19,639
You'll forgive me.

23
00:02:20,140 --> 00:02:23,351
Make my apologies to
Lady Catherine, Fitzwilliam.

24
00:02:49,127 --> 00:02:51,128
To Miss Elizabeth Bennet.

25
00:02:57,469 --> 00:03:00,263
Be not alarmed, madam,
on receiving this letter,

26
00:03:00,347 --> 00:03:02,682
that it contains any repetition
of those sentiments

27
00:03:02,683 --> 00:03:07,186
or offers which were this
evening so disgusting to you.

28
00:03:15,612 --> 00:03:19,782
But I must be allowed to defend myself
against the charges laid at my door.

29
00:03:19,867 --> 00:03:22,201
In particular those
relating to Mr Wickham,

30
00:03:22,286 --> 00:03:25,204
which if true, would indeed be grievous,

31
00:03:25,289 --> 00:03:28,165
but are wholly without foundation,
and which I can only refute

32
00:03:28,250 --> 00:03:31,502
by laying before you
his connection with my family.

33
00:03:35,257 --> 00:03:38,301
Mr Wickham is the son
of a very respectable man,

34
00:03:38,385 --> 00:03:41,470
who had the management of our estates.

35
00:03:41,555 --> 00:03:45,474
My own father was fond of him
and held him in high esteem.

36
00:03:50,606 --> 00:03:52,690
We played together as boys.

37
00:03:56,945 --> 00:03:59,655
After his father's early death,
my father supported him at school

38
00:03:59,740 --> 00:04:05,036
and at Cambridge, and hoped
he would make the church his profession.

39
00:04:08,332 --> 00:04:10,666
But by then George Wickham's
habits were as dissolute

40
00:04:10,751 --> 00:04:13,920
as his manners were engaging.

41
00:04:21,470 --> 00:04:24,388
My own excellent
father died five years ago.

42
00:04:25,390 --> 00:04:28,809
His attachment to Mr Wickham
was to the last so steady,

43
00:04:28,894 --> 00:04:30,937
that he desired that a
valuable family living

44
00:04:31,021 --> 00:04:32,939
might be his as soon as it was vacant.

45
00:04:33,023 --> 00:04:36,609
Mr Wickham declined any
interest in the church as a career,

46
00:04:36,693 --> 00:04:38,361
but requested, and was granted,

47
00:04:38,445 --> 00:04:41,364
the sum of 3,000 pounds
instead of the living.

48
00:04:45,869 --> 00:04:48,955
He expressed an intention
of studying the law.

49
00:04:49,039 --> 00:04:52,208
I wished, rather than
believed him to be sincere.

50
00:04:54,670 --> 00:04:56,170
Thank you.

51
00:04:59,341 --> 00:05:01,717
I'm most exceedingly obliged.

52
00:05:03,720 --> 00:05:06,889
All connection between us
seemed now dissolved.

53
00:05:10,102 --> 00:05:11,435
Georgiana.

54
00:05:16,858 --> 00:05:19,819
Being now free from all restraint,

55
00:05:19,903 --> 00:05:22,947
his life was one of
idleness and dissipation.

56
00:05:25,450 --> 00:05:27,576
How he lived, I know not.

57
00:05:28,203 --> 00:05:32,915
But last summer our paths crossed again,
under the most painful circumstances,

58
00:05:33,208 --> 00:05:35,960
which I myself would wish to forget.

59
00:05:36,837 --> 00:05:40,923
My sister, Georgiana,
who is more than ten years my junior,

60
00:05:41,258 --> 00:05:45,177
was left to the guardianship
of Colonel Fitzwilliam and myself.

61
00:05:46,763 --> 00:05:50,433
About a year ago, she was taken
from school to Ramsgate,

62
00:05:50,934 --> 00:05:53,894
and placed in the care of a Mrs Younge,

63
00:05:53,979 --> 00:05:56,355
in whose character we were
most unhappily deceived.

64
00:05:57,441 --> 00:06:01,402
And thither also went Mr Wickham,
undoubtedly by design.

65
00:06:03,822 --> 00:06:08,492
She was persuaded to believe herself in
love, and to consent to an elopement.

66
00:06:08,785 --> 00:06:11,746
She was then but fifteen years old.

67
00:06:15,751 --> 00:06:20,004
A day or two before the intended
elopement, I joined them unexpectedly.

68
00:06:35,187 --> 00:06:37,813
Unable to support the
idea of grieving a brother

69
00:06:37,898 --> 00:06:40,274
whom she looked up
to almost as a father,

70
00:06:40,358 --> 00:06:43,360
she acknowledged the whole
plan to me at once.

71
00:06:43,570 --> 00:06:46,489
You may imagine what I felt
and how I acted.

72
00:06:48,158 --> 00:06:50,868
Mr Wickham left the place immediately.

73
00:06:55,916 --> 00:06:57,458
(DARCY): Come.

74
00:07:03,423 --> 00:07:05,424
Mr Wickham relinquished his object,

75
00:07:05,509 --> 00:07:08,803
which was of course, my sister's
fortune of 30,000.

76
00:07:10,013 --> 00:07:13,724
A secondary motive must have been
to revenge himself on me.

77
00:07:14,101 --> 00:07:18,187
Had he succeeded, his revenge would
have been complete indeed.

78
00:07:18,396 --> 00:07:24,193
This, madam, is a faithful narrative
of all my dealings with Mr Wickham.

79
00:08:14,369 --> 00:08:17,997
You do look pale, Lizzy.
Why don't you have some breakfast?

80
00:08:18,081 --> 00:08:19,623
I'm sure it will do you good.

81
00:08:19,708 --> 00:08:21,584
I am well, Charlotte.

82
00:08:22,043 --> 00:08:25,546
I've stayed indoors too long.
Fresh air and exercise is all I need.

83
00:08:25,630 --> 00:08:29,550
The woods around Rosings are
so beautiful at this time of year.

84
00:09:15,222 --> 00:09:16,639
Miss Bennet!

85
00:09:19,142 --> 00:09:20,392
Mr Darcy.

86
00:09:20,936 --> 00:09:24,939
I've been walking the grove some time
in the hope of meeting you.

87
00:09:25,065 --> 00:09:28,275
Will you do me the honour
of reading this letter?

88
00:09:44,668 --> 00:09:46,669
(DARCY): This, madam, is a faithful

89
00:09:46,753 --> 00:09:48,879
narrative of my
dealings with Mr Wickham,

90
00:09:48,964 --> 00:09:52,883
and for its truth I can appeal to the
testimony of Colonel Fitzwilliam,

91
00:09:52,968 --> 00:09:55,469
who knows every particular
of these transactions.

92
00:09:55,553 --> 00:09:59,223
I know not under what form of falsehood
Mr Wickham imposed himself on you,

93
00:09:59,349 --> 00:10:01,767
but I hope you'll acquit me
of cruelty towards him.

94
00:10:01,851 --> 00:10:05,187
I found that I'd better
not meet Mr Darcy.

95
00:10:05,272 --> 00:10:08,148
Scenes might arise,
unpleasant to more than myself.

96
00:10:09,150 --> 00:10:11,068
The other charge levelled at me,

97
00:10:11,152 --> 00:10:13,904
is that regardless of the
sentiments of either party,

98
00:10:13,989 --> 00:10:16,699
I detached Mr Bingley from your sister.

99
00:10:17,534 --> 00:10:19,451
I have no wish to deny this,

100
00:10:19,536 --> 00:10:22,246
nor can I blame myself for any
of my actions in this matter.

101
00:10:22,664 --> 00:10:23,831
(GASPING)

102
00:10:27,585 --> 00:10:29,295
I had not long been in Hertfordshire

103
00:10:29,379 --> 00:10:32,172
before I saw that Bingley
admired your sister,

104
00:10:32,257 --> 00:10:34,049
but it was not until
the dance at Netherfield

105
00:10:34,134 --> 00:10:36,552
that I suspected a serious attachment.

106
00:10:37,512 --> 00:10:39,596
His partiality was clear,

107
00:10:39,681 --> 00:10:42,099
but though she received
his attentions with pleasure,

108
00:10:42,183 --> 00:10:45,352
I did not detect any
symptoms of peculiar regard.

109
00:10:46,104 --> 00:10:48,981
The serenity of her countenance
convinced me that her heart

110
00:10:49,065 --> 00:10:51,233
was not likely to be easily touched.

111
00:10:52,068 --> 00:10:53,610
Insufferable presumption!

112
00:10:53,695 --> 00:10:56,280
I did not wish to believe
her to be indifferent.

113
00:10:56,364 --> 00:10:58,115
I believed it on impartial conviction.

114
00:10:58,783 --> 00:11:00,409
Very impartial!

115
00:11:00,493 --> 00:11:03,203
You've missed the two gentlemen!
They came to take their leave!

116
00:11:03,288 --> 00:11:04,621
Mr Darcy came here?

117
00:11:04,706 --> 00:11:09,543
He went away directly, but the Colonel
waited for you over half an hour!

118
00:11:09,627 --> 00:11:11,670
Now they are gone abroad!

119
00:11:11,755 --> 00:11:15,466
I dare say we shall be able
to bear the deprivation.

120
00:11:28,438 --> 00:11:30,814
As to my objections to the marriage,

121
00:11:30,899 --> 00:11:34,026
the situation of your family,
though objectionable,

122
00:11:34,110 --> 00:11:36,945
was nothing in comparison with
the total want of propriety

123
00:11:37,030 --> 00:11:39,656
so frequently betrayed by your mother,

124
00:11:39,741 --> 00:11:43,285
your younger sisters,
and even occasionally your father.

125
00:11:44,496 --> 00:11:46,747
(LIZZY REMEMBERS MARY SINGING)

126
00:11:49,042 --> 00:11:52,961
That will do extremely well, child.
You have delighted us long enough.

127
00:11:53,797 --> 00:11:56,382
Now there will be a great marriage!

128
00:11:56,966 --> 00:12:02,179
And you know, that will throw the girls
into the paths of other rich men!

129
00:12:10,438 --> 00:12:13,899
My friend left Netherfield for London
on the following day.

130
00:12:13,983 --> 00:12:16,860
There I pointed out to
him the certain evils of

131
00:12:16,945 --> 00:12:19,863
his choice of your sister
as a prospective bride.

132
00:12:20,156 --> 00:12:23,325
It was not difficult to convince him
of your sister's indifference to him.

133
00:12:23,660 --> 00:12:26,829
I cannot blame myself for
having done thus much.

134
00:12:27,705 --> 00:12:30,124
For destroying all her
hope of happiness?

135
00:12:30,208 --> 00:12:32,835
Yes, I'm sure you do not blame yourself.
Hateful man!

136
00:12:33,169 --> 00:12:36,422
There is but one part of my conduct
in the affair on which I do not

137
00:12:36,506 --> 00:12:38,257
reflect with satisfaction.

138
00:12:38,508 --> 00:12:39,883
Astonish me!

139
00:12:39,968 --> 00:12:43,387
That I concealed from him
your sister's being in town.

140
00:12:49,018 --> 00:12:51,937
Perhaps this concealment was beneath me.

141
00:12:52,021 --> 00:12:54,523
It was done, however, for the best.

142
00:12:54,649 --> 00:12:59,111
On this subject I have nothing more to
say, and no other apology to offer.

143
00:12:59,195 --> 00:13:00,696
Insufferable!

144
00:13:01,698 --> 00:13:04,741
- (CHARLOTTE): Lizzy!
- (COLLINS): Charlotte, we will be late!

145
00:13:04,826 --> 00:13:06,535
(CHARLOTTE): Lizzy!

146
00:13:08,538 --> 00:13:11,123
(COLLINS): I have endeavoured
to count the times

147
00:13:11,207 --> 00:13:14,334
Lady Catherine has invited
us since your arrival.

148
00:13:14,419 --> 00:13:17,463
I believe it may be as
many as ten invitations!

149
00:13:17,547 --> 00:13:20,632
- (MARIA): Eleven, counting this one!
- (COLLINS): Eleven!

150
00:13:20,717 --> 00:13:25,846
There! You have indeed been favoured
with peculiar condescension.

151
00:13:26,222 --> 00:13:29,766
- Do you not agree, Miss Elizabeth?
- Oh... yes!

152
00:13:29,851 --> 00:13:32,644
How could anybody think otherwise?

153
00:13:32,729 --> 00:13:36,648
And this is your last invitation,
on this visit, at least.

154
00:13:36,733 --> 00:13:39,485
It is truly a very cruel deprivation.

155
00:13:39,569 --> 00:13:43,655
I hardly know how I'll bear the loss of
her ladyship's company!

156
00:13:44,073 --> 00:13:45,949
You feel it keenly!

157
00:13:46,784 --> 00:13:50,245
Yes, of course you do,
my poor young cousin.

158
00:13:51,414 --> 00:13:54,124
(LADY CATHERINE): They
were such fine young men,

159
00:13:54,209 --> 00:13:57,503
and so particularly attached to me!

160
00:13:57,921 --> 00:14:02,549
They were excessively sorry to go,
but so they always are!

161
00:14:03,051 --> 00:14:07,679
The dear Colonel rallied
his spirits tolerably,

162
00:14:07,931 --> 00:14:11,225
but Darcy seemed to
feel it most acutely.

163
00:14:11,768 --> 00:14:15,938
His attachment to
Rosings certainly increases.

164
00:14:19,359 --> 00:14:23,403
You are very dull this evening,
Miss Elizabeth Bennet.

165
00:14:23,488 --> 00:14:28,492
You have scarce spoke two words
together. Are you so out of spirits?

166
00:14:28,576 --> 00:14:31,036
- No indeed, madam.
- Of course you are,

167
00:14:31,120 --> 00:14:33,205
to be going away yourself.

168
00:14:33,289 --> 00:14:37,042
Who indeed would not be sad
to be deprived of Rosings,

169
00:14:37,126 --> 00:14:38,877
and indeed of the gracious...

170
00:14:38,962 --> 00:14:43,006
You will write to your mother
and say you wish to stay longer.

171
00:14:43,091 --> 00:14:46,009
Surely she could spare
you for another fortnight.

172
00:14:46,094 --> 00:14:47,594
But my father cannot.

173
00:14:49,138 --> 00:14:51,682
He wrote to hurry my return.

174
00:14:51,766 --> 00:14:53,016
Your ladyship is very kind,

175
00:14:53,101 --> 00:14:55,561
but I believe we must
leave as planned on Friday.

176
00:14:55,645 --> 00:14:59,398
Your father may spare
you if your mother can.

177
00:14:59,482 --> 00:15:02,317
Daughters are never of much
consequence to a father.

178
00:15:02,402 --> 00:15:05,904
And if you will stay
another month complete,

179
00:15:06,614 --> 00:15:10,242
it will be in my power to take you
as far as London myself,

180
00:15:10,326 --> 00:15:12,327
in the Barouche box!

181
00:15:12,704 --> 00:15:18,417
For I cannot bear the idea of two young
women travelling post by themselves.

182
00:15:18,501 --> 00:15:20,794
It is highly improper!

183
00:15:21,879 --> 00:15:25,215
I am excessively attentive
to all those things.

184
00:15:25,300 --> 00:15:29,177
My uncle is to send a servant for us
when we change to the post.

185
00:15:29,262 --> 00:15:35,225
Your uncle!
He keeps a manservant, does he?

186
00:15:36,185 --> 00:15:39,062
I'm very glad you have somebody
who thinks of these things.

187
00:15:39,147 --> 00:15:40,856
Where will you change horses?

188
00:15:40,940 --> 00:15:43,233
- At Brom...
- Bromley, of course.

189
00:15:43,318 --> 00:15:46,695
Mention my name at the Bell
and they will attend you.

190
00:15:47,530 --> 00:15:49,698
Your ladyship is very kind.

191
00:15:49,782 --> 00:15:52,576
Indeed, we are all infinitely
indebted to your ladyship's

192
00:15:52,660 --> 00:15:54,536
kindly bestowed solicitude...

193
00:15:54,621 --> 00:15:58,624
Yes, yes, but this is
all extremely vexing!

194
00:16:00,043 --> 00:16:02,210
I'm quite put out.

195
00:16:03,212 --> 00:16:06,465
What are you doing? I thought the trunks
went outside before breakfast.

196
00:16:06,549 --> 00:16:10,969
Lady Catherine was so severe about the
only right way to place gowns,

197
00:16:11,054 --> 00:16:15,015
that I couldn't sleep,
and I'm determined to start afresh!

198
00:16:15,099 --> 00:16:17,643
Maria, this is your trunk
and your gowns.

199
00:16:17,727 --> 00:16:22,147
You may arrange them in any way you
wish. Lady Catherine will never know!

200
00:16:23,274 --> 00:16:26,735
(COLLINS): My dear sister,
you'll have much to tell your father...

201
00:16:26,819 --> 00:16:29,446
(CHARLOTTE): Bring that one round here.

202
00:16:29,530 --> 00:16:31,531
(BACKGROUND CONVERSATION)

203
00:16:39,749 --> 00:16:41,416
Well, cousin...

204
00:16:41,709 --> 00:16:45,003
..you have seen for yourself now
the happiness of our situation.

205
00:16:45,797 --> 00:16:50,008
Our intimacy at Rosings is a blessing
of which few could boast!

206
00:16:50,093 --> 00:16:53,428
- Indeed they could not.
- Indeed.

207
00:16:54,305 --> 00:16:56,223
Now you have seen our felicity.

208
00:16:56,307 --> 00:17:00,894
Perhaps you may think your friend
has made a fortunate alliance.

209
00:17:01,104 --> 00:17:03,230
Perhaps more so than...

210
00:17:04,190 --> 00:17:07,067
But on this point it will
be as well to be silent.

211
00:17:07,151 --> 00:17:08,944
You are very good.

212
00:17:11,114 --> 00:17:14,408
Only let me assure you that I can,
from my heart,

213
00:17:14,492 --> 00:17:18,787
most cordially wish you
equal felicity in marriage.

214
00:17:18,871 --> 00:17:22,916
Charlotte and I have but one mind
and one way of thinking.

215
00:17:24,168 --> 00:17:27,170
We seem to have been
designed for each other!

216
00:17:49,026 --> 00:17:52,654
Oh, Lizzy! It seems but a day or two
since we first came!

217
00:17:52,739 --> 00:17:57,242
- And yet how many things have happened!
- A great many, indeed.

218
00:17:57,326 --> 00:18:00,328
(MARIA): We have dined
nine times at Rosings!

219
00:18:01,122 --> 00:18:03,832
Oh, how much I shall have to tell!

220
00:18:05,084 --> 00:18:07,502
How much I shall have to conceal.

221
00:18:18,473 --> 00:18:22,517
You must allow me to tell you
how ardently I admire and love you.

222
00:18:45,374 --> 00:18:48,418
Lizzy!

223
00:18:58,137 --> 00:19:01,181
To see your faces when you looked up!

224
00:19:01,265 --> 00:19:03,433
You didn't expect we'd come to meet you.

225
00:19:03,518 --> 00:19:04,893
No, we did not.

226
00:19:04,977 --> 00:19:07,395
There! Is not this nice?

227
00:19:07,480 --> 00:19:10,690
Cold ham, and pork,
and salads, and every good thing!

228
00:19:10,775 --> 00:19:15,362
We mean to treat you, but you must
lend us money, we spent ours. Look!

229
00:19:15,446 --> 00:19:18,073
It's not pretty,
but I thought I'd buy it anyway.

230
00:19:18,157 --> 00:19:20,116
It's vile, isn't it?

231
00:19:20,201 --> 00:19:22,702
Very ugly.
What possessed you to buy it?

232
00:19:22,787 --> 00:19:24,996
There were two or three much uglier!

233
00:19:25,081 --> 00:19:29,084
I shall pull it to pieces
and see if I can make it up any better.

234
00:19:29,961 --> 00:19:31,878
It doesn't signify what anyone wears,

235
00:19:31,963 --> 00:19:35,507
for the regiment
will be at Brighton the whole summer!

236
00:19:35,591 --> 00:19:37,008
Our hearts are broken!

237
00:19:37,093 --> 00:19:40,929
And papa refuses to take us to Brighton.

238
00:19:41,055 --> 00:19:45,141
- I'm glad to hear it.
- Shouldn't you like to go to Brighton?

239
00:19:45,351 --> 00:19:47,435
- I should not.
- She would.

240
00:19:47,520 --> 00:19:51,940
She would love it, when she hears the
news about a certain person we know!

241
00:19:52,024 --> 00:19:56,528
- Shall we tell her?
- Yes, and see if she blushes!

242
00:19:57,113 --> 00:19:59,656
You may go.
We'll call if you're needed again.

243
00:19:59,740 --> 00:20:01,366
Very good, miss.

244
00:20:06,414 --> 00:20:09,374
Wickham is not to marry
Mary King after all!

245
00:20:09,458 --> 00:20:12,961
She's been taken away to Liverpool
and Wickham is safe!

246
00:20:14,255 --> 00:20:16,715
Perhaps we should say Mary King is safe.

247
00:20:16,799 --> 00:20:20,176
Was there a very strong attraction
between them, do you think?

248
00:20:20,261 --> 00:20:24,389
Not on his side! I shouldn't think
he cared three straws about her.

249
00:20:24,473 --> 00:20:27,851
Who could about such a
nasty freckled little thing?

250
00:20:28,769 --> 00:20:32,480
Don't look at me like that, Lizzy.
You think just as ill of her!

251
00:20:32,565 --> 00:20:33,899
Pass the celery, Kitty.

252
00:20:33,983 --> 00:20:37,986
Glad we came to meet you?
It'll be merry on the journey home.

253
00:20:38,446 --> 00:20:40,488
(LYDIA): Kitty, you're
squashing my bandbox!

254
00:20:40,573 --> 00:20:43,909
(KITTY): You should
have put it on the roof!

255
00:20:43,993 --> 00:20:46,494
(LYDIA): If you don't lollop
about there is room.

256
00:20:46,579 --> 00:20:49,623
(KITTY): I don't lollop, you do!

257
00:20:50,291 --> 00:20:54,336
Mr Darcy proposed!
I can scarce believe it!

258
00:20:55,379 --> 00:20:58,673
Not that anyone admiring you
should be astonishing.

259
00:20:58,758 --> 00:21:02,552
But he always seemed so severe,
so cold, apparently.

260
00:21:03,721 --> 00:21:07,474
And yet he was in love with
you all the time! Poor Mr Darcy.

261
00:21:08,184 --> 00:21:10,685
I cannot feel so much
compassion for him.

262
00:21:10,770 --> 00:21:15,357
He has other feelings which will soon
drive away any regard he felt for me.

263
00:21:16,734 --> 00:21:20,987
- You do not blame me for refusing him?
- Blame you? Oh, no.

264
00:21:24,033 --> 00:21:27,243
But you do blame me for speaking
so warmly of Wickham?

265
00:21:27,328 --> 00:21:30,789
No. How could you have
known about his vicious character?

266
00:21:30,873 --> 00:21:33,041
If indeed he was so very bad.

267
00:21:33,334 --> 00:21:38,213
But I cannot believe Mr Darcy would
fabricate such dreadful slander,

268
00:21:38,631 --> 00:21:40,840
involving his own sister too.

269
00:21:42,218 --> 00:21:43,969
No, it must be true.

270
00:21:45,429 --> 00:21:47,097
Perhaps there has been
some terrible mistake.

271
00:21:47,181 --> 00:21:52,811
No, Jane. That won't do!
You can't make them both good!

272
00:21:53,020 --> 00:21:57,232
There is just enough merit between them
to make one good sort of man.

273
00:21:58,067 --> 00:22:01,611
And for my part I'm inclined to
believe it's all Mr Darcy's.

274
00:22:01,696 --> 00:22:03,196
Poor Mr Darcy.

275
00:22:04,323 --> 00:22:06,282
Poor Mr Wickham!

276
00:22:06,367 --> 00:22:09,953
There is such an expression
of goodness in his countenance.

277
00:22:10,037 --> 00:22:12,497
Yes.
I'm afraid one has all the goodness,

278
00:22:12,581 --> 00:22:14,916
and the other all the appearance of it!

279
00:22:16,335 --> 00:22:20,255
But Lizzy, I am sure that when you
first read that letter,

280
00:22:20,881 --> 00:22:23,633
you could not have made so
light of it as you do now.

281
00:22:24,760 --> 00:22:26,469
Indeed I could not.

282
00:22:26,971 --> 00:22:31,766
I was very uncomfortable.
Till that moment I never knew myself.

283
00:22:32,852 --> 00:22:35,186
And I had no Jane to comfort me.

284
00:22:36,522 --> 00:22:38,314
Oh, how I wanted you!

285
00:22:43,279 --> 00:22:46,281
There is one point on
which I want your advice.

286
00:22:46,365 --> 00:22:51,161
Should our general acquaintance be
informed of Wickham's true character?

287
00:22:53,539 --> 00:22:57,125
Surely there can be no occasion
to expose him so cruelly.

288
00:22:58,002 --> 00:23:01,296
- What is your opinion?
- That it oughtn't be attempted.

289
00:23:01,380 --> 00:23:05,216
Mr Darcy has not authorised
me to make it public,

290
00:23:05,301 --> 00:23:07,343
especially as regards his sister.

291
00:23:09,805 --> 00:23:12,432
As for the rest, who would believe it?

292
00:23:12,516 --> 00:23:15,769
The general prejudice against
Mr Darcy is so violent,

293
00:23:15,853 --> 00:23:17,103
and Wickham will soon be gone.

294
00:23:17,188 --> 00:23:20,398
I believe we should
say nothing at present.

295
00:23:20,483 --> 00:23:21,983
Yes, I agree.

296
00:23:23,819 --> 00:23:25,904
Perhaps he is sorry now
for what he has done,

297
00:23:25,988 --> 00:23:29,282
and is anxious to
re-establish his character.

298
00:23:29,408 --> 00:23:31,659
We must not make him desperate.

299
00:23:31,744 --> 00:23:36,206
Oh, Jane! I wish I could think
so well of people as you do.

300
00:23:38,334 --> 00:23:41,044
Won't you speak to papa, Lizzy,
about our going to Brighton?

301
00:23:41,128 --> 00:23:43,755
You know he listens to your advice.

302
00:23:43,839 --> 00:23:48,093
You flatter me, Lydia. In any case,
I shouldn't attempt to persuade him.

303
00:23:48,177 --> 00:23:52,597
I think it's a very good thing that the
regiment is removed from Meryton,

304
00:23:52,723 --> 00:23:55,100
and that we are removed
from the regiment.

305
00:23:55,184 --> 00:23:58,228
Oh, Lizzy,
how can you say such a thing?

306
00:23:58,312 --> 00:23:59,938
Very easily, ma'am.

307
00:24:00,022 --> 00:24:03,608
If one company causes
such havoc in our family,

308
00:24:03,692 --> 00:24:06,361
what would a whole
campful of soldiers do?

309
00:24:07,530 --> 00:24:10,448
A whole campful of soldiers!

310
00:24:10,533 --> 00:24:12,700
(MOTHER): I remember when I was a girl.

311
00:24:12,785 --> 00:24:16,454
I cried for two days when
Colonel Miller's regiment went away.

312
00:24:16,539 --> 00:24:18,790
I thought I should have broke my heart!

313
00:24:18,874 --> 00:24:20,667
I shall break mine.

314
00:24:20,751 --> 00:24:22,127
And I!

315
00:24:23,504 --> 00:24:25,755
There, there, my dears.

316
00:24:25,840 --> 00:24:28,466
But your father is
determined to be cruel.

317
00:24:28,551 --> 00:24:30,051
I confess I am.

318
00:24:30,636 --> 00:24:34,889
I'm sorry to be breaking hearts,
but I have no intention of yielding.

319
00:24:35,141 --> 00:24:37,308
I shall not break my heart, papa.

320
00:24:37,393 --> 00:24:39,936
The pleasures of Brighton
would have no charms for me.

321
00:24:40,020 --> 00:24:42,397
I should infinitely prefer a book.

322
00:24:42,481 --> 00:24:44,983
Mrs Forster says she
plans to go sea-bathing.

323
00:24:45,067 --> 00:24:47,944
I am sure I should love
to go sea-bathing!

324
00:24:48,571 --> 00:24:51,489
A little sea-bathing
would set me up forever!

325
00:24:51,574 --> 00:24:53,575
And yet, I am unmoved.

326
00:24:53,951 --> 00:24:55,410
Well, well.

327
00:24:55,995 --> 00:25:00,540
I'm glad you are come back, Lizzy.
I'm glad you are come back, Jane.

328
00:25:05,421 --> 00:25:07,755
I want to go to Brighton!

329
00:25:32,323 --> 00:25:34,282
You are not happy, Jane.

330
00:25:35,117 --> 00:25:38,870
- It pains me to see it.
- It is just that I did...

331
00:25:39,955 --> 00:25:43,791
I'm afraid I still do prefer Mr Bingley
to any other man I've met,

332
00:25:43,876 --> 00:25:47,045
and Lizzy, I did believe he...

333
00:25:49,215 --> 00:25:51,633
Well, I was mistaken, that is all.

334
00:25:53,552 --> 00:25:56,179
I am resolved to think of him no more.

335
00:25:56,639 --> 00:25:59,057
There. Enough.

336
00:25:59,975 --> 00:26:03,645
I shall be myself again,
as if I had never set eyes on him.

337
00:26:07,524 --> 00:26:10,318
Truly, Lizzy, I promise.
I shall be well.

338
00:26:10,486 --> 00:26:15,448
I shall be myself again.
I shall be perfectly content.

339
00:26:26,335 --> 00:26:31,130
Well, Lizzy, what do you think now
about this sad business of Jane's?

340
00:26:31,757 --> 00:26:35,635
I cannot find out that she saw
anything of Bingley in London.

341
00:26:36,178 --> 00:26:37,303
Well.

342
00:26:38,180 --> 00:26:42,183
An undeserving young man!

343
00:26:42,268 --> 00:26:45,520
And I don't suppose there's any
chance of her getting him now.

344
00:26:46,188 --> 00:26:49,983
If he should come back
to Netherfield, though.

345
00:26:50,067 --> 00:26:52,193
I think there's little
chance of that, mamma.

346
00:26:52,278 --> 00:26:54,487
Oh, well. Just as he chooses.

347
00:26:55,197 --> 00:26:57,198
No one wants him to come!

348
00:26:57,700 --> 00:27:02,704
I shall always say he used
my daughter extremely ill!

349
00:27:02,705 --> 00:27:05,123
If I was her,
I would not have put up with it.

350
00:27:05,207 --> 00:27:08,584
My comfort is,
she will die of a broken heart,

351
00:27:08,669 --> 00:27:10,586
and then he'll be sorry
for what he's done!

352
00:27:11,588 --> 00:27:16,009
So, the Collinses live
quite comfortable, do they?

353
00:27:16,093 --> 00:27:18,094
I only hope it will last.

354
00:27:18,887 --> 00:27:23,641
And I suppose they talk about having
this house too when your father is dead?

355
00:27:23,767 --> 00:27:26,978
They look on it as quite their own,
I dare say?

356
00:27:27,563 --> 00:27:30,398
They could hardly discuss such
a subject in front of me.

357
00:27:30,482 --> 00:27:34,485
I make no doubt they talk about it
constantly when they're alone!

358
00:27:34,611 --> 00:27:38,740
If they can be easy with an estate
that is not lawfully their own,

359
00:27:38,824 --> 00:27:40,408
so much the better!

360
00:27:40,576 --> 00:27:44,579
I should be ashamed of having one
that was only entailed upon me!

361
00:27:45,998 --> 00:27:48,833
Mamma, mamma! Lizzy!

362
00:27:49,460 --> 00:27:53,171
Guess what!
You never will, so I'll tell you.

363
00:27:53,255 --> 00:27:56,049
Mrs Forster has invited me,
as her particular friend,

364
00:27:56,133 --> 00:27:58,301
to go with her to Brighton.

365
00:27:58,385 --> 00:27:59,886
Colonel Forster is to
take a house for us!

366
00:27:59,970 --> 00:28:02,680
I'm so happy!

367
00:28:02,765 --> 00:28:06,851
- What an honour, to be singled out!
- Is it not unfair, Lizzy?

368
00:28:06,935 --> 00:28:09,437
Mrs Forster should
have asked me as well.

369
00:28:09,521 --> 00:28:12,982
I may not be her dearest friend,
but have as much right to be asked!

370
00:28:13,067 --> 00:28:14,233
(LYDIA LAUGHS SCORNFULLY)

371
00:28:14,318 --> 00:28:17,028
And more too, for I am two years older!

372
00:28:20,783 --> 00:28:23,534
I'll buy her a present, I dare say.

373
00:28:23,619 --> 00:28:27,121
There's no call to be in a miff because
Mrs Forster likes me best.

374
00:28:27,831 --> 00:28:31,584
Before you crow too loud, remember papa
has not given you permission to go.

375
00:28:31,668 --> 00:28:33,419
Nor is he like to.

376
00:28:33,587 --> 00:28:35,213
Papa won't stop me.

377
00:28:35,297 --> 00:28:40,301
Not when I'm invited by the Colonel to
be his wife's particular companion!

378
00:28:40,969 --> 00:28:42,929
I need new clothes,

379
00:28:43,013 --> 00:28:45,723
for I've nothing fit to wear, and there
will be balls and parties!

380
00:28:45,808 --> 00:28:48,476
Of course you shall have new things!

381
00:28:48,560 --> 00:28:51,562
We wouldn't see you disgraced
in front of all the officers!

382
00:28:51,647 --> 00:28:53,856
(LYDIA): Oo! All the officers!

383
00:28:57,778 --> 00:29:01,823
I understand your concern,
my dear, but consider:

384
00:29:02,658 --> 00:29:07,829
Lydia will never be easy until she has
exposed herself in some public place,

385
00:29:07,955 --> 00:29:10,832
and here is an opportunity
for her to do so,

386
00:29:10,916 --> 00:29:13,543
with very little expense
or inconvenience to her family.

387
00:29:13,627 --> 00:29:17,088
If you were aware of the very
great disadvantage to us all,

388
00:29:17,172 --> 00:29:21,592
which has already arisen from Lydia's
unguarded and imprudent manner,

389
00:29:21,677 --> 00:29:24,387
you'd judge differently.

390
00:29:24,471 --> 00:29:27,557
Already arisen? Has she frightened
away some of your lovers?

391
00:29:27,641 --> 00:29:29,308
Don't be cast down, Lizzy.

392
00:29:29,393 --> 00:29:32,186
Such squeamish youths are
not worth your regret.

393
00:29:32,521 --> 00:29:35,398
- Oh come, Lizzy.
- Indeed you are mistaken.

394
00:29:36,024 --> 00:29:40,820
I have no injuries to resent. I speak
of general, not particular evils.

395
00:29:41,196 --> 00:29:42,196
Our...

396
00:29:43,532 --> 00:29:46,242
position as a family,
our very respectability,

397
00:29:46,326 --> 00:29:49,287
is called into question by
Lydia's wild behaviour.

398
00:29:52,499 --> 00:29:56,294
I must speak plainly.
If you do not check her,

399
00:29:56,378 --> 00:29:58,629
she will soon be beyond
the reach of amendment.

400
00:29:58,714 --> 00:30:01,340
She will become the
most determined flirt

401
00:30:01,425 --> 00:30:04,177
that ever made herself
and her family ridiculous!

402
00:30:06,054 --> 00:30:09,223
You know that Kitty
follows wherever Lydia leads.

403
00:30:09,433 --> 00:30:13,436
Don't you see that they will be censured
and despised wherever they are known?

404
00:30:13,520 --> 00:30:16,606
And that they will involve their
sisters in their disgrace.

405
00:30:16,690 --> 00:30:18,316
Lizzy, come here.

406
00:30:22,738 --> 00:30:25,281
Don't make yourself uneasy, my love.

407
00:30:25,532 --> 00:30:30,411
Wherever you and Jane are known,
you must be respected and valued.

408
00:30:30,787 --> 00:30:34,999
And you will not appear to any less
advantage for having a couple or...

409
00:30:35,083 --> 00:30:37,752
..I may say, three very silly sisters.

410
00:30:38,754 --> 00:30:43,090
We shall have no peace at Longbourn
if Lydia does not go to Brighton.

411
00:30:44,635 --> 00:30:47,094
Colonel Forster is a sensible man.

412
00:30:48,847 --> 00:30:53,684
And luckily she's too poor to be an
object of prey to a fortune hunter.

413
00:30:55,103 --> 00:30:59,774
Leave it now, Lizzy.
I believe all will turn out well.

414
00:31:10,285 --> 00:31:14,622
We are so desolated, Colonel,
that the regiment is to leave Meryton,

415
00:31:14,957 --> 00:31:19,710
but words cannot express what we feel
about your kindness to our dear Lydia.

416
00:31:20,128 --> 00:31:23,464
Well, ma'am, it appears that
Mrs Forster cannot do without her.

417
00:31:24,800 --> 00:31:27,385
Look at the pair of them.
Thick as thieves!

418
00:31:27,469 --> 00:31:29,971
Lord knows what they find to talk about.

419
00:31:30,055 --> 00:31:34,767
But anything to keep the ladies happy.
What do you say, Wickham?

420
00:31:34,851 --> 00:31:36,852
I say amen to that, sir.

421
00:31:46,154 --> 00:31:49,240
There's one lady I shall be
very loath to part from.

422
00:31:49,324 --> 00:31:53,286
We must try to bear it.
You are for Brighton,

423
00:31:53,370 --> 00:31:55,246
I'll be touring the Lakes
with my aunt and uncle.

424
00:31:55,455 --> 00:32:00,251
I dare say we'll find ample sources
of consolation and delight...

425
00:32:00,335 --> 00:32:02,003
in our different ways.

426
00:32:02,129 --> 00:32:05,381
Perhaps. How did you find Rosings?

427
00:32:05,465 --> 00:32:08,843
Interesting. Colonel Fitzwilliam was
there with Mr Darcy.

428
00:32:08,927 --> 00:32:10,928
Are you acquainted with the Colonel?

429
00:32:11,013 --> 00:32:12,138
I...

430
00:32:13,599 --> 00:32:17,518
To some respects, yes, in former years.
A very gentlemanly man.

431
00:32:18,186 --> 00:32:21,772
- How did you like him?
- I liked him very much.

432
00:32:22,232 --> 00:32:25,151
His manners are very
different from his cousin's.

433
00:32:25,235 --> 00:32:26,319
Yes.

434
00:32:27,821 --> 00:32:32,325
But I think Mr Darcy improves
on closer acquaintance.

435
00:32:32,909 --> 00:32:34,118
Indeed?

436
00:32:35,329 --> 00:32:36,912
In what respect?

437
00:32:38,165 --> 00:32:41,292
Has he acquired a touch
of civility in his address?

438
00:32:41,376 --> 00:32:43,878
For I dare not hope he
is improved in essentials.

439
00:32:43,962 --> 00:32:48,299
No. In essentials,
I believe he is very much...

440
00:32:48,383 --> 00:32:50,176
as he ever was.

441
00:32:51,553 --> 00:32:52,595
Ah.

442
00:32:53,722 --> 00:32:56,974
I don't mean to imply
that either his mind

443
00:32:57,059 --> 00:33:00,061
or his manners are
changed for the better.

444
00:33:00,854 --> 00:33:05,900
Rather: my knowing him better
improved my opinion of him.

445
00:33:06,985 --> 00:33:08,152
I see.

446
00:33:08,236 --> 00:33:11,739
(MRS FORSTER): Wickham. Wickham.

447
00:33:12,074 --> 00:33:16,327
- Come here.
- At your service, ma'am!

448
00:33:17,371 --> 00:33:19,664
Yes, go, go.

449
00:33:19,748 --> 00:33:22,083
I would not wish you back again.

450
00:33:27,881 --> 00:33:29,715
Goodbye, papa. Goodbye, mamma.

451
00:33:29,800 --> 00:33:33,511
Lydia, my dear,
we shall miss you most cruelly!

452
00:33:33,595 --> 00:33:36,806
I shall write every day of what I'm
doing and make you wild with envy.

453
00:33:36,890 --> 00:33:41,185
- I can't help it!
- I shall not envy her a jot!

454
00:33:41,478 --> 00:33:44,605
I must go. Goodbye, Jane.
Goodbye, Lizzy!

455
00:33:44,690 --> 00:33:48,776
If I see any eligible beaux for you,
I'll send word express!

456
00:33:49,361 --> 00:33:52,697
Lord, what a laugh if I should fall
and break my head!

457
00:33:52,781 --> 00:33:54,365
I wish you would!

458
00:33:54,449 --> 00:33:59,286
Oh, my dear girl. Take every
opportunity of enjoying yourself!

459
00:34:00,288 --> 00:34:02,289
Bye! Bye!

460
00:34:19,349 --> 00:34:23,144
Never mind, Kitty.
I dare say, in a year or two

461
00:34:23,228 --> 00:34:25,104
you'll have got over it tolerably well.

462
00:34:26,982 --> 00:34:31,777
If anyone should ask for me, I shall be
in my library, and not to be disturbed.

463
00:34:52,048 --> 00:34:56,844
(JANE): Hello! I can see, I can see
Alicia. Look how she has grown!

464
00:35:00,265 --> 00:35:02,767
(JANE): You must be so tired.

465
00:35:05,187 --> 00:35:10,024
You have all grown! I think you've all
grown since we last said goodbye!

466
00:35:10,108 --> 00:35:12,735
And very pretty too!
Come into the house, then.

467
00:35:12,819 --> 00:35:15,696
Such a sweet, steady girl!

468
00:35:15,906 --> 00:35:17,406
Well, Lizzy!

469
00:35:19,701 --> 00:35:23,788
We bear you bad tidings.
Not too grievous though, I hope.

470
00:35:23,872 --> 00:35:25,247
The guilt is mine.

471
00:35:25,332 --> 00:35:28,751
My business won't allow me
time away to visit all the Lake country.

472
00:35:28,835 --> 00:35:31,670
We shall have to content
ourselves with Derbyshire.

473
00:35:31,755 --> 00:35:32,797
Oh.

474
00:35:33,673 --> 00:35:36,675
But Derbyshire has many
beauties, has it not?

475
00:35:36,760 --> 00:35:40,137
Indeed. To me Derbyshire
is the best of all counties.

476
00:35:40,388 --> 00:35:44,433
You will judge for yourself whether
Chatsworth is not the equal of Blenheim.

477
00:35:44,518 --> 00:35:48,813
And surely these southern counties
have nothing to compare to the wild

478
00:35:48,897 --> 00:35:51,690
and untamed beauty of the Peaks.

479
00:35:58,031 --> 00:36:01,200
(UNCLE GARDINER): Nature and culture
in harmony, you see, Lizzy.

480
00:36:01,284 --> 00:36:05,996
Wildness and artifice,
and all in the one perfect county!

481
00:36:06,081 --> 00:36:10,000
(AUNT GARDINER): I was born here,
so I should never disagree with that!

482
00:36:10,085 --> 00:36:11,168
(LIZZY): Where?

483
00:36:11,253 --> 00:36:13,879
(AUNT): At Lambton,
a town of no consequence,

484
00:36:13,964 --> 00:36:16,924
but to those fortunate
enough to have lived in it.

485
00:36:17,133 --> 00:36:20,553
I think it the dearest
place in the world!

486
00:36:20,637 --> 00:36:23,722
Then I shall not be
happy till I have seen it.

487
00:36:23,932 --> 00:36:26,809
It has one further
claim on your interest:

488
00:36:26,893 --> 00:36:29,103
it is but five miles from Pemberley,

489
00:36:29,187 --> 00:36:32,857
and owes much of its
prosperity to that great estate.

490
00:36:32,941 --> 00:36:34,024
So near?

491
00:36:34,109 --> 00:36:36,694
Not that I or anyone of my acquaintance

492
00:36:36,778 --> 00:36:40,197
enjoyed the privilege
of intimacy with that family.

493
00:36:40,282 --> 00:36:43,033
We moved in very different circles.

494
00:36:54,754 --> 00:36:57,298
A hit! Acknowledged. Very good, sir!

495
00:36:58,800 --> 00:37:01,719
- Enough, sir?
- Enough. Thank you, Baines.

496
00:37:01,803 --> 00:37:05,764
- Will you come again tomorrow, sir?
- No, I have business in the North.

497
00:37:05,849 --> 00:37:09,894
- I'll come tomorrow week.
- Very good, sir. Bid you good day, sir.

498
00:37:09,978 --> 00:37:12,104
Thank you, Baines. Good day.

499
00:37:16,651 --> 00:37:20,154
I shall conquer this. I shall!

500
00:37:33,168 --> 00:37:35,461
(AUNT): Elizabeth, be careful!

501
00:37:35,545 --> 00:37:38,881
How could I face your
father if you took a fall?

502
00:37:43,011 --> 00:37:44,345
Beautiful!

503
00:37:52,062 --> 00:37:54,897
- Thank you, Hannah.
- You're welcome, sir.

504
00:37:57,651 --> 00:38:01,278
I should be quite happy to stay
my whole life in Derbyshire!

505
00:38:01,363 --> 00:38:06,450
I'm happy to hear it. What do you say
to visiting Pemberley tomorrow?

506
00:38:06,534 --> 00:38:10,287
It's not more than a mile
or two out of our way.

507
00:38:10,372 --> 00:38:12,581
Do you especially wish to see it, aunt?

508
00:38:12,666 --> 00:38:15,918
I thought you would,
having heard so much about it.

509
00:38:16,294 --> 00:38:19,046
The associations are
not all unpleasant.

510
00:38:19,130 --> 00:38:21,966
Wickham passed all
his youth there, you know.

511
00:38:22,050 --> 00:38:23,842
We have no business there.

512
00:38:23,927 --> 00:38:28,138
I should feel awkward to visit the place
without a proper invitation.

513
00:38:28,223 --> 00:38:32,309
No more than Blenheim or Chatsworth.
There was no awkwardness there.

514
00:38:32,394 --> 00:38:34,687
I shouldn't care for it myself, Lizzy,

515
00:38:34,771 --> 00:38:37,982
if it were merely a fine house,
richly furnished.

516
00:38:38,066 --> 00:38:40,067
But the grounds are delightful.

517
00:38:40,151 --> 00:38:42,987
They have some of the
finest woods in the country.

518
00:38:43,071 --> 00:38:47,449
- How far is Pemberley, my dear?
- Not more than five miles, sir.

519
00:38:47,534 --> 00:38:49,493
The grounds are very fine, are they not?

520
00:38:49,577 --> 00:38:52,496
As fine as you'll see anywhere, ma'am.

521
00:38:52,580 --> 00:38:55,582
My oldest brother is
an under-gardener there.

522
00:38:56,751 --> 00:38:59,920
- Is the family here for the summer?
- No, ma'am.

523
00:39:02,507 --> 00:39:03,549
Well?

524
00:39:06,803 --> 00:39:09,638
Perhaps we might visit
Pemberley after all.

525
00:39:42,589 --> 00:39:44,798
I think we've seen
woods and groves enough

526
00:39:44,883 --> 00:39:48,010
to satisfy even your
enthusiasm for them, Lizzy!

527
00:39:48,094 --> 00:39:51,722
I confess I had no idea Pemberley
was such a great estate.

528
00:39:51,806 --> 00:39:54,391
Shall we reach the house
itself before dark?

529
00:39:54,476 --> 00:39:56,518
Be patient. Wait.

530
00:40:00,648 --> 00:40:02,149
(AUNT): There!

531
00:40:02,817 --> 00:40:04,902
(UNCLE): Stop the coach!

532
00:40:09,574 --> 00:40:13,911
I think one would put up with a good
deal to be mistress of Pemberley.

533
00:40:13,995 --> 00:40:17,372
The mistress of Pemberley will
have to put up with a good deal,

534
00:40:17,457 --> 00:40:18,624
from what I hear.

535
00:40:18,708 --> 00:40:21,335
She's not likely to be anyone we know.

536
00:40:23,129 --> 00:40:27,216
- How do you like the house, Lizzy?
- Very well.

537
00:40:28,676 --> 00:40:32,554
I don't think I've ever seen a
place so happily situated.

538
00:40:33,681 --> 00:40:35,766
I like it very well indeed.

539
00:40:37,519 --> 00:40:39,103
(UNCLE): Drive on!

540
00:40:39,187 --> 00:40:43,565
A pity then, its owner should be
such a proud and disagreeable man.

541
00:40:44,400 --> 00:40:46,151
Yes, a great pity.

542
00:40:49,072 --> 00:40:50,614
Perhaps the beauty of the house

543
00:40:50,698 --> 00:40:54,118
renders its owner a little
less repulsive, Lizzy?

544
00:40:54,369 --> 00:40:56,286
Yes, perhaps.

545
00:40:58,039 --> 00:40:59,998
Perhaps a very little.

546
00:41:01,334 --> 00:41:06,380
Well, shall we apply to the housekeeper
to see inside the place?

547
00:41:23,273 --> 00:41:26,525
That's where Mrs Darcy used to
write her letters every morning.

548
00:41:26,609 --> 00:41:28,610
It was her favourite room.

549
00:41:34,242 --> 00:41:36,118
This is the music room.

550
00:41:38,746 --> 00:41:41,915
- (AUNT): Charming!
- (UNCLE): What a lovely room!

551
00:41:42,167 --> 00:41:43,917
(AUNT): Delightful!

552
00:41:47,755 --> 00:41:52,217
And there's a fine prospect from that
window down towards the lake.

553
00:41:53,553 --> 00:41:57,681
- (AUNT): Look at this, my dear.
- (UNCLE): It's quite magnificent!

554
00:42:03,646 --> 00:42:05,480
Of all this I might have been mistress.

555
00:42:05,565 --> 00:42:07,774
This piano has just come down.

556
00:42:07,859 --> 00:42:10,903
It's a present from my
master for Miss Georgiana.

557
00:42:10,987 --> 00:42:13,280
Your master is from home,
we understand.

558
00:42:13,364 --> 00:42:16,200
Yes, but we expect
him here tomorrow, sir.

559
00:42:16,409 --> 00:42:20,621
He is coming with a large party of
friends and Miss Georgiana.

560
00:42:25,543 --> 00:42:30,005
This portrait was painted earlier this
year, for her sixteenth birthday.

561
00:42:30,882 --> 00:42:33,800
She is a very handsome young lady!

562
00:42:33,885 --> 00:42:37,971
Oh, yes! The handsomest young
lady that ever was seen.

563
00:42:38,056 --> 00:42:43,227
And so accomplished.
She plays and sings all day long!

564
00:42:43,478 --> 00:42:44,645
Lizzy!

565
00:42:45,104 --> 00:42:46,939
Look at this picture.

566
00:42:50,151 --> 00:42:53,111
It reminds me very much
of someone we know!

567
00:42:53,196 --> 00:42:54,821
This one, ma'am?

568
00:42:55,156 --> 00:43:00,577
That young gentleman was the son of the
late Mr Darcy's steward, Mr Wickham.

569
00:43:00,662 --> 00:43:04,122
He is gone into the army now.
But he's turned out very wild.

570
00:43:04,207 --> 00:43:06,166
Very wild indeed, I'm afraid.

571
00:43:07,502 --> 00:43:11,880
And that's my master.
And very like him too.

572
00:43:11,965 --> 00:43:14,841
It's a handsome face,
but I've never seen the original.

573
00:43:14,926 --> 00:43:16,260
Is it like him, Lizzy?

574
00:43:16,344 --> 00:43:22,099
- Does this young lady know the master?
- Yes, a little.

575
00:43:22,183 --> 00:43:25,602
And he is a handsome gentleman,
is he not, ma'am?

576
00:43:25,687 --> 00:43:30,357
- Yes, very handsome.
- I'm sure I know none so handsome.

577
00:43:30,441 --> 00:43:32,567
- Nor so kind.
- (UNCLE): Indeed?

578
00:43:32,652 --> 00:43:36,655
Aye, sir.
I've never had a cross word from him,

579
00:43:36,739 --> 00:43:39,324
and I've known him since
he was four years old.

580
00:43:39,617 --> 00:43:44,288
I've observed that they that are
good-natured as children,

581
00:43:44,372 --> 00:43:46,665
are good-natured when they grow up.

582
00:43:46,749 --> 00:43:48,458
(AUNT): His father was an excellent man.

583
00:43:48,543 --> 00:43:52,296
He was, ma'am.
His son will be just like him.

584
00:43:52,380 --> 00:43:58,302
The best landlord, and the best master.
Ask any of his tenants or his servants.

585
00:43:58,928 --> 00:44:03,974
Some call him proud. I fancy that's only
because he don't rattle away,

586
00:44:04,058 --> 00:44:06,268
like other young men do.

587
00:44:06,352 --> 00:44:07,644
Now if you will follow me,

588
00:44:07,729 --> 00:44:11,773
there's a finer, larger portrait of
him in the gallery upstairs.

589
00:44:12,317 --> 00:44:14,526
This way, sir, if you please.

590
00:44:14,986 --> 00:44:17,654
This fine account of
Darcy is not quite consistent

591
00:44:17,739 --> 00:44:19,990
with his behaviour to poor Wickham.

592
00:44:20,074 --> 00:44:21,825
Perhaps we might have
been deceived there.

593
00:44:21,909 --> 00:44:24,494
That's not likely, is it?

594
00:45:21,636 --> 00:45:22,719
Ah!

595
00:45:24,472 --> 00:45:26,306
(UNCLE): Magnificent!

596
00:45:38,653 --> 00:45:40,737
(MRS REYNOLDS): There!

597
00:46:57,398 --> 00:46:58,857
(GROOM): Would you not
like to ride him, sir?

598
00:46:58,941 --> 00:47:01,526
(DARCY): No, take
him back to the stables.

599
00:47:35,353 --> 00:47:36,603
Mr Darcy.

600
00:47:38,981 --> 00:47:42,108
Miss Bennet. I...

601
00:47:42,193 --> 00:47:45,278
I did not expect to see you, sir.

602
00:47:45,363 --> 00:47:48,198
We understood the family were from home,
or we should never have...

603
00:47:48,282 --> 00:47:50,283
I returned a day early.

604
00:47:51,244 --> 00:47:53,620
Excuse me,
your parents are in good health?

605
00:47:54,080 --> 00:47:57,958
Yes, they are very well.
I thank you, sir.

606
00:47:58,459 --> 00:48:00,252
I'm glad to hear it.

607
00:48:01,879 --> 00:48:04,422
How long have you been in
this part of the country?

608
00:48:04,507 --> 00:48:06,174
But two days, sir.

609
00:48:08,135 --> 00:48:10,178
- Where are you staying?
- Lambton Inn.

610
00:48:10,263 --> 00:48:11,805
Yes, of course.

611
00:48:14,684 --> 00:48:16,935
Well, I'm just arrived myself.

612
00:48:18,813 --> 00:48:22,315
And your parents are in good health?
And all your sisters?

613
00:48:22,400 --> 00:48:26,236
Yes, they are all in
excellent health, sir.

614
00:48:28,990 --> 00:48:30,323
Excuse me.

615
00:48:39,292 --> 00:48:43,169
- The man himself, I presume!
- As handsome as in his portrait.

616
00:48:43,254 --> 00:48:46,256
Though perhaps a little
less formally attired.

617
00:48:46,340 --> 00:48:48,425
We must leave here at once!

618
00:48:48,509 --> 00:48:52,012
- Of course, if you wish.
- Oh, I wish we'd never come!

619
00:48:53,014 --> 00:48:56,808
- What must he think of me?
- (AUNT): What did he say?

620
00:48:57,476 --> 00:49:00,979
Nothing of consequence.
He enquired after my parents...

621
00:49:18,789 --> 00:49:20,373
Miss Bennet.

622
00:49:21,000 --> 00:49:25,337
Allow me to apologise for not receiving
you properly. Were you leaving?

623
00:49:25,421 --> 00:49:27,964
We were, sir. I think we must.

624
00:49:28,049 --> 00:49:30,675
I hope you are not
displeased with Pemberley?

625
00:49:32,094 --> 00:49:33,637
No, not at all.

626
00:49:34,513 --> 00:49:36,806
Then you approve of it?

627
00:49:36,891 --> 00:49:40,435
Very much.
I think there are few who would not.

628
00:49:40,519 --> 00:49:44,397
Your good opinion is rarely bestowed,
and therefore more worth the earning.

629
00:49:45,316 --> 00:49:46,650
Thank you.

630
00:49:48,361 --> 00:49:50,737
Would you introduce me to your friends?

631
00:49:51,238 --> 00:49:52,405
Certainly.

632
00:49:52,865 --> 00:49:55,825
Mr and Mrs Edward Gardiner, Mr Darcy.
Mrs Gardiner is my aunt, Mr Darcy.

633
00:49:55,910 --> 00:50:01,998
My sister Jane stayed at their house in
Cheapside when she was in London.

634
00:50:02,083 --> 00:50:05,001
Delighted to make your acquaintance,
madam, sir.

635
00:50:05,086 --> 00:50:06,544
You're staying at Lambton, I hear.

636
00:50:06,629 --> 00:50:09,631
Yes, sir. I grew up there as a girl.

637
00:50:09,715 --> 00:50:10,882
Delightful village.

638
00:50:10,966 --> 00:50:15,178
I ran to Lambton as a boy almost every
day in the horse-chestnut season.

639
00:50:15,429 --> 00:50:19,599
- There was one very fine tree there.
- On the green, by the smithy!

640
00:50:21,852 --> 00:50:26,356
- Mr Gardiner, do you care for fishing?
- Indeed I do, when I get the chance.

641
00:50:26,440 --> 00:50:29,150
You must fish in my trout stream.

642
00:50:29,235 --> 00:50:33,071
There are carp, tench and pike in
the lake, for coarse fishing.

643
00:50:33,280 --> 00:50:36,783
I'll gladly provide you with rods and
tackle, show you the best spots.

644
00:50:36,867 --> 00:50:38,118
Let's walk down now.

645
00:50:38,202 --> 00:50:41,246
Follow us to the lake.
My man will show you.

646
00:50:41,956 --> 00:50:44,082
(DARCY): There's a place down there
where we...

647
00:50:44,166 --> 00:50:46,710
Is this the proud Darcy you told us of?

648
00:50:46,794 --> 00:50:50,463
He is all ease and friendliness.
No false dignity at all!

649
00:50:50,631 --> 00:50:52,632
I'm as astonished as you are.

650
00:50:52,717 --> 00:50:55,385
I can't imagine what has
affected this transformation.

651
00:50:55,469 --> 00:50:56,970
Can you not?

652
00:51:17,491 --> 00:51:19,576
- (DARCY): Do you...
- (LIZZY): I...

653
00:51:19,660 --> 00:51:21,536
(DARCY): Pray continue.

654
00:51:22,496 --> 00:51:26,833
I was going to say again, sir,
how very unexpected your arrival was.

655
00:51:27,126 --> 00:51:29,627
If we had known you were to be here,
we should not have

656
00:51:29,712 --> 00:51:32,422
dreamt of invading your privacy.

657
00:51:32,757 --> 00:51:35,759
The housekeeper assured us
you would not be here until tomorrow.

658
00:51:35,843 --> 00:51:39,471
Do not make yourself uneasy.
I had planned it so myself,

659
00:51:39,555 --> 00:51:41,097
but I found I had
business with my steward.

660
00:51:41,182 --> 00:51:44,809
I rode on ahead
of the rest of the party.

661
00:51:46,061 --> 00:51:48,188
They will join me tomorrow.

662
00:51:49,356 --> 00:51:53,067
And among them are those who claim
an acquaintance with you.

663
00:51:54,153 --> 00:51:56,488
It's Mr Bingley and his sisters.

664
00:51:59,909 --> 00:52:00,992
Oh.

665
00:52:03,746 --> 00:52:05,955
There is the other
person in the party who

666
00:52:06,040 --> 00:52:08,750
more particularly wishes to know you.

667
00:52:10,586 --> 00:52:12,587
Will you allow me to...

668
00:52:13,506 --> 00:52:18,176
Do I ask too much to introduce my sister
to you, during your stay at Lambton?

669
00:52:20,930 --> 00:52:24,098
I should be very happy to
make her acquaintance.

670
00:52:25,267 --> 00:52:44,160
Thank you.

671
00:52:45,204 --> 00:52:47,789
I hope we shall meet again very soon.

672
00:52:48,165 --> 00:52:51,125
Good day, Mr Gardiner. Mrs Gardiner.

673
00:52:52,461 --> 00:00:00,-001
Good day, Miss Bennet.

