1
00:01:08,610 --> 00:01:12,029
(FATHER): I hope, my dear,
you have ordered a good dinner today,

2
00:01:12,114 --> 00:01:16,993
because I have reason to expect
an addition to our family party.

3
00:01:17,202 --> 00:01:19,454
Mr Bingley!

4
00:01:19,788 --> 00:01:23,458
Why, Jane, you sly thing,
you never dropped a word!

5
00:01:23,667 --> 00:01:25,918
(MOTHER): And no fish to be got!

6
00:01:26,003 --> 00:01:29,839
Lydia, my love, ring the bell.
I must speak to Hill!

7
00:01:31,425 --> 00:01:33,134
It is not Mr Bingley.

8
00:01:33,343 --> 00:01:36,846
It is a person I never saw
in the whole course of my life.

9
00:01:37,973 --> 00:01:39,891
- Colonel Forster!
- Captain Carter!

10
00:01:39,975 --> 00:01:41,267
No, I know. Denny!

11
00:01:46,940 --> 00:01:49,567
About a month ago
I received this letter.

12
00:01:50,736 --> 00:01:52,945
About a fortnight ago, I answered it,

13
00:01:53,030 --> 00:01:56,491
for it was a case of some delicacy,
requiring early attention.

14
00:01:56,825 --> 00:01:59,410
It is from my cousin, Mr Collins,

15
00:02:00,329 --> 00:02:05,166
who, when I am dead, may turn you all
out of this house as soon as he pleases.

16
00:02:05,250 --> 00:02:08,711
Oh, my dear,
pray don't mention that odious man!

17
00:02:09,046 --> 00:02:10,797
It is the hardest thing in the world,

18
00:02:10,881 --> 00:02:14,467
that your estate should be
entailed away from your children.

19
00:02:14,551 --> 00:02:16,969
Indeed, my dear,
nothing can clear Mr Collins

20
00:02:17,054 --> 00:02:19,305
of the iniquitous crime
of inheriting Longbourn,

21
00:02:19,389 --> 00:02:21,182
but if you'll listen to his letter,

22
00:02:21,266 --> 00:02:24,477
you may be softened
by how he expresses himself.

23
00:02:26,396 --> 00:02:27,522
"My dear sir,

24
00:02:27,606 --> 00:02:32,568
"the disagreement subsisting between
yourself and my late honoured father"

25
00:02:32,653 --> 00:02:35,029
"always gave me much uneasiness,

26
00:02:35,113 --> 00:02:38,032
"and since I have had
the misfortune to lose him..."

27
00:02:38,116 --> 00:02:39,534
(LYDIA SNORTS)

28
00:02:40,744 --> 00:02:45,665
"..to lose him, I have frequently wished
to heal the breach."

29
00:02:45,749 --> 00:02:50,461
There, Mrs Bennet. "My mind, however,
is now made up on the subject..."

30
00:02:50,754 --> 00:02:53,506
(COLLINS): ..for,
having received my ordination at Easter,

31
00:02:53,590 --> 00:02:56,175
I've been fortunate to be distinguished

32
00:02:56,260 --> 00:03:00,555
by the patronage of the Right Honourable
Lady Catherine de Bourgh,

33
00:03:03,642 --> 00:03:05,184
whose bounty and beneficence

34
00:03:05,269 --> 00:03:07,937
has preferred me
to the valuable rectory at Hunsford,

35
00:03:08,605 --> 00:03:11,232
where it's my endeavour to demean myself

36
00:03:11,316 --> 00:03:14,652
with grateful respect
towards her Ladyship.

37
00:03:16,029 --> 00:03:20,408
As a clergyman, moreover, I feel it
my duty to promote and establish

38
00:03:20,492 --> 00:03:24,954
the blessing of peace in all families
within the reach of my influence,

39
00:03:25,205 --> 00:03:27,999
and on these grounds I flatter myself

40
00:03:28,083 --> 00:03:31,669
that my overtures of goodwill
are highly commendable,

41
00:03:31,753 --> 00:03:36,090
and will not lead you to reject
the offered olive branch.

42
00:03:36,174 --> 00:03:38,551
I am, sir, keenly conscious

43
00:03:38,635 --> 00:03:41,637
of being the means
of injuring your amiable daughters,

44
00:03:41,722 --> 00:03:46,142
and assure you of my readiness to
make them every possible amends.

45
00:03:46,435 --> 00:03:48,311
I propose myself the satisfaction

46
00:03:48,395 --> 00:03:51,522
of waiting on you and
your family on Monday the 18th...

47
00:03:52,774 --> 00:03:54,275
Have care, Dawkins!

48
00:03:54,735 --> 00:03:57,236
..and shall probably
trespass on your hospitality

49
00:03:57,321 --> 00:03:59,488
till the Saturday sevenight following.

50
00:03:59,823 --> 00:04:03,743
I shall travel as far as the turnpike
in my own modest equipage,

51
00:04:03,827 --> 00:04:07,747
where I hope to catch the Bromley Post
at 35 minutes past ten,

52
00:04:07,831 --> 00:04:09,415
and thence to Watford,

53
00:04:09,499 --> 00:04:13,336
from whence I shall engage
a hired carriage to Longbourn.

54
00:04:13,754 --> 00:04:19,300
Where, God willing, you may expect me
by four in the afternoon.

55
00:04:19,384 --> 00:04:21,052
And here he comes.

56
00:04:22,387 --> 00:04:24,430
He must be an oddity, don't you think?

57
00:04:24,514 --> 00:04:27,600
If he's disposed
to make our girls any amends,

58
00:04:27,684 --> 00:04:29,852
I shan't be the person
to discourage him.

59
00:04:30,437 --> 00:04:33,773
- Can he be a sensible man, sir?
- I think not, my dear.

60
00:04:34,316 --> 00:04:39,028
Indeed, I have great hopes
of finding him quite the reverse.

61
00:04:43,992 --> 00:04:45,534
(FATHER): Mr Collins!

62
00:04:45,953 --> 00:04:47,370
You are very welcome!

63
00:04:56,046 --> 00:04:59,131
My dear Mr and Mrs Bennet!

64
00:05:05,597 --> 00:05:07,473
(FATHER): You seem very...

65
00:05:08,850 --> 00:05:11,227
..fortunate in your patroness, sir.

66
00:05:12,396 --> 00:05:14,438
Lady Catherine de Bourgh.

67
00:05:15,065 --> 00:05:17,066
Indeed I am, sir.

68
00:05:17,234 --> 00:05:21,195
I have been treated with
such affability, such condescension,

69
00:05:21,279 --> 00:05:24,073
as I would never have dared to hope for.

70
00:05:24,908 --> 00:05:29,245
I have been invited twice
to dine at Rosings Park.

71
00:05:31,206 --> 00:05:33,416
That so? Amazing.

72
00:05:34,668 --> 00:05:36,502
Does she live near you, sir?

73
00:05:37,254 --> 00:05:39,672
The garden,
in which stands my humble abode,

74
00:05:39,756 --> 00:05:43,467
is separated only by a lane
from Rosings Park.

75
00:05:43,635 --> 00:05:47,638
Only a lane, eh? Fancy that, Lizzy.

76
00:05:51,601 --> 00:05:55,813
I think you said she was a widow, sir?
Has she any family?

77
00:05:55,897 --> 00:05:57,565
She has one daughter, ma'am.

78
00:05:57,649 --> 00:06:01,944
The heiress of Rosings,
and of very extensive property.

79
00:06:02,529 --> 00:06:04,739
And has she been presented at court?

80
00:06:06,825 --> 00:06:09,702
She is unfortunately
of a sickly constitution

81
00:06:09,786 --> 00:06:12,204
which unhappily
prevents her being in town.

82
00:06:12,748 --> 00:06:17,543
And by that means,
as I told Lady Catherine myself one day,

83
00:06:17,836 --> 00:06:22,798
she has deprived the British Court
of its brightest ornament.

84
00:06:24,134 --> 00:06:26,218
You may imagine, sir, how happy I am

85
00:06:26,303 --> 00:06:29,013
on every occasion to offer
those little delicate compliments,

86
00:06:29,097 --> 00:06:31,474
which are always acceptable to ladies.

87
00:06:33,351 --> 00:06:35,227
That is fortunate for you,

88
00:06:35,312 --> 00:06:40,399
that you possess such an extraordinary
talent for flattering with delicacy.

89
00:06:40,942 --> 00:06:44,403
May I ask
whether these pleasing attentions

90
00:06:44,488 --> 00:06:47,073
proceed from the impulse of the moment,

91
00:06:47,157 --> 00:06:50,743
or are they the result
of previous study?

92
00:06:52,537 --> 00:06:55,623
They arise chiefly
from what is passing at the time, sir.

93
00:06:56,917 --> 00:06:59,126
I do sometimes amuse myself
by writing down

94
00:06:59,211 --> 00:07:01,462
and arranging such little compliments

95
00:07:01,546 --> 00:07:04,507
as may be adapted to ordinary occasions.

96
00:07:05,467 --> 00:07:08,385
But I try to give them
as unstudied an air as possible.

97
00:07:08,678 --> 00:07:09,845
Excellent.

98
00:07:11,723 --> 00:07:12,973
(FATHER): Excellent.

99
00:07:29,032 --> 00:07:31,784
(COLLINS): I must confess myself
quite overwhelmed

100
00:07:31,868 --> 00:07:33,994
with the charms of your daughters.

101
00:07:34,079 --> 00:07:38,290
Oh, you're very kind, sir. They are
sweet girls, though I say it myself.

102
00:07:38,959 --> 00:07:42,628
Perhaps especially the eldest
Miss Bennet?

103
00:07:42,712 --> 00:07:46,006
Ah, yes, Jane is admired
wherever she goes.

104
00:07:46,299 --> 00:07:48,467
But I think I should tell you,

105
00:07:48,552 --> 00:07:51,929
I think it very likely
she will be very soon engaged.

106
00:07:53,140 --> 00:07:55,599
- Ah.
- As for my younger daughters,

107
00:07:55,892 --> 00:07:57,309
if any of them...

108
00:07:57,394 --> 00:08:00,813
In their case
I know of no prior attachment at all.

109
00:08:00,897 --> 00:08:02,106
Ah.

110
00:08:15,287 --> 00:08:18,330
We're going to Meryton
to see if Denny is returned from town!

111
00:08:19,082 --> 00:08:22,042
Perhaps you would care
for a little exercise, Mr Collins?

112
00:08:23,378 --> 00:08:25,421
Indeed I would, Mrs Bennet.

113
00:08:26,965 --> 00:08:28,465
Cousin Elizabeth!

114
00:08:31,136 --> 00:08:35,139
Would you do me the great honour
of walking with me into town?

115
00:08:45,609 --> 00:08:49,153
(COLLINS): You visit your Aunt Philips
in Meryton frequently, I understand?

116
00:08:49,237 --> 00:08:50,988
(LIZZY): Yes, she is fond of company,

117
00:08:51,281 --> 00:08:53,365
but you'll find her gatherings
poor affairs

118
00:08:53,450 --> 00:08:55,284
after the splendours of Rosings Park.

119
00:08:56,036 --> 00:08:59,580
No, I think not.
I believe I possess the happy knack,

120
00:08:59,831 --> 00:09:01,874
much to be desired in a clergyman,

121
00:09:02,292 --> 00:09:06,921
of adapting myself to every kind
of society, whether high or low.

122
00:09:07,505 --> 00:09:09,048
That is fortunate indeed.

123
00:09:09,132 --> 00:09:12,176
Yes, indeed,
and though it is a gift of nature,

124
00:09:12,552 --> 00:09:15,971
constant study has enabled me,
I flatter myself,

125
00:09:16,473 --> 00:09:18,307
to make a kind of art of it.

126
00:09:41,289 --> 00:09:43,916
There! I'm sure that's new in
since Friday.

127
00:09:44,000 --> 00:09:46,418
Isn't it nice?
Don't you think I'd look well in it?

128
00:09:46,503 --> 00:09:49,004
- Not as well as me. Come on!
- No, I shan't.

129
00:09:49,506 --> 00:09:52,424
Jane! Come here. Look at this!

130
00:09:53,843 --> 00:09:55,636
Jane, I'm determined
to have this bonnet!

131
00:09:56,471 --> 00:09:57,972
Look, there's Denny!

132
00:09:59,140 --> 00:10:01,058
- Where?
- There. Look!

133
00:10:02,519 --> 00:10:04,687
- (KITTY): Who's with him?
- (LYDIA): Don't know.

134
00:10:04,771 --> 00:10:06,230
(KITTY): He's handsome!

135
00:10:06,314 --> 00:10:07,856
(LYDIA): He might be
if he were in regimentals.

136
00:10:08,024 --> 00:10:10,234
A man looks nothing without regimentals!

137
00:10:10,735 --> 00:10:12,111
They're looking over.

138
00:10:12,612 --> 00:10:14,655
Lizzy, isn't he mightily good-looking?

139
00:10:15,282 --> 00:10:17,241
- Denny!
- Lydia!

140
00:10:23,415 --> 00:10:24,790
We thought you were still in town!

141
00:10:24,874 --> 00:10:27,126
There was nothing amusing enough
to hold us there.

142
00:10:27,210 --> 00:10:30,045
May I introduce my friend
George Wickham?

143
00:10:30,380 --> 00:10:33,799
Miss Bennet, Miss Elizabeth Bennet,
Miss Mary Bennet,

144
00:10:33,883 --> 00:10:37,553
Miss Catherine Bennet
and Miss Lydia Bennet.

145
00:10:37,887 --> 00:10:39,805
This is our cousin, Mr Collins.

146
00:10:41,308 --> 00:10:43,225
Do you stay long in Meryton, Mr Wickham?

147
00:10:43,977 --> 00:10:45,561
All winter, I'm happy to say.

148
00:10:46,271 --> 00:10:48,814
I've taken a commission
in Colonel Forster's regiment.

149
00:10:49,399 --> 00:10:51,442
There, Lydia!
He will be dressed in regimentals.

150
00:10:52,527 --> 00:10:54,653
And lend them much distinction,
I dare say.

151
00:10:54,738 --> 00:10:56,613
Outswagger us all, eh, Wickham?

152
00:10:56,698 --> 00:10:59,283
You misrepresent me
to these young ladies.

153
00:10:59,659 --> 00:11:01,577
Shall you come with us
to Aunt Philips tonight?

154
00:11:02,412 --> 00:11:03,871
-(KITTY): Denny is coming!

155
00:11:03,955 --> 00:11:05,289
(LYDIA): It's only supper and cards.

156
00:11:06,666 --> 00:11:09,293
I haven't been invited
by Mr and Mrs Philips.

157
00:11:09,377 --> 00:11:11,795
(LYDIA): No one cares
about that nowadays!

158
00:11:11,880 --> 00:11:14,840
(WICKHAM): If Mrs Philips
extended the invitation to include me,

159
00:11:15,258 --> 00:11:16,508
I should be delighted.

160
00:11:19,429 --> 00:11:21,597
(KITTY): Look, Jane. It's Mr Bingley!

161
00:11:26,561 --> 00:11:31,106
How very fortunate! We were on our way
to Longbourn to ask after your health.

162
00:11:31,858 --> 00:11:35,736
(JANE): You're very kind, sir.
I'm quite recovered, as you see.

163
00:11:36,029 --> 00:11:38,280
(BINGLEY): Yes.
I'm very glad to know it.

164
00:11:59,469 --> 00:12:01,637
- Look, there's Denny!
- And Chamberlayne.

165
00:12:02,680 --> 00:12:06,100
(COLLINS): ..such a variety
of social intercourse.

166
00:12:07,560 --> 00:12:11,313
What a charming apartment you have here,
Mrs Philips.

167
00:12:12,190 --> 00:12:14,566
Upon my word, it reminds me greatly

168
00:12:14,651 --> 00:12:17,236
of the small summer breakfast room
at Rosings!

169
00:12:17,946 --> 00:12:21,824
Does it indeed, sir?
I'm much obliged to you, I'm sure.

170
00:12:21,991 --> 00:12:25,577
I'm sure Mr Collins
wishes to pay a compliment, Aunt.

171
00:12:25,662 --> 00:12:27,329
Does he? I see.

172
00:12:28,456 --> 00:12:33,419
Rosings Park, we must understand,
is very grand indeed.

173
00:12:33,503 --> 00:12:34,962
Indeed it is!

174
00:12:35,839 --> 00:12:39,258
My dear Madam,
if you thought I intended any slight

175
00:12:39,342 --> 00:12:43,303
on your excellent and very comfortable
arrangements, I am mortified!

176
00:12:44,431 --> 00:12:47,349
Rosings Park is the residence
of my noble patroness,

177
00:12:47,934 --> 00:12:50,018
Lady Catherine de Bourgh.

178
00:12:50,103 --> 00:12:52,646
Oh, now I understand.

179
00:12:52,730 --> 00:12:55,315
(COLLINS): The chimney piece
in the second drawing room alone

180
00:12:55,400 --> 00:12:57,443
cost 800 pounds!

181
00:12:57,527 --> 00:13:01,196
(MRS PHILIPS): Now I see,
there's no offence at all.

182
00:13:03,825 --> 00:13:06,994
Will you oblige me and sit down
to a game of whist?

183
00:13:07,454 --> 00:13:09,663
I must confess
I know little of the game, madam,

184
00:13:09,747 --> 00:13:12,499
but I shall be glad to improve myself.

185
00:13:13,376 --> 00:13:16,753
If my fair cousin
will consent to release me?

186
00:13:17,422 --> 00:13:19,089
With all my heart, sir.

187
00:13:39,611 --> 00:13:42,362
Oh, Mr Collins!

188
00:13:42,697 --> 00:13:47,284
- What were trumps again?
- Hearts, Mr Collins! Hearts.

189
00:14:03,051 --> 00:14:06,720
I must confess I thought
I'd never escape your younger sisters.

190
00:14:07,764 --> 00:14:11,058
They can be very determined.
Lydia especially.

191
00:14:12,602 --> 00:14:13,685
But they're pleasant girls.

192
00:14:14,395 --> 00:14:17,814
I find that society in Hertfordshire
quite exceeds my expectations.

193
00:14:19,776 --> 00:14:22,277
I don't see Mr Bingley
and his friends here.

194
00:14:23,321 --> 00:14:27,366
I think some of Mr Bingley's friends
would consider it beneath their dignity.

195
00:14:27,992 --> 00:14:29,117
Really?

196
00:14:32,288 --> 00:14:34,081
Have you known Mr Darcy long?

197
00:14:35,667 --> 00:14:38,460
- About a month.
- I've known him all my life.

198
00:14:39,128 --> 00:14:42,673
- We played together as children.
- But...

199
00:14:43,216 --> 00:14:44,675
Yes, you're surprised.

200
00:14:45,760 --> 00:14:48,554
Perhaps you noticed the cold manner
of our greeting?

201
00:14:50,139 --> 00:14:51,640
I confess I did.

202
00:14:53,017 --> 00:14:54,268
Do you...

203
00:14:56,646 --> 00:14:58,981
Are you much acquainted with Mr Darcy?

204
00:15:01,025 --> 00:15:03,986
As much as I ever wish to be.

205
00:15:04,320 --> 00:15:06,238
I've spent three days
in the same house with him,

206
00:15:06,322 --> 00:15:09,491
and I find him very disagreeable.

207
00:15:10,785 --> 00:15:15,247
I fear there are few who would share
that opinion... except myself.

208
00:15:17,166 --> 00:15:19,334
But he's not at all liked
in Hertfordshire.

209
00:15:20,003 --> 00:15:22,421
Everybody is disgusted with his pride.

210
00:15:23,256 --> 00:15:24,548
Do you know...

211
00:15:25,967 --> 00:15:28,260
Does he intend to stay long
at Netherfield?

212
00:15:28,344 --> 00:15:29,553
I do not know.

213
00:15:30,179 --> 00:15:33,682
I hope his being in the neighbourhood
will not affect your plans to stay.

214
00:15:34,517 --> 00:15:40,439
Thank you. But it is not for me
to be driven away by Mr Darcy.

215
00:15:40,523 --> 00:15:42,608
If he wishes to avoid seeing me,
he must go.

216
00:15:43,359 --> 00:15:45,444
We're not on friendly terms,

217
00:15:45,528 --> 00:15:49,114
but I have no reason to avoid him
but one: he's done me great wrong.

218
00:15:52,368 --> 00:15:55,621
His father, the late Mr Darcy,
was my Godfather,

219
00:15:55,705 --> 00:15:57,664
and one of the best men
that ever breathed.

220
00:15:59,167 --> 00:16:00,542
My father was his steward,

221
00:16:01,544 --> 00:16:03,962
and when he died,
old Mr Darcy cared for me,

222
00:16:05,173 --> 00:16:06,840
provided for me, loved me, I believe,

223
00:16:07,842 --> 00:16:12,471
as though I were his own son.
He intended me for the church.

224
00:16:14,182 --> 00:16:16,933
And it was my dearest wish
to enter into that profession.

225
00:16:18,811 --> 00:16:23,398
But after he died, and the living
he'd promised me fell vacant,

226
00:16:25,193 --> 00:16:28,904
the son refused point blank
to honour his father's promises.

227
00:16:30,198 --> 00:16:33,367
And so, you see,
I have to make my own way in the world.

228
00:16:34,410 --> 00:16:36,078
This is quite shocking!

229
00:16:36,245 --> 00:16:38,538
I had not thought Mr Darcy
as bad as this.

230
00:16:39,332 --> 00:16:43,293
To descend to such malicious revenge.
He deserves to be publicly disgraced!

231
00:16:43,920 --> 00:16:45,837
Some day he will be, but not by me.

232
00:16:46,839 --> 00:16:50,175
Till I can forget his father,
I can't defy or expose him.

233
00:16:50,259 --> 00:16:52,344
(LYDIA LAUGHS)

234
00:16:56,307 --> 00:17:00,310
(LIZZY): I wonder at the pride
of this man. How abominable!

235
00:17:00,728 --> 00:17:03,814
You're more temperate
than I'd be in your situation.

236
00:17:04,941 --> 00:17:07,776
Well, I have not the resentful temper
that some men have.

237
00:17:09,278 --> 00:17:11,655
And my situation, you know,
is not so bad.

238
00:17:12,949 --> 00:17:15,033
At present I have every cause for cheer!

239
00:17:15,243 --> 00:17:17,160
I can't bear to be idle,

240
00:17:17,912 --> 00:17:20,330
and my new profession
gives me active employment.

241
00:17:21,165 --> 00:17:23,250
My fellow officers are excellent men.

242
00:17:24,127 --> 00:17:27,504
And now I find myself in a society
as agreeable as any I've ever known.

243
00:17:28,840 --> 00:17:31,883
I absolutely forbid you
to feel sorry for me!

244
00:17:31,968 --> 00:17:35,387
Lizzy? Lizzy, why should you feel sorry
for Mr Wickham?

245
00:17:36,639 --> 00:17:38,473
Why? Because...

246
00:17:39,517 --> 00:17:42,769
Because I've not had a dance
these three months together!

247
00:17:42,854 --> 00:17:46,398
Poor Mr Wickham!
Well, you shall have one now.

248
00:17:46,482 --> 00:17:48,942
Mary, Mary! The Barley Mow!

249
00:17:50,153 --> 00:17:53,780
(MRS PHILIPS): Oh, Mr Collins!

250
00:18:08,212 --> 00:18:10,088
I cannot believe it!

251
00:18:10,173 --> 00:18:13,425
Mr Darcy's respect
for his father's wishes

252
00:18:13,509 --> 00:18:15,969
wouldn't allow him to behave
in such an unchristian way.

253
00:18:16,512 --> 00:18:21,308
Lizzy, consider, how could his most
intimate friends be so deceived in him?

254
00:18:22,518 --> 00:18:26,104
I could more easily imagine Mr Bingley
being imposed upon,

255
00:18:26,189 --> 00:18:29,024
than to think that Mr Wickham
could invent such a history!

256
00:18:30,359 --> 00:18:32,903
I believe you like Mr Wickham, Lizzy.

257
00:18:36,115 --> 00:18:37,741
I confess I do like him.

258
00:18:40,286 --> 00:18:42,579
I do not see how anyone
could not like him.

259
00:18:44,081 --> 00:18:46,875
There's something very open
and artless in his manner.

260
00:18:48,002 --> 00:18:49,795
He feels deeply, I believe,

261
00:18:50,922 --> 00:18:55,217
and yet has a natural merriment
and energy, despite all this.

262
00:18:57,094 --> 00:18:59,429
Yes, Jane,
I confess I like him very much.

263
00:19:01,057 --> 00:19:03,391
But after so short an acquaintance,

264
00:19:04,769 --> 00:19:07,562
do you think we should believe in him
so implicitly?

265
00:19:08,064 --> 00:19:09,564
How could he be doubted?

266
00:19:11,025 --> 00:19:14,653
He gave me all the circumstances, Jane.
Names, facts.

267
00:19:16,072 --> 00:19:17,948
And everything without ceremony.

268
00:19:19,075 --> 00:19:20,826
Let Mr Darcy contradict it!

269
00:19:20,910 --> 00:19:23,161
Besides, there was truth
in all his looks.

270
00:19:25,790 --> 00:19:27,415
It is difficult, indeed.

271
00:19:29,335 --> 00:19:33,421
It is distressing.
One does not know what to think.

272
00:19:35,258 --> 00:19:38,468
I beg your pardon,
one knows exactly what to think!

273
00:19:39,262 --> 00:19:44,307
(MOTHER): Oh, girls! Girls, we have all
been invited to a ball at Netherfield!

274
00:19:44,392 --> 00:19:46,560
- I love a ball!
- So do I!

275
00:19:46,644 --> 00:19:49,771
This will be a compliment to you, Jane,
you know.

276
00:19:51,190 --> 00:19:54,317
The invitation includes you, Mr Collins.

277
00:19:57,864 --> 00:19:59,573
But shall you accept, sir?

278
00:19:59,699 --> 00:20:02,242
Would it be entirely proper?
Would your bishop approve?

279
00:20:02,910 --> 00:20:05,912
Your scruples do you credit,
my dear cousin.

280
00:20:06,163 --> 00:20:08,999
I am of the opinion
that a ball of this kind,

281
00:20:09,208 --> 00:20:12,627
given by a man of good character
to respectable people,

282
00:20:13,462 --> 00:20:15,463
can have no evil tendency.

283
00:20:16,299 --> 00:20:19,968
And I am so far
from objecting to dancing myself,

284
00:20:20,052 --> 00:20:21,553
that I shall hope to be honoured

285
00:20:21,637 --> 00:20:25,765
with the hands of all my fair cousins
during the evening!

286
00:20:28,477 --> 00:20:32,272
And I take this opportunity
of soliciting yours...

287
00:20:33,816 --> 00:20:37,360
..Miss Elizabeth,
for the first two dances!

288
00:20:37,445 --> 00:20:38,570
(LYDIA AND KITTY GIGGLE)

289
00:20:38,654 --> 00:20:40,655
(COLLINS HUMS A SONG)

290
00:20:49,832 --> 00:20:54,169
I dare say you'll be able to imagine
the scope of the whole, Mr Wickham,

291
00:20:54,253 --> 00:20:58,715
when I tell you that the chimney piece
alone, in the second drawing room,

292
00:20:58,799 --> 00:21:01,593
cost all of 800 pounds!

293
00:21:01,677 --> 00:21:05,847
800 pounds, sir! I hazard a guess
it must be a very large one?

294
00:21:06,265 --> 00:21:08,642
It is very large, indeed, sir.

295
00:21:09,310 --> 00:21:11,645
Her Ladyship is fond
of a good blaze, then?

296
00:21:11,729 --> 00:21:13,188
Oh...

297
00:21:13,272 --> 00:21:15,023
(JANE): Mr Collins!

298
00:21:15,524 --> 00:21:19,110
How fortunate!
I must claim you for my sister Mary.

299
00:21:19,195 --> 00:21:23,031
She's found a passage in Fordyce's
Sermons that she can't make out.

300
00:21:23,324 --> 00:21:24,699
Well, I...

301
00:21:24,784 --> 00:21:27,661
I believe it is of
great doctrinal import, sir.

302
00:21:29,246 --> 00:21:31,665
- In that case...
- You're very kind, sir.

303
00:21:32,249 --> 00:21:33,708
She's in the drawing room.

304
00:21:41,509 --> 00:21:43,510
Mr Collins' conversation is very...

305
00:21:44,679 --> 00:21:45,720
..wholesome.

306
00:21:46,514 --> 00:21:49,140
And there is plenty to be had of it,
I assure you!

307
00:21:53,729 --> 00:21:55,730
Have you made
Mr Bingley's acquaintance yet?

308
00:21:55,898 --> 00:21:56,898
No.

309
00:21:57,483 --> 00:21:59,651
But I'm disposed to approve of him.

310
00:22:00,277 --> 00:22:03,154
He has issued a general invitation
to the officers for his ball,

311
00:22:03,239 --> 00:22:05,782
which has caused great joy
in more than one quarter.

312
00:22:07,118 --> 00:22:09,786
- He must be a very amiable gentleman.
- Oh, yes.

313
00:22:10,913 --> 00:22:13,081
He is eager to approve
of everyone he meets,

314
00:22:13,165 --> 00:22:15,834
but he's a sensible man,
with taste and judgement.

315
00:22:16,669 --> 00:22:20,463
I wonder very much
how Mr Darcy could impose upon him.

316
00:22:20,548 --> 00:22:22,632
He cannot know what Mr Darcy is.

317
00:22:22,717 --> 00:22:23,925
Probably not.

318
00:22:24,593 --> 00:22:27,971
Mr Darcy can please what he chooses,
if he thinks it worth his while.

319
00:22:28,514 --> 00:22:30,348
Among his equals
in wealth and consequence,

320
00:22:30,433 --> 00:22:31,933
he can be liberal-minded,

321
00:22:32,560 --> 00:22:35,186
honourable, even agreeable.

322
00:22:36,355 --> 00:22:38,732
I wonder you can speak of him
so tolerantly.

323
00:22:39,108 --> 00:22:40,442
He is not wholly bad.

324
00:22:44,447 --> 00:22:47,991
Tell me,
what sort of girl is Miss Darcy?

325
00:22:49,285 --> 00:22:51,036
I wish I could call her amiable.

326
00:22:52,246 --> 00:22:55,331
As a child, she was affectionate
and pleasing, and fond of me.

327
00:22:56,167 --> 00:22:58,418
I've devoted hours to her amusement,

328
00:22:58,627 --> 00:23:03,339
but she is grown too much
like her brother. Very... proud.

329
00:23:04,300 --> 00:23:07,886
I never see her now. Since her father's
death, her home has been in London.

330
00:23:08,804 --> 00:23:12,474
She is but 1 6 years old.
Your sister Lydia's age.

331
00:23:13,684 --> 00:23:15,685
Lydia is 1 5.

332
00:23:28,491 --> 00:23:31,743
I was amused by your cousin's reference
to Lady Catherine de Bourgh.

333
00:23:32,536 --> 00:23:36,956
She's Mr Darcy's aunt, and her daughter
Anne, who will inherit a large fortune,

334
00:23:37,041 --> 00:23:38,958
is destined to be Mr Darcy's bride.

335
00:23:40,336 --> 00:23:41,419
Really?!

336
00:23:45,007 --> 00:23:46,091
Poor Miss Bingley.

337
00:23:56,310 --> 00:23:59,521
Ah, you look very well, Lizzy!

338
00:23:59,855 --> 00:24:02,190
You'll never be as pretty
as your sister Jane,

339
00:24:02,274 --> 00:24:05,360
but I will say
you look very well indeed!

340
00:24:06,070 --> 00:24:07,362
Thank you, mamma.

341
00:24:07,988 --> 00:24:11,074
I hope you will pay Mr Collins
every courtesy tonight,

342
00:24:11,158 --> 00:24:13,326
because he's been very attentive to you!

343
00:24:13,536 --> 00:24:15,703
(KITTY): Your gown
is very unbecoming, too!

344
00:24:16,288 --> 00:24:20,083
- Then I shall ask Lizzy!
- Lydia, what are you doing?

345
00:24:20,167 --> 00:24:22,293
Go back in your room and dress yourself!

346
00:24:22,378 --> 00:24:24,045
I have to ask Lizzy something!

347
00:24:26,132 --> 00:24:29,342
Lizzy, look. What do you think?

348
00:24:29,552 --> 00:24:31,845
Kitty says not,
but I think it becomes me very well.

349
00:24:31,929 --> 00:24:35,098
- I wonder that you ask me.
- You look very nice.

350
00:24:35,391 --> 00:24:36,391
Thank you.

351
00:24:36,809 --> 00:24:39,018
Don't keep Wickham to yourself.

352
00:24:39,228 --> 00:24:41,146
Kitty and I want to
dance with him as well.

353
00:24:41,230 --> 00:24:43,648
I promise I shall not.
Even if I wished to, I could not.

354
00:24:44,441 --> 00:24:47,360
I have to dance the first two
with Mr Collins.

355
00:24:47,570 --> 00:24:50,155
Lord, yes.
He's threatened to dance with us all!

356
00:25:02,209 --> 00:25:05,378
(LYDIA GIGGLES)

357
00:25:15,556 --> 00:25:20,310
(LAUGHS HEARD FROM LYDIA AND KITTY)

358
00:26:15,366 --> 00:26:19,077
My dear Jane, how delightful to see you,
and so well recovered!

359
00:26:19,954 --> 00:26:23,456
Louisa and I have been quite desolate
without you, haven't we?

360
00:26:23,707 --> 00:26:25,333
- Mr Hurst?
- What?

361
00:26:26,210 --> 00:26:29,087
- Oh, Mrs Bennet!
- Delighted.

362
00:26:29,171 --> 00:26:30,421
Mr Bennet.

363
00:26:30,506 --> 00:26:33,007
Mrs Bennet, Mr Bennet! Quite delighted.

364
00:26:33,968 --> 00:26:36,261
- And all your daughters.
- There's Denny!

365
00:26:36,345 --> 00:26:39,973
- And Chamberlayne!
- And my cousin Mr Collins.

366
00:26:40,057 --> 00:26:43,810
(COLLINS): May I congratulate you on
your very elegant arrangements, ma'am?

367
00:26:43,894 --> 00:26:45,979
(COLLINS): It puts me to mind
greatly of...

368
00:26:46,063 --> 00:26:49,065
Perhaps you may have
visited Rosings Park?

369
00:26:57,491 --> 00:26:58,574
Miss Bennet.

370
00:28:01,305 --> 00:28:04,349
Miss Bennet. You look quite
remarkably well this evening.

371
00:28:04,433 --> 00:28:05,558
Thank you.

372
00:28:06,268 --> 00:28:09,687
I'm instructed to convey
my friend Wickham's regrets

373
00:28:09,772 --> 00:28:12,148
that he cannot attend the ball.

374
00:28:12,399 --> 00:28:14,901
He's gone to town
on a matter of urgent business,

375
00:28:15,444 --> 00:28:19,113
which probably became urgent as
he wished to avoid a certain gentleman.

376
00:28:25,621 --> 00:28:28,664
Denny! I hope you're prepared
to dance with us tonight!

377
00:28:28,749 --> 00:28:30,291
Forgive the intrusion.

378
00:28:30,376 --> 00:28:33,544
I would dance with both of your sisters
at once if I could, but...

379
00:28:33,629 --> 00:28:35,296
Never mind that. Come on, Denny!

380
00:28:55,025 --> 00:28:56,150
Charlotte!

381
00:28:56,902 --> 00:28:58,820
I have so much to acquaint you with!

382
00:29:01,615 --> 00:29:06,619
Charlotte, may I present our cousin,
Mr Collins? My friend, Miss Lucas.

383
00:29:06,995 --> 00:29:09,163
- How do you do, sir?
- Miss Lucas.

384
00:29:09,248 --> 00:29:12,542
I'm indeed honoured
to meet any friend of my fair cousins.

385
00:29:13,377 --> 00:29:15,253
So many agreeable young ladies!

386
00:29:15,921 --> 00:29:17,255
I'm quite enraptured!

387
00:29:51,373 --> 00:29:54,876
- Other way, Mr Collins!
- Madam, a thousand apologies...

388
00:29:54,960 --> 00:29:57,044
My dear cousin, I apologize.

389
00:30:16,565 --> 00:30:19,567
(THE MUSIC DROWNS MOTHER'S VOICE)

390
00:31:24,800 --> 00:31:27,969
It's extraordinary!
Are you sure it's true?

391
00:31:28,053 --> 00:31:29,637
Charlotte, how could it be otherwise?

392
00:31:29,721 --> 00:31:31,180
Every circumstance confirms it.

393
00:31:31,265 --> 00:31:34,433
And Mr Darcy has boasted to me
himself of his resentful....

394
00:31:34,518 --> 00:31:36,602
- Lizzy!
- What?

395
00:31:42,109 --> 00:31:43,943
If you're not otherwise engaged,

396
00:31:44,027 --> 00:31:46,487
would you do me the honour
of dancing the next with me?

397
00:31:46,572 --> 00:31:48,990
Why I... had not...

398
00:31:50,742 --> 00:31:52,118
I thank you. Yes.

399
00:31:55,706 --> 00:31:58,833
Why couldn't I think of an excuse?
Hateful man!

400
00:31:59,126 --> 00:32:01,252
I promised myself
I'd never dance with him.

401
00:32:01,336 --> 00:32:04,505
He pays you a great compliment
in singling you out, Lizzy.

402
00:32:05,257 --> 00:32:08,426
Think what you are doing.
You'd be a simpleton

403
00:32:08,510 --> 00:32:09,885
if you let your fancy for Wickham

404
00:32:09,970 --> 00:32:13,347
lead you to slight a man
of ten times his consequence.

405
00:33:15,994 --> 00:33:19,121
I believe we must have
some conversation, Mr Darcy.

406
00:33:21,124 --> 00:33:23,125
A very little will suffice.

407
00:33:30,258 --> 00:33:32,718
You should say
something about the dance, perhaps.

408
00:33:34,137 --> 00:33:36,222
I might remark on the number of couples.

409
00:33:41,770 --> 00:33:43,521
Do you talk by rule when you're dancing?

410
00:33:43,605 --> 00:33:45,523
Sometimes it's best.

411
00:33:45,607 --> 00:33:48,734
Then we may enjoy the advantage
of saying as little as possible.

412
00:33:57,035 --> 00:34:00,454
Do you consult your own feelings
in this case, or seek to gratify mine?

413
00:34:06,336 --> 00:34:07,670
Both, I imagine.

414
00:34:15,470 --> 00:34:18,639
We are both unwilling to speak

415
00:34:18,724 --> 00:34:21,392
unless we expect to say something
that will amaze the whole room.

416
00:34:22,519 --> 00:34:25,646
This is no striking resemblance of
your own character, I'm sure.

417
00:35:14,613 --> 00:35:18,115
- Do you often walk into Meryton?
- Yes, quite often.

418
00:35:23,371 --> 00:35:26,290
When you met us, we had
just been forming a new acquaintance.

419
00:35:34,800 --> 00:35:37,802
Mr Wickham's happy manners
enable him to make friends.

420
00:35:37,886 --> 00:35:40,888
Whether he is equally capable
of keeping them, is less certain.

421
00:35:46,645 --> 00:35:48,521
He has been unlucky
to lose your friendship

422
00:35:48,605 --> 00:35:50,731
in a way he'll suffer from all his life.

423
00:35:54,402 --> 00:35:56,237
Allow me to congratulate you, sir!

424
00:35:56,321 --> 00:35:59,031
Such superior dancing
is rarely to be seen.

425
00:35:59,115 --> 00:36:02,743
I'm sure your fair partner
is well worthy of you.

426
00:36:02,953 --> 00:36:05,037
I hope this pleasure is repeated often.

427
00:36:05,121 --> 00:36:09,500
Especially when a certain
desirable event takes place.

428
00:36:09,584 --> 00:36:10,751
Eh, Miss Lizzy?

429
00:36:11,962 --> 00:36:14,213
What congratulations will then flow in!

430
00:36:14,297 --> 00:36:15,339
Sir, I...

431
00:36:15,423 --> 00:36:19,677
I understand! I'll not detain you longer
from your bewitching partner!

432
00:36:19,761 --> 00:36:22,930
A great pleasure, sir. Capital! Capital!

433
00:36:27,936 --> 00:36:31,105
I remember hearing you once say
that you hardly ever forgave.

434
00:36:31,189 --> 00:36:33,607
That your resentment once created
was implacable.

435
00:36:34,359 --> 00:36:37,778
You're careful, aren't you,
in allowing resentment to be created?

436
00:36:37,863 --> 00:36:38,946
I am.

437
00:36:51,793 --> 00:36:54,295
And never allow yourself to be blinded
by prejudice?

438
00:36:55,922 --> 00:36:57,006
I hope not.

439
00:36:57,632 --> 00:36:59,675
May I ask to what these questions tend?

440
00:37:00,844 --> 00:37:04,471
Merely to the illustration of your
character. I'm trying to make it out.

441
00:37:05,473 --> 00:37:08,434
- What is your success?
- I don't get on at all.

442
00:37:09,060 --> 00:37:12,229
I hear such different accounts of you
as to puzzle me exceedingly.

443
00:37:39,883 --> 00:37:42,718
I wish that you wouldn't attempt
to sketch my character

444
00:37:42,802 --> 00:37:44,053
at the present moment.

445
00:37:44,763 --> 00:37:47,431
The performance should reflect no credit
on either of us.

446
00:37:48,266 --> 00:37:51,727
If I don't take your likeness now,
I may never have another opportunity!

447
00:37:52,437 --> 00:37:54,897
I would by no means suspend any pleasure
of yours.

448
00:38:00,153 --> 00:38:03,238
(VOICES DROWNED IN PARTY SOUNDS)

449
00:38:22,092 --> 00:38:25,719
Miss Eliza, I hear you're quite
delighted with George Wickham.

450
00:38:26,096 --> 00:38:29,556
No doubt he forgot to tell you,
among his other communications,

451
00:38:29,849 --> 00:38:32,267
that he was merely
the son of old Wickham,

452
00:38:32,352 --> 00:38:34,478
the late Mr Darcy's steward!

453
00:38:37,482 --> 00:38:39,608
But, Eliza, as a friend,

454
00:38:39,734 --> 00:38:43,737
let me recommend you not to give credit
to all his assertions.

455
00:38:43,822 --> 00:38:46,865
Wickham treated Darcy
in an infamous manner.

456
00:38:47,242 --> 00:38:49,159
Has he? How?

457
00:38:49,452 --> 00:38:51,662
I don't remember the particulars,

458
00:38:51,746 --> 00:38:55,416
but I do know that Mr Darcy
was not in the least to blame.

459
00:38:56,835 --> 00:39:01,296
I pity you, Eliza, for the discovery
of your favourite's guilt,

460
00:39:01,381 --> 00:39:05,467
but really, considering his descent,
one could not expect much better.

461
00:39:06,386 --> 00:39:10,264
His guilt and his descent
appear by your account to be the same.

462
00:39:10,348 --> 00:39:14,309
You accuse him only of being
the son of Mr Darcy's steward,

463
00:39:14,394 --> 00:39:16,103
which he informed me of himself.

464
00:39:16,855 --> 00:39:17,938
I beg your pardon.

465
00:39:19,107 --> 00:39:22,276
Excuse my interference.
It was kindly meant.

466
00:39:35,040 --> 00:39:37,041
- Insolent girl!
- Lizzy!

467
00:39:37,125 --> 00:39:38,792
I see nothing in her paltry attack

468
00:39:38,877 --> 00:39:41,503
but her own ignorance
and the malice of Mr Darcy!

469
00:39:41,880 --> 00:39:43,422
Yes, but Lizzy...

470
00:39:46,509 --> 00:39:49,470
Mr Bingley said, that though
he doesn't know the whole history,

471
00:39:49,804 --> 00:39:53,932
he fears that Mr Wickham
is by no means a respectable young man.

472
00:39:54,142 --> 00:39:56,935
- Does he know Mr Wickham?
- No.

473
00:39:57,020 --> 00:39:59,813
Well, then he just had his account
from Mr Darcy.

474
00:40:01,107 --> 00:40:05,486
I don't doubt Mr Bingley's sincerity.
Of course he would believe his friend.

475
00:40:05,653 --> 00:40:07,321
As to the other two gentlemen,

476
00:40:08,156 --> 00:40:10,574
I shall venture to think of them both
as I did before.

477
00:40:11,034 --> 00:40:15,120
Shall we not have some music?
I have a great desire for a song!

478
00:40:15,497 --> 00:40:17,122
Caroline, can we persuade you?

479
00:40:21,002 --> 00:40:22,127
Miss Mary Bennet.

480
00:40:23,797 --> 00:40:25,339
You've anticipated me.

481
00:40:41,773 --> 00:40:47,861
# Slumber,

482
00:40:47,946 --> 00:40:50,864
# dear maid

483
00:40:56,788 --> 00:41:02,167
# Green bows will cover thee

484
00:41:02,252 --> 00:41:07,798
# Cometh breathe over thee

485
00:41:08,091 --> 00:41:11,969
# Where thou art laid

486
00:41:12,512 --> 00:41:16,682
# Slumber, dear maid...

487
00:41:16,766 --> 00:41:18,267
Lizzy! Look.

488
00:41:20,395 --> 00:41:21,979
But they haven't been introduced!

489
00:41:22,063 --> 00:41:25,149
- Can we not prevent him?
- Too late.

490
00:41:27,318 --> 00:41:33,115
Mr Darcy. I have made a remarkable...
I must say, an amazing discovery!

491
00:41:33,366 --> 00:41:34,908
I understand that you are the nephew

492
00:41:34,993 --> 00:41:38,036
of Lady Catherine de Bourgh
of Rosings Park!

493
00:41:39,372 --> 00:41:43,125
Mr Darcy, I am happy
to be able to inform you

494
00:41:43,209 --> 00:41:46,003
that her Ladyship
was in the best of health...

495
00:41:46,754 --> 00:41:48,422
..eight days ago.

496
00:41:50,508 --> 00:41:51,758
I'm glad to hear it.

497
00:41:56,139 --> 00:42:00,934
- And what is your name, sir?
- My name is William Collins, Mr Darcy.

498
00:42:01,477 --> 00:42:04,771
And I have a very great honour to...

499
00:42:05,607 --> 00:42:08,442
Well. Well.

500
00:42:12,071 --> 00:42:17,367
# Green bows will cover thee

501
00:42:17,702 --> 00:42:22,831
# Cometh breathe over thee

502
00:42:22,916 --> 00:42:25,083
(THE DOG JOINS IN THE SINGING)

503
00:42:26,711 --> 00:42:28,045
Rowley!

504
00:42:31,049 --> 00:42:36,136
# Where thou art laid

505
00:42:49,525 --> 00:42:54,655
# My Mother bids me bind my hair

506
00:42:54,739 --> 00:42:59,159
# With bands of rosy hue

507
00:43:00,119 --> 00:43:04,331
That'll do extremely well, child.
You've delighted us long enough.

508
00:43:06,209 --> 00:43:09,586
Let the other young ladies
have time to exhibit.

509
00:43:17,428 --> 00:43:20,764
If I were so fortunate
as to be able to sing,

510
00:43:20,848 --> 00:43:25,394
I should have great pleasure
in obliging the company with an air.

511
00:43:25,478 --> 00:43:31,608
Indeed I should, for I consider music
as a very innocent diversion,

512
00:43:31,693 --> 00:43:35,696
and perfectly compatible
with the profession of a clergyman!

513
00:43:56,467 --> 00:44:00,262
Mr Collins is such a sensible,
respectable young man.

514
00:44:00,346 --> 00:44:03,015
He's taken quite a fancy to Lizzy,

515
00:44:03,099 --> 00:44:05,976
and I don't think
he could find a better wife.

516
00:44:06,394 --> 00:44:10,480
He favoured Jane at first,
but Bingley was there before him.

517
00:44:10,565 --> 00:44:13,358
Now there will be a great marriage!

518
00:44:13,651 --> 00:44:18,989
And, of course, that will throw the
girls into the path of other rich men!

519
00:44:21,159 --> 00:44:24,119
(DENNY): Lydia!

520
00:44:25,079 --> 00:44:26,204
Lydia!

521
00:44:31,961 --> 00:44:35,881
Lord! Denny, fetch me a glass of wine.
I can scarce draw breath, I'm so fagged!

522
00:44:46,100 --> 00:44:48,185
(KITTY): ...and Chamberlayne
and Denny again!

523
00:44:48,269 --> 00:44:50,187
Lydia only danced with him twice!

524
00:44:50,271 --> 00:44:53,690
- I thought Mary sang very ill.
- Oh, yes. Poor Mary.

525
00:44:54,150 --> 00:44:57,444
- But she is determined to do it.
- More fool her, I say.

526
00:44:58,404 --> 00:45:00,489
Mr Collins trod on my frock and tore it.

527
00:45:00,573 --> 00:45:01,782
(MOTHER): Lizzy!

528
00:45:02,700 --> 00:45:06,661
Mr Collins, I'm sure
there can be no objection!

529
00:45:07,747 --> 00:45:09,039
Kitty, don't leave me.

530
00:45:09,123 --> 00:45:12,042
- Lizzy, dear!
- (KITTY): Why? It's only Mr Collins.

531
00:45:12,752 --> 00:45:15,003
Come, Kitty. I want you upstairs.

532
00:45:15,088 --> 00:45:17,547
Mr Collins has something
to say to Lizzy!

533
00:45:18,341 --> 00:45:20,884
Dear Mamma, don't go.

534
00:45:20,968 --> 00:45:24,096
Mr Collins can have nothing to say
that anyone could not hear.

535
00:45:24,722 --> 00:45:30,811
Lizzy. I insist that you stay
where you are and hear Mr Collins!

536
00:45:32,397 --> 00:45:34,648
Come, Kitty! Come along.

537
00:45:47,870 --> 00:45:49,704
Believe me, my dear Miss Elizabeth,

538
00:45:49,831 --> 00:45:53,834
that your modesty adds
to your other perfections.

539
00:45:54,836 --> 00:45:57,671
But you can hardly doubt the object
of my discourse,

540
00:45:58,214 --> 00:46:01,842
however your feminine delicacy
may lead you to dissemble.

541
00:46:03,052 --> 00:46:06,596
For, as almost as soon
as I entered the house,

542
00:46:07,014 --> 00:46:11,852
I singled you out as the companion
of my future life!

543
00:46:14,021 --> 00:46:17,190
But before I am run away by my feelings
on this subject,

544
00:46:18,484 --> 00:46:24,322
perhaps it would be advisable for me
to state my reasons for marrying.

545
00:46:24,907 --> 00:46:26,199
Mr Collins...

546
00:46:32,373 --> 00:46:34,666
My reasons for marrying are:

547
00:46:34,792 --> 00:46:38,336
First, I think it a right thing
for every clergyman

548
00:46:38,421 --> 00:46:41,047
to set the example of matrimony
in his parish.

549
00:46:42,049 --> 00:46:46,803
Secondly, that I am convinced it will
add very greatly to my happiness.

550
00:46:47,346 --> 00:46:52,058
And thirdly, which perhaps I should have
mentioned first,

551
00:46:52,685 --> 00:46:55,103
that it is the particular recommendation

552
00:46:55,188 --> 00:46:58,732
of my noble patroness
Lady Catherine de Bourgh!

553
00:46:58,816 --> 00:47:02,486
"Mr Collins," she said,
"you must marry."

554
00:47:02,695 --> 00:47:06,823
"Choose properly," she said.
"Choose a gentlewoman for my sake,"

555
00:47:06,908 --> 00:47:10,577
"and for your own, let her be an active,
useful sort of person,

556
00:47:11,412 --> 00:47:13,497
"not brought up too high."

557
00:47:14,040 --> 00:47:16,500
"Find such a woman as soon as you can,

558
00:47:16,584 --> 00:47:20,378
"bring her to Hunsford,
and I will visit her!"

559
00:47:21,589 --> 00:47:25,133
And your wit and vivacity,

560
00:47:25,468 --> 00:47:28,053
I think, must be acceptable to her,

561
00:47:28,179 --> 00:47:30,722
when tempered
with the silence and respect

562
00:47:30,806 --> 00:47:33,099
which her rank will inevitably excite.

563
00:47:34,936 --> 00:47:36,061
Yes.

564
00:47:37,688 --> 00:47:40,482
So much for my general intention
in favour of matrimony.

565
00:47:40,566 --> 00:47:42,943
Now, as to my particular choice:

566
00:47:44,070 --> 00:47:45,278
My dear cousin,

567
00:47:46,322 --> 00:47:50,992
being, as I am, to inherit all this
estate after the death of your father,

568
00:47:51,452 --> 00:47:53,578
I could not satisfy myself

569
00:47:53,663 --> 00:47:57,123
without resolving to choose a wife
from among his daughters.

570
00:48:00,920 --> 00:48:04,673
And now nothing remains,

571
00:48:06,300 --> 00:48:09,928
but to assure you,
in the most animated language,

572
00:48:10,137 --> 00:48:12,806
of the violence of my affections!

573
00:48:12,890 --> 00:48:17,310
- Mr Collins, please...
- To fortune I am perfectly indifferent.

574
00:48:17,478 --> 00:48:21,565
I'm well aware that 1 ,000 pounds
in the four per cents

575
00:48:21,649 --> 00:48:23,650
is all that you may be entitled to,

576
00:48:23,734 --> 00:48:29,155
but rest assured, I shall never reproach
on that score when we are married!

577
00:48:30,491 --> 00:48:32,492
You are too hasty, sir!

578
00:48:34,287 --> 00:48:37,205
You forget that I've made no answer.
Let me do so now.

579
00:48:37,290 --> 00:48:40,333
I thank you for your compliments.

580
00:48:40,501 --> 00:48:44,129
I am very sensible of the honour
of your proposals, but...

581
00:48:45,339 --> 00:48:47,382
..it is impossible for me
to accept them.

582
00:48:56,017 --> 00:48:59,227
I am by no means discouraged.
Indeed not.

583
00:48:59,562 --> 00:49:02,355
I understand that young ladies

584
00:49:02,440 --> 00:49:06,192
often reject the addresses of the man
they mean to accept,

585
00:49:06,277 --> 00:49:08,278
when he first applies for their favour,

586
00:49:08,362 --> 00:49:11,948
and therefore I shall hope,
my dear cousin,

587
00:49:12,366 --> 00:49:14,868
to lead you to the altar before long.

588
00:49:15,661 --> 00:49:18,288
Upon my word,
your hope is an extraordinary one

589
00:49:18,372 --> 00:49:19,873
in view of my declaration.

590
00:49:20,875 --> 00:49:24,377
I was perfectly serious in my refusal.

591
00:49:25,421 --> 00:49:29,758
You could not make me happy, and I am
the last woman who could make you so.

592
00:49:30,176 --> 00:49:31,718
My dear Miss Elizabeth,

593
00:49:32,470 --> 00:49:37,432
my situation in life, my connection
with the noble family of de Bourgh,

594
00:49:37,516 --> 00:49:40,602
are circumstances highly in my favour.

595
00:49:42,063 --> 00:49:44,648
Consider that it is by no means certain

596
00:49:44,732 --> 00:49:47,984
that another offer of marriage
may be made to you.

597
00:49:48,819 --> 00:49:51,738
You cannot be serious in your rejection.

598
00:49:53,407 --> 00:49:57,327
I must attribute it to your wish
of increasing my love by suspense,

599
00:49:57,787 --> 00:50:00,914
in the usual manner of elegant females.

600
00:50:02,833 --> 00:50:03,917
I assure you, sir,

601
00:50:04,001 --> 00:50:06,711
that I have no pretensions
to the kind of elegance

602
00:50:06,796 --> 00:50:10,298
which consists in
tormenting a respectable man.

603
00:50:10,841 --> 00:50:13,176
I thank you
for the honour of your proposals,

604
00:50:13,260 --> 00:50:16,096
but to accept them
is absolutely impossible.

605
00:50:16,472 --> 00:50:19,265
My feelings forbid it in every respect.

606
00:50:20,184 --> 00:50:24,938
- Can I speak plainer?
- You are uniformly charming!

607
00:50:26,691 --> 00:50:32,362
And I am persuaded that when sanctioned
by your excellent parents...

608
00:50:35,241 --> 00:50:40,745
..my proposals will not fail
of being acceptable.

609
00:50:46,627 --> 00:50:50,088
Oh, Mr Bennet!
You are wanted immediately.

610
00:50:50,923 --> 00:50:52,298
We are all in uproar!

611
00:50:53,467 --> 00:50:58,054
You must come and make Lizzy marry
Mr Collins. She vows she won't have him,

612
00:50:58,139 --> 00:51:02,767
and if you don't make haste, Mr Collins
will change his mind and won't have her!

613
00:51:03,060 --> 00:51:07,021
I have not the pleasure of understanding
you. Of what are you talking?

614
00:51:08,149 --> 00:51:11,401
Of Mr Collins and Lizzy!

615
00:51:12,486 --> 00:51:15,321
Lizzy declares
she will not have Mr Collins,

616
00:51:15,406 --> 00:51:18,283
and Mr Collins begins to say
he will not have Lizzy!

617
00:51:18,993 --> 00:51:22,287
What am I to do on the occasion?
It seems a hopeless business.

618
00:51:23,372 --> 00:51:25,248
Speak to Lizzy about it yourself!

619
00:51:25,791 --> 00:51:28,626
Tell her you insist
upon her marrying him!

620
00:51:31,881 --> 00:51:33,006
Let her come in.

621
00:51:35,968 --> 00:51:38,470
Lizzy! Lizzy!

622
00:51:39,013 --> 00:51:40,930
Your father wishes to speak to you.

623
00:51:46,353 --> 00:51:47,604
Come here, my child.

624
00:51:53,360 --> 00:51:54,402
I...

625
00:51:55,696 --> 00:51:59,616
I understand Mr Collins has made you
an offer of marriage.

626
00:52:00,576 --> 00:52:02,702
- Is this true?
- Yes, sir.

627
00:52:04,079 --> 00:52:08,291
Very well. And this offer of marriage
you have refused?

628
00:52:09,084 --> 00:52:10,877
- I have.
- (FATHER): I see.

629
00:52:12,171 --> 00:52:13,838
Right, we now come to the point.

630
00:52:13,923 --> 00:52:18,051
Your mother insists
on your accepting it.

631
00:52:19,386 --> 00:52:24,432
- Is it not so, Mrs Bennet?
- Yes, or I will never see her again!

632
00:52:25,893 --> 00:52:28,394
An unhappy alternative
is before you, Elizabeth.

633
00:52:29,063 --> 00:52:32,357
From this day you must be a stranger
to one of your parents.

634
00:52:32,900 --> 00:52:37,654
Your mother will never see you again
if you do not marry Mr Collins.

635
00:52:38,656 --> 00:52:39,781
And...

636
00:52:40,533 --> 00:52:43,618
..I will never see you again if you do.

637
00:52:46,413 --> 00:52:48,790
Oh, Mr Bennet!

638
00:52:58,425 --> 00:53:03,555
(MOTHER): Sit down, Miss Lizzy!
I insist upon you marrying Mr Collins!

639
00:53:03,639 --> 00:53:08,184
- Why, Charlotte, what do you do here?
- I am come to see Elizabeth.

640
00:53:10,771 --> 00:53:14,732
Mr Collins has made Lizzy an offer, and
what do you think? She won't have him!

641
00:53:15,776 --> 00:53:19,612
Then I am very sorry for him,
though I couldn't say I'm surprised.

642
00:53:19,697 --> 00:53:22,824
(MOTHER): If you don't,
I will never speak to you again!

643
00:53:25,369 --> 00:53:28,788
- I won't discuss the matter any longer.
- Mr Collins!

644
00:53:29,707 --> 00:53:33,251
Mamma's beside herself.
He says he won't stay another night.

645
00:53:33,794 --> 00:53:36,629
I wonder, should I invite him
to dine with us?

646
00:53:37,172 --> 00:53:40,508
Aye, do! Do! Take him away and feed him.

647
00:53:40,593 --> 00:53:42,886
For he's been in high dudgeon
all morning!

648
00:53:54,315 --> 00:53:56,816
- Oh, Mr Collins!
- I am resigned.

649
00:53:58,986 --> 00:54:01,237
Resignation is never so perfect,

650
00:54:01,405 --> 00:54:04,908
as when the blessing denied
begins to lose somewhat of its value

651
00:54:04,992 --> 00:54:06,200
in our estimation.

652
00:54:08,162 --> 00:54:09,662
Until tomorrow then, madam.

653
00:54:14,168 --> 00:54:15,543
I take my leave.

654
00:54:20,341 --> 00:00:00,-001
Oh, Mr Collins!

