1
00:00:54,012 --> 00:00:56,431
Lizzy! Jane!

2
00:01:00,018 --> 00:01:06,274
What do you think? Mr Collins has made
an offer of marriage to Charlotte Lucas!

3
00:01:07,776 --> 00:01:09,777
She's accepted him!

4
00:01:11,864 --> 00:01:13,948
Charlotte?

5
00:01:14,116 --> 00:01:16,659
Engaged to Mr Collins?

6
00:01:17,411 --> 00:01:19,662
Impossible!

7
00:01:19,747 --> 00:01:24,125
The fireplace in the great room at
Rosings would be much larger than that.

8
00:01:24,209 --> 00:01:28,171
A fireplace of truly
prodigious dimensions.

9
00:01:28,964 --> 00:01:32,341
But why should you be surprised,
my dear Lizzy?

10
00:01:33,051 --> 00:01:35,928
Do you think it incredible
that Mr Collins could procure

11
00:01:36,013 --> 00:01:37,680
any woman's good opinion,

12
00:01:37,765 --> 00:01:40,183
because he didn't succeed with you?

13
00:01:40,350 --> 00:01:42,935
Charlotte, I didn't mean...

14
00:01:45,898 --> 00:01:48,149
I was surprised.

15
00:01:49,359 --> 00:01:54,030
Charlotte, if Mr Collins has been so
fortunate as to secure your affections,

16
00:01:55,574 --> 00:01:57,700
I'm delighted for you both.

17
00:01:57,785 --> 00:02:00,369
I see what you are feeling.

18
00:02:02,289 --> 00:02:05,041
I'm not romantic, you know.

19
00:02:05,209 --> 00:02:10,129
I never was.
I ask only a comfortable home.

20
00:02:10,756 --> 00:02:14,884
And, considering Mr Collins' character
and situation in life,

21
00:02:14,968 --> 00:02:17,136
I'm convinced my chance
of happiness with him

22
00:02:17,221 --> 00:02:20,515
is as fair as most
who enter the marriage state.

23
00:02:21,058 --> 00:02:22,850
(COLLINS): My dear Charlotte!

24
00:02:24,019 --> 00:02:28,189
Cousin Elizabeth, you can see before you
the happiest of men!

25
00:02:31,318 --> 00:02:34,487
Jane, it was such a
humiliating spectacle!

26
00:02:34,571 --> 00:02:37,698
She knows she's marrying
one of the stupidest men in England.

27
00:02:38,075 --> 00:02:40,284
I never believed her capable of that.

28
00:02:40,410 --> 00:02:44,664
Lizzy, you do not make allowances
for differences of situation and temper.

29
00:02:44,748 --> 00:02:48,751
Our cousin Mr Collins is not the
cleverest of men, perhaps,

30
00:02:48,836 --> 00:02:50,628
but he is respectable.

31
00:02:50,712 --> 00:02:56,133
He is not vicious, and as far as
fortune goes, it's an eligible match.

32
00:02:56,218 --> 00:02:59,345
Veryeligible! You wouldn't think of
marrying a man like that,

33
00:02:59,429 --> 00:03:01,180
simply to secure your own comfort.

34
00:03:01,265 --> 00:03:04,433
No, but Lizzy, not everyone is the same.

35
00:03:11,441 --> 00:03:13,568
DearJane!

36
00:03:14,528 --> 00:03:17,071
I doubt that
you will have to make a choice

37
00:03:17,155 --> 00:03:21,576
between marrying for love and marrying
for more material considerations.

38
00:03:21,910 --> 00:03:23,911
Though you may, perhaps?

39
00:03:23,996 --> 00:03:26,455
(THERE IS A KNOCK ON THE DOOR)

40
00:03:29,543 --> 00:03:31,836
This came just now
from Netherfield, ma'am.

41
00:03:31,920 --> 00:03:33,462
Thank you.

42
00:03:38,343 --> 00:03:40,094
It's from Caroline Bingley.

43
00:03:42,639 --> 00:03:44,974
She writes...

44
00:03:45,058 --> 00:03:49,228
..that the whole party will have left
Netherfield by now, for London.

45
00:03:50,188 --> 00:03:53,149
And without any intention of
coming back again.

46
00:03:56,820 --> 00:04:00,573
(MISS BINGLEY): Charles first thought
that his business in London

47
00:04:00,657 --> 00:04:02,909
would only take a few days,

48
00:04:02,993 --> 00:04:05,828
but we're certain
that this cannot be so.

49
00:04:05,913 --> 00:04:08,414
I am convinced that when Charles
gets to town,

50
00:04:08,498 --> 00:04:11,083
he will be in no hurry
to leave it again.

51
00:04:11,168 --> 00:04:13,044
I do not pretend to regret

52
00:04:13,128 --> 00:04:16,255
anything I shall leave in Hertfordshire,
my dearest friend,

53
00:04:16,340 --> 00:04:18,466
except your society.

54
00:04:18,550 --> 00:04:21,719
Mr Darcy, of course, is impatient
to see his sister.

55
00:04:21,803 --> 00:04:23,596
And to confess the truth,

56
00:04:23,680 --> 00:04:26,474
I'm scarcely less eager
to meet her again,

57
00:04:26,558 --> 00:04:32,855
from the hope I dare to entertain
of her being hereafter... my sister.

58
00:04:32,981 --> 00:04:35,358
Am I wrong, my dearest Jane,

59
00:04:35,442 --> 00:04:37,026
in indulging the hope of an event

60
00:04:37,110 --> 00:04:40,196
which would secure the happiness
of so many?

61
00:04:41,490 --> 00:04:42,990
Is it not clear enough?

62
00:04:43,075 --> 00:04:45,701
Caroline Bingley believes her brother
is indifferent to me, and

63
00:04:45,786 --> 00:04:48,704
she means to put me on my guard.

64
00:04:48,789 --> 00:04:51,457
Can there be any other opinion
on the subject?

65
00:04:51,541 --> 00:04:53,876
Yes, there can!

66
00:04:53,961 --> 00:04:57,046
Miss Bingley sees that
her brother is in love with you, and

67
00:04:57,130 --> 00:04:59,548
she wants him to marry Miss Darcy.

68
00:04:59,800 --> 00:05:02,176
She hopes to keep him in town, and

69
00:05:02,260 --> 00:05:05,012
persuade you that
he does not care about you.

70
00:05:06,181 --> 00:05:09,934
Indeed, Jane, you ought to believe me.

71
00:05:10,686 --> 00:05:14,146
No one who has seen you and Bingley
together can doubt his affection.

72
00:05:14,231 --> 00:05:17,817
I cannot believe Caroline is capable of
wilful deceit.

73
00:05:17,901 --> 00:05:21,028
All I can hope for is that
she is deceived herself.

74
00:05:21,113 --> 00:05:23,739
Believe her to be deceived,
by all means,

75
00:05:23,824 --> 00:05:25,908
but she can hardly convince a man
so much in love

76
00:05:25,993 --> 00:05:28,536
that he's in love
with someone else instead!

77
00:05:29,955 --> 00:05:35,835
If Bingley is not back by your side and
dining at Longbourn within two weeks,

78
00:05:35,961 --> 00:05:38,295
I shall be very much surprised.

79
00:05:47,931 --> 00:05:52,143
I don't envy Charlotte in the slightest!
Fancy marrying a clergyman!

80
00:05:52,227 --> 00:05:54,854
He'll read from Fordyce's sermons
every night.

81
00:05:54,938 --> 00:05:56,981
Before they go to bed!

82
00:05:58,275 --> 00:06:02,528
Look at that hideous cloth!
It would do very well for Mary.

83
00:06:03,530 --> 00:06:06,657
Look! There's Denny and Carter.

84
00:06:08,076 --> 00:06:09,535
And Wickham!

85
00:06:09,619 --> 00:06:12,079
I suppose you'll keep him
all to yourself again?

86
00:06:12,164 --> 00:06:14,623
Of course.
She's violently in love with him!

87
00:06:15,292 --> 00:06:17,877
For heaven's sake, lower your voice.

88
00:06:17,961 --> 00:06:20,421
Good afternoon to you, Ladies!

89
00:06:21,256 --> 00:06:24,925
How fortunate! We were
going to Longbourn in search of you.

90
00:06:25,010 --> 00:06:27,386
We came into town in search of you!

91
00:06:43,945 --> 00:06:46,864
We hoped we would see you
at the Netherfield ball.

92
00:06:46,948 --> 00:06:50,743
I was very sorry to lose the pleasure
of dancing with you.

93
00:06:51,036 --> 00:06:53,746
But fate, it would seem...

94
00:06:53,997 --> 00:06:56,457
No. With you I must be entirely open.

95
00:06:57,667 --> 00:07:00,377
I decided that it would be wrong
for me to be there.

96
00:07:00,462 --> 00:07:03,839
I found that I had better not meet
with Mr Darcy.

97
00:07:03,924 --> 00:07:06,634
Scenes might arise
unpleasant to more than myself.

98
00:07:06,843 --> 00:07:09,095
I understand and admire
your forbearance.

99
00:07:09,179 --> 00:07:12,264
Not that it would give me
a moment's concern

100
00:07:12,349 --> 00:07:14,266
to see Mr Darcy publicly set down,

101
00:07:14,351 --> 00:07:17,436
but in Mr Bingley's house...

102
00:07:17,521 --> 00:07:20,606
It would grieve me
to see him embarrassed and discomfited.

103
00:07:20,690 --> 00:07:23,317
And through him, your sister.

104
00:07:24,319 --> 00:07:26,362
Yes.

105
00:07:27,948 --> 00:07:30,658
I hear Mr Collins
is engaged to be married.

106
00:07:30,742 --> 00:07:33,869
Yes, to my good friend Charlotte Lucas.

107
00:07:34,204 --> 00:07:38,207
I had thought that his intentions
tended in another direction.

108
00:07:38,875 --> 00:07:44,505
Perhaps they did, but they took a little
turn, to everybody's satisfaction.

109
00:07:44,589 --> 00:07:46,048
And relief.

110
00:07:47,968 --> 00:07:51,178
I hope that you will stay and
take tea with us.

111
00:07:51,263 --> 00:07:54,557
I should like to introduce you
to my mother and father.

112
00:07:55,058 --> 00:07:57,143
Thank you.

113
00:08:20,709 --> 00:08:21,917
Denny!

114
00:08:36,975 --> 00:08:42,188
Oh, young George Wickham is such a
charming young man, is he not, my dear?

115
00:08:42,689 --> 00:08:45,316
What? Oh, indeed he is.

116
00:08:45,400 --> 00:08:48,110
It was very good of him
to entertain us so eloquently

117
00:08:48,195 --> 00:08:50,863
with stories about his misfortunes.

118
00:08:50,947 --> 00:08:54,783
With such narratives to hand,
who would read novels?

119
00:08:54,868 --> 00:08:58,787
But I believe he has been treated
contemptibly by Mr Darcy, father.

120
00:08:59,873 --> 00:09:04,835
I dare say he has. Though Darcy may be
no more of a black-hearted villain

121
00:09:04,920 --> 00:09:08,297
than your average rich man,
used to his own way.

122
00:09:08,465 --> 00:09:11,884
It behoves us all
to take very careful thought

123
00:09:11,968 --> 00:09:15,596
before pronouncing an adverse judgement
on any of our fellow men.

124
00:09:16,306 --> 00:09:17,514
Lord!

125
00:09:17,599 --> 00:09:20,476
I feel very sorry for poor Mr Wickham.

126
00:09:20,769 --> 00:09:23,604
And so becoming in his regimentals!

127
00:09:24,481 --> 00:09:28,734
I remember the time when I liked
a red coat myself well enough.

128
00:09:31,821 --> 00:09:34,365
And I do still in my heart.

129
00:09:36,743 --> 00:09:39,995
And there's no need to smile like that,
Miss Lizzy!

130
00:09:40,330 --> 00:09:42,790
Though Mr Wickham
has taken a fancy to you,

131
00:09:42,874 --> 00:09:45,209
I'm sure you've done nothing
to deserve it,

132
00:09:45,293 --> 00:09:47,878
after your dealings with Mr Collins!

133
00:09:47,963 --> 00:09:51,257
Well, it is all in vain,
it will all come to nothing!

134
00:09:51,925 --> 00:09:53,008
The poor young man!

135
00:09:53,093 --> 00:09:56,053
If only he had five or
six thousand a year,

136
00:09:56,137 --> 00:09:59,056
I'd be happy to see him marry
any of the girls!

137
00:09:59,766 --> 00:10:02,518
But nothing turns out the way it should.

138
00:10:02,602 --> 00:10:08,482
And now Mr Bingley, of whom we all had
such expectations, is gone off forever!

139
00:10:09,192 --> 00:10:10,776
What?

140
00:10:11,444 --> 00:10:14,530
I've heard again from Caroline Bingley.

141
00:10:14,698 --> 00:10:18,867
It's now definite that they will stay
in town for the whole winter.

142
00:10:19,494 --> 00:10:21,662
I cannot believe it.

143
00:10:22,038 --> 00:10:23,831
It is true.

144
00:10:24,124 --> 00:10:26,208
Come now, Jane, take comfort.

145
00:10:26,293 --> 00:10:30,212
Next to being married, a girl likes
to be crossed in love now and then.

146
00:10:30,964 --> 00:10:35,551
When is it your turn, Lizzy?
You can't be long outdone by Jane,

147
00:10:35,635 --> 00:10:38,053
when here are officers enough in Meryton

148
00:10:38,138 --> 00:10:40,556
to disappoint all the young ladies
in the country.

149
00:10:40,849 --> 00:10:43,309
Let Wickham be your man.
He's a pleasant fellow.

150
00:10:43,393 --> 00:10:45,019
He would jilt you creditably.

151
00:10:45,270 --> 00:10:47,646
Thank you, sir,
but a less agreeable man would do.

152
00:10:47,731 --> 00:10:50,482
We must not all expect
Jane's good fortune.

153
00:10:50,567 --> 00:10:53,110
True, but it is a comfort to think...

154
00:10:54,029 --> 00:10:56,155
that whatever of that kind
may befall you,

155
00:10:56,239 --> 00:11:00,659
you have an affectionate mother
who will always make the most of it.

156
00:11:02,746 --> 00:11:05,497
I don't know what will become of us all,
indeed I do not!

157
00:11:07,500 --> 00:11:10,878
And I cannot bear to think of
Charlotte Lucas

158
00:11:10,962 --> 00:11:12,880
being mistress of this house!

159
00:11:12,964 --> 00:11:17,634
That I should be forced to make way
for her, and see her take my place!

160
00:11:17,719 --> 00:11:23,432
My dear, don't give way to such gloomy
thoughts. Let us hope for better things.

161
00:11:23,850 --> 00:11:27,561
Let us flatter ourselves
that I might outlive you.

162
00:11:39,449 --> 00:11:42,076
You mustn't be anxious for me, Lizzy.

163
00:11:43,495 --> 00:11:45,954
He will be forgot,

164
00:11:46,039 --> 00:11:48,707
and we shall all be as we were before.

165
00:11:54,089 --> 00:11:56,507
But, I may remember him as...

166
00:11:58,301 --> 00:12:01,470
..the most amiable man
of my acquaintance.

167
00:12:02,263 --> 00:12:04,390
That is all.

168
00:12:04,474 --> 00:12:07,267
I have nothing either to hope or fear...

169
00:12:07,852 --> 00:12:12,147
..and nothing to reproach him with.
At least I have not had that pain.

170
00:12:18,613 --> 00:12:20,906
My dear Jane.

171
00:12:20,990 --> 00:12:25,285
You're too good. Your sweetness and
disinterestedness are truly angelic.

172
00:12:25,370 --> 00:12:29,415
- Don't tease me, Lizzy.
- Indeed I do not tease you.

173
00:12:31,501 --> 00:12:36,713
There are few people whom I really love,
and even fewer of whom I think well.

174
00:12:36,798 --> 00:12:40,801
The more I see of the world,
the more I am dissatisfied with it.

175
00:12:44,347 --> 00:12:47,057
Jane, what if you were to go to town?

176
00:12:47,142 --> 00:12:49,518
Aunt and Uncle Gardiner
would gladly take you

177
00:12:49,602 --> 00:12:52,563
with them to Gracechurch Street
after Christmas.

178
00:12:52,647 --> 00:12:55,190
Why would you have me
go to London, Lizzy?

179
00:12:55,275 --> 00:12:57,276
No reason.

180
00:12:57,360 --> 00:13:00,154
A change of scene and society?

181
00:13:15,378 --> 00:13:17,254
Why are you so late?

182
00:13:17,338 --> 00:13:20,090
I'm sure I feared your coach
had overset itself,

183
00:13:20,175 --> 00:13:22,634
or you had been attacked by robbers!

184
00:13:23,511 --> 00:13:26,180
Nonsense, we made good time.
How do you do, Fanny?

185
00:13:26,264 --> 00:13:30,392
Very ill, Edward. No one knows
what I suffer with my nerves.

186
00:13:31,436 --> 00:13:32,978
But then I never complain.

187
00:13:33,062 --> 00:13:36,648
That's the best way, Fanny.
You're very good.

188
00:13:36,733 --> 00:13:41,320
- Have you brought us some presents?
- I see you've not changed, Lydia.

189
00:13:41,404 --> 00:13:45,199
- Why, have I not grown?
- Aye, in everything but good sense.

190
00:13:46,075 --> 00:13:47,493
Lizzy!

191
00:13:47,577 --> 00:13:50,037
Get yourselves in, get yourselves in,

192
00:13:50,121 --> 00:13:53,040
for you have barely time
for a change of clothes!

193
00:13:53,124 --> 00:13:55,667
We are bidden to the Philips'
this evening.

194
00:13:55,752 --> 00:13:59,338
I have no desire to be going
here and there at night.

195
00:13:59,422 --> 00:14:03,509
I should much rather sit at home
and rest my poor nerves.

196
00:14:03,885 --> 00:14:09,348
# God rest ye merry gentlemen,
Let nothing you dismay,

197
00:14:09,432 --> 00:14:15,062
# Remember Christ our Saviour
Was born on Christmas Day,

198
00:14:15,146 --> 00:14:18,273
# To save us all from Satan's pow'r...

199
00:14:18,358 --> 00:14:22,069
(SONG CONTINUES IN THE BACKGROUND)

200
00:14:31,287 --> 00:14:36,458
Aye, poor Jane. I would not have you
think I blame poor Jane at all!

201
00:14:36,543 --> 00:14:39,336
Who could blame poor Jane
for the matter?

202
00:14:39,420 --> 00:14:42,381
She is the dearest girl in the world!

203
00:14:42,465 --> 00:14:46,343
I was telling our dear sister,
Mrs Gardiner, she did her best.

204
00:14:46,427 --> 00:14:48,637
She would have got Bingley if she could.

205
00:14:48,721 --> 00:14:52,349
She did her best,
and no one could do more.

206
00:14:53,142 --> 00:14:57,104
But, oh, sister,
when I think about Lizzy!

207
00:14:57,188 --> 00:15:00,732
- It must be very hard, sister.
- It is very hard.

208
00:15:00,817 --> 00:15:03,652
She could have been
Mr Collins' wife by now!

209
00:15:03,736 --> 00:15:05,737
That would have given you such comfort!

210
00:15:05,822 --> 00:15:09,241
Oh, those Lucases are
such artful people indeed.

211
00:15:09,325 --> 00:15:12,286
They are all for what they can get!

212
00:15:12,370 --> 00:15:16,707
However, your coming just at this time
is the greatest of comforts.

213
00:15:16,791 --> 00:15:18,125
And we are very pleased to hear

214
00:15:18,209 --> 00:15:21,837
what you tell us about
the latest fashions for long sleeves.

215
00:15:29,596 --> 00:15:32,889
May I present Mr Wickham to you, Aunt?

216
00:15:33,016 --> 00:15:35,767
I understand you come from Derbyshire,
Mr Wickham.

217
00:15:35,852 --> 00:15:38,729
Indeed I do, ma'am.
Do you know the country?

218
00:15:38,813 --> 00:15:39,980
Very well.

219
00:15:40,064 --> 00:15:43,942
I spent some of the
happiest years of my life at Lambton.

220
00:15:44,027 --> 00:15:47,070
Not five miles from where I grew up,
at Pemberley!

221
00:15:47,155 --> 00:15:51,366
Pemberley! Surely it is the most
handsome house in Derbyshire,

222
00:15:51,451 --> 00:15:53,702
and consequently in the world!

223
00:15:53,786 --> 00:15:56,413
I see you take my view of things, ma'am.

224
00:15:56,497 --> 00:16:00,584
- Are you acquainted with the family?
- No.

225
00:16:00,668 --> 00:16:04,463
I had the good fortune
to be the protégé of old Mr Darcy.

226
00:16:04,547 --> 00:16:08,467
He was the very best of men.
I wish you'd known him.

227
00:16:08,551 --> 00:16:12,387
And a four on yours, and I'm out!
Lord, I've won again!

228
00:16:14,223 --> 00:16:17,643
Let's have some dancing now.
I long for a dance!

229
00:16:18,728 --> 00:16:20,437
Mary!

230
00:16:21,397 --> 00:16:23,565
Mary, play Grimstock.

231
00:16:39,832 --> 00:16:41,750
Capital! Capital!

232
00:16:45,213 --> 00:16:49,341
- Fine girls, are they not, Mr Gardiner?
- Indeed they are, Sir William.

233
00:16:49,425 --> 00:16:52,761
- The two eldest in particular, perhaps?
- Indeed, indeed.

234
00:16:52,845 --> 00:16:56,348
They would grace
the court of St. James itself!

235
00:16:56,432 --> 00:16:59,601
But let's not forget
the younger Miss Bennets!

236
00:16:59,686 --> 00:17:03,021
Aye, they have arms and legs enough
between them,

237
00:17:03,106 --> 00:17:05,440
and are three of the silliest girls
in England.

238
00:17:58,661 --> 00:18:01,037
When do you go into Kent?

239
00:18:01,122 --> 00:18:03,165
We shall spend the wedding night
at Lucas Lodge,

240
00:18:03,249 --> 00:18:05,667
and then travel to Hunsford on Friday.

241
00:18:14,177 --> 00:18:16,261
You will write to me, Lizzy?

242
00:18:16,345 --> 00:18:19,097
I believe I am not likely to leave Kent
for some time.

243
00:18:19,182 --> 00:18:22,309
I shall depend on hearing from you
very often.

244
00:18:22,393 --> 00:18:24,144
That you certainly shall.

245
00:18:24,228 --> 00:18:27,230
My father and Maria
are to come to me in March.

246
00:18:27,315 --> 00:18:29,399
Lizzy, will you promise to be
one of the party?

247
00:18:29,525 --> 00:18:32,444
You will be as welcome
as either of them.

248
00:18:32,528 --> 00:18:33,612
Then how could I refuse?

249
00:18:33,696 --> 00:18:37,491
But I'll only come if you guarantee me
a glimpse of the famous chimney piece

250
00:18:37,575 --> 00:18:39,326
at Rosings Park!

251
00:18:39,410 --> 00:18:42,788
That you could scarcely avoid,
even if you wished to!

252
00:18:42,872 --> 00:18:44,039
(MARIA): Charlotte!

253
00:18:46,042 --> 00:18:49,377
Have you asked her?
Is she to come to Hunsford with us?

254
00:18:49,504 --> 00:18:51,254
- Yes.
- Good!

255
00:18:51,339 --> 00:18:53,381
I shan't be half so frightened
of Lady Catherine

256
00:18:53,466 --> 00:18:55,550
if you are with us, Lizzy!

257
00:18:56,469 --> 00:18:59,304
Who is that girl
dancing with Mr Wickham?

258
00:19:00,014 --> 00:19:02,098
Her name is Mary King.

259
00:19:02,183 --> 00:19:04,518
She's come to stay with her uncle
in Meryton.

260
00:19:05,937 --> 00:19:10,482
- She's not very pretty, is she?
- Beauty is not the only virtue, Maria.

261
00:19:10,566 --> 00:19:14,319
She's just inherited a fortune
of 1 0,000 pounds, I understand.

262
00:19:14,403 --> 00:19:16,988
Now that is a definite virtue!

263
00:19:30,837 --> 00:19:35,215
(MOTHER): It is very hard.
And I feel sorry for Lizzy,

264
00:19:35,299 --> 00:19:37,384
because she's done little to deserve it.

265
00:19:37,468 --> 00:19:40,345
(LYDIA): For Wickham to pursue Miss King
all the way to Barnet,

266
00:19:40,429 --> 00:19:43,348
just for her 1 0,000 pounds!

267
00:19:43,432 --> 00:19:46,560
(KITTY): I wish someone would die
and leave me 1 0,000 pounds.

268
00:19:46,727 --> 00:19:49,020
(KITTY): Then all the officers
would love me!

269
00:19:49,105 --> 00:19:53,191
(MOTHER): I'm sure they would,
Kitty dear.

270
00:19:53,276 --> 00:19:54,818
(KITTY): Did you think
her pretty, mamma?

271
00:19:54,902 --> 00:19:58,947
No indeed,
she has nothing to any of you.

272
00:19:59,031 --> 00:20:04,244
(LYDIA): A little short freckled thing!
Poor Wickham. How he must be suffering.

273
00:20:06,080 --> 00:20:08,665
(JANE): January the 1 2th.

274
00:20:08,749 --> 00:20:10,542
My dearest Lizzy,

275
00:20:10,626 --> 00:20:14,379
here we continue at Gracechurch Street
to be quiet and comfortable.

276
00:20:14,463 --> 00:20:17,549
Aunt and Uncle could not be kinder
or more attentive.

277
00:20:17,633 --> 00:20:22,220
All I lack here, dear Lizzy, is you,
to make me laugh at myself.

278
00:20:24,181 --> 00:20:28,059
Three weeks ago, when our Aunt
was going to that part of town,

279
00:20:28,144 --> 00:20:32,397
I took the opportunity of calling on
Miss Bingley in Grosvenor Street.

280
00:20:34,191 --> 00:20:39,487
I was very eager to see Caroline again.
And I thought she was glad to see me,

281
00:20:40,239 --> 00:20:42,574
though a little out of spirits.

282
00:20:42,658 --> 00:20:45,577
She reproached me for giving her
no notice of my coming to London,

283
00:20:45,661 --> 00:20:47,037
and I thought it very strange

284
00:20:47,121 --> 00:20:49,497
that both my letters
should have gone astray.

285
00:20:51,167 --> 00:20:53,710
Very strange indeed.

286
00:20:55,755 --> 00:21:00,383
My visit was not long, as Caroline
and Mrs Hurst were going out.

287
00:21:00,468 --> 00:21:01,551
Goodbye, Miss Bennet.

288
00:21:01,636 --> 00:21:05,805
They promised to call at
Gracechurch Street in a day or two.

289
00:21:13,356 --> 00:21:17,108
I waited at home every morning
for three weeks,

290
00:21:17,193 --> 00:21:21,071
and at length, today she came.

291
00:21:25,368 --> 00:21:27,369
I know, my dear Lizzy,

292
00:21:27,453 --> 00:21:30,163
you will be incapable
of triumphing at my expense,

293
00:21:30,247 --> 00:21:33,333
when I confess I have been
entirely deceived

294
00:21:33,417 --> 00:21:35,710
in Miss Bingley's regard for me.

295
00:21:36,879 --> 00:21:41,049
She made it very evident
that she took no pleasure in seeing me.

296
00:21:44,345 --> 00:21:46,429
When I asked after her brother,

297
00:21:46,514 --> 00:21:49,975
she made it clear
that he knows of my being in town,

298
00:21:50,059 --> 00:21:53,478
but is much engaged at present
with Mr Darcy and his sister.

299
00:22:00,069 --> 00:22:02,862
I must conclude then,

300
00:22:02,947 --> 00:22:05,615
that Mr Bingley
now no longer cares for me.

301
00:22:47,950 --> 00:22:51,244
Lizzy! Come quick!
Denny and Carter are here.

302
00:22:51,328 --> 00:22:53,955
And guess who else? Wickham!

303
00:22:56,459 --> 00:22:58,918
I heard you were going into Kent.

304
00:22:59,003 --> 00:23:01,880
I felt I could not let you go
without calling to see you once.

305
00:23:01,964 --> 00:23:05,467
I'm very glad you did.
I've missed our conversations.

306
00:23:06,594 --> 00:23:08,970
I hear I am to congratulate you

307
00:23:09,055 --> 00:23:11,014
on your forthcoming betrothal
to Miss King?

308
00:23:14,268 --> 00:23:15,602
You must despise me.

309
00:23:15,686 --> 00:23:17,729
Indeed I do not!

310
00:23:17,813 --> 00:23:20,231
I understand, as my younger sisters
are not yet able to,

311
00:23:20,316 --> 00:23:22,400
that handsome young men must have
something to live on,

312
00:23:22,485 --> 00:23:24,527
as well as the plain ones.

313
00:23:30,826 --> 00:23:33,161
Miss Bennet...

314
00:23:33,245 --> 00:23:38,374
..I would wish you to believe me that...
had circumstances been different...

315
00:23:38,459 --> 00:23:41,961
Had old Mr Darcy never had a son.

316
00:23:42,046 --> 00:23:44,422
Oh, yes.

317
00:23:44,507 --> 00:23:48,802
But life is full of these trials,
as my sister Mary reminds us daily.

318
00:23:58,521 --> 00:24:02,273
I sincerely wish you
every happiness in the world.

319
00:24:02,691 --> 00:24:07,278
- You are very forbearing.
- I flatter myself I am!

320
00:24:07,988 --> 00:24:10,698
I think Jane would be quite proud of me.

321
00:24:11,534 --> 00:24:15,620
I hope you and I, at least,
will always be good friends.

322
00:24:16,122 --> 00:24:17,914
I'm sure we shall, Mr Wickham.

323
00:24:30,803 --> 00:24:34,222
(FATHER): Well, Lizzy,
on pleasure bent again.

324
00:24:35,391 --> 00:24:39,227
Never a thought of what your poor
parents will suffer in your absence?

325
00:24:39,311 --> 00:24:43,439
It is a pleasure I could well forego,
father, as I think you know.

326
00:24:44,567 --> 00:24:47,026
But I shall be happy to see Charlotte.

327
00:24:47,111 --> 00:24:51,239
What of your cousin Mr Collins
and the famous Lady Catherine de Bourgh?

328
00:24:51,323 --> 00:24:53,491
As a connoisseur of human folly,

329
00:24:53,576 --> 00:24:57,120
I thought you impatient
to be savouring these delights.

330
00:24:57,204 --> 00:25:01,499
Of some delights, I believe, sir,
a little goes a long way.

331
00:25:01,584 --> 00:25:05,336
Yes. Well, think of me, Lizzy.

332
00:25:05,421 --> 00:25:07,672
Until you or your sister Jane return,

333
00:25:07,756 --> 00:25:11,259
I shall not hear two words of sense
spoken together.

334
00:25:13,179 --> 00:25:15,263
You'll be very much missed, my dear.

335
00:25:20,060 --> 00:25:23,688
Very well, very well. Go along then.
Get along with you.

336
00:25:36,285 --> 00:25:40,788
Aye, Maria. All that land to the left
of us belongs to Rosings Park.

337
00:25:40,873 --> 00:25:45,210
All of it? Oh, Lady Catherine must be
very rich indeed!

338
00:25:45,294 --> 00:25:49,756
I believe so, I believe so!
And she has many favours in her gift.

339
00:25:49,840 --> 00:25:53,218
Your sister has made
a fortunate alliance!

340
00:25:54,970 --> 00:25:56,638
(SIR WILLIAM): Yes, well,

341
00:25:56,722 --> 00:25:59,849
I believe the next turn
takes us on to Hunsford.

342
00:26:23,832 --> 00:26:25,750
Sir William! Maria!

343
00:26:26,835 --> 00:26:28,962
Cousin Elizabeth.

344
00:26:29,046 --> 00:26:34,634
I am truly honoured to be able
to welcome you to my humble abode!

345
00:26:35,678 --> 00:26:39,347
- My dear Sir!
- My dear Mr Collins!

346
00:26:40,266 --> 00:26:45,144
I am deeply honoured to make
a humble welcome to the Parsonage...

347
00:26:50,734 --> 00:26:54,487
- I am happy to see you, Elizabeth.
- And I you.

348
00:26:56,031 --> 00:26:58,658
The staircase, I flatter myself,

349
00:26:58,742 --> 00:27:01,661
is eminently suitable
for a clergyman in my position,

350
00:27:01,745 --> 00:27:04,622
being neither too shallow nor too steep.

351
00:27:04,707 --> 00:27:08,918
As serviceable a staircase as I've ever
seen, sir. At St. James' Court...

352
00:27:09,003 --> 00:27:12,839
Though it is nothing to the staircases
you will see at Rosings.

353
00:27:12,923 --> 00:27:16,301
I say staircases,
because there are several,

354
00:27:16,385 --> 00:27:19,178
and each in its way very fine.

355
00:27:19,930 --> 00:27:24,267
And here, if you would permit me,
cousin Elizabeth.

356
00:27:27,938 --> 00:27:32,108
This will be your bedchamber,
while you are with us.

357
00:27:32,860 --> 00:27:37,155
And I trust you will find it comfortable
and convenient.

358
00:27:37,239 --> 00:27:41,367
- Indeed it is a very pleasant room.
- Observe that closet, cousin Elizabeth.

359
00:27:41,452 --> 00:27:45,038
- What do you say to that?
- Well...

360
00:27:45,122 --> 00:27:49,167
Is it not the very essence
of practicality and convenience?

361
00:27:49,251 --> 00:27:51,794
Lady Catherine de Bourgh herself

362
00:27:51,879 --> 00:27:56,466
was kind enough to suggest that
these shelves be fitted.

363
00:27:56,550 --> 00:28:01,012
Shelves in the closet...
Happy thought indeed.

364
00:28:01,096 --> 00:28:03,431
She is kindness itself.

365
00:28:03,515 --> 00:28:07,685
Nothing is too small to be
beneath her notice, is it not, my dear?

366
00:28:07,770 --> 00:28:09,437
She is a very attentive neighbour.

367
00:28:09,521 --> 00:28:13,149
We dine at Rosings Park
twice every week!

368
00:28:13,233 --> 00:28:15,026
And are never allowed to walk home.

369
00:28:15,110 --> 00:28:18,696
That is generosity itself,
is it not, Maria?

370
00:28:18,781 --> 00:28:22,033
Her ladyship's carriage
is regularly ordered for us.

371
00:28:22,117 --> 00:28:25,995
I should say one of her ladyship's
carriages, for she has several.

372
00:28:27,164 --> 00:28:29,040
And now, Sir William,

373
00:28:29,124 --> 00:28:32,710
you were kind enough
to express a wish to see my gardens.

374
00:28:41,303 --> 00:28:43,388
Mr Collins tends the gardens himself,

375
00:28:43,472 --> 00:28:46,516
and spends a good part of every day
in them.

376
00:28:47,142 --> 00:28:50,395
- The exercise must be beneficial.
- Oh, yes.

377
00:28:50,479 --> 00:28:54,023
I encourage him to be in his garden
as much as possible.

378
00:28:55,442 --> 00:28:58,611
And he has to walk to Rosings
nearly every day.

379
00:28:58,695 --> 00:29:01,989
So often? Is that necessary?

380
00:29:02,116 --> 00:29:07,161
Perhaps not, but I confess
I encourage him in that as well.

381
00:29:09,998 --> 00:29:13,668
- Walking is very beneficial exercise.
- Oh, indeed it is.

382
00:29:15,254 --> 00:29:18,631
When he's in the house,
he is mostly in his book room,

383
00:29:18,715 --> 00:29:20,299
which affords a good view of the road,

384
00:29:20,384 --> 00:29:23,678
whenever Lady Catherine's carriage
should drive by.

385
00:29:24,972 --> 00:29:28,724
- And you prefer to sit in this parlour?
- Yes.

386
00:29:29,643 --> 00:29:32,728
So, it often happens
that a whole day passes

387
00:29:32,813 --> 00:29:37,024
in which we haven't spent more than
a few minutes in each other's company.

388
00:29:37,192 --> 00:29:38,609
I see.

389
00:29:38,819 --> 00:29:42,280
I find that I can bear the solitude
very cheerfully.

390
00:29:42,364 --> 00:29:44,740
I find myself...

391
00:29:45,200 --> 00:29:47,994
..quite content
with my situation, Lizzy.

392
00:29:52,207 --> 00:29:55,376
- (COLLINS): Charlotte, come quickly!
- (CHARLOTTE): What is it?

393
00:29:55,461 --> 00:29:58,296
(MARIA): Lizzy! Lizzy!

394
00:30:00,174 --> 00:30:01,299
Come into the dining room.

395
00:30:01,383 --> 00:30:04,427
There's such a sight to be seen!
Make haste!

396
00:30:09,016 --> 00:30:11,058
Look, Lizzy, look!

397
00:30:12,352 --> 00:30:15,646
Is this all? I expected
the pigs had got into the garden!

398
00:30:15,731 --> 00:30:17,315
Here's only Lady Catherine and
her daughter.

399
00:30:17,399 --> 00:30:19,942
No, that's old Mrs Jenkinson.

400
00:30:20,027 --> 00:30:22,069
With her is Miss Anne de Bourgh!

401
00:30:22,154 --> 00:30:25,198
She's rude to keep Charlotte
out in this wind!

402
00:30:25,282 --> 00:30:29,076
- What a little creature she is!
- I like her appearance.

403
00:30:29,161 --> 00:30:32,955
She looks sickly and cross.
Yes, she will do very well.

404
00:30:33,040 --> 00:30:35,708
She'll make him a proper wife.

405
00:30:35,792 --> 00:30:37,460
Who, Lizzy?

406
00:30:51,683 --> 00:30:53,518
(COLLINS): Mark the windows.

407
00:30:53,602 --> 00:30:57,230
There are 64 in all. 64!

408
00:30:57,314 --> 00:30:58,856
And I have it on good authority

409
00:30:58,941 --> 00:31:03,528
that the glazing alone originally cost
in excess of 600 pounds!

410
00:31:03,612 --> 00:31:07,281
It's a very handsome building,
and prettily situated, sir.

411
00:31:07,366 --> 00:31:11,077
And by no means lacking in windows.

412
00:31:11,161 --> 00:31:14,872
Do not make yourself uneasy,
my dear cousin, about your apparel.

413
00:31:14,957 --> 00:31:19,043
Lady Catherine is far from requiring
that elegance of dress,

414
00:31:19,127 --> 00:31:21,170
which becomes herself and her daughter.

415
00:31:21,255 --> 00:31:24,632
She won't think the worse of you
for being simply dressed.

416
00:31:24,716 --> 00:31:27,552
She likes to preserve
the distinction of rank.

417
00:31:27,636 --> 00:31:31,013
Thank you, Mr Collins,
that is a great comfort.

418
00:31:31,098 --> 00:31:34,475
(LADY CATHERINE): An apothecary
will serve your needs quite adequately.

419
00:31:34,560 --> 00:31:38,062
Make sure it be no one but Nicholson,
Mrs Collins.

420
00:31:38,146 --> 00:31:42,024
I shall be extremely angry
if I hear you have gone elsewhere.

421
00:31:42,109 --> 00:31:44,485
I have no intention to, Lady Catherine.

422
00:31:44,570 --> 00:31:47,113
No indeed. No intention at all.

423
00:31:47,197 --> 00:31:48,781
Well.

424
00:31:58,000 --> 00:32:00,293
Your friend appears to be
quite a genteel

425
00:32:00,377 --> 00:32:02,670
pretty sort of girl, Mrs Collins.

426
00:32:03,672 --> 00:32:08,092
Her father's estate is entailed
on Mr Collins, I understand.

427
00:32:08,176 --> 00:32:10,261
Yes, ma'am, and I am, believe me...

428
00:32:10,345 --> 00:32:13,598
Do you have brothers and sisters,
Miss Bennet?

429
00:32:13,682 --> 00:32:16,601
Yes, ma'am,
I am the second of five sisters.

430
00:32:16,685 --> 00:32:19,395
Are any of your younger sisters out?

431
00:32:19,479 --> 00:32:22,523
- Yes, ma'am, all of them.
- All?

432
00:32:24,610 --> 00:32:28,446
What? All five out at once?

433
00:32:29,364 --> 00:32:33,909
The younger ones out
before the older are married?

434
00:32:35,996 --> 00:32:39,624
Your youngest sisters
must be very young?

435
00:32:40,334 --> 00:32:43,169
Yes, ma'am, my youngest is not sixteen.

436
00:32:45,464 --> 00:32:47,048
Well!

437
00:32:48,717 --> 00:32:52,219
She is full young
to be out much in company.

438
00:32:52,888 --> 00:32:56,682
But really, ma'am, I think it would be
hard upon younger sisters,

439
00:32:56,767 --> 00:32:59,769
that they not have their share
of society and amusement,

440
00:32:59,853 --> 00:33:02,605
simply because their elder sisters
have not the means or

441
00:33:02,689 --> 00:33:04,732
inclination to marry early.

442
00:33:05,525 --> 00:33:07,902
Sir William, wouldn't you agree?

443
00:33:09,196 --> 00:33:12,323
- Well...
- (LADY CATHERINE): Upon my word!

444
00:33:12,407 --> 00:33:17,370
You give your opinion very decidedly
for so young a person!

445
00:33:18,413 --> 00:33:20,247
Pray, what is your age?

446
00:33:20,749 --> 00:33:22,249
With three younger sisters grown up,

447
00:33:22,334 --> 00:33:25,002
your ladyship can hardly expect me
to own it.

448
00:33:25,087 --> 00:33:29,090
Miss Bennet, you cannot be
more than twenty, I am sure.

449
00:33:29,174 --> 00:33:32,843
Therefore there is no need
to conceal your age!

450
00:33:32,928 --> 00:33:35,012
I am not one and twenty.

451
00:33:40,936 --> 00:33:45,690
Mrs Collins, did I tell you of
Lady Metcalf's calling on me yesterday

452
00:33:45,774 --> 00:33:49,777
to thank me for sending her Miss Pope?
"Lady Catherine," said she,

453
00:33:49,861 --> 00:33:53,906
"you have given me a treasure." Yes!

454
00:33:58,745 --> 00:34:00,496
Yes.

455
00:34:05,585 --> 00:34:07,670
It is beautiful.

456
00:34:07,754 --> 00:34:11,882
I could grow almost as fond
of these woods and hills as you have.

457
00:34:11,967 --> 00:34:14,093
Lizzy?

458
00:34:14,177 --> 00:34:16,053
We have been here three weeks,

459
00:34:16,138 --> 00:34:19,682
and already we have dined
at Rosings Park six times!

460
00:34:19,766 --> 00:34:22,059
I would never have expected it
to be so many!

461
00:34:22,144 --> 00:34:23,894
No, nor I.

462
00:34:23,979 --> 00:34:25,938
(COLLINS): My dear!

463
00:34:26,314 --> 00:34:29,358
Maria! Cousin Elizabeth!

464
00:34:31,153 --> 00:34:33,404
Mr Darcy is arrived at Rosings!

465
00:34:33,488 --> 00:34:36,282
And with him his cousin,
Colonel Fitzwilliam!

466
00:34:36,366 --> 00:34:38,242
The younger son of the Earl of Matlock!

467
00:34:38,326 --> 00:34:40,619
They have vouchsafed us
the greatest honour.

468
00:34:40,704 --> 00:34:42,788
They are coming to call upon us!

469
00:34:42,873 --> 00:34:45,583
- When, my dear?
- Even now, Mrs Collins!

470
00:34:45,667 --> 00:34:48,085
They're hard upon my heels! Make haste!

471
00:34:48,587 --> 00:34:50,421
This must be due to you.

472
00:34:50,505 --> 00:34:53,215
Mr Darcy wouldn't come so soon
to wait upon me.

473
00:34:53,300 --> 00:34:57,052
You're mistaken, for he dislikes me
as much as I do him.

474
00:34:57,137 --> 00:34:59,346
Make haste! Make haste!

475
00:35:02,350 --> 00:35:04,602
Delighted to make
your acquaintance at last!

476
00:35:04,686 --> 00:35:05,728
At last, sir?

477
00:35:05,812 --> 00:35:09,023
I've heard much of you,
and the praise hasn't been exaggerated.

478
00:35:09,107 --> 00:35:12,485
I can well believe that.
Mr Darcy is my severest critic.

479
00:35:13,570 --> 00:35:16,030
I hope we shall see you
frequently at Rosings.

480
00:35:16,406 --> 00:35:20,576
- I'm fond of lively conversation.
- This you do not find at Rosings Park?

481
00:35:20,869 --> 00:35:24,580
My aunt does talk a great deal,
but seldom requires a response.

482
00:35:25,373 --> 00:35:28,626
My friend speaks hardly a word
when he comes into Kent,

483
00:35:28,710 --> 00:35:31,212
though he's lively in other places.

484
00:35:31,296 --> 00:35:34,340
Nobody plays, nobody sings.

485
00:35:34,424 --> 00:35:38,344
- I believe you play and sing?
- A little, and very ill.

486
00:35:38,428 --> 00:35:40,930
I wouldn't wish to excite
your anticipation.

487
00:35:41,014 --> 00:35:42,640
I'm sure you're too modest.

488
00:35:42,849 --> 00:35:45,726
Any relief would be profoundly welcome.

489
00:35:48,063 --> 00:35:51,023
Can you tell me why Mr Darcy
keeps staring at me?

490
00:35:51,107 --> 00:35:53,400
What do you think offends him?

491
00:36:02,160 --> 00:36:06,288
- I hope your family is in good health.
- I thank you, yes.

492
00:36:12,003 --> 00:36:14,171
My sister has been in town
these three months.

493
00:36:14,256 --> 00:36:15,923
Have you not seen her?

494
00:36:17,801 --> 00:36:19,218
No.

495
00:36:19,928 --> 00:36:22,346
No, I have not had that pleasure.

496
00:36:31,982 --> 00:36:34,400
Mr Darcy and I
are not the best of friends.

497
00:36:34,484 --> 00:36:36,360
I'm surprised.

498
00:36:36,444 --> 00:36:40,865
Why should you be?
I always believe in first impressions,

499
00:36:40,949 --> 00:36:44,076
and his good opinion once lost,
is lost forever.

500
00:36:47,789 --> 00:36:51,834
So you see, it is a hopeless case,
is it not, Colonel Fitzwilliam?

501
00:38:28,932 --> 00:38:34,520
You will never play really well,
Miss Bennet, unless you practise more.

502
00:38:34,604 --> 00:38:37,648
(LADY CATHERINE): You may come
to Rosings as often as you like,

503
00:38:37,732 --> 00:38:41,944
and play on the pianoforte
in Mrs Jenkinson's room.

504
00:38:42,529 --> 00:38:46,448
She would be in nobody's way
in that part of the house.

505
00:38:46,533 --> 00:38:47,533
Thank you, ma'am.

506
00:38:47,617 --> 00:38:49,284
There are few people in England,

507
00:38:49,369 --> 00:38:54,748
I suppose, who have more true enjoyment
in music than myself.

508
00:38:55,792 --> 00:38:58,836
(LADY CATHERINE): Or a better taste.

509
00:38:58,920 --> 00:39:04,758
And if I had ever learnt,
I should be a true proficient.

510
00:39:05,301 --> 00:39:07,845
(LADY CATHERINE): And so would Anne.

511
00:39:11,099 --> 00:39:16,145
Do you mean to frighten me, Mr Darcy,
by coming in all this state to hear me?

512
00:39:16,229 --> 00:39:17,688
I won't be alarmed.

513
00:39:17,772 --> 00:39:21,942
My courage always rises
with every attempt to intimidate me.

514
00:39:23,862 --> 00:39:26,447
I know you find great enjoyment
in professing opinions

515
00:39:26,531 --> 00:39:28,741
which are not your own.

516
00:39:28,825 --> 00:39:30,534
Your cousin would teach you

517
00:39:30,618 --> 00:39:33,370
not to believe a word I say,
Colonel Fitzwilliam.

518
00:39:33,455 --> 00:39:37,791
- That is ungenerous of him, is it not?
- It is indeed, Darcy!

519
00:39:37,876 --> 00:39:41,211
Impolitic too,
for it provokes me to retaliate

520
00:39:41,296 --> 00:39:43,547
and say somewhat of his behaviour
in Hertfordshire,

521
00:39:43,631 --> 00:39:46,050
which may shock his relations.

522
00:39:46,134 --> 00:39:49,720
- I'm not afraid of you.
- What can you accuse him of?

523
00:39:49,804 --> 00:39:53,057
I should like to know how he behaves
among strangers!

524
00:39:53,141 --> 00:39:56,143
The first time I ever saw Mr Darcy
was at a ball,

525
00:39:56,227 --> 00:40:00,064
where he danced only four dances,
though gentlemen were scarce,

526
00:40:00,148 --> 00:40:04,985
and more than one lady
was in want of a partner.

527
00:40:05,070 --> 00:40:08,906
- I'm sorry, but so it was.
- I can well believe it!

528
00:40:08,990 --> 00:40:12,159
I fear I am ill qualified
to recommend myself to strangers.

529
00:40:13,495 --> 00:40:15,579
Shall we ask him why?

530
00:40:16,081 --> 00:40:20,751
Why a man of sense and education,
who has lived in the world,

531
00:40:20,835 --> 00:40:24,505
should be ill qualified
to recommend himself to strangers?

532
00:40:27,175 --> 00:40:28,550
I...

533
00:40:30,887 --> 00:40:33,222
I have not that talent
which some possess,

534
00:40:33,306 --> 00:40:35,390
of conversing easily with strangers.

535
00:40:36,976 --> 00:40:41,271
I do not play this instrument
so well as I should wish to,

536
00:40:41,356 --> 00:40:44,608
but I have supposed that
to be my own fault,

537
00:40:44,692 --> 00:40:47,319
because I would not take the trouble
of practising!

538
00:40:50,031 --> 00:40:54,076
You are perfectly right.
You have employed your time much better.

539
00:40:54,536 --> 00:40:57,746
No one privileged of hearing you
could think anything wanting.

540
00:40:59,666 --> 00:41:02,793
We neither of us perform to strangers.

541
00:41:05,922 --> 00:41:08,048
(LADY CATHERINE): What are you
talking of?

542
00:41:08,133 --> 00:41:09,925
What are you telling Miss Bennet?

543
00:41:10,009 --> 00:41:13,011
I must have my share
in the conversation!

544
00:41:13,555 --> 00:41:16,181
As for the daughter,
she is a pale sickly creature

545
00:41:16,266 --> 00:41:18,517
with little conversation and no talent.

546
00:41:18,601 --> 00:41:21,979
I'm sorry to be hard
on any of our sex, but...

547
00:41:22,063 --> 00:41:24,398
Mr Darcy shows no inclination for her,

548
00:41:24,482 --> 00:41:28,235
and treats her with the same
indifference he shows everyone,

549
00:41:28,319 --> 00:41:31,989
but Lady Catherine is determined
to have him for a son-in-law,

550
00:41:32,073 --> 00:41:34,658
and she is not a woman to be gainsaid.

551
00:41:34,742 --> 00:41:36,827
(THE DOORBELL RINGS)

552
00:41:47,881 --> 00:41:50,591
Mr Darcy.

553
00:41:53,511 --> 00:41:54,887
Mrs Collins and Maria

554
00:41:54,971 --> 00:41:58,182
are just now gone into Hunsford village
with my cousin.

555
00:41:58,266 --> 00:42:01,185
You find me all alone this morning,
Mr Darcy.

556
00:42:01,269 --> 00:42:05,314
I beg your pardon. I would not wish
to intrude upon your privacy.

557
00:42:08,443 --> 00:42:11,778
I was just writing a letter
to my sister Jane in London.

558
00:42:32,717 --> 00:42:36,261
Mr Bingley and his sisters were well,
I hope, when you left London?

559
00:42:37,263 --> 00:42:39,640
Perfectly so, I thank you.

560
00:42:40,391 --> 00:42:44,311
I understand Mr Bingley has not much
idea for ever returning to Netherfield?

561
00:42:45,897 --> 00:42:50,692
It is probable that he may spend
little time there in the future.

562
00:42:50,777 --> 00:42:55,197
If so, it would be better for the
neighbourhood that he give up the place.

563
00:42:55,281 --> 00:42:56,865
I should not be surprised
if he were to give it up,

564
00:42:56,950 --> 00:42:59,701
as soon as any eligible purchase offers.

565
00:43:10,838 --> 00:43:14,091
This seems a very comfortable house.

566
00:43:14,175 --> 00:43:17,970
Lady Catherine, I believe,
did much to it when Mr Collins came.

567
00:43:18,054 --> 00:43:19,429
I believe she did.

568
00:43:19,514 --> 00:43:23,267
And she couldn't have bestowed her
kindness on a more grateful recipient.

569
00:43:24,560 --> 00:43:27,771
Mr Collins appears extremely fortunate
in his choice of wife.

570
00:43:27,855 --> 00:43:32,442
Yes, indeed he is.
Though seen in a prudential light,

571
00:43:32,527 --> 00:43:34,820
it is a good match for her as well.

572
00:43:36,489 --> 00:43:40,575
It must be agreeable to her to live
within easy distance of her family.

573
00:43:40,660 --> 00:43:43,620
Easy distance? It's nearly fifty miles!

574
00:43:43,705 --> 00:43:47,499
What is fifty miles of good road?
Yes, an easy distance.

575
00:43:47,583 --> 00:43:49,960
Near and far are relative terms.

576
00:43:50,044 --> 00:43:53,839
It is possible for a woman
to be settled too near her family.

577
00:43:53,923 --> 00:43:55,215
Yes, exactly.

578
00:43:56,551 --> 00:44:00,137
You would not wish to be always
near Longbourn, I think.

579
00:44:06,519 --> 00:44:08,812
I shall trespass on your time no longer.

580
00:44:08,896 --> 00:44:11,940
Please convey my regards to
Mrs Collins and her sister.

581
00:44:12,942 --> 00:44:16,069
No, no, please don't trouble yourself.

582
00:44:38,760 --> 00:44:42,387
- Miss Bennet!
- Colonel Fitzwilliam.

583
00:44:48,478 --> 00:44:51,772
I've been making the yearly tour
of the Park.

584
00:44:51,856 --> 00:44:53,023
Shall we take this way together?

585
00:44:53,107 --> 00:44:54,608
With pleasure.

586
00:44:59,447 --> 00:45:01,907
Do you know Mr Bingley and his sisters?

587
00:45:01,991 --> 00:45:03,492
A little.

588
00:45:03,576 --> 00:45:06,661
Bingley is a pleasant,
gentleman-like man.

589
00:45:06,746 --> 00:45:08,246
He's a great friend of Darcy's.

590
00:45:08,331 --> 00:45:11,917
Yes. Mr Darcy is uncommonly
kind to Mr Bingley,

591
00:45:12,001 --> 00:45:13,710
and takes a prodigious
deal of care of him.

592
00:45:13,795 --> 00:45:16,630
Yes, I believe Darcy
does take care of him.

593
00:45:17,673 --> 00:45:21,927
I... I understand
that he congratulates himself

594
00:45:22,011 --> 00:45:23,970
on having saved Mr Bingley

595
00:45:24,055 --> 00:45:27,099
the inconvenience
of a most imprudent marriage.

596
00:45:29,394 --> 00:45:33,355
Did Mr Darcy give his reasons
for this interference?

597
00:45:33,439 --> 00:45:37,234
I understand there were some very strong
objections to the lady.

598
00:45:37,318 --> 00:45:39,986
And why was he to be the judge?

599
00:45:40,780 --> 00:45:43,407
You're disposed to think
his interference officious?

600
00:45:43,491 --> 00:45:46,284
I don't see what right Mr Darcy had
to determine and direct

601
00:45:46,369 --> 00:45:49,121
in what way his friend was to be happy.

602
00:45:50,206 --> 00:45:53,375
But, as you say,
we know none of the particulars.

603
00:45:53,459 --> 00:45:56,920
- Perhaps there was not much affection.
- Perhaps not.

604
00:45:57,422 --> 00:45:58,505
But if that were the case,

605
00:45:58,589 --> 00:46:03,009
it lessens the honour of my cousin's
triumph very sadly, don't you think?

606
00:46:10,810 --> 00:46:14,604
- Miss Bennet, are you unwell?
- A sudden headache.

607
00:46:15,940 --> 00:46:18,859
Perhaps I have walked too far today.

608
00:46:20,027 --> 00:46:22,446
Let us take the shorter way back.

609
00:46:28,995 --> 00:46:32,164
You're sure?
I would willingly stay at home with you,

610
00:46:32,248 --> 00:46:34,249
and brave
all Lady Catherine's displeasure.

611
00:46:34,333 --> 00:46:37,127
My dear Charlotte,
I beg you to consider...

612
00:46:37,211 --> 00:46:39,796
I shall be quite all right.
It's only a headache.

613
00:46:39,881 --> 00:46:43,508
It will pass, and more speedily
in quiet and solitude.

614
00:46:43,593 --> 00:46:44,759
I am quite sure,

615
00:46:44,844 --> 00:46:48,013
when all the circumstances
are explained to Lady Catherine,

616
00:46:48,097 --> 00:46:49,556
she will not be angry,

617
00:46:49,640 --> 00:46:52,976
for she has indeed
such Christian generosity of spirit...

618
00:46:53,060 --> 00:46:57,939
- My dear, the time!
- My dear! Why did you not say before?

619
00:46:58,024 --> 00:46:59,733
I cannot begin to count the occasions

620
00:46:59,817 --> 00:47:05,447
on which her ladyship has impressed
upon me the importance of punctuality...

621
00:47:27,887 --> 00:47:29,971
(DOORBELL RINGS)

622
00:47:44,320 --> 00:47:47,113
Forgive me.
I hope you are feeling better.

623
00:47:48,950 --> 00:47:50,617
I am, thank you.

624
00:47:51,953 --> 00:47:54,162
Will you not sit down?

625
00:48:44,338 --> 00:48:47,090
In vain I have struggled.
It will not do!

626
00:48:48,843 --> 00:48:50,760
My feelings will not be repressed.

627
00:48:50,845 --> 00:48:54,514
You must allow me to tell you
how ardently I admire and love you.

628
00:48:57,685 --> 00:48:59,936
In declaring myself thus I'm aware

629
00:49:00,021 --> 00:49:03,273
that I will be going expressly against
the wishes of my family,

630
00:49:03,357 --> 00:49:07,110
my friends, and, I hardly need add,
my own better judgement.

631
00:49:07,862 --> 00:49:09,821
The relative situation of our families

632
00:49:09,905 --> 00:49:14,367
makes any alliance between us
a reprehensible connection.

633
00:49:16,287 --> 00:49:21,166
As a rational man I cannot but regard it
as such myself, but it cannot be helped.

634
00:49:22,710 --> 00:49:26,838
Almost from the earliest moments,
I have come to feel for you...

635
00:49:28,341 --> 00:49:32,510
..a passionate admiration and regard,

636
00:49:34,138 --> 00:49:37,265
which despite my struggles,
has overcome every rational objection.

637
00:49:37,350 --> 00:49:41,811
I beg you, most fervently,
to relieve my suffering

638
00:49:41,896 --> 00:49:43,980
and consent to be my wife.

639
00:49:48,402 --> 00:49:49,903
In such cases as these,

640
00:49:49,987 --> 00:49:54,157
I believe the established mode
is to express a sense of obligation.

641
00:49:55,576 --> 00:49:57,077
But I cannot.

642
00:50:01,749 --> 00:50:03,541
I have never desired your good opinion,

643
00:50:03,626 --> 00:50:06,961
and you have certainly bestowed it
most unwillingly.

644
00:50:08,673 --> 00:50:12,175
I'm sorry to cause pain to anyone,
but it was unconsciously done,

645
00:50:12,259 --> 00:50:14,886
and I hope will be of short duration.

646
00:50:34,281 --> 00:50:37,075
And this is all the reply
I am to expect?

647
00:50:40,121 --> 00:50:43,790
I might wonder why, with so little
effort at civility, I am rejected.

648
00:50:43,874 --> 00:50:47,460
I might wonder why,
with so evident a desire to offend me,

649
00:50:47,545 --> 00:50:50,046
you chose to tell me that
you like me against your will,

650
00:50:50,131 --> 00:50:53,133
your reason, and
even against your character!

651
00:50:53,884 --> 00:50:57,470
Was this not some excuse
for incivility if I was uncivil?

652
00:50:59,682 --> 00:51:03,101
I have every reason in the world
to think ill of you.

653
00:51:03,978 --> 00:51:06,813
What could tempt me to accept the man

654
00:51:06,897 --> 00:51:10,650
who has ruined the happiness
of a most beloved sister?

655
00:51:12,319 --> 00:51:14,863
Can you deny that you have done it?

656
00:51:15,781 --> 00:51:17,824
I have no wish to deny it.

657
00:51:18,826 --> 00:51:21,578
I did everything in my power
to separate my friend from your sister,

658
00:51:21,662 --> 00:51:24,289
and I rejoice in my success.

659
00:51:24,373 --> 00:51:26,875
Towards him I have been kinder
than towards myself.

660
00:51:26,959 --> 00:51:31,212
It's not merely that on which
my dislike of you is founded.

661
00:51:31,297 --> 00:51:34,257
Long before, my dislike was decided

662
00:51:34,341 --> 00:51:37,677
when I heard Mr Wickham's story
of your dealings with him.

663
00:51:38,471 --> 00:51:40,388
How can you defend yourself
on that subject?

664
00:51:40,473 --> 00:51:43,224
Such interest
in that gentleman's concerns!

665
00:51:43,350 --> 00:51:46,728
Who that knows of his misfortunes,
can help feeling an interest?

666
00:51:46,812 --> 00:51:50,356
His misfortunes! Yes, his misfortunes
have been great indeed!

667
00:51:50,441 --> 00:51:52,609
And of your infliction!

668
00:51:52,693 --> 00:51:55,111
You have reduced him
to his present state of poverty,

669
00:51:55,196 --> 00:51:59,449
and yet you can treat his misfortunes
with contempt and ridicule!

670
00:52:03,370 --> 00:52:05,705
And this is your opinion of me?

671
00:52:07,124 --> 00:52:10,210
My faults by this calculation
are heavy indeed.

672
00:52:15,049 --> 00:52:17,675
Perhaps these offences
might have been overlooked,

673
00:52:17,760 --> 00:52:21,179
had not your pride been hurt
by the confession of the scruples

674
00:52:21,263 --> 00:52:24,390
long prevented my forming
serious design on you.

675
00:52:25,392 --> 00:52:28,478
Had I concealed my struggles
and flattered you.

676
00:52:28,854 --> 00:52:31,773
But disguise of every sort
is my abhorrence.

677
00:52:32,691 --> 00:52:36,569
Nor am I ashamed of the feelings
I related. They were natural.

678
00:52:36,695 --> 00:52:40,573
Did you expect me to rejoice
in the inferiority of your connections?

679
00:52:40,658 --> 00:52:42,617
To congratulate myself
on the hope of relations

680
00:52:42,701 --> 00:52:45,829
whose condition in life
is so below my own?

681
00:52:47,623 --> 00:52:50,041
You are mistaken, Mr Darcy.

682
00:52:50,125 --> 00:52:54,212
Your declaration merely spared me
any concern for refusing you,

683
00:52:54,296 --> 00:52:56,756
had you been more gentleman-like.

684
00:52:57,508 --> 00:53:00,677
You could not make me
the offer of your hand in any way

685
00:53:00,761 --> 00:53:03,179
that would tempt me to accept it.

686
00:53:03,848 --> 00:53:08,184
From the beginning, your manners
convinced me of your arrogance,

687
00:53:08,269 --> 00:53:11,479
your conceit, and your selfish disdain
for the feelings of others.

688
00:53:11,564 --> 00:53:16,192
Within a month, I felt you were the
last man whom I could ever marry!

689
00:53:17,528 --> 00:53:19,904
You've said quite enough, madam.

690
00:53:21,031 --> 00:53:23,449
I perfectly comprehend your feelings...

691
00:53:25,077 --> 00:53:29,163
..and now have only to be ashamed of
what my own have been.

692
00:53:29,540 --> 00:53:32,876
Please forgive me
for having taken up your time...

693
00:53:32,960 --> 00:00:00,-001
..and accept my best wishes
for your health and happiness.

