1
00:01:03,397 --> 00:01:07,358
- (BINGLEY): It's a fair prospect.
- (DARCY): Pretty enough, I grant you.

2
00:01:07,443 --> 00:01:09,569
It's nothing to Pemberley, I know.

3
00:01:09,653 --> 00:01:13,239
But I must settle somewhere.
Have I your approval?

4
00:01:13,323 --> 00:01:15,616
You'll find the society
something savage.

5
00:01:15,701 --> 00:01:18,995
Country manners?
I think they're charming.

6
00:01:19,079 --> 00:01:22,665
- Then you'd better take it.
- Thank you, I shall.

7
00:01:22,750 --> 00:01:25,835
I shall close
with the attorney directly.

8
00:02:34,696 --> 00:02:38,199
(KITTY): I want to wear it today.
Look what you've done to it!

9
00:02:38,283 --> 00:02:40,868
(KITTY): Mamma, mamma!

10
00:02:41,745 --> 00:02:43,996
(KITTY): Lydia has torn up my bonnet

11
00:02:44,081 --> 00:02:46,749
and says she will wear it to church.
Tell her she shall not!

12
00:02:46,834 --> 00:02:50,002
I shall wear it,
for it's all my own work.

13
00:02:50,087 --> 00:02:53,130
She'd be a fright in it.
She's too plain to look well in it!

14
00:02:53,674 --> 00:02:56,843
- No, you shall not have it!
- Lydia! Kitty! Girls!

15
00:02:56,927 --> 00:03:01,264
Would you tear my nerves into shreds?
Let her have it, Kitty.

16
00:03:01,348 --> 00:03:05,268
But it's mine! You let her have
everything that is mine!

17
00:03:13,694 --> 00:03:20,241
Oh, what is to become of us all?
Jane, Lizzy, where are you?

18
00:03:20,325 --> 00:03:23,327
- Here, mamma.
- Coming, mamma.

19
00:03:38,302 --> 00:03:43,347
My dear! Mr Bennet! Wonderful news!

20
00:03:43,432 --> 00:03:46,517
- Netherfield Park is let at last!
- Is it?

21
00:03:46,602 --> 00:03:50,146
Yes, it is, for I have just had it
from Mrs Long.

22
00:03:50,230 --> 00:03:52,440
Do you not want to know who's taken it?

23
00:03:52,524 --> 00:03:55,735
I have no objection to hearing it.

24
00:03:55,819 --> 00:04:00,364
It is taken by a young man of large
fortune from the north of England.

25
00:04:00,449 --> 00:04:03,242
A single man of large fortune, my dear.

26
00:04:03,327 --> 00:04:06,579
He came down on Monday to see the place.

27
00:04:06,663 --> 00:04:10,750
His name is Bingley and he will be
in possession by Michaelmas.

28
00:04:10,834 --> 00:04:15,087
Andhe has 5,000 a year!

29
00:04:15,172 --> 00:04:19,967
- What a fine thing for our girls!
- How so? How can it affect them?

30
00:04:20,052 --> 00:04:22,386
Mr Bennet, why are you so tiresome?

31
00:04:22,471 --> 00:04:25,556
You know that I'm thinking
of his marrying one of them.

32
00:04:26,725 --> 00:04:31,228
For a single man with a good fortune
must be in want of a wife.

33
00:04:31,313 --> 00:04:35,274
Yes, he must indeed! And who better
than one of our five girls?

34
00:04:35,359 --> 00:04:36,442
(LYDIA SNORTS)

35
00:04:36,526 --> 00:04:37,610
Lydia!

36
00:04:37,694 --> 00:04:40,738
- What a fine joke if he chose me!
- Or me!

37
00:04:40,822 --> 00:04:45,451
So that is his design in settling here?
To marry one of our daughters?

38
00:04:45,535 --> 00:04:48,621
"Design"? How can you talk
such nonsense?

39
00:04:48,705 --> 00:04:51,916
But he may fall in love
with one of them.

40
00:04:52,000 --> 00:04:54,585
Therefore you must visit him
directly he comes.

41
00:04:54,670 --> 00:04:57,630
No, no, I see no occasion for that.

42
00:04:57,714 --> 00:05:00,007
- Mr Bennet!
- Go yourself with the girls.

43
00:05:00,092 --> 00:05:02,927
- Still better, send them by themselves.
- By themselves?!

44
00:05:03,011 --> 00:05:04,762
Aye, for you're as handsome
as any of them.

45
00:05:04,846 --> 00:05:07,640
Mr Bingley might like you
best of the party.

46
00:05:07,724 --> 00:05:08,891
(LYDIA SNORTS)

47
00:05:08,976 --> 00:05:10,017
Lydia...

48
00:05:19,736 --> 00:05:21,028
Hill!

49
00:05:21,113 --> 00:05:22,613
Oh, Hill!

50
00:05:22,698 --> 00:05:25,449
Hill, I am so distressed!

51
00:05:25,534 --> 00:05:29,203
Mr Bennet says he will not visit
Mr Bingley when he comes.

52
00:05:29,287 --> 00:05:31,998
- There, there.
- Can't you reason with him?

53
00:05:32,082 --> 00:05:36,919
- I daresay it'll all be well.
- No, it will not!

54
00:05:37,004 --> 00:05:41,674
- For he is bent on ruining us all.
- Mamma, he's teasing you.

55
00:05:41,758 --> 00:05:44,885
He will call on Mr Bingley.
He calls on any new neighbour.

56
00:05:44,970 --> 00:05:48,556
Jane, how can you say that?
You heard him!

57
00:05:48,640 --> 00:05:51,434
You know your father
has a will of iron.

58
00:05:51,518 --> 00:05:53,352
You're in the right, my dear.

59
00:05:53,437 --> 00:05:57,857
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I shall write to Mr Bingley,

60
00:05:57,941 --> 00:06:01,027
informing him that
I have five daughters,

61
00:06:01,111 --> 00:06:04,321
and he is welcome to any of them.

62
00:06:04,406 --> 00:06:07,116
They're all silly and ignorant,
like other girls.

63
00:06:07,200 --> 00:06:09,827
Well, Lizzy has more wit than the rest.

64
00:06:09,911 --> 00:06:14,498
But he may prefer a stupid wife,
as others have done before him.

65
00:06:14,583 --> 00:06:18,836
- There, will that do?
- No! I beg you will not write if you...

66
00:06:18,920 --> 00:06:21,839
You take delight in vexing me!

67
00:06:21,923 --> 00:06:24,341
You have no compassion
on my poor nerves!

68
00:06:24,426 --> 00:06:27,887
You mistake me.
I have a high respect for your nerves.

69
00:06:27,971 --> 00:06:30,556
They've been my old friends
for 20 years.

70
00:06:31,516 --> 00:06:35,853
- You don't know what I suffer.
- Well, I hope you'll get over it,

71
00:06:35,937 --> 00:06:40,441
and live to see many young men
of 5,000 a year move here.

72
00:06:40,525 --> 00:06:44,945
It's no use if 20 such should come,
since you won't visit them.

73
00:06:45,030 --> 00:06:49,450
Depend upon it, my dear.
When there are 20, I'll visit them all.

74
00:06:52,287 --> 00:06:57,083
You see, Jane? He won't be
prevailed upon. He'll see us all ruined.

75
00:06:57,167 --> 00:07:00,169
If only we'd been able to have sons!

76
00:07:02,172 --> 00:07:06,592
Misfortunes, we are told,
are sent to test our fortitude,

77
00:07:06,676 --> 00:07:10,679
and may often reveal themselves
as blessings in disguise.

78
00:07:12,265 --> 00:07:15,101
Lord, I'm so hungry!

79
00:07:26,029 --> 00:07:28,614
If I could love a man
who would love me enough

80
00:07:28,698 --> 00:07:31,784
to take me for 50 pounds a year,

81
00:07:32,369 --> 00:07:34,620
I should be very well pleased.

82
00:07:34,704 --> 00:07:35,746
Yes.

83
00:07:37,749 --> 00:07:39,208
But such a man could hardly be sensible

84
00:07:39,292 --> 00:07:42,044
and I could never love a man
who was out of his wits.

85
00:07:43,088 --> 00:07:45,381
Oh, Lizzy.

86
00:07:47,717 --> 00:07:52,930
A marriage... where either partner
cannot love nor respect the other,

87
00:07:54,349 --> 00:07:58,102
that cannot be agreeable...
to either party.

88
00:07:58,645 --> 00:08:01,730
As we have daily proof.

89
00:08:01,815 --> 00:08:04,775
But beggars, you know,
cannot be choosers.

90
00:08:04,860 --> 00:08:07,278
We're not verypoor, Lizzy.

91
00:08:07,821 --> 00:08:12,825
With father's estate withheld from the
female line, we have only our charms.

92
00:08:14,786 --> 00:08:18,247
One of us at least will have
to marry verywell.

93
00:08:18,748 --> 00:08:22,042
And since you're five times as pretty
as the rest of us,

94
00:08:22,127 --> 00:08:26,380
and have the sweetest disposition,
the task will fall on you.

95
00:08:26,464 --> 00:08:28,465
But, Lizzy...

96
00:08:30,218 --> 00:08:32,178
I would wish...

97
00:08:33,221 --> 00:08:37,308
I should so much like...
to marry for love.

98
00:08:38,435 --> 00:08:42,396
And so you shall, I'm sure.

99
00:08:42,480 --> 00:08:46,442
Only take care you fall in love
with a man of good fortune.

100
00:08:46,526 --> 00:08:50,112
Well, I shall try. To please you.

101
00:08:50,197 --> 00:08:51,614
And you?

102
00:08:53,283 --> 00:08:59,705
I am determined that only the deepest
love will induce me into matrimony.

103
00:09:01,291 --> 00:09:05,085
So... I shall end an old maid,

104
00:09:05,170 --> 00:09:08,088
and teach your 1 0 children
to embroider cushions

105
00:09:08,173 --> 00:09:11,300
and play their instruments very ill.

106
00:09:21,978 --> 00:09:26,649
- Good night, mamma.
- My head is very ill tonight.

107
00:09:27,567 --> 00:09:31,487
I said, I wouldn't dance with him
if he was the last man in Meryton!

108
00:09:31,905 --> 00:09:35,324
- Good night, Lydia. Good night, Kitty.
- Good night, Lizzy!

109
00:10:24,249 --> 00:10:26,083
(LYDIA): Lizzy!

110
00:10:27,002 --> 00:10:29,545
Wait till you hear our news!

111
00:10:34,551 --> 00:10:37,594
- Mr Bingley has come!
- Sir William Lucas called on him!

112
00:10:37,679 --> 00:10:41,807
- Save your breath. I will tell mamma.
- I don't wish to know.

113
00:10:41,891 --> 00:10:45,436
Why care for Mr Bingley?
We'll never be acquainted with him.

114
00:10:45,520 --> 00:10:46,895
But, mamma!

115
00:10:47,605 --> 00:10:51,942
Don't keep coughing so, Kitty!
Have a little compassion on my nerves.

116
00:10:52,027 --> 00:10:56,572
- I don't cough for my own amusement.
- 40 servants, and he's very handsome.

117
00:10:56,656 --> 00:11:00,117
- He declared that he loves to dance!
- He said he'd come to the next ball!

118
00:11:00,201 --> 00:11:01,869
- At the Assembly Rooms!
- On Saturday!

119
00:11:01,953 --> 00:11:05,622
- With six ladies and four gentlemen.
- It was 1 2 ladies and seven gentlemen.

120
00:11:05,707 --> 00:11:09,335
- Too many ladies.
- Lydia, I beg you would stop!

121
00:11:09,419 --> 00:11:13,213
We will never know Mr Bingley
and it pains me to hear of him.

122
00:11:13,298 --> 00:11:16,175
- (LYDIA): But mamma!
- I'm sick of Mr Bingley!

123
00:11:16,259 --> 00:11:18,135
I'm sorry to hear that.

124
00:11:18,219 --> 00:11:22,348
If I'd known as much this morning,
I should never have called on him.

125
00:11:23,350 --> 00:11:26,518
(MOTHER): You have called on him?!

126
00:11:26,603 --> 00:11:30,064
I'm afraid we cannot escape
the acquaintance now.

127
00:11:32,233 --> 00:11:37,029
My dear Mr Bennet!
How good you are to us.

128
00:11:37,113 --> 00:11:41,492
- Well, well.
- Girls, girls, is he not a good father?

129
00:11:41,576 --> 00:11:43,994
And never to tell us! What a good joke!

130
00:11:45,330 --> 00:11:48,916
And now you shall all dance
with Mr Bingley!

131
00:11:49,667 --> 00:11:53,087
I hope he has a strong constitution!

132
00:11:53,171 --> 00:11:55,631
And a fondness for silly young women.

133
00:11:55,715 --> 00:12:00,386
My dear Mr Bennet, nothing you say
shall ever vex me again.

134
00:12:00,470 --> 00:12:03,180
I'm sorry to hear it. Well, Kitty.

135
00:12:03,264 --> 00:12:06,975
I think you may cough as much
as you choose now.

136
00:12:46,724 --> 00:12:51,979
- Shall we be quite safe here, Mr Darcy?
- Damned silly way to spend an evening.

137
00:13:58,922 --> 00:14:01,131
Mr Bingley!

138
00:14:02,342 --> 00:14:06,345
Allow me the pleasure of welcoming
you to our little assembly.

139
00:14:06,429 --> 00:14:09,264
Sir William, I am very glad to see you.

140
00:14:09,766 --> 00:14:13,352
There's nothing that I love better
than a country dance.

141
00:14:22,320 --> 00:14:27,199
- Do you know who the two ladies are?
- Mr Bingley's sisters, I understand.

142
00:14:27,283 --> 00:14:30,244
One is married to that gentleman,
Mr Hurst.

143
00:14:30,328 --> 00:14:32,538
- The taller gentleman?
- No, the other.

144
00:14:32,622 --> 00:14:34,748
(ELIZABETH): Better and better!

145
00:14:34,832 --> 00:14:36,875
Very elegant.

146
00:14:36,960 --> 00:14:40,128
Better pleased with themselves
than what they see, I think.

147
00:14:40,964 --> 00:14:43,966
Lizzy! Jane! Come here!

148
00:14:48,471 --> 00:14:54,351
You see that gentleman? Lady Lucas
says he is Mr Bingley's oldest friend.

149
00:14:54,435 --> 00:14:57,145
His name is Darcy and he has
a mighty fortune

150
00:14:57,230 --> 00:14:59,648
and a great estate in Derbyshire.

151
00:14:59,732 --> 00:15:02,943
Bingley's wealth is nothing to his!

152
00:15:03,027 --> 00:15:06,029
1 0,000 a year! At least!

153
00:15:06,948 --> 00:15:10,951
Don't you think he's the handsomest
man you've ever seen, girls?

154
00:15:11,035 --> 00:15:14,705
I wonder if he'd be as handsome
if he weren't so rich.

155
00:15:16,833 --> 00:15:20,877
Oh, Lizzy! They're coming over.
Smile, girls! Smile!

156
00:15:22,589 --> 00:15:24,089
Mrs Bennet.

157
00:15:24,173 --> 00:15:29,011
Mr Bingley would want to become
acquainted with you and your daughters.

158
00:15:29,095 --> 00:15:32,097
Sir, that is very good of you.

159
00:15:34,892 --> 00:15:37,853
This is Jane, my eldest.

160
00:15:37,937 --> 00:15:41,732
And Elizabeth. And Mary sits over there.

161
00:15:42,692 --> 00:15:46,695
And Kitty and Lydia, my youngest,
you see there dancing.

162
00:15:51,034 --> 00:15:55,996
- Do you like to dance yourself?
- There is nothing I love better, madam.

163
00:15:56,080 --> 00:15:58,915
If Miss Bennet is not otherwise engaged,

164
00:15:59,000 --> 00:16:02,628
may I be so bold as to claim
the next two dances?

165
00:16:02,712 --> 00:16:06,006
- I am not engaged, sir.
- Good.

166
00:16:06,090 --> 00:16:10,761
You do us great honour, sir.
Thank the gentleman, Jane.

167
00:16:11,554 --> 00:16:13,221
Mamma.

168
00:16:13,306 --> 00:16:17,309
And you, sir?
Are you fond of dancing, too?

169
00:16:17,393 --> 00:16:22,564
Oh, I beg your pardon. Mrs Bennet,
may I present my friend, Mr Darcy?

170
00:16:23,775 --> 00:16:27,319
You are very welcome to Hertfordshire
I am sure, sir.

171
00:16:27,403 --> 00:16:31,406
I hope you have come here
eager to dance, as your friend has?

172
00:16:32,659 --> 00:16:35,202
Thank you, madam. I rarely dance.

173
00:16:35,286 --> 00:16:37,996
Let this be one of the occasions, sir,

174
00:16:38,081 --> 00:16:44,002
for I wager you'll not easily find such
lively music or such pretty partners.

175
00:16:51,135 --> 00:16:53,261
Pray, excuse me, ma'am.

176
00:16:55,515 --> 00:17:00,519
Well! Did you ever meet such a proud
disagreeable man!

177
00:17:00,603 --> 00:17:03,397
- He will hear you.
- I don't care if he does.

178
00:17:03,481 --> 00:17:08,694
And his friend disposed to be
so agreeable and everything charming.

179
00:17:08,778 --> 00:17:12,406
(MOTHER): Who is he to think himself
so far above his company?

180
00:17:12,490 --> 00:17:15,534
The very rich can afford to give offence
wherever they go.

181
00:17:15,618 --> 00:17:19,287
- We need not care for his good opinion.
- No, indeed!

182
00:17:20,623 --> 00:17:23,709
Perhaps he's not so very handsome
after all?

183
00:17:23,793 --> 00:17:28,046
No, indeed! Quite ill-favoured.

184
00:17:28,131 --> 00:17:31,800
(MOTHER): Certainly nothing at all to
Mr Bingley!

185
00:18:12,049 --> 00:18:14,050
I'll show them!

186
00:19:11,651 --> 00:19:16,279
I wonder at Kitty and Lydia,
that they are so fond of dancing.

187
00:19:16,364 --> 00:19:18,740
(MARY): I take little pleasure
in a ball.

188
00:19:18,825 --> 00:19:20,158
(ELIZABETH): I would take pleasure,

189
00:19:20,243 --> 00:19:23,620
if there were enough partners
as agreeable as Jane's.

190
00:19:24,205 --> 00:19:29,292
I believe the rewards of observation
and reflection are much greater.

191
00:19:29,377 --> 00:19:32,254
Yes, when there are none others
to be had.

192
00:19:32,338 --> 00:19:35,340
We shall have to be philosophers, Mary.

193
00:19:52,483 --> 00:19:55,318
Come, Darcy, I must have you dance!

194
00:19:55,403 --> 00:19:58,780
I must. I hate to see you standing about
in this stupid manner!

195
00:19:58,865 --> 00:20:01,074
You had much better dance!

196
00:20:01,450 --> 00:20:07,539
I certainly shall not. At an assembly
such as this? It would be insupportable.

197
00:20:12,044 --> 00:20:14,004
Your sisters are engaged.

198
00:20:15,298 --> 00:20:19,217
(DARCY): You know it would punish me
to stand up with any other woman.

199
00:20:19,302 --> 00:20:23,722
Good God, Darcy! I wouldn't be
as fastidious as you are for a kingdom!

200
00:20:23,806 --> 00:20:27,893
(BINGLEY): Upon my honour, I never met
so many pleasant girls in my life!

201
00:20:27,977 --> 00:20:30,979
Several of them uncommonly pretty.

202
00:20:32,356 --> 00:20:35,525
You have been dancing
with the only handsome girl in the room.

203
00:20:36,485 --> 00:20:41,114
Darcy, she is the most
beautiful creature I ever beheld.

204
00:20:42,700 --> 00:20:44,492
Look, look!

205
00:20:45,036 --> 00:20:48,622
(BINGLEY): There's one of her sisters.
She's very pretty too.

206
00:20:49,248 --> 00:20:51,249
(BINGLEY): I daresay very agreeable.

207
00:20:51,334 --> 00:20:56,755
(DARCY): She's tolerable, I suppose,
but not handsome enough to tempt me.

208
00:20:57,590 --> 00:21:02,552
I'm in no humour to consider young
ladies who are slighted by other men.

209
00:21:02,637 --> 00:21:04,387
Go back to your partner.
Enjoy her smiles.

210
00:21:04,472 --> 00:21:06,681
You're wasting your time on me.

211
00:22:21,966 --> 00:22:25,218
Jane was so admired!

212
00:22:25,302 --> 00:22:27,971
There was nothing like it!

213
00:22:28,055 --> 00:22:32,434
- Oh, Lord! I'm so fagged!
- Lydia and I danced every dance.

214
00:22:32,560 --> 00:22:34,394
And Mary none!

215
00:22:35,146 --> 00:22:39,357
And Mr Bingley favoured Jane
above every other girl.

216
00:22:39,442 --> 00:22:41,651
For he danced the first two with her,

217
00:22:41,736 --> 00:22:45,196
and then the next with Charlotte Lucas,
which vexed me greatly,

218
00:22:45,281 --> 00:22:48,783
but lo, there in the very next nothing
would please him

219
00:22:48,868 --> 00:22:50,702
but to stand up with Jane again.

220
00:22:50,786 --> 00:22:54,706
And then he danced with Lizzy,
and what do you think he did next?

221
00:22:54,790 --> 00:22:59,377
Enough, madam! For God's sake!
Let's hear no more of his partners!

222
00:22:59,462 --> 00:23:01,755
Would he had sprained his ankle
in the first dance!

223
00:23:01,839 --> 00:23:06,593
And his sisters! Oh,
such charming women!

224
00:23:06,677 --> 00:23:10,055
So elegant and obliging!
I wish you had seen them.

225
00:23:10,139 --> 00:23:16,227
- The lace on Mrs Hurst's gown...
- No lace, Mrs Bennet, I beg you.

226
00:23:16,312 --> 00:23:20,857
But the man he brought with him!
'Mr Darcy', as he calls himself,

227
00:23:20,941 --> 00:23:26,237
is not worth our concern, though he
may be the richest man in Derbyshire.

228
00:23:26,322 --> 00:23:30,408
The proudest,
the most horrid, disobliging...

229
00:23:30,493 --> 00:23:35,080
He slighted poor Lizzy,
and flatly refused to stand up with her.

230
00:23:35,164 --> 00:23:37,499
Slighted my Lizzy, did he?

231
00:23:37,583 --> 00:23:40,376
I didn't care for him either,
so it's of little matter.

232
00:23:40,461 --> 00:23:44,923
Another time, Lizzy, I would not dance
with him if he should ask you.

233
00:23:45,007 --> 00:23:50,011
I believe, ma'am, I may safely promise
you neverto dance with Mr Darcy.

234
00:23:53,974 --> 00:23:58,269
So none of the Hertfordshire ladies
could please you, Mr Darcy?

235
00:23:58,354 --> 00:24:01,856
Not even the famous Miss Bennets?

236
00:24:01,941 --> 00:24:05,777
I never met with pleasanter people
or prettier girls!

237
00:24:05,861 --> 00:24:10,115
You astonish me. I saw little beauty,
and no breeding at all.

238
00:24:10,199 --> 00:24:13,618
The eldest Miss Bennet is,
I grant you, very pretty.

239
00:24:13,702 --> 00:24:18,081
A fine concession!
Admit it, she's an angel!

240
00:24:18,165 --> 00:24:21,668
- She smiles too much.
- Jane Bennet is a sweet girl.

241
00:24:21,752 --> 00:24:24,546
But the mother!

242
00:24:25,422 --> 00:24:29,175
I heard Eliza Bennet described
as a famous local beauty.

243
00:24:29,260 --> 00:24:30,969
What do you say to that, Mr Darcy?

244
00:24:31,053 --> 00:24:33,221
I should as soon call her mother a wit.

245
00:24:33,722 --> 00:24:35,849
That's too cruel!

246
00:24:37,810 --> 00:24:41,104
I don't understand why you
go through the world

247
00:24:41,188 --> 00:24:45,608
determined to be displeased
with everything and everyone.

248
00:24:45,693 --> 00:24:50,989
I will never understand why you approve
of everything and everyone you meet.

249
00:24:51,073 --> 00:24:53,992
You shall not make me think ill
of Miss Bennet.

250
00:24:54,076 --> 00:24:57,453
Indeed he shall not!
I shall dare his disapproval

251
00:24:57,538 --> 00:24:59,747
and declare she is a dear sweet girl,

252
00:24:59,832 --> 00:25:01,958
despite her unfortunate relations,

253
00:25:02,084 --> 00:25:03,835
and I should not be sorry to know
her better!

254
00:25:03,919 --> 00:25:09,090
No, nor I! You see, Mr Darcy,
we are not afraid of you.

255
00:25:09,175 --> 00:25:11,217
I would not have you so.

256
00:25:11,302 --> 00:25:13,261
(SNORING)

257
00:25:13,345 --> 00:25:18,266
What? Aye, very true.
Damned tedious waste of an evening.

258
00:25:20,102 --> 00:25:22,353
(JANE): He's just what a young man
ought to be.

259
00:25:23,022 --> 00:25:28,359
Sensible, lively, and I never saw
such happy manners!

260
00:25:28,444 --> 00:25:31,905
Handsome too, which a young man
ought to be if he possibly can.

261
00:25:31,989 --> 00:25:35,366
He seems to like you very much,
which shows good judgement.

262
00:25:35,451 --> 00:25:38,661
You may like him.
You've liked many a stupider person.

263
00:25:38,746 --> 00:25:40,371
Dear Lizzy!

264
00:25:40,456 --> 00:25:43,541
He could be happier in his choice
of sisters and friends.

265
00:25:43,626 --> 00:25:46,252
- But the sisters he cannot help.
- Did you not like them?

266
00:25:46,378 --> 00:25:49,797
Not at all. Their manners
are quite different from his.

267
00:25:49,882 --> 00:25:53,468
At first, perhaps, but after a while
they were pleasing.

268
00:25:53,552 --> 00:25:57,722
Miss Bingley is to keep house.
They will be very charming neighbours.

269
00:25:57,806 --> 00:26:02,560
- One of them maybe.
- No, Lizzy, I'm sure you're wrong.

270
00:26:02,645 --> 00:26:06,397
Even Mr Darcy may improve
on closer acquaintance.

271
00:26:06,482 --> 00:26:10,735
Will he be in humour to consider young
ladies who are slighted by other men?

272
00:26:10,819 --> 00:26:12,820
Never!

273
00:26:13,280 --> 00:26:16,449
"She is tolerable, I suppose,

274
00:26:17,034 --> 00:26:19,911
but not handsome enough to tempt me. "

275
00:26:19,995 --> 00:26:24,624
- It was very wrong of him to speak so.
- Indeed it was!

276
00:26:24,708 --> 00:26:26,626
Capital offence!

277
00:26:27,461 --> 00:26:29,879
Oh, look! Charlotte is come.

278
00:26:31,382 --> 00:26:33,258
Charlotte!

279
00:26:33,342 --> 00:26:37,929
Lizzy! My father is to give a party
at Lucas Lodge and you are all invited!

280
00:26:42,935 --> 00:26:48,106
I hope Lucas Lodge will be graced
with your presence on many occasions.

281
00:26:48,190 --> 00:26:52,443
Here, you see, we are all easy
with no awkwardness or ceremony.

282
00:26:52,528 --> 00:26:53,861
Quite.

283
00:26:53,946 --> 00:26:58,157
Oh, yes, my dear. 5,000 a year!

284
00:26:58,242 --> 00:27:03,538
(MOTHER): Don't they look well together?
A most agreeable young man!

285
00:27:15,050 --> 00:27:19,512
And he would dance every dance
with Jane. Nothing else would do!

286
00:27:19,596 --> 00:27:22,682
Are you pleased with Hertfordshire,
Colonel Forster?

287
00:27:22,766 --> 00:27:25,810
Very much, Lady Lucas.
Especially this evening.

288
00:27:25,894 --> 00:27:29,147
A regiment of infantry doesn't find
a ready welcome everywhere.

289
00:27:29,231 --> 00:27:32,984
I think your officers will be very well
pleased with Meryton.

290
00:27:33,068 --> 00:27:34,694
(LAUGHTER)

291
00:27:36,030 --> 00:27:38,740
Denny and Sanderson
seem well pleased already!

292
00:27:39,825 --> 00:27:43,411
No doubt you attend assemblies
at St. James's Court?

293
00:27:43,495 --> 00:27:47,874
- We go but rarely, sir.
- Indeed! I am surprised.

294
00:27:47,958 --> 00:27:53,338
I should be happy to introduce you
there at any time when I'm in town.

295
00:27:53,422 --> 00:27:55,965
You're too kind, sir.

296
00:27:57,676 --> 00:27:59,719
Well! Well!

297
00:27:59,803 --> 00:28:02,096
Good, good.

298
00:28:02,181 --> 00:28:04,724
Capital! Capital!

299
00:28:04,808 --> 00:28:10,521
Insufferable conceit! To imagine that we
would need his assistance in society.

300
00:28:10,606 --> 00:28:13,524
I am sure he is a good sort of man,
Caroline.

301
00:28:13,609 --> 00:28:16,194
And I am sure he kept a good sort
of shop

302
00:28:16,278 --> 00:28:18,613
before his elevation to the Knighthood.

303
00:28:21,450 --> 00:28:25,370
Poor Darcy. What agonies he must
be suffering.

304
00:28:44,473 --> 00:28:48,184
Are you in Meryton to subdue
the discontented populace, sir,

305
00:28:48,268 --> 00:28:50,686
or to defend Hertfordshire
against the French?

306
00:28:50,771 --> 00:28:54,482
Neither, ma'am. We hope
to winter peacefully at Meryton.

307
00:28:54,566 --> 00:28:56,567
My soldiers
are in great need of training

308
00:28:56,652 --> 00:28:59,654
and my officers
in ever great need of society.

309
00:29:00,989 --> 00:29:03,658
When you are settled,
I hope you'll give a ball.

310
00:29:03,742 --> 00:29:07,245
- Oh, yes, my dear, do!
- Would a ball be well received?

311
00:29:07,329 --> 00:29:11,374
Who's giving a ball? I long for a ball,
and so does Denny!

312
00:29:11,458 --> 00:29:15,503
- And Sanderson. Don't you?
- I d-do indeed.

313
00:29:15,587 --> 00:29:18,923
- Most passionately.
- Little Sanderson, I knew you would!

314
00:29:19,007 --> 00:29:22,427
Make him give a ball!
We'll dance with all the officers.

315
00:29:22,511 --> 00:29:25,930
If Mary would play something,
we could dance now!

316
00:29:26,014 --> 00:29:30,435
Mary, no more dull stuff,
play something jolly. We want to dance!

317
00:29:30,519 --> 00:29:35,440
But there are still two movements.
Mamma! Tell them it isn't fair!

318
00:29:35,524 --> 00:29:40,236
Oh, play a jig, Mary.
No one wants your concertos here.

319
00:29:42,156 --> 00:29:45,867
I fear their taste is not as fine
as yours and mine, Mary,

320
00:29:45,951 --> 00:29:47,827
but let's oblige them this once.

321
00:29:47,911 --> 00:29:51,706
There is no one here
who plays as well as you!

322
00:29:51,790 --> 00:29:55,960
Very well. Though you know it gives me
little pleasure.

323
00:29:56,545 --> 00:30:00,256
- Jane, Mr Bingley, come and dance!
- Not now, Lydia.

324
00:30:00,340 --> 00:30:02,467
(SIR WILLIAM): Capital! Capital!

325
00:30:13,896 --> 00:30:17,482
Mr Bingley continues his attentions
to Jane, Lizzy.

326
00:30:20,486 --> 00:30:25,239
- I'm very happy for her, Charlotte.
- She seems well pleased with him.

327
00:30:25,324 --> 00:30:28,576
If he continues so, she's in a fair way
to be in love with him.

328
00:30:29,411 --> 00:30:32,747
And Mr Bingley?
Do you think he is in love?

329
00:30:33,624 --> 00:30:36,083
It's clear that he likes her very much.

330
00:30:36,168 --> 00:30:38,961
Then she should leave him in no doubt.

331
00:30:39,046 --> 00:30:41,672
She should show more affection
than she feels,

332
00:30:41,757 --> 00:30:44,342
not less, if she is to secure him.

333
00:30:44,426 --> 00:30:49,680
- "Secure him"? Charlotte.
- Yes, she should secure him soon!

334
00:30:50,474 --> 00:30:55,102
Before she is sure of his character
and certain of her own regard for him?

335
00:30:55,187 --> 00:31:00,233
But of course! Happiness in marriage
is entirely a matter of chance.

336
00:31:00,317 --> 00:31:03,361
There will always be vexation and grief.

337
00:31:03,445 --> 00:31:06,572
It's better to know in advance
as little as possible

338
00:31:06,657 --> 00:31:08,699
of the defects of your partner.

339
00:31:08,784 --> 00:31:10,660
Is it not?

340
00:31:10,744 --> 00:31:13,829
You would never act like that yourself!

341
00:31:13,914 --> 00:31:16,082
Well, it seems that Jane will not.

342
00:31:16,166 --> 00:31:18,251
So we must hope that Mr Bingley will.

343
00:31:19,419 --> 00:31:22,547
He gets little encouragement
from his sisters.

344
00:31:22,631 --> 00:31:25,007
(ELIZABETH): Or his friend.

345
00:31:29,471 --> 00:31:33,224
- Mr Darcy looks at you a great deal.
- I can't think why!

346
00:31:33,308 --> 00:31:36,227
Unless to frighten me with his contempt.

347
00:31:36,311 --> 00:31:40,648
I wish he would not come into society.
He only makes people uneasy.

348
00:31:41,817 --> 00:31:45,987
What a charming amusement
for young people this is!

349
00:31:46,071 --> 00:31:48,072
Nothing like dancing!

350
00:31:48,156 --> 00:31:51,200
A refinement of every polished society.

351
00:31:51,285 --> 00:31:54,870
- And every unpolished society.
- Sir?

352
00:31:54,955 --> 00:31:57,582
Every savage can dance.

353
00:31:57,666 --> 00:32:00,167
Oh, yes. Yes, quite.

354
00:32:03,297 --> 00:32:07,800
I should speak to my sister
before she exposes us all to ridicule.

355
00:32:07,884 --> 00:32:10,595
(SIR WILLIAM): Capital! Capital!

356
00:32:12,306 --> 00:32:16,309
Miss Eliza! Why are you not dancing?

357
00:32:16,393 --> 00:32:19,103
Mr Darcy, allow me to present
this young lady

358
00:32:19,187 --> 00:32:22,064
to you as a very desirable partner.

359
00:32:22,149 --> 00:32:26,736
You cannot refuse to dance, I'm sure,
when so much beauty is before you.

360
00:32:26,820 --> 00:32:29,947
Indeed, sir. I have not
the least intention of dancing.

361
00:32:30,032 --> 00:32:34,619
Please don't suppose that I moved
this way in order to beg for a partner.

362
00:32:34,703 --> 00:32:38,331
I would be happy if you would dance
with me, Miss Bennet.

363
00:32:38,415 --> 00:32:39,790
Thank you.

364
00:32:40,334 --> 00:32:43,628
But excuse me,
I... am not inclined to dance.

365
00:32:43,712 --> 00:32:47,465
Why not, when you see Mr Darcy
has no objection?

366
00:32:47,549 --> 00:32:51,135
Although he dislikes the amusement
in general.

367
00:32:51,219 --> 00:32:54,305
- Mr Darcy is all politeness.
- He is!

368
00:32:54,389 --> 00:32:57,642
And why should he not be,
considering the inducement?

369
00:32:57,726 --> 00:33:01,062
Who could object to such a partner?
Eh, Darcy?

370
00:33:01,146 --> 00:33:03,189
I beg you would excuse me.

371
00:33:03,899 --> 00:33:08,277
Well, well...
Oh, Capital, Lydia! Capital!

372
00:33:13,909 --> 00:33:17,912
I believe I can guess your thoughts
at this moment.

373
00:33:18,580 --> 00:33:20,748
I should imagine not.

374
00:33:21,917 --> 00:33:24,669
You are thinking how insupportable
it would be

375
00:33:24,753 --> 00:33:28,506
to spend many evenings
in such tedious company.

376
00:33:28,715 --> 00:33:34,220
My mind was more agreeably engaged.
I've been meditating on the pleasure,

377
00:33:34,304 --> 00:33:39,141
which a pair of fine eyes in the face
of a pretty woman can bestow.

378
00:33:40,352 --> 00:33:46,565
And may one dare ask whose are the eyes
that inspired these reflections?

379
00:33:46,650 --> 00:33:48,776
Miss Elizabeth Bennet's.

380
00:33:52,823 --> 00:33:54,907
Miss Elizabeth Bennet?

381
00:33:57,285 --> 00:34:00,079
I am all astonishment.

382
00:34:06,211 --> 00:34:09,797
From Netherfield! Oh, Jane!
Well, what does it say?

383
00:34:10,173 --> 00:34:15,428
- It is from Miss Bingley.
- Oh, well, that is a good sign, too.

384
00:34:16,304 --> 00:34:17,763
Give it to me.

385
00:34:19,474 --> 00:34:21,726
"My dear friend!"

386
00:34:21,810 --> 00:34:23,227
There now!

387
00:34:24,062 --> 00:34:26,522
"Dine with Louisa and me today..."

388
00:34:26,606 --> 00:34:30,067
La di da, la di da, la di da,
la di da...

389
00:34:30,152 --> 00:34:34,196
"..as the gentlemen are to dine
with the officers." That's unlucky!

390
00:34:34,281 --> 00:34:36,866
Still, you must go and make
what you can of it.

391
00:34:36,950 --> 00:34:41,746
"Yours ever, Caroline Bingley."
Very elegant hand!

392
00:34:41,830 --> 00:34:46,125
- May I have the carriage, father?
- (MOTHER): The carriage! No, indeed.

393
00:34:46,209 --> 00:34:49,295
You must go on horseback,
for it looks like rain.

394
00:34:49,379 --> 00:34:52,631
- Then you will have to stay the night.
- Mother!

395
00:34:53,675 --> 00:34:55,092
Why do you look at me like that?

396
00:34:55,177 --> 00:34:58,554
Would you go there without seeing
Mr Bingley?

397
00:34:58,638 --> 00:35:00,264
No, indeed.

398
00:35:00,348 --> 00:35:03,726
You will go on Nellie.
That will do very well indeed!

399
00:35:19,868 --> 00:35:22,453
There, Lizzy. You see?

400
00:35:22,537 --> 00:35:26,332
It is all exactly as I planned.

401
00:35:42,182 --> 00:35:46,852
Now... let me see
if I've got this right, Jane.

402
00:35:46,937 --> 00:35:51,148
Your mother's sister is named
Mrs Philips?

403
00:35:51,233 --> 00:35:55,736
- Yes.
- And Mr Philips' estate is...?

404
00:35:56,655 --> 00:35:58,572
He lives in Meryton.

405
00:35:59,449 --> 00:36:01,909
He's an attorney.

406
00:36:05,956 --> 00:36:09,583
And your mother's brother lives
in London?

407
00:36:09,668 --> 00:36:13,212
Yes. In Gracechurch Street.

408
00:36:14,005 --> 00:36:18,509
In which part of London
is Gracechurch Street, Jane?

409
00:36:18,593 --> 00:36:20,219
I...

410
00:36:21,429 --> 00:36:23,430
Forgive me, I...

411
00:36:26,893 --> 00:36:29,520
Fosset, get help. Miss Bennet is unwell.

412
00:36:33,608 --> 00:36:38,195
Well, my dear, ifJane should die
of this fever,

413
00:36:38,280 --> 00:36:41,657
it will be comfort to know that
it was all in pursuit of Mr Bingley,

414
00:36:41,741 --> 00:36:43,367
and under your orders.

415
00:36:43,451 --> 00:36:49,081
Oh, nonsense! People do not die
of little trifling colds.

416
00:36:49,165 --> 00:36:53,586
- She will be very well taken care of.
- I think I must go to Netherfield.

417
00:36:53,670 --> 00:36:56,130
(MOTHER): No, there's no call for that!

418
00:36:56,214 --> 00:36:58,799
Jane is very well where she is.

419
00:36:58,884 --> 00:37:01,385
And you know there is nothing
for you there.

420
00:37:02,137 --> 00:37:05,222
Go to Meryton with your sisters
and meet the officers.

421
00:37:05,307 --> 00:37:07,641
Aye, there are more than enough
to go around.

422
00:37:09,185 --> 00:37:12,271
I know that Jane would wish me
to be with her.

423
00:37:12,355 --> 00:37:16,233
I suppose that's a hint for me
to send for the carriage.

424
00:37:16,318 --> 00:37:19,194
No, father, I'd much rather walk.

425
00:37:19,654 --> 00:37:24,450
It's barely three miles to Netherfield
and I'll be back for dinner.

426
00:37:24,534 --> 00:37:29,496
Walk three miles in all that dirt?
You'll not be fit to be seen.

427
00:37:29,581 --> 00:37:33,000
I shall be fit to see Jane,
which is all I want.

428
00:37:33,501 --> 00:37:35,628
I'm quite determined, mother.

429
00:37:35,712 --> 00:37:38,714
I know! Lydia and I will set you
as far as Meryton.

430
00:37:38,798 --> 00:37:43,969
Aye, let's call on Denny early, before
he is dressed. What a shock he will get!

431
00:37:44,054 --> 00:37:45,512
Ammm!

432
00:37:45,597 --> 00:37:48,223
Our life holds few distinctions,
Mrs Bennet,

433
00:37:48,308 --> 00:37:50,768
but I think we may safely boast
that here sit

434
00:37:50,852 --> 00:37:53,103
two of the silliest girls
in the country.

435
00:37:59,861 --> 00:38:04,448
- 'Bye, Lizzy!
- Isn't that Captain Carter? Make haste!

436
00:38:46,908 --> 00:38:49,618
- Miss Bennet.
- Mr Darcy.

437
00:38:52,038 --> 00:38:54,581
I am come to enquire after my sister.

438
00:38:56,334 --> 00:38:59,169
- On foot?
- As you see.

439
00:39:03,425 --> 00:39:06,844
Would you be so kind
as to take me to her?

440
00:39:33,288 --> 00:39:38,667
Well, we must allow her to be
an excellent walker, I suppose.

441
00:39:38,752 --> 00:39:43,213
But her appearance this morning!
She really looked almost wild!

442
00:39:43,298 --> 00:39:45,507
(MISS BINGLEY): I could hardly keep
my countenance!

443
00:39:45,592 --> 00:39:51,722
Scampering about the country because
her sister has a cold! Her hair, Louisa!

444
00:39:51,806 --> 00:39:55,559
Her petticoat!
I hope you saw it, brother.

445
00:39:55,643 --> 00:39:58,312
Six inches deep in mud, I am certain!

446
00:39:58,396 --> 00:40:02,524
It escaped my notice.
I thought she looked remarkably well.

447
00:40:02,609 --> 00:40:07,154
- You observed it, I'm sure, Mr Darcy.
- I did.

448
00:40:07,238 --> 00:40:11,575
I'm inclined to think you wouldn't wish
your sister to make such an exhibition.

449
00:40:11,659 --> 00:40:13,410
Certainly not.

450
00:40:14,287 --> 00:40:20,250
It seems to me to show an abominable
sort of conceited independence.

451
00:40:20,335 --> 00:40:23,378
It shows a pleasing affection
for her sister.

452
00:40:23,463 --> 00:40:30,052
Mr Darcy, has this escapade affected
your admiration for her fine eyes?

453
00:40:30,762 --> 00:40:34,139
Not at all. They were brightened
by the exercise.

454
00:40:37,685 --> 00:40:41,188
ButJane Bennet is a sweet girl!

455
00:40:41,272 --> 00:40:43,941
It's very sad
she has such an unfortunate family,

456
00:40:44,025 --> 00:40:45,609
such low connections.

457
00:40:45,693 --> 00:40:50,781
Their uncle, she told us, is in trade,
and lives in Cheapside!

458
00:40:50,865 --> 00:40:54,785
Perhaps we should call,
when we are next in town.

459
00:40:56,538 --> 00:41:00,541
They'd be as agreeable, had they
uncles enough to fill all Cheapside!

460
00:41:00,625 --> 00:41:05,045
With such connections they have
little chance of marrying well, Bingley.

461
00:41:05,130 --> 00:41:08,006
That is the material point.

462
00:41:12,053 --> 00:41:15,806
Miss Bennet, how does your sister do?
Is she any better?

463
00:41:15,890 --> 00:41:20,060
- I'm afraid that she is quite unwell.
- Let me send for MrJones.

464
00:41:20,145 --> 00:41:24,815
- You must stay until she is recovered.
- I would not wish to inconvenience you.

465
00:41:24,899 --> 00:41:29,278
I won't hear of anything else.
I'll send to Longbourn for your clothes.

466
00:41:29,362 --> 00:41:30,696
You're very kind, sir.

467
00:41:30,780 --> 00:41:34,116
(HURST): Is there any sport today,
or not?

468
00:41:36,327 --> 00:41:38,328
Get in there!

469
00:42:14,574 --> 00:42:18,285
There. Shall I disgrace you,
do you think?

470
00:42:19,579 --> 00:42:24,041
You look very pretty, Lizzy,
as you are well aware.

471
00:42:24,125 --> 00:42:25,918
Oh, Jane.

472
00:42:26,002 --> 00:42:29,171
I'd much rather stay here with you.

473
00:42:29,255 --> 00:42:32,716
The Superior Sisters wish me miles away.

474
00:42:32,800 --> 00:42:37,012
Only your Mr Bingley is civil
and attentive.

475
00:42:37,096 --> 00:42:41,642
- He's not myMr Bingley.
- Oh, I think he is.

476
00:42:42,977 --> 00:42:46,146
Or he very soon will be.

477
00:42:57,742 --> 00:43:01,620
I believe you will find Mr Bingley
is in the drawing room, ma'am.

478
00:43:01,704 --> 00:43:03,580
Thank you.

479
00:43:37,323 --> 00:43:41,535
Mr Darcy, come and advise me.
Mr Hurst carries all before him!

480
00:43:41,619 --> 00:43:43,328
- Ha!
- Ooh!

481
00:43:50,169 --> 00:43:52,963
May I enquire after your sister,
Miss Bennet?

482
00:43:53,256 --> 00:43:56,300
Thank you.
I believe she's a little better.

483
00:43:56,384 --> 00:43:57,676
I am very glad to hear it.

484
00:43:58,386 --> 00:44:02,014
- Mr Hurst, I'm quite undone!
- (HURST): Should have played the deuce.

485
00:44:02,140 --> 00:44:05,183
(MISS BINGLEY): He's undone us all,
Mr Darcy!

486
00:44:06,519 --> 00:44:10,731
- Will you join us, Miss Bennet?
- I thank you, no.

487
00:44:10,815 --> 00:44:14,318
You prefer reading to cards? Singular!

488
00:44:14,402 --> 00:44:17,738
Miss Bennet despises cards.
She's a great reader

489
00:44:17,822 --> 00:44:20,449
and has no pleasure in anything else.

490
00:44:21,242 --> 00:44:24,328
I deserve neither such praise
nor such censure.

491
00:44:24,412 --> 00:44:28,623
I am not a great reader
and take pleasure in many things.

492
00:44:30,376 --> 00:44:34,004
And what do you do so secretly, sir?

493
00:44:37,342 --> 00:44:40,677
It's no secret.
I'm writing to my sister.

494
00:44:40,762 --> 00:44:44,306
(MISS BINGLEY): Dear Georgiana!
I long to see her!

495
00:44:44,390 --> 00:44:48,769
Is she much grown since the Spring?
Is she as tall as me?

496
00:44:50,772 --> 00:44:55,275
She's now about Miss Elizabeth
Bennet's height, or a little taller.

497
00:44:55,360 --> 00:45:00,655
And so accomplished! Her performance
at the pianoforte is exquisite!

498
00:45:00,740 --> 00:45:04,409
- Do you play, Miss Bennet?
- Aye, but very ill indeed.

499
00:45:04,494 --> 00:45:08,872
All young ladies are accomplished!
They sing, they draw, they dance,

500
00:45:08,956 --> 00:45:13,835
speak French and German, cover screens,
and I know not what!

501
00:45:13,920 --> 00:45:17,130
Not half a dozen would satisfy me
as accomplished.

502
00:45:17,215 --> 00:45:21,259
(MISS BINGLEY): Certainly! No woman
can be esteemed accomplished,

503
00:45:21,344 --> 00:45:24,888
who does not also possess a certain
something in her air,

504
00:45:24,972 --> 00:45:27,891
in the manner of walking,
in the tone of her voice,

505
00:45:27,975 --> 00:45:30,644
her address and expressions.

506
00:45:30,728 --> 00:45:34,564
(DARCY): And to this she must yet add
something more substantial,

507
00:45:34,649 --> 00:45:38,110
in the improvement of her mind
by extensive reading.

508
00:45:39,320 --> 00:45:44,241
I'm no longer surprised at you knowing
only six accomplished women.

509
00:45:44,325 --> 00:45:46,535
I wonder at your knowing any.

510
00:45:46,786 --> 00:45:49,871
(MRS HURST): You're severe upon
your sex, Miss Bennet.

511
00:45:50,832 --> 00:45:52,249
(ELIZABETH): I must speak as I find.

512
00:45:52,333 --> 00:45:57,379
Perhaps you haven't had the advantage
of moving in society enough.

513
00:45:57,463 --> 00:46:01,925
There are many very accomplished
young ladies amongst our acquaintance.

514
00:46:02,009 --> 00:46:06,805
(HURST): Come, come! This is a fine
way to play cards! You're all light!

515
00:46:14,355 --> 00:46:17,774
Look, girls! Is it not a fair prospect?

516
00:46:29,454 --> 00:46:34,082
And now the mother! Are we to be invaded
by every Bennet in the country?

517
00:46:34,167 --> 00:46:36,751
It's too much to be borne!

518
00:46:42,633 --> 00:46:47,471
Mrs Bennet! Welcome! I hope you don't
find Miss Bennet worse than expected.

519
00:46:47,555 --> 00:46:52,225
Indeed I do, sir! She's very ill indeed,
and suffers a vast deal,

520
00:46:52,310 --> 00:46:54,478
though with the greatest patience
in the world,

521
00:46:54,562 --> 00:46:57,314
for she has the sweetest temper.

522
00:46:57,398 --> 00:47:00,525
But she is much too ill to be moved.

523
00:47:00,610 --> 00:47:03,987
We must trespass a little longer
on your kindness.

524
00:47:04,614 --> 00:47:06,323
But of course!

525
00:47:06,407 --> 00:47:10,494
Miss Bennet will receive every possible
attention, I assure you.

526
00:47:10,620 --> 00:47:13,538
You are very good.

527
00:47:13,623 --> 00:47:17,375
Well, you have a sweet room here!

528
00:47:17,460 --> 00:47:21,171
I think you will never want
to leave Netherfield.

529
00:47:21,255 --> 00:47:23,840
I'd be happy to live
in the country forever.

530
00:47:23,925 --> 00:47:25,217
Wouldn't you, Darcy?

531
00:47:25,885 --> 00:47:30,680
You would? You don't find the society
somewhat confined and unvarying?

532
00:47:30,765 --> 00:47:34,768
Confined and unvarying?
Indeed it is not, sir!

533
00:47:35,228 --> 00:47:37,312
The country is a vast deal pleasanter
than town,

534
00:47:37,396 --> 00:47:40,232
whatever you may say about it!

535
00:47:41,901 --> 00:47:44,819
Mamma, you mistake Mr Darcy's meaning.

536
00:47:44,904 --> 00:47:48,406
Do I? He seems to think the country
nothing at all!

537
00:47:48,491 --> 00:47:50,784
- Mamma.
- Confined, unvarying!

538
00:47:50,868 --> 00:47:54,829
I would have him know
we dine with 24 families!

539
00:47:54,914 --> 00:47:58,208
(GIGGLES)

540
00:48:02,630 --> 00:48:06,800
Mamma? Have you seen Charlotte Lucas
since I came away?

541
00:48:06,926 --> 00:48:09,594
Yes, she called yesterday
with Sir William.

542
00:48:09,679 --> 00:48:12,055
What an agreeable man he is!

543
00:48:12,139 --> 00:48:14,683
That is my idea of good breeding.

544
00:48:14,767 --> 00:48:17,060
Those persons who fancy themselves

545
00:48:17,144 --> 00:48:19,813
very important,
and never open their mouths,

546
00:48:19,981 --> 00:48:22,399
quite mistake the matter.

547
00:48:23,901 --> 00:48:27,529
Mr Bingley, did you not promise a ball
when you were settled here?

548
00:48:27,613 --> 00:48:30,615
It will be a scandal if you don't
keep your word.

549
00:48:30,700 --> 00:48:32,951
I am perfectly ready to keep
my engagement.

550
00:48:33,035 --> 00:48:34,744
When your sister is recovered,

551
00:48:34,829 --> 00:48:37,330
you shall name the day of the ball,
if you please.

552
00:48:38,624 --> 00:48:42,502
There, now, Lydia!
That's a fair promise for you!

553
00:48:42,587 --> 00:48:45,005
That's generosity for you!

554
00:48:47,300 --> 00:48:51,177
That's what I call
gentlemanly behaviour!

555
00:50:43,916 --> 00:50:45,542
Miss Eliza Bennet.

556
00:50:45,626 --> 00:50:47,794
Let me persuade you to follow my example

557
00:50:47,878 --> 00:50:51,131
and take a turn about the room.
It's so refreshing!

558
00:51:03,310 --> 00:51:05,979
Will you not join us, Mr Darcy?

559
00:51:06,939 --> 00:51:10,900
- That would defeat the object.
- What do you mean, sir?

560
00:51:10,985 --> 00:51:12,485
What can he mean?

561
00:51:12,570 --> 00:51:15,071
I think we would do better
not to enquire.

562
00:51:15,156 --> 00:51:18,241
Nay, we insist on knowing
your meaning, sir!

563
00:51:19,326 --> 00:51:21,870
That your figures are to best advantage
when walking,

564
00:51:21,954 --> 00:51:24,956
and that I might best admire them
from here.

565
00:51:25,583 --> 00:51:28,251
Shocking! Abominable reply!

566
00:51:28,335 --> 00:51:34,174
- How shall we punish him, Miss Eliza?
- Nothing so easy. Tease him.

567
00:51:35,092 --> 00:51:38,636
- Laugh at him.
- Laugh at Mr Darcy?

568
00:51:39,555 --> 00:51:41,473
Impossible!

569
00:51:41,557 --> 00:51:45,643
- He is a man without fault.
- Is he indeed?

570
00:51:46,771 --> 00:51:48,813
A man without fault?

571
00:51:49,607 --> 00:51:52,358
That is not possible for anyone.

572
00:51:53,027 --> 00:51:57,489
But it has been my study to avoid
those weaknesses which expose ridicule.

573
00:51:58,699 --> 00:52:02,827
Such as vanity, perhaps, and pride?

574
00:52:05,998 --> 00:52:07,999
Yes, vanity is a weakness indeed.

575
00:52:09,376 --> 00:52:10,794
(DARCY): But pride...

576
00:52:12,171 --> 00:52:16,925
Where there is a superiority of mind,
pride will always be under regulation.

577
00:52:19,220 --> 00:52:22,597
I have faults, but I hope they're not
of understanding.

578
00:52:23,808 --> 00:52:25,850
My temper I cannot vouch for.

579
00:52:29,814 --> 00:52:32,482
It might be called resentful.

580
00:52:32,566 --> 00:52:35,360
My good opinion, once lost,
is lost forever.

581
00:52:35,903 --> 00:52:40,740
That is a failing indeed,
but I cannot laugh at it.

582
00:52:42,993 --> 00:52:46,496
I believe every disposition
has a tendency to some evil.

583
00:52:46,956 --> 00:52:49,582
Your defect is a propensity
to hate everyone.

584
00:52:49,667 --> 00:52:52,043
Yours is wilfully to misunderstand them.

585
00:52:52,127 --> 00:52:53,461
Some music?

586
00:53:13,315 --> 00:53:16,150
Give your parents
my warmest salutations.

587
00:53:16,235 --> 00:53:20,238
Your father is most welcome to shoot
with us at any time convenient.

588
00:53:20,322 --> 00:53:22,740
Thank you, sir. You are very kind.

589
00:53:24,285 --> 00:53:28,037
Goodbye.

590
00:53:32,209 --> 00:53:34,460
Drive on, Rossiter.

591
00:53:44,263 --> 00:53:49,267
(MISS BINGLEY): How pleasant it is
to have one's house to oneself again!

592
00:53:51,562 --> 00:53:54,105
But I fear Mr Darcy is mourning the loss

593
00:53:54,189 --> 00:53:58,568
of Miss Eliza Bennet's pert opinions
and fine eyes.

594
00:54:00,613 --> 00:54:03,489
Quite the contrary, I assure you.

595
00:54:10,581 --> 00:54:12,707
(ELIZABETH): Oh, Jane!

596
00:54:14,001 --> 00:54:17,921
I'm sorry to say it, but notwithstanding
your excellent Mr Bingley,

597
00:54:18,005 --> 00:00:00,-001
I've never been so happy
to leave a place in my life!

