I dunno, man.
I mean, I'm kinda sad.
Them towers be home to me.
You gonna cry over
a housing project, now?
Man, they shoulda blew them motherfuckers up
a long time ago, you ask me.
Man, it ain't all been bad.
I mean, I been seen some shit happen up
in them towers it still make me smile, yo.
A few moments from now,
the Franklin Terrace towers behind me,
which sadly came to represent
some of the city's most entrenched problems,
will be gone.
Ya'll talkin' about steel
and concrete, man.
- Steel and fucking concrete.
- Man, I'm talkin' about people.
Memories an' shit.
Ain't the same.
Look, they gonna tear this building down,
they gonna build some new shit.
But people?
They don't give
a fuck about people.
You are very soon
going to see low
and moderately priced houses
built in their place.
My cousins used
to live in 2-2-1.
- I used to be up in there all the time.
- Ma who you tellin'?
I caught my first
pussy up in there.
The girl Chantay.
Man, why didn't you
say something before?
They probably wouldn't be
tearin' this tower down now.
They gonna put a big-ass
sign in front sayin'
"here's where Malik Carr
first got his dick wet".
You know what I'm sayin'.
Poot, you can be takin' pictures,
tourists takin' pictures an' shit,
souvenirs of your dick
about this size.
He ain't funny, yo,
he just jealous.
What? Jealous of that?
You crazy, Chantay?
Man, the mention of that
bitch make my dick burn.
Yo, ain't no bad pussy, fool.
Yeah, that's what they keep tellin'
your ass down at the clinic, man.
Keep that shit up.
You ever see this motherfucker
when he walkin' down to the clinic burnt?
Poot be like this.
He looks like a backward
ass cowboy an' shit.
Instead of like this.
Only he walkin' like this.
Dick lookin' like
a fried chicken wing.
Mistakes have been made.
And we will learn
from those mistakes.
Reform is not just a watchword
with my administration, unh-huh,
no, it's a philosophy.
Shit, no matter how many
times you get burnt, man,
you just keep on
doin' the same.
Nigger do not learn.
Now, what do you say, huh?
Are you ready
for a new Baltimore?
Shit gonna be off
the hook, yo.
Man, my whole life been
around them towers, you know.
I mean I feel.
Shit, I feel like
I don't got no home now.
Housing just moved your mama
up off Poplar Prove, didn't they?
You ain't homeless,
nigga, you got a home.
Shit, you just damn
near outta work is all.
What you mean?
I mean look all over the city,
even out in the county,
you had people, coke or dope,
24/7, where was it they go?
Man, look, you live in the
projects, you ain't shit.
But you sling product there.
You got the game
by the ass, man.
Shit.
Now these downtown,
suit-wearin' ass bitches
just snatched up the best
territory in the city from y'all.
You wanna cry over
some shit, cry over that.
Alright, everyone,
count with me.
Ten
nine
eight
seven
six
five
four
three
two
one!
Oh shit.
Time After Time
Fuck.
I just stepped
in dogshit, man.
You hope.
Is it Cheese,
can you see him?
Yo, where he at?
Who you mean?
Cheese, I'm lookin'
for Cheese, man.
Nigga, you ain't supposed to be
droppin' names an' shit.
Ain't you got no sense?
I ain't say shit
about shit, man.
I'm jus' lookin'
to get together with the man.
Need to see him
about nuthin' at all.
So he be
where he be, fool.
Is he at the place
that we was at?
'Cause I'm lookin' to,
you know, saddle up
and then put another bat
on this motherfucker.
He need to feel
with me today,
or I'ma take it to someone
who can handle them, man.
- It's nothin' you let him know.
- A-ight.
"Saddle up an' put another
bat on the motherfucker?"
"Settle" up
and put another "bet".
But what was that last part?
Man said, "he need
to deal with me today
or I'ma take it to
someone who can handle them. "
Girl, you do have an ear.
He lookin'
to get with him.
A-ight.
- Same thing as before?
- Same thing I tell 'em.
A-ight.
What'r you seeing?
Call comes in
to Cheese's number two,
he whispers in the man's
ear and off they go.
Yeah.
Nothing to the call here.
Figured that.
These guys come correct.
The phones only go so far,
above that, it's all done
as a face-to-face meet.
Three months and we've
yet to hear his voice.
And Herc takes the alley
to cut that off from Calhoun.
So, me an' Truck go up the wrong
way on Stricker Street?
You gotta badge, remember?
And we're doing
the same one block over.
So they can't go to ground
in that block neither.
Now the thing is when we jump
out on these little cocksuckers,
there'll be
a designated runner.
Who's gonna sky up just so
we get to chase his ass.
But fuck him.
We let him go and jack every
other motherfucker who stays.
Let's mount up.
Carv.
He's a complicated man.
And the only one who
understands him is his woman.
Seek therapy.
Narcos! Back off!
See your hands.
Against the wall.
Hands up. Get your hands up.
Get your hands up against the wall.
There he goes.
Later son, step light!
Yo, was that the stash?
Fuck.
Let's go, let's go,
cut him off at Stricker!
I've got Calhoun.
Where you at?
Lost him.
Rear Stricker 800 block.
Clear on Riggs.
He just went across Stricker
in an alley headed for Gilmore.
Fuck.
We have rabbit in the alleys
near Gilmore and Riggs.
How bout some back up?
Roger that.
Dozerman, what's your 20?
Hey, Doze,
where you at, man?
He's across Stricker,
definitely.
Everybody to Lambert's 20.
Who's the man who would risk
his neck for his brother man?
He went to ground
in this block, man.
Hey, listen to me you little
fuckin' piece of shit!
I'ma tell you one thing,
and one thing only
about the Western boys
you are playing with!
We do not lose!
And we do not forget!
And we do not give up!
Ever!
So I'm only going
to say this one time:
If you march your ass
out here right now
and put the bracelets on,
we will not kick
the living shit out of you!
But if you make us go
into them weeds for you,
or if you make us come back
out here tomorrow night,
catch you on a corner.
I swear to fucking Christ
we will beat you longer
and harder than you
beat your own dick!
'Cause you do not
get to win, shitbird!
We do!
With these towers down,
we need to take
the rest of them low-rises
an' all them Fayette
Street corners.
Take 'em?
Take 'em how, Mr. Bodie?
Ya say fuck it and take 'em.
Nigga, you ain't
got the floor.
The chair don't
recognize your ass.
Take 'em how?
I dunno, just...
let them Fayette
niggers know,
you know,
we serious, right?
You know, get or get got.
Yeah, yeah, like you did
on McCulloh Street last year?
Snatch the real estate,
load up,
and just wait for some
shit to happen, right?
Naw, man, we done worryin'
about territory, man.
What corner we got,
what project?
Game ain't about that no more.
It's about product.
Yeah.
And we got the best
goddamn product
so we gonna sell no matter
where we are, right?
Product, motherfuckers.
Product.
Chair recognize Slim Charles.
Chair, our people got to stand
somewhere, don't it?
I mean, all the product
in the world don't mean nothin'
if you constantly
getting your ass whooped
for standin' on another
fool's corner.
A- ight.
We had six of the towers
of the Terrace right,
all running 24/7,
but three of those we had
to give to Prop Joe's people
to upgrade the package
that we was
puttin' out there, right?
Now how much you think
we lost in the deal?
Alright, the answer
is we made more.
Half the real estate,
twice the product.
And our profit went up
like eight, nine percent.
Yo, get it straight.
Your territory ain't gonna mean
shit if your product's weak.
Go ahead and ask
them motherfuckers
tryin' to sell them Ford Tempos
an' you got niggas ridin' around
in Japanese and German cars
in America all day.
Territory ain't shit.
Especially when you consider
it's the fight
for the territory
that be bringin' the bodies.
And the bodies that
bring the police.
Yeah, but how
we gonna stand...
Yo, chair ain't
recognize your ass, man.
- How we gonna stand on some...
- Come on, man.
How we gonna stand on some
corner that's not ours?
Well, we got
the best product, right?
So the chances are,
we gonna be able to bring in
the competition by offering the
re-up with us from our package.
Feel me?
Everybody makin' money,
sharing the real estate.
Slim Charles?
What if they don't
cop our re-up though?
Well, I'ma worry about
that when it happen.
Until then, Mr. Charles,
we gonna handle this shit
like businessmen.
Sell the shit,
make the profit and later
for that gangster bullshit.
Yeah?
Do the chair
know we gonna look
like some punk-ass
bitches out there?
Motherfucker, I will punk
your ass for sayin' such shit!
- Yo, String.
- What?!
Poot did have the floor, man.
Shut the fuck up, man!
This nigga too ignorant
to have the fuckin' floor.
Y'all niggas need to start
lookin' at the world
in a new fucking light.
Start thinkin' about this shit
like some grown fucking men,
not some niggas
off the fuckin' corner.
You heard me?
Adjourn your asses.
Y'all look like shit.
We been stuck in that
vacant since before dawn.
How should we look?
Proud to know you, Detective.
Nice look on you.
Dress for success.
I watched that motherfucker
Cheese take re-ups,
move weight all day
and not once did he go
near a fucking telephone.
Closest it comes
is a call to a hanger-on's
cellphone 10 feet away.
Which brings me back
to what I was just discussing
with the Lieutenant.
So far, we've been up
on some of these cellphones
for nearly six months,
the only drug talk we have
is from street-level small fry.
So, the feeling is
that maybe two weeks from now,
we don't go back to the court
for another extension.
We charge what we have,
we try to roll someone up
at Cheese or one of Joe's
other lieutenants.
Are you kidding?
We don't have
a case worth making yet.
And at this rate,
we never will.
For chrissake.
As a plan on paper
it was a good one:
We came out of
the port investigation
with good phone numbers
for some of Prop Joe's people
and the P.C. To get up
on those phones.
I guarantee if we can push
this thing a level or two
above the street we're gonna
start seeing Prop Joe himself.
We start seeing Joe,
we're gonna see Stringer.
I can't ask for more time
on a wire that's going nowhere.
Either we figure a way
to punch through the wall,
or we let it go.
- Baker.
- Yes, Sir.
So you must be Castor.
Yes, Sir.
Officer Aaron Castor.
You any kin
to Lloyd Castor?
Yes, Sir, that's my uncle.
Good police.
Do you know where you are?
You too. Where are you?
The Western, Major?
Right this very goddamn second
you're getting your
hindparts kicked
and you're on the horn
screaming for help.
And you got your backup
lookin' all over the place,
'cause you don't know
where the fuck you are.
And that means I got
to explain to your next of kin
how you went and got
yourselves killed on my watch.
Sir, we're at 1034 North Mount,
first floor rear.
Good.
Now which way's north?
Point.
That's east.
Now, don't you think
if you're in a foot pursuit,
it might help
your backup to know
what direction
you're running?
Even numbers tell you
north and west,
odd, south and east.
Compasses.
'Til you learn that much,
you carry one.
Welcome to the Western.
Gentlemen?
Scuff yourselves up a little.
And learn the stare.
Hey Carv, where you at?
I'm at a desk outside
the roll call room
on the first floor of
1034 North Mount.
And my feet
are facing west
and my dick is
pointing south, southwest.
Bunny Colvin's been
giving that speech
as long as you guys
been sucking air.
Where you at, shitbird?
You're in handcuffs,
in my house,
lookin' stupid, ain't you?
Fleeing and eluding?
Do we have
a drug charge here?
Loitering in a designated
drug-free zone.
Let me re-phrase.
Do we have drugs?
He raised up when we hit his
corner and he grabbed this bag.
We pursued
and recovered the bag.
But no drugs.
An' they whipped my ass.
The Western District way.
So, what do we learn?
Using half my district,
canine and the copter
to bring a 14-year-old
to bay, what did we learn?
That you can't raise up
and run from a drug corner
in sector one without
my boot finding your ass.
Right?
I got it, I got it, I got it.
Got it, got it, got it.
Cast-iron. 20 at least.
It be better if it was copper.
Be better if it was copper.
It be better if it was gold.
But you know you got to
take life as it goes along,
you know?
Oh shit, oh shit.
- What's wrong with you!?
- Sorry.
You past sorry.
Chill, chill.
We don't mean this, man.
You think you fucked up now.
S'up?
Look what they
did to my ride.
Do it or don't.
But I got someplace to be.
Thank you for your kindness.
Y'all got to
pay something, anything!
Be a principle here.
If we had a dime,
you would have a dime.
We a little insufficient
right now, okay?
We on our way
to the metal man.
We'll come back and pay for
everything I promise you.
Hey, hey, after this junk, man,
we gotta rolpast K-Mart.
Definitely.
One last question,
Commissioner.
Looking back over
the past couple months,
if I read the felony
breakdowns correctly,
you've been seeing
an uptick in shootings
and serious assaults in
the Eastern District especially.
Can we assume that you're
already addressing this?
Let me throw
that over to Bill.
As Deputy for Operations,
I'm sure he's got
a handle on our response.
I do indeed.
In answer to your question,
Councilman,
I can assure you that we put
additional tactical teams
on a seven-to-three shift
in every eastern sector.
Additionally, we've put
the district flex squad
on a seven-to-three shift
being as those are the hours
when we're seeing a spike
in aggravated assaults.
Thank you, Deputy.
Anything else for
these esteemed constables?
No?
Okay, then I guess
I'll see you all tomorrow night
for the quarterly budget review.
Erv, hey, you don't mind,
I'd like to get with
you about a couple things.
Can we get lunch?
Glad to, Mr. Chairman.
How 'bout Werner's
in half hour?
Half hour. Good.
- You see Watkins in the back?
- Yeah.
Who's that skirt with him?
That's him there
in the orange?
That's Drac.
Our last best hope.
The talkingest motherfucker
I ever heard on a wiretap.
Listen.
No, no, the other thing.
The other thing, nigga.
You talkin' about him.
No, her, I mean her.
Oh.
Cocaine, nigga,
you feel me now?
Goddamn, you ignorant.
When was the last time
you heard that on a wire?
Shame he doesn't report
to anyone who matters.
Right now, Drac's reups
are with Lavell Manns,
he's got those corners
over on Preston and Bond.
And is pretty close
to selling us weight.
No shit.
Sydnor's been working toward him
for a couple of months now.
Lavell's a soldier.
He's not gonna
roll up on Prop Joe.
That's true.
But if we take him off
with a hand-to-hand,
they gotta promote
someone to replace him.
Why Drac?
One thing about our boy?
That's Prop Joe's nephew.
On his momma's side.
20 and two.
Y'all know you
ain't got pants?
And there's Dominic
standing in line,
and when he finally
gets up to meet the President,
who's looking the other way,
Dominic reaches
around behind Carter,
grabs his belt, yanks it up...
secret service musta shit.
He says, "hey, Mister
President, remember me?"
And Carter,
actually remembers,
"sure, Dominic Dipietro
from Baltimore,
on the campaign trail".
And Dominic
doesn't miss a beat.
He puts a finger in Jimmy
Carter's face and says,
"so where's that money you
promised me three years ago
to fix up my streets
and alleys?"
Unbelievable.
That's nothing.
After losing to Reagan,
Carter comes back here
to speak at a Jefferson-Jackson
dinner or something,
and Dominic's
ushered up to him.
Carter asks about
his health and Dominic says:
"You sonofabitch,
I'm still waiting on that money
for my streets and alleys".
- Come on.
- No shit.
Carter's just grinning
through those big teeth,
some guy grabs Dominic's arm,
and off he goes.
Guy says, "christ, Dominic,
you just called
"the President of
the United States an S.O.B."
He shrugs he says, "fuck 'im,
I don't need him. He lost. "
That's good. That is good.
And that is from whence I come,
proud son of the fighting
first district.
But the truth is...
I don't wanna be just another
muldoon like Dominic Dipietro,
warming the backbench.
Not with the way things
are right now in the city.
We're losing 10, 12,000
residents a year
and when you ask 'em why
they're moving to the county,
you know what they say?
Schools.
And crime.
Schools and crime
and there goes our tax base
right across the line.
And the Mayor's acting
like a 10% bump
in the murder rate
is business as usual.
Check, please?
And you know what?
If you were smart, you'd come
to me when the Mayor shorts you.
On hiring, on equipment,
on overtime, on cars.
You get the shit end
of the stick,
you come to me.
Not publicly.
I know you can't cross
the Mayor publicly.
But back door, you come to me
and I can use that subcommittee
to give you what you need.
Thanks.
Kind offer.
Erv, I can help you
and we can turn this thing...
but long ago, when I was just
starting out in the department
I had the good fortune
to be taught
a little something
about chain of command.
And right now,
in my capacity as
Acting Commissioner,
I report to Mayor Royce.
I got your coffee.
Leave a tip if you want.
So, what do you need
to see me for?
Gettin' out tomorrow, right?
Yeah.
He probably
tryin' to reach out.
What you
gonna do first?
Huh?
Tomorrow, what you gonna do?
I dunno.
I know what be first.
You don't know?
Time out.
Back in.
Short-timer.
You only got
the one day left, huh.
You done the one,
just got to do the other.
Like they say...
you only do two days.
- It's the day you go in.
- The day you come out.
I don't know, I did 14 years.
Yeah, well,
you know you did you
a little stretch there, true.
But you still
a soldier, right?
You know them towers
came down now, huh?
The Terrace,
the Murphy homes.
All that shit is gone, man.
A lot of things are different
now since you been up in here.
You'll see.
Lotta changes.
Yeah, no doubt.
But I mean you know, shit,
some things they
stay the same, man.
I mean,
the game's the game.
And the thing is,
since the towers gone,
I'm gonna need to take
my thing to some new places.
Feel me?
You know I'ma be home
soon enough, right?
First parole hearing, I'm out.
For real.
Shit is fixed right.
I come home.
Shit, there's gonna be
a little hell to be paid.
You know, what I mean?
A good soldier ain't
gonna lack for work.
Take that number, man.
When you out, you call.
We'll hook you up,
man, no problem.
Like a coming-home
gift, a-ight.
Call it.
Joint mighta broke him.
Boss, you talkin' about
a homey walked up
an' shot Elijah Davis
in broad daylight
at Pennsie and Gold,
then picked up the phone,
dialed 9-1-1, told the police,
"I just shot a nigger,
come get him".
And do they break him?
Naw.
Look we had the 20, you know,
we had to go buy some pants,
so if you just take
this short money,
we get back at you
tomorrow, man.
We get you on the comeback.
He want two for 16.
Tell him to get two.
This young motherfucker.
Naw.
You see we
a little short now,
but tomorrow, I be right
back here with the four.
Joey said "no".
Fucking guy, man.
At these prices, I can't
afford more phone surveillance.
I'm aware of that
and right now,
the plan is to go for a
hand-to-hand on one lieutenant
a couple rungs down
from Proposition Joe.
And then roll
the lieutenant up?
We don't think he'll
have much roll to him.
Joe's people are
pretty schooled.
The hope is that they promote
this mid-level dealer
who's a fool to replace him.
Name a Drac.
We're on his cellphone,
if he gets promoted,
maybe he talks to Joe
or Joe's top people.
We get that far, maybe
we start to see Stringer Bell.
What makes you think they'll
promote the wrong man?
We do it all the time.
Look, speaking of promotions,
I sent yours over to the hall.
As promised.
And?
The Mayor's holding it up.
My understanding is
he wants to know
what your wife is doing.
- My wife?
- Yeah.
There's a rumor
that she's going to
take a run at
a council seat,
maybe try to knock off
Eunetta Perkins.
That's my wife's business.
Yes, it is.
But the Mayor counts
Eunetta as an ally.
Our deal was
for a permanent unit
and the next vacancy
for major.
You got your unit and I sent
your name over to the hall.
I kept my word.
But the Mayor,
he may want to know
who his friends are
before he makes
a new commander.
Where'd she say
she was gonna be at?
Near the dugout, first-base side.
She'll turn up.
When she supposed
to bring 'em over to you?
Middle of the fourth.
Dad, can I have a hotdog?
Yeah, as soon as
the guy comes around.
Speaking of which,
where's the beer man?
There they are.
Oh, damn,
they got great seats.
Ah, hell.
What?
The guy on her left, the suit.
Just a friend.
Nah, he's in the cake.
Who goes to
an Orioles game in a suit,
spends half the time
on a his cellphone?
Downtown lawyer.
Someone wealthy like that.
Wish we had more of it.
Long way to go
for half a shot.
We'll do better
tomorrow, Bubs.
What kinda dope fiend
be talkin' about tomorrow?
Tomorrow ain't shit.
Today, Johnny.
Today I hunted down
all that metal,
lugged it around like a dog,
and nearly got kilt
over a scratch of metal
so that I had to
beg for my life.
Lost my trousers, man.
My fuckin' trousers.
And then I'm beggin'
again for half a shot.
Swear to god, man,
I'm not even high.
We just missed
a foul pop.
Yeah?
Our seats are great.
We're practically
on the field.
Yeah my friend, Dennis,
he gets company seats
every now and then.
Where are you sitting?
Mezzanine. Come on.
- Aw...
- No, no, you guys go.
Your dad hasn't
seen you all week.
Now, don't take
their jackets off
'cause Sean's just
getting over a cold. Okay?
Jimmy, right?
Dennis Kerpelman.
Great kids.
Anyway, nice meeting you.
You want anything
from the stand?
No, thank you.
Don't stay 'til the last inning
'cause it's a school night.
Bye.
You got spatter going in
two different directions,
just off the curb.
Yeah.
Shooting on the West Side.
Another one?
Christ, where?
North and Polanski,
Cole's up.
Cole's working
a cutting off Belvedere.
Call Crutchfield
and see if he's back
from the Westport scene.
Crutchfield.
If not, call Bunk at home.
It's his off day.
Fuck his off-day.
I love this town.
Maz's kinda quick
to yank a pitcher, ain't he?
I'm thinking
of becoming a woman.
Office.
Yeah.
I'm at the ball game.
The ball game.
Yeah, what about Cole?
Call him.
Ah, shit.
Alright.
Can you believe this?
They caught five tonight,
they're telling me I gotta
come in on my day off.
Five?
City's jumpin' bad, man.
Hey, listen,
- I gotta go to work, alright?
- Alright.
Mr. Jimmy's gonna...
He's gonna take you home.
You're on your own, partner.
Mee-maw.
And Ertman Avenue?
No ballistic information.
Are you sure?
Take your time, Major.
Can you believe
that cocksucker Carcetti?
Thinkin' I'm talkin'
out of school.
Any day now, Marvin.
What can a white
councilman give me
that a black mayor can't?
No, you played it right.
It was a 38 recorded
on Ertman Avenue, Sir.
So what you are
in effect saying, Major,
is rather than lookin'
at this cluster of robberies
you had along
Monument Street,
you chose to investigate
each using separate personnel.
No, Sir.
Three of those cases
were commercial robberies
so we sent those
downtown to C.I.D.
My people had responsibility.
Goddamnit, Marvin,
did you just invoke the word
responsibility to explain why
you didn't get on
top of this shit?
Did you just do that?
I don't think you know
what the word means
when I look at
the 24s and plainly see
that some 38 caliber asshole
is raping your entire district.
All the way from Greenmount
to fucking Edison Highway.
It's policing like that
makes it possible for us
to get hit with
five fucking homicides
in a single fucking
night people.
Poor fucking Marvin.
Better him than us, right?
Based on your testimony,
the buy itself will be
enough to charge.
But you get him saying
something on tape,
it's even better.
Are you sure this guy wants
to be selling you weight?
We don't want to be forcing this.
I been strokin' this guy
for two months, man.
That's not what
he asked you.
The guy is ripe
and ready, Kima.
It ain't no thing.
They're about ready.
You livin' out
of the office, Cedric?
Alright. Drac is depending
on you people.
Mount up.
Find your way home.
Look a little light to be
an ounce, don't you think?
Naw, man,
ain't nuthin' light.
It just settled is all.
Weight, man, if it
does what it should,
I'ma come back to you
for three, maybe four a week.
That could work.
We good then.
We good.
That's it.
Take 'em down.
- Somebody snitchin'.
- Shut the fuck up!
Let's go, Lavell.
This Cutty.
Told I could call for help.
What 'bout the oxbow?
The oxbow
on Laurens, at Fulton.
A- ight.
I'm sayin', they caught 'em
with a whole ounce.
Might not be no bail
for that much weight.
They might just take it federal,
run wild on they ass.
And you know Joey's gotta give
Lavell's corner to someone right?
Might be my turn.
Our boy won't shut up.
Caroline, you say it like
it's a bad thing.
Let's just hope we're listening
to a candidate for elevation.
I heard about you, man.
I hear your name
used to ring out.
You got somethin' for me?
You see where Shorty
sittin' right there,
you find a little help.
But when you ready, we got some
real work for ya, a-ight?
Jesus.
Hey, how you doing?
Okay.
We were just talking about you.
Really?
You know Denise
from the sorority.
Charles of course.
- Always a pleasure Lieutenant.
- Good to see you.
And I don't think you've
ever met Delegate Watkins.
- How do you do?
- Nice to meet you.
We were saying you fill out
a lieutenant's uniform nicely.
Makes an impression
on the campaign lit.
That matters?
Marla's a new face taking
on a longtime incumbent.
Everything matters, I'm afraid.
Well, anything
I can do to help.
I'll, um...
get out of the way
and leave you all to it.
Marla, I have to tell you
that your photo with Cedric
works really well
on the mailing.
Yeah.
I sure hope he knows
what he's in for
because it's going to be
a long race for the both of you.
speaking of which,
you've got to make some...
Jesus, who called the media?
Naw, you think
the man might respect
my shit enough
to let me step up,
but it ain't
even go like that.
Why not?
He gonna give Lavell's corners
to that off-brand nigga Cheese.
An' you know what?
Joe my uncle an' shit.
I mean, I'm kin to
the fat motherfucker.
That idiot worked for us he'd
be a deputy commissioner by now.
Ain't no luck
at all to this case.
And how in all good
conscience can I,
as chairman
of this subcommittee,
authorize anymore above-the-line
overtime.
When it's clear enough
from the data in front of me
that that money is not going
to go to line officers
or working detectives.
But is being to be paying
for drivers and clerical
and Jesus look at this.
So that two colonels
and three majors can attend
a community policing
seminar in Miami, Florida?
Mr. Chairman.
What does South Beach
have to teach this department
about making Baltimore
a safer place, Commissioner?
I have no idea
and you have no idea
and it is an embarrassment.
Cedric?
They're gone.
I want to thank you for this.
No problem.
It's not easy, I know.
But they seem
to think it matters
that I present myself as...
I'm fine with it.
All those years you were
all about my career,
Well, it's the least
I can do, right?
Goodnight.
We're not holding
anything up in his district.
Repaving, foot patrols,
streetlights.
He's getting his share.
Unless, it's not
about his district.
It's about him.
Maybe he's got
big eyes for something.
For what?
Not me, not my chair.
Not in this town.
Oh, no.
If the man came off any whiter,
he'd be see-through.
But, if that's it,
come on with it.
In fact, please Jesus.
Or maybe John the Baptist.
Soften you up
for someone else.
If he's gonna
bang us on crime.
Bang me on crime.
Look, is there any way
for you to talk to this guy?
Keep him from
crawling up my ass?
He's old first district.
Not a lot of favors we can call
in over that side of town.
So, we gotta show
him something, right?
Four to five percent
drop in felonies.
And murders.
Get the murders down
to under 250 for the year.
All due respect,
Mr. Mayor, we're at 232 now.
What can you
realistically do?
Best case scenario,
if we bump the overtime
is 275 maybe.
275, Christ.
That's a promise, right?
275 and this asshole
Carcetti has no issue.
Gentlemen,
the word from on high
is that felony rates
district by district
will decline by five percent
before the end of the year.
We are dealing in certainties.
You will reduce
the U.C.R. felonies
by five percent or more, or...
I've always wanted
to say this...
let no man come back alive.
In addition, we will hold this
year's murders to 275 or less.
Christ.
Feeling a little fazed,
Colonel Foerster?
A little dyspeptic?
Dis-who?
No, Sir.
I'm good to go.
He's a fun fact
for you people:
If Baltimore had
New York's population,
we'd be clocking 4000 murders
a year at this rate.
There is no excuse
I will except.
I don't care how you do it,
just fucking do it.
Deputy, as familiar
as we all are with the urban
crime environment,
I think we all understand
there's certain processes,
by which you can reduce
the number of overall felonies.
You can re-classify
an agg assault
or you can
unfound a robbery.
But, how do you
make a body disappear?
There is not
one of you in this room
who isn't here
by appointment.
If you want to continue
wearing those oak clusters,
you will shut up
and step up.
Any of you who can't bring
the numbers we need
will be replaced
by someone who can.
That is all.
Jesus, Bunny.
What got into you?
I got six months to my 30,
I'm out the door
on a major's pension.
The hell can they do to me?
Spider bags, red tops.
Any other bright ideas?
- How about a bug?
- A bug?
Yeah, bug one or two of the big
corners where these mopes hang.
Watchin' those corners
over on Ashland yesterday,
I'm seeing dumpsters,
weeds, maybe utility poles.
You hide a bug
on the right corner
at the right moment
you make this case.
We don't have the manpower.
Not to mention the money.
And for what?
We're still a long way
from a quality target.
I say we come down off the wire,
charge what we can and move on.
We come down early
two years ago
and we left a real bastard
on the street.
You're telling me
we're gonna let
that same sonofabitch
beat me again?
How many times
do you let a cocksucker
like Stringer Bell
go 'round the board?
Collect another
fuckin' 200 million.
There's other fish
in the barrel, McNulty.
Stringer's the target.
There isn't a better
motherfucker out there,
you know it, Lieutenant.
Don't you let him
go soft on this.
It's you against
the world, is it?
What the fuck did I do?
Red tops! Spider bags!
You up?
Step the fuck off,
motherfucker.
You got a need you
talk to one of the younguns.
I ain't in the market.
I'm sellin'.
You look like the right person
to be talkin' to, chief.
You seem like you steady
runnin' this shit here.
What, you some kind
of police or somethin'?
I'm a long motherfuckin'
way from the police.
I just finished
a 14 year bit in Jessup.
Got a package as
a comin' home present.
G- pack.
Why not sell that shit
your own self?
I just came home.
I ain't tryin' to get
my ass violated.
- Even split.
- Sheet.
It's all profit to you.
Risk mine, too.
What make you think
I ain't on paper or someshit?
60/40.
Cool.
Give your shit to my boy.
He good with it,
then come past tonight.
A'ight.
And one last item
for you gents.
It seems foxtrot was hovering
over the station house
a few days ago
and caught a lovely view
of about seven or 800 discarded
beer cans on the garage roof.
Seriously, no off-duty
drinking on the station lot
and if you do find
yourself holding a beer can
don't throw it on the roof,
take it home with you.
Come on, guys,
the memo came down
from our beloved Deputy
of Operations.
Alright, get outta here.
Don't get captured.
At ease.
Anything from day shift?
Nothing that'll make the papers.
Alright then.
I'm gonna ride the district
until the Deputy Major gets in.
If you need me, hit the radio.
Distribution?
Possession,
and some loitering.
Loitering?
And behaving like assles
in the presence
of sworn officers, boss.
5-0 creepin'!
Midnight relief comin' in.
The hell is all this?
You don't look at
what you did before,
you do the same shit
all over.
I'm outta here.
Where he at?
The fuck you lookin' at?
Huh?
What, you want a go?
Just my split.
Some bad luck there.
Poh-leece came through snatched
up a grod stash or two.
Shit happened to be yours.
Fuck, right?
You got a number?
A number?
Back in the day,
when a player tried to say
he lost a package
to the police,
he had to give up
a number for the report.
We ain't back in the day.
I'm gettin' fuckin'
tired of your ass.
Yeah, walk it off,
motherfucker.
Fuckin' old school ass bitch.
Got them spider bags.
Two get you three.
What?
You up?
Spider bags.
Two gets three.
You up or you not?
Don't you know five-o?
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
Transcript par Raceman
Synchronisation: El Uploador
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net