I got Redis, son.
Two for one,
two for one.
Got that Rasheed and Beno.
Rasheed and Beno.
Put some ice on his nuts.
Tried and true, that shit
always bring a nigger back.
Where we gonna
get ice from down here?
Walk him up to bon secours.
Rasheed and Beno, Rasheed and Ben.
Can we have an eight-ball?
An eight-ball?
So, how you doin' today?
No offense, but could we
just get the eight-ball?
A- ight, a-ight, just bein' social.
Got it right here, yo.
Thank you.
Yo, y'all hear about Mack Man jewelers
got took off las' night?
All this shit in that rowhouse.
Down yonder.
Like a must-move situation.
15 on the dollar.
Y'all want some slammin' ice,
go inside and tell my man Rafik sent you.
Lighters, pipes, matches.
Pipes, lighters.
You need 'em, I got 'em right here.
Pipes.
Redis.
Two for one, two for one.
As' me if it's loaded, bitch.
Redi-sons, two for one.
Anything up?
Just a good package.
Three O.D.'s
last one didn't look too good
before by the ambo came, neither.
There's more inside, Carv.
Gah-damn!
Can't yoever get a fucking poh-lice
'round here when you need one?!
Moral Midgetry
Okay, on that burner?
I called Trac,
gave 'em the serial number.
Trac Corporation tells me
that they sent it to Northland
a purchasing corporation.
Northland tells me they sent it
to their distribution center in Hagerstown.
Hagerstown tells me they sent it
to buddy's Mondo Mart
at one-four-four-o Propane Road,
Falls Church, Virginia
that's where it went out
into the street.
What?
Did buddy have them on display to the left
or the right of the cash register?
How would I know that?
Alright.
As for the numbers
in the phone's speed dial
we got one local number
one number that tracks
to Bodie's grandmother's house
on West Baltimore Street
and six others numbers
that are all assigned
to Trac disposable cell phones.
And those phones were
all purchased outside the city.
One each in Catonsville,
Laurel, Bethesda
and stores in Virginia,
at Springfield, Dumfries and Lakeside.
Everything is along I-95, from
here to almost Richmond.
They're driving 200 miles
every couple of weeks
out of sheer caution.
It's beautiful.
What is?
The discipline of it.
In your life, did you think you
would ever again see
Mount and Fayette like this?
Those ain't touts,
ya hearing, brother.
Those are birds chirpin'.
How?
I'll show you.
You say no whistles,
no muscle, no flexin'.
You supposed to be
all over that shit, man.
You even said it's supposed
to be like the valley of eden.
To serve, and protect,
motherfuckers.
- Call it poetic injustice.
- I want to file a report.
- Say what?
- You heard me.
You want to make
a complaint to us
that you were selling drugs
and someone took your money?
Fuck yes.
Fredericksburg?
They're going all
that way to buy cell phones?
One here, two there.
No wholesale purchases.
They're dumping phones
every two weeks or so
and still they're worried
about catching a wiretap.
Just 'cause you're paranoid doesn't
mean someone's not out to get you.
Right?
Be nice to know who's buying
all those cell phones, though.
Oh, God.
Yo, yo, yo, yo. You up, ol' man?
They do have a point though, right?
I mean, we tell 'em to comedown
here without the guns
and then we fall down
on providing protection.
It's like the stickup crews
have these hoppers feelin'
like they live in a lamb pen.
They see one more gun?
Gandhi-world falls apart,
this I guarantee.
So what are you doing about it?
I sent a few of the vics
over to the district with Herc.
Let 'em play with an ident-a-kit,
but you know how that goes.
But can I be honest?
It's not just the wolves
circling the corral.
We got 50, 60 kids on the inside
been fight or flight since they
popped out of the chute
and right now they're just
thumb-up-their-ass hangin'.
All these ex-runners, ex-lookouts.
That shit worries me as much
as any carnivores out there.
If you want to neutralize a threat?
Give it a job.
As?
Auxiliary cops.
Keep an eye out for the predators.
You got the dealers payin' 'em
to do nothing now anyway?
Kill two birds and all that.
Right.
Throw 'em some bikes,
maybe police radios.
We could do that.
I was being...
you're serious?
What in God's name did you do here?
W.M.D. Got them W.M.D.'s
Hey, how you doing?
We're looking for a guy
who came in here
10, 11 days ago, dropped cash on
a couple of disposable phones?
10, 11 days ago?
Yeah. Black, most likely.
That really narrows it down.
How about we just check
on some of your security tapes?
From 10 days ago?
Unless there's an incident.
We re-use those video tapes every week.
Every week?
It's Mondo Mart policy.
That went well.
Yeah?
Brianna Barksdale called for you.
Who?
D'angelo Barksdale's mother.
You get her number?
You got a pen?
Four-one-oh, seven-one-eight,
nine-four-apple-three. Got it?
Alright.
You gonna call her?
I dunno...
- It's all yours.
- Thanks, Jay.
Hey, check it out.
Mondo Mart, Mondo Mart,
Mondo Mart, Mondo Mart.
We're fucked. Until we get here...
Baba Jani Food Mart,
Dumfries, Virginia.
We're gonna go 100 miles
on the off-chance this guy
has a memory or a camera?
Do you really wanna go home early
and disappoint Lester Freamon?
Who was that who rang?
Guess who's calling homicide
looking for me on D'Angelo Barksdale?
His mama.
Yeah?
Shit, I forgot I'd even tried
to press that thing
and now she's
calling up asking questions.
Waste of her time as it was mine.
Kinda like this road trip.
He do look natural.
This motherfucker Marlo?
We gonna have to get
deep on this nigger.
I mean it feels like
ain't shit change
except for a growing
lightness in my wallet.
Where's my letter of approval, man,
from the preservation motherfuckers?
My right-of-way agreement?
My sign-offs.
Hold on, hold on, hold on,
everything's right around the corner.
We got both the plumbing and
the electrical inspectors on for tomorrow
tuesday the fire department's coming out,
and that should do it, String
you'll be on your way.
And by the way, congratulations.
You are now minority contractor
for light bulb supply
to the Board of Education,
city of Baltimore.
What the fuck I know
about light bulbs, man?
Do you know how to put the words
on a B-and-B letterhead?
Come on, man, relax,
white guy's doing all the work.
You're just his beard
for the empowerment grant.
That's an extra five g's a month
for just laying in the cut.
See how it work?
I'm gonna bring you along,
String, but...
it ain'tonna be an overnight thing.
We spend this year
dealing with the city
the next doing business
with the state.
However, year three?
Then we go for the gold.
Then we go federal.
Then we see the man
with his hand on the faucet.
What faucet?
The hud faucet, the money faucet.
Look, man, I don't know why we got
to wait three years for that shit?
I'm ready to run now.
No, you're not.
I mean, forgive me, but...
you still showin' a little bit of that
street corner mentality.
buggin' about every dime you spend
about the permits,
about setting up a pac
about dropping cash
into re-election war chests
which by the way,
is how i get my gravy.
Look, it takes money
to make money, String
otherwise, hell,
every pauper'd be a king.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm ready to run now.
Three years.
Crawl, walk, and then run.
Naw man, nappy up there
a little bit more.
And the eyes.
He had little beanie eyes.
What the fuck is beanie eyes?
You know, little rat-eyes.
Yeah, a-ight.
Yo, put a mole on there.
He didn't have a mole.
He did too.
You was just too busy shitting
yourself with that whistle
to your dome
to see the motherfucker.
Shit, fuck I did.
How do you know how to do this?
Man, how you don't now
how to do this?
Make his ears stick out.
- Why?
- 'Cause I told you to.
Ho shit, okay.
Give him light eyes.
- Why?
- 'Cause I fuckin' told you to.
Okay, can you make 'em cross?
This is fuckin' cool.
Check out these knuckleheads
on the make-a-face.
Fuck this shit.
Look, I'm just tryin'
to make my district liveable.
Write off a few blocks
in a few places but I save the rest.
No offense, but you're like
the blind man and the elephant.
It's a lot bigger than what
you got your hand on
you just can't see it.
See what?
A great village of pain,
and you're the mayor.
Where's your drinking water?
Where's your toilets,
your heat, your electricity?
Where's the needle truck, the condom
distribution, the drug treatment intake?
Half these people
are dying on their feet
and the other half's
gonna catch what's killin' 'em.
Look, they ain't no worse off
than when they were all over the map.
Now they just in one place is all.
And that place is hell.
Look, I'm a police.
So I can lock a man up or I can
move his ass off the corner.
Now, you want anything
more than that
you're in the wrong shop.
Hey, yo, make her hair
a little bit more straight.
Make it long.
With bangs.
Yeah, that's what
I'm talkin' about.
Now chinese up them eyes,
like Beyonce.
Get them cheekbones
up a little bit.
Naw, man, that's too much.
She startin' to look like
a pie tin with hair now, yo.
Hang on.
Yeah, alright.
Pillow up them lips a little bit.
Oh yeah, hook me up with that.
Yo, you got one
of these does asses?
What?
Yeah, that's what's up, dang.
Hey, guys.
How you doing?
We're looking
for a cash purchase in here
maybe a couple Trac phones,
week or so back.
Black guy most likely.
Oh sure, that guy.
Every two weeks for him.
Last time, eight phones.
Almost $900.
That's a lot of ring dings, no?
Ring dings?
A joke.
You got some kind
of transaction record?
Sikh and ye shall find.
Hang on.
$927.24.
Can we have the tape for that day?
No tape. I rewind every day.
- Keep this?
- Sure.
The fuck do we do now?
Buy this guy a box of videotapes?
Or camp out in this shithole for a week,
hoping our boy runs the same route?
I just know, I got to put my mind
on something or I'm gonna slide back.
Need to be in control of myself,
you know what I'm sayin'?
Take command of your life.
Something.
Cultivate some self-discipline.
Or whatever.
What if I told you that there's
a certain liberation
not in command or in self-control
but in surrendering?
Well, that depends on
who you're surrendering to.
Oh, that.
All due respect?
You can stow that patter
right here and now.
Look, it ain't about me
doin' for me, I don't think.
Might need to be
about more than that.
So you're bringing in an overall decline
of two percent for the month
but if I read this correctly,
almost half of that's coming from
an eight percent drop
in the western district?
Major Colvin is himself
willing to acknowledge
the possibility of a statistical
variation from the mean
in his monthly stats.
Variation, huh?
Gentlemen, if I look through
the western incident reports
am I likely to find less crime,
or more incidents
which have been
downgraded or unfounded?
Because this kind of variation
screams manipulation to me.
And if I'm wrong about that
if indeed there is
no manipulation involved
I would like to know exactly
what it is that Major Colvin
has learned about police work
that eludes the rest of your commanders.
Councilman, I assure you
these stats are not massaged.
We don't do that.
I don't do that.
And I won't allow
my people to do that.
Our feeling is that
it's genuinely an aberration
and if it repeats
itself next month
then it bears closer
examination, otherwise...
Moving on to new business then.
How are we fixed for witness assistance?
Does the department have
sufficient funds
to ensure pre-trial security
for any endangered witnesses?
We have the resources that
the city can afford, I'm sure.
I understand you're in no
position to criticize the Mayor.
- Nor would I.
- Nor would you.
So allow me to ask the question:
What is this city willing to pay,
to make it possible for ordinary people
to come down to the courthouse
and perform the civic duty
of bearing witness against
gangsters and criminals?
What resources are commensurate
with that kind of commitment?
You can play the good soldier,
if you want, Commissioner.
But I want to go on the record here
in saying that this administration
has passed the buck time and again.
And failed to protect those citizens
who demonstrate that kind of commitment
and put their lives
and livelihood at risk.
And I would only like to add,
that I feel as my colleague does
that this administration has
failed this community miserably.
And we need to do
something about this.
Y'all are friends.
Y'all like brothers.
You lose that you lose
every damn thing.
Kids messed up the good hoop
now they got one looks like
the original peach basket
an' they hangin' onto it like a tit.
I don't know.
Maybe I should get up
some kind of tournament.
You play basketball?
Never was much
for balls and sticks.
I was all about my hands.
Boxer?
Yeah.
Boxing.
I know a place where
some of the kids go, but...
it ain't nearly
close enough to here.
I wouldn't mind
takin' a look at it.
Get a mental picture at least.
What the hell is goin' on here?
Police pushed all the action
down here and a couple other places.
The Deacon thinks
that maybe some people
should come in here
and take over this situation?
You that people?
One of 'em, maybe.
Roman, man.
Dennis.
You should lay back on this one.
Lemme go talk to Buford Pusser
in there alone.
Excuse me?
And what it shows people
is that I know my business
that I will hold people
accountable based on the facts.
- This is about what's right.
- There you go again.
What?
Do you think politics is only
about winning the argument?
That whoever has the right fact
at the right moment wins?
Clinton had facts.
Kennedy had facts, yeah.
But Reagan?
He couldn't have summoned a fact
if his life depended on it.
It's not just facts,
it's how you use them.
And Tommy, when you
get hold of a fact or two
you go smartass
and start beating on people.
- That's because...
- Clinton and Reagan?
When they got up to speak
they gave everyone in the room
comfort and confidence.
You liked those guys.
You were happy to think
that they even liked you.
You're saying I'm not likeable?
Jen?
When you're at home, talking with me
not the council, not the cameras,
you're great.
When you tell me
what's really important to you
I believe.
You're smart and you're ambitious
and you've got
a sharper tongue than most.
You can hold court
and you can tell a good story
and you can win
the argument if you want.
All of that shows, Tommy
and at a Baltimore
city council meeting it shows well
but if you want to be mayor
or senator, or governor one day...
...show them something more.
Baltimore, huh?
Went up there to the harbor with
my wife for our anniversary?
Charged us $12 for two beers.
Shit, that's the least of it.
The whole damn town's
gone to hell in a handbasket
and guess who's running the show?
Who?
Who do you think?
The department, city hall, the courts.
Shit, the courts?
You know what they call it when judge
jury and perp all go
to the same family barbecue?
Catch and release.
No shit.
May God have mercy on any poor
white boy going to trial.
That's when everybody's got their ass
in the air talking' about justice
can't wait to throw away the key.
I mean, they're not all so bad.
Actually, there's a lot of good ones.
I'm on the radio if you need me.
My wife, Carol Ann.
Some very good ones.
Is there anything
specific I can help you with
while you're down here, detective?
Or is this just a courtesy call?
You know, you should meet my partner.
You'd like her.
Can't go through
the front on this boy.
So I'm thinkin' we're gonna
have to creep around the back.
Get Devonne on it?
I got this for that other problem.
- Who this?
- Remember Fat Face Rick, right?
Been going to them co-op
meetings with String?
That's his cousin, Trina.
Oh you mean,
Trina with the big old ass.
Yeah, you on it.
That's her work number.
You know where she work nowadays?
She over at the department
of social services.
So you thinkin' Omar gettin' a check?
Not now. But i mean
once upon a time, before...
some fool gave lil' Omar
Little a shotgun, I mean
cocksucker was
somebody's child, right?
So I'm thinking somewhere
down in them records
is one or two names
of Omar's people.
You feel me?
You sure you want us
on Marlo and Omar both?
I mean, Omar ain't come back
on us since we got his bitch
- so maybe...
- Look, I'm home, Charles.
I'm home.
Was up?
Takin' care of business, String?
Me too, man.
Me too.
East side wasn't
ready for us, huh?
That's what I'm saying.
Yeah, I know all about Baba Jani
and his 24-hour turnover.
It's a real pain in my ass too.
He's got a little problem
with the school kids there.
Every afternoon come 3:00
they go in there,
crowd him at the counter
boost all the car
and gun magazines.
That surveillance tape's
so grainy now
it's like watching a herd
of buffalo in a snowstorm.
But my insurance man, Bob?
Got him to turn this camera here
right on Baba's parking lot.
Now anytime I have a real problem?
I just come to Bob
and pull his tape.
I can get a copy of that
for you in the morning.
Your...
Your partner there?
Bit of an asshole.
For real?
Keep your right hand up.
You know what this is?
It's moral midgetry.
Turn the fuckin' world upside down.
Treat these braindead
corner yo's like princelings.
You see how clean the corners are?
In every sector, street traffic
is half of what it was.
Fuck that.
It's wrong, and it's wrong.
Like the other way was right
because we were doing so well.
And Colvin's answer is what?
Ride shotgun for hoppers?
Drown them in cash money paid?
Colvin?
He's always been good police.
He's got to know
what a fuckin' heartbreaker
it is to wake up every morning,
suit up for this shit.
He's got to suit up too, man.
Somebody should dime
the brass about this shit.
Or the Sun papers.
Let me ask you something.
Anybody here ever get jammed up
and not have Colvin
go to the wall for you?
The man is trying something.
It may be hard to stomach,
but it's working.
After 30 years don't you think
he's earned the right
to some elbow room on this?
What the fuck. This thing is
on borrowed time anyhow.
And when we do decide
to jump on the Hamsterdams
they're just gonna go back to
their regular corners, right?
If we ever jump out on it.
I don't know that we're gonna.
All I'm sayin' is we give
the guy the same back-up
he's always given us.
That's all I'm sayin'.
I swear as soon as the sun comes
up we grab the damn tape and go.
This place makes me want to cry.
Hey, I spent half my marriage
in rooms like this.
How could you do it?
What?
Go non-stop hound
on your ex like that.
It was easy.
Just tell her I was on the road
working an extradition.
Lots of extraditions.
Brought back something
like 500 fugitives
in a three-year period, I think.
That's not what I meant.
Right.
So, you back in the house, huh?
Ate some shit
and she took me back, yeah.
Ain't sure I even want
to be back, though.
Extraditions, huh?
Cheryl'd see right
through that shit.
Nah, it's easy.
Just keep your cell off,
make sure she can reach your partner.
Partner tells her:
"Kima's in court" or whatever.
Partner calls you at the motel
gives you the heads up
you call her back later like:
"hey, what's up?"
Ain't even have a quarter box
for magic fingers.
Maybe you don't need
a quarter box for that.
For what?
Magic fingers.
Hey, you know me.
... we'll talk with a singer
songwriter who's burning up
the charts with a hit
he'll perform for us tonight.
You hustlin'?
Educatin'.
Charging for it or tuition-free?
Tuition will come back to him
ten-fold in acquired wisdom.
Besides, nothing in the world's
more expensive than "free".
S'all she wrote.
Let's double it.
Naw man, I don't like takin'
money from a church-goin' man.
Triple it.
Your break, Deacon.
We need to talk
some more about Amsterdam.
Look, man,
I never said it was pretty.
Pretty don't even
come close to the problem.
We need to talk.
I've got comstat meeting.
I'll drop by later on.
So we good with the permits?
Yeah, this week, so far, so good.
A- ight.
Look at you.
Who?
Chunky Coates.
Who's that?
You don't know Chunky?
He's got the properties
down the block and over
on the even side of Paca Street.
When I first met that fat man,
he had an office so small
you had to leave
the room to change your mind.
Then two years ago he started running
with your man, Clay Davis.
Look at you now,
you big sassy bitch.
That better?
Hey, special agent Fitzhugh
if that is in fact your real name.
FBI in on this?
I am only loved for my toys.
Lester called and I delivered.
You got the tape?
Date of ten-ten-oh-four,
fifteen-oh-four hours
30 seconds, by the register tape.
Mama Barksdale?
D'Angelo's mother.
She cold-called McNulty
about her son on the jailhouse hangin'.
She's callin' us
on that weak shit?
Is this, uh...
Brianna?
Right.
You called about your son.
I'm returning that message.
Nothing there.
It's so tiny.
No mere mortal can.
You see what he just did?
What? He did it again?
Who is this man?
Where does he come from?
Can anybody stop him?
Please don't hurt us.
Please my eyes, my eyes.
It's so big and clear and bright.
I'll be at homicide.
Sometimes, you still scare me,
you know that?
In my world, do you have
any idea what I had to do
to get where I am today?
Now when I say i ready,
you best believe it.
Through the effective
use of resources
an increased police presence
and an intensive reach
out into the community
we've been able to have
a significant impact on these areas
to the effect
of a 12% decrease overall.
12%.
Cumulatively.
Over four weeks.
Major, I know I gave you shit
when your stats took
a jump a few weeks back
but now you're gonna shove
the numbers right up my ass.
It's kind of pouty of you,
isn't it?
12%.
I didn't cook 'em then,
I ain't cookin' 'em now.
Seriously, Bunny. I already got
the City Council asking questions
about the eight percent drop
you posted last week.
We just want to please the Mayor,
not go to jail behind this shit.
Sometimes the Gods do listen, sir.
Not in the Western they don't.
Lieutenant Daniels.
Sir?
You want to take credit
for any of this?
Your unit's been working in
that district a couple of weeks.
We're barely up on anything.
In fact, the crews we're
looking at are still beefing
still dropping bodies.
Amazing.
Crime is down and no one
wants to take any credit.
What is wrong with this picture?
You don't mind
if I have planning and research
pull all your C.C. numbers
make sure there's not a decimal point
missing between the one and the two?
Pull everything, Deputy.
My number will stand.
Hey, tell Landsman, line
twenty-one-oh-three's for him.
I called because I heard
you went and visited Donette
told her my son's death
couldn't have been no suicide.
Is that right?
I did do that.
D'Angelo hung himself.
Not with the belt
they found around his neck.
Not at that distance between
the doorknob and the floor.
So what are you saying?
What am I saying.
No.
Nobody would've dared.
My brother,
his uncle would have...
I agree with you.
Nobody would've dared.
Unless...
Avon and Dee was family.
Family, right.
This is just you talking, right?
I mean, anyone else saying that...
Nah, just me.
No one else cares.
Right.
It's just, I dunno, on the inside
if somebody's going after you
has got a beef, sees red,
they use a shank.
It's quick and it's over.
D'Angelo was strangled
which is planned.
You need the time,
you need the isolation.
Look, I'm just sorry I brought
this whole mess up to begin with
because frankly nobody's
gonna do shit about it anyhow.
Whoever killed him wanted
to pass it off as a suicide
and the cops are happy enough
to have one less murder to investigate.
On top of that, the Anne Arundel
State's Attorney doesn't give a fuck
I'm not supposed
to give a fuck, so...
I guess your son just got
squeezed between the sides.
Squeezed between what sides?
Look, two years ago
we hung more wire
on your brother's crew than AT&T
and at the end, D'Angelo was
this close to flipping.
Giving up everybody, everything.
But you know all that right?
You were the one who went down
to that detention center
and talked your son out of a deal.
I kinda liked your son, you know?
All things considered,
he was a pretty decent kid.
And it grinds me that no one
ever spoke up for him
and seems to me
that nobody ever will.
But mostly at this point?
I'm sorry I bothered his girl
and I'm sorry she bothered you.
Why go to her?
Why not come to me first?
Honestly?
I was looking for somebody
who cared about the kid.
I mean, like I said...
you were the one how made him
take the years, right?
Red leader to red boys.
Red two come in.
Cheese steak has a problem, bitch.
Save me some fries, yo...
You want fries.
I suggest you bring
some cash up here.
You believe this?
No muscle,
it's all out in the open.
Naw naw naw, man...
This right here, boy.
This too good.
Hey yo, this some kinda
full-tilt setup, man
to catch some master-scoundrel,
Capone an' whatnot.
Boy, they prob'ly got police behind
every one of those rowhouse windows.
Hit this?
You must be trippin'.
Home, James...
I'ma tell you, boy,
you better keep your head
back in the game or you gonna
land us both in the pokey.
- What you lookin' at?
- You.
Yeah.
I like you're eyes.
They like cat's eyes.
Who you here with?
Them.
That's it?
What kind of cat?
What?
What kind of cat my eyes like?
A big cat.
You here with them
and no one else?
I said that.
You want to dance?
Hell, no.
You want a drink?
No, don't do that neither.
What do you do?
Gene, this spot
I'm telling you about?
We're talking TB, HIV, syphilis, herpes, lice...
It's like a five-acre petri dish.
You get in there now
you can run every health program
or social program you want.
Every kinda liberal-ass project
never got off the page
it was written on.
Jurassic park.
So, you're saying this is a
sanctioned open-air drug market.
No, it's not officially sanctioned.
It's more like it's tolerated.
That's why we came to
you and the public health school
not the city health department.
Needle exchange, drug outreach,
condoms, HIV-testing.
Y'all ain't never gonna reach
more people in the same spot.
So if the city doesn't know about it.
That makes it...
Complicated.
That means temporary.
You move it or you lose it, boss.
That was nice.
Work for me.
You free tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
You could come back to my crib,
nobody's there but my grandma.
Get us a real bed,
take some time with it.
Give me your number.
The reason I'm sayin'
tomorrow not to push
but day after that I got
to go visit my aunt in Florida.
We hook up tomorrow,
I got something real nice
to think about
on that long-ass bus ride.
After you.
What was it again?
Devonne.
This guys running
his route every five days.
That's a shitload of burners.
I don't get it.
They're were so careful
spreading out the purchases
up and down the three states
you'd think he'd also
switch up rental agencies.
Maybe the guy felt bad for us.
You got a copier, right?
Damn, girl,
what you lose some weight?
Excuse me?
It's just a compliment.
Yo, at's Mrs. Omar?
Yeah, his grandmoms.
So what, we jack her
an' make her talk?
Fool, she probably got no clue
where he lay his head.
Naw, man,
we sit an' we wait, right?
Man, wait on what?
You see, if we go upstairs,
we'll spook him.
So he's coming down.
Alright.
Russell Bell.
I know B-and-B like I know
a thousand other outfits
but I don't know him.
Why should I talk to him?
Because Russell's a good man.
And he's ready to run.
Then let him run for you.
Hang on.
Wait a minute, partner.
I don't think you know who
you're dealing with here.
You know who that is?
Got your running shoes on?
You're in.
That's the faucet?
Shit, as far as the federal money's
concerned, he's everything.
The faucet, the goose...
What goose?
The one that lays them golden eggs.
Madison Square Garden it ain't
but it could work.
You're gonna need
a little help with the clean-up.
I'll piece that together.
This my trip, man.
Need to go from
"a" to "b" all by my self.
... Am I likely to find less crime
or more incidents that have
been downgraded or unfounded?
Because this kind of variation
screams manipulation to me.
Slow your words.
Indeed there is no
manipulation involved...
Try to lock your eyes
on whoever you talk to.
Make them think they matter.
Use open, warm phrases.
nothing sharp, nothing that bites.
Where's the fun in that?
Do you want this?
What is this city willing to pay
to make it possible
for ordinary people to...
It's me.
Hey, how you cat eyes?
When you say ya leaving again?
Tomorrow, wanna
get together tonight?
Yeah, we can hook up tonight.
How about coming over
to my crib?
Naw, not your crib.
Where then?
Go to a motel.
You want me to meet you?
Which one?
I don't know which one.
I'll tell you when I see you.
I'd like to see you soon.
Alright, you know the Lake Trout?
Carryout?
Where?
On Woodland.
Off Midtown Road.
That one.
Later this afternoon?
I'll be there.
What time you want to meet?
Like five.
And five mean five.
I don't truck C.P. time.
Five and change, I'm gone.
I ain't gonna be late.
Alright then.
See you then.
What you think about that?
I don't know.
Might be walkin'
into something a little later.
So I'm gonna need
for you to go up there
get me a read up front.
Where's my brother?
Shut the door, man.
Yo, we at war right now, sis.
So he on that.
I need to get with him.
Well, he ain't on the cell phone
soon as I speak to him,
I'll get him to you, alright?
Can't believe this shit.
Heard from this cop.
He sayin' Dee was murdered.
Oh, that'd be McNulty.
How you know?
Levy figured he couldn't
talk you out of that meet
but I sure wish he'da tried.
I need to get with my brother.
Oh, c'mon.
This fucking cop.
He trying to drive
a wedge up in here.
You can't see it.
Look, I can imagine
how hard it is
for a mother to have to deal
with some shit like that.
No doubt. But the fact is,
these places, they press on niggers.
Dee just figured a way
to get out of there early.
Ain't nothing nobody
could do about that.
I mean, how do you
protect a man from himself?
Where Avon at?
I'll go to him.
I told you. We beefin' for corners
right now and as soon as I speak to him
I'll get him to you, I promise.
A cop shouldn't mess
with a mother's pain like that.
No one should.
Yeah, let me get
four trout on white
extra mayo on one,
hot sauce on two
and the other with ketchup,
and four orange sodas.
This clown ass nigger went
and got four sammiches.
Four sodas, you heard me?
Cool.
Niggas don't roll out in a few
minutes, we on to something.
Drop one, get one.
Nah, baby, this one's sentimental.
Here, it's bleach.
Just soak your works
and you're good to go.
Drop one get one.
Drop one, get one.
Get the other girls to come by.
Or wait.
Just pass these out for me, okay?
Yo, I get swoled up
from Peanut Butter.
You got anything else?
The fuck I look like to you,
Chef Boyardee?
Who?
Hey, when all this bullshit falls apart,
I'm gonna kick your fucking...!
Go by them slow.
Oh shit!
Oh, my god!
You hit?
No.
Drive, motherfucker,
get out of here!
Your man better be
as good as his word.
Or your word.
If you are still in possession
of that kind of mentality?
Then you are definitely not ready.
- String?
- Not now.
- It's Avon...
- Shut the door.
Let's do this.
I'll be in touch, partner.
- What is it, man?
- Avon's been hit.
- Where?
- In the shoulder.
Tater got kilt, but Avon
still breathin', man.
But Brianna all over me,
calling me, man.
- I need to tell her.
- Naw, fuck Brianna.
What?
Just keep the bitch
away from me, ya hear me?
If you put them
pitbull-style stitches in me
the next patient's gonna be you.
For real.
What, you don't like rawhide?
Oooh, Marlo.
We're finally gettin'
back to old times, baby.
Hey, Anthony, where you at?
First-floor, 10-34 North Mount, sir.
Good.
They expecting us to hit back wild.
That's what they just waiting for
and we're gonna sit
back on it for awhile
let 'em sweat on it.
Yo, we gotta talk.
Hold on.
I mean, he got to come out on his corners,
that's how he make money, right?
We gonna see who got
the bigger war chest. Avon.
Straight to the mattresses, huh?
Whatever, what you want, man?
War, man, we're past this bullshit.
Oh yeah, I forgot.
I knew I forgot something.
We the Trump brothers.
You don't give this shit up
you're gonna turn
everything we built to shit.
Naw.
The chump brothers.
You know what the difference's
between me and you?
I bleed red
you bleed green.
What you been building for us?
I look at you these days
you know what I see?
I see a man without a country.
Not hard enough for this right here
and maybe, just maybe
not smart enough
for them out there.
Not hard enough.
No offense.
I don't think you ever really were.
You got skills, yeah,
no doubt, but... what?
What, 'cause I don't
shoot up a block
indiscriminate I ain't hard enough?
Huh? Because I think
before I snatch a life,
I ain't into this bullshit?
Snatch a life.
What life you snatch, huh?
You know Brianna went downtown,
man, saw that detective.
Man stokin' her head sayin' that
D'Angelo's death was no suicide.
Yeah, so...
Man ain't wrong about that.
What?
I knew you couldn't do it
and Brianna wouldn't do that shit.
But there goes a life
that had to be snatched, Avon.
Yo man, I took that shit off you
and put it on me, man
because that motherfucker
was out of pocket with that shit!
20 years above his fucking head.
He flip, man, they got you,
me and fucking Brianna!
And no fucking way, man.
Hell no!
Now, I know you family.
You loved that nigger.
But you want to talk that blood
is thicker than water bullshit
take that shit
somewhere else, nigger!
That motherfucker woulda taken down
the whole fucking show
starting with you, killer!
It's fucking everything
and everybody!
Let me up.
Shit.
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
Transcript par Raceman
Synchronisation: El Uploador
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net