Yo, Renaldo.
- Renaldo!
- Que?
Next time you finish up
the box,
you need to holler on it, yo.
Si, si.
Yo mala mia.
Hey, y'all, it's Omar.
Omar.
There he is.
Omar step, yo.
Omar, yo.
Y'all ain't got no honey nut?
Whatever you see.
An' a carton of newport.
Omar comin'.
Hey, y'all, here he come.
Omar. Omar.
Omar strollin'.
They no have the honey nut?
I don't even want this, dog.
Why not?
It ain't what you takin', it's who
you takin' it from. You feelin' me?
How you expect to run
with the wolves come night
when you spend all day
sportin' with the puppies?
4x03 - Home Room
So you stayin' with Royce, I see?
What you mean?
Oh, man.
Make sense, since I know
you got your fill of Carcetti.
They been puttin' up
a crop of these things
on every lawn on the block.
And as fast as I take 'em down,
they bring more.
That's what they
do this time of year.
I see you at your leisure.
I work 2 nights a week,
3 dayshifts,
and no weekends.
I'm off till this afternoon.
You good with it?
It ain't the Hopkins gig,
but it'll do.
Pullin' 52, good bennies,
got a take-home car.
I mean the hotel manager's
a pain in the ass, but still.
Well, if you was a bit free,
I heard something.
This thing over at university of
Maryland school of social work?
They got a grant. Big money.
Just stop.
Half a million to look at
repeat violent offenders.
Clinical intervention,
all that mess.
So, they gonna study some shit?
Melvin, I had me a good helping
of them downtown, tie-wearing,
come-to-do-good, stay-to-do-well
college-types last year.
You sure?
'Cause I sold 'em on it
should you want it.
Bunny, you a big man
down on the campus.
You the police that legalized it.
The college boys loved that mess.
Nobody else did, though.
Well, I tried.
You did.
Yo, blacktops, pandemic.
Pandemic.
Got that pandemic.
Yo, my man, pandemic,
blacktops right here.
That's my boy, right?
Ain't take no handouts,
but he workin' for it.
See what I mean?
This nigga's made a little
something out this corner.
Now hold on, son.
We jus' talkin' now.
A'ight?
Man,
y'all did good with this spot.
You a rightful hustler.
What's your name again, man?
Boney? Ditty?
What was it now?
You know my name.
Yeah, but now here's the thing.
With this spot all built up an' shit?
We need it, yo. Yeah.
- What?
- 2 choices.
You can start takin' our
packages or you can step off.
My man Chris is gonna
holla at you, all right?
You tell him what it need to be.
Don't wait for the pandemic.
It's right here, y'all.
Don't sleep on the pandemic.
Wanna know more about
that boy right there.
Got good signs on him.
Big paws on a puppy, huh?
Yeah, big paws on a puppy.
To a "t."
Get that blacktop before you flop.
That pandemic.
The truth is we don't know
why he was killed.
Coulda had something to do
with him being a witness
or, it could be unrelated.
Now, whoever leaked that shit
to Carcetti's camp lied on us.
Yeah, well, that's it.
8 points--
Close as Carcetti gets.
He wants to go big dick with me?
I'll show him one he can't handle.
We put it out there:
anyone contributing to both sides
gets frozen outta my next term.
- No one rides the middle anymore.
- Done.
Next, I want D.P.W.
And H.C.D. out there today
tearing down all Carcetti signs.
Any lamppost, median,
any city-owned buildings--
unless the homeowner's
out there arguing, tear it down.
- Done.
- Third, I want transpo
camped outside
of Carcetti's headquarters.
Any car, any violation,
meter flag goes up,
inspection sticker-- tow it.
- Done.
- Next,
you 2...
slow it down.
Nothing else
comes out about that murder
until after the primary.
And I want both of you--
go to the press and talk down
that witness angle.
Take the full weight
either way it goes.
Clarence, I'm running
dead even with bond right now.
How you gonna be running
if I drop you from the ticket?
OK, that's it.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Go to it. Now.
Mr. Mayor?
- What?
- Carcetti has a point.
I went down to Annapolis,
got matching funds
for witness protection.
You didn't earmark a dime
to put 'em into play.
Next fiscal year.
Don't claim poverty on this.
We're only talking a quarter million.
I match those funds now
and that motherfucker Carcetti,
he's got a campaign highlight:
"Tommy Carcetti expands
witness protection program.
Fought for and won extra funds."
Hell with that!
I go after that state-match funds
after the election.
Naw, naw, I paid for 3 pills.
Look, blue shirt gets 2.
Naw, I get 2.
White shirt gets one.
- Cheatin' motherfucker.
- I get 4.
Look, blue shirt gets 2,
white one, no shirt one.
Now y'all can take what
y'all paid for and walk away
or just walk away with nothing.
Motherfuck a refund.
Naw, nigger, I paid for 3.
You need to re-think what putting
a hand on me's gonna get you.
You can thank your friend here
for snatching away y'all highs.
Yo, yo, hold up. Hold up.
Can I get my 2?
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
You don't rattle.
Yo, you come up
under my wing, young'un?
You ain't gonna do nothin'
but rise, man.
I don't even know why you
thinkin' about quittin'.
Look, man, like I already told you--
I'm all the way repaid,
and tomorrow's school.
Come on, man, what the fuck
you want to go to school for?
What do you want to be,
an astronaut?
A dentist?
A pay lawyer, nigger?
Look, check it out.
Why don't you just
come down here after school
and just work these rush hours for me.
How 'bout that?
That's great. Thank you.
I know that kind of money...
I said I know that kind of money
doesn't come easy to anyone.
No, it's just something on my end here.
Some construction or something...
right.
Yeah, right. Thanks again.
2 hours, 30 grand.
Am I getting the hang of this or what?
The fuck is that?
D.P.W. tearing up the sidewalk
right outside our door.
You really pissed him off.
Yes, I did, didn't I?
C'mon. Door-to-door in Irvington.
- Right.
- And we got that dead witness tonight.
Yeah. Federal?
Naw, she ain't no federal.
That there a city girl.
I like shorty, too.
She all right.
Long as she don't get in my way.
Reup right there.
Por que?
School ain't start till
tomorrow, right?
Little one be all dressed up
with nowhere to go.
Yeah, you know it, too,
don't you, girl?
The camera?
- If you go in front, they gonna...
- they supposed to know it's me, man.
I'm my own trademark.
You feel me?
Si, but if they know it's you, then--
What, you scared on bein' made?
Claro que si.
How 'bout I put you in one
of them full-body Bunny suits?
Be like a 6-foot rabbit
puttin' a pistol in they face.
Let me get a pack of juicy Fruit.
You like one of them
half-soul, half-Chinese types.
From Vietnam and shit.
Come again now, Mama-San.
Patience, girl.
Mo' patience.
The guy drives a shitbox,
he's got a 2-bit mini-mart,
but the back door in there
is reinforced steel
and the security camera
on the street is high-end.
Not only that, but I think
I made the reup today.
Schoolgirl with a heavy backpack.
I pulled Andre's phone history
trying to find Marlo's organization,
cross-referencing D.N.R.S
to other cells.
This is Fruit, this is Monk,
and there's 3 or 4
other good probables.
Not likely to find a direct
line to Marlo that way.
Andre had to go through Monk
to get to him.
No. But we might get
a cell on Chris Partlow
or for Tote or for one
of the top Lieutenants.
We're gettin' close.
Deputy pulled me downtown.
You guys aren't into any shit, are you?
No, sir.
Good he wasn't down
at the ocean today.
And the subpoenas?
You won't see a page of anything
until after the primary.
After that, if a document lands
and there's no one there to read it,
will the mayor and his people
honestly give a shit?
Other than that,
what can I tell you
except to get that unit back
on the street where it belongs.
Lieutenant,
you are relieved
from command of major crimes.
You've done exceptional work,
and in light of that,
we want you to improve the performance
of another vital aspect of our mission.
- Sir?
- Telephone reporting unit.
You report there tomorrow 0800.
Have I done something wrong?
Lieutenant Marimow will
be taking over major crimes.
If you need to brief him,
do so promptly.
Yes, sir.
Jimmy, how's that beach house coming?
Beach... fine, sir.
Great. Sounds great.
Yeah, hand me the colander, will ya?
- He's early.
- Yeah.
You get the door. I'll do that.
- Hey.
Come in.
Smells good.
Spaghetti. Nothing fancy.
Cote du rhone.
Yeah, sommelier behind
the plexi said it was dry.
Hey, Beadie.
Hey, Bunk, how ya doin'?
Look at you. Blonde and all.
- You like it?
- I do. I do. Hey, kids.
This is Jack, that's Kari.
This is Detective Moreland.
- Hi.
- Hi!
- Call me Bunk.
- Let me open this wine.
Yeah, that's right.
Let that shit breathe.
I'm sorry.
- That's all right. They hear worse.
- Yeah, no doubt.
So, you want ice in yours?
No, man, that's a double-digit vino.
Even has a cork.
So.
I like your binders.
- Thanks.
- McNulty gave them to us.
- McNulty?
- Yeah.
- Not Jimmy?
- No.
Uncle Jimmy? Jim?
- Jim?
- No.
No?
Daddy? Pops?
McNulty.
Oh, just plain McNulty.
An' if I take his weak-ass product,
that mean I'm gonna be
makin' less money. Know what I'm sayin'?
Only reason I could bring
any life to this strip
is because of the good shit
that y'all was givin' me.
And then I'm standing here
like a asshole
holding my Charles Dickens
'Cause I ain't got no muscle, no backup.
Shit, man.
Yo, if this was the old days?
Yeah, now, well,
the thing about the old days?
They the old days.
People I'm working with now?
So you want to bump
with Marlo over real estate?
You're on your own.
But, if you want my advice?
I don't, man. I don't.
Bodie. Yo, Bodie.
Me? I lost the wholesale to
every crew in Winchester homes.
Them horses takin' Marlo's shit now.
He pushin' the independents
over hilltop, too.
I lost 3 crews there this month.
What about the eastside?
There we got a much bigger problem:
All those ugly-ass bitches
in Yankee hats
chasin' all the locals away.
I heard them New York boys
ran off most of Delroy's people,
and those that stay
gotta take they package.
Man, all this theorizing
about how it be product,
not territory?
You can't talk that shit
if a nigga snatchin'
all of the territory
an' won't take none of your product.
See, the thing is Marlo's
only takin' a little bite.
Them New York cats is like
Wal-Mart comin' to town.
Me, personally,
I think it's time Wal-Mart went home.
If we gonna bump with 'em,
it's got to be all of us.
I tell you what?
I'd like to see Marlo
with us in on that one.
You know what I mean?
One big Baltimore team.
Yeah, Marlo can make an
inconvenient nigga disappear,
can't he?
I heard he got some kinda hookup
at this funeral home in Westport.
Coffin goes in there
needs 2 pallbearer.
Come out,
you need 8 to carry that bitch,
- you know what I mean?
- Nah, nah.
He usin' them shut-up rowhouses.
Dump a body in there,
no one can tell one smell from another.
Well, whatever he doin',
he cold, but he ain't stupid.
Think it's time to try again
to talk to the boy.
I hope you got better
shit to say than Stringer
'cause young'un ain't given
no one an ear yet.
Dag, Jimmy, you're
a domesticated motherfucker.
Yeah, I guess I am.
Yeah, we're good.
How's everything at the port?
Quiet.
It's quiet everywhere.
Even the western.
Yeah.
I'm having a hard time with it, though.
Somethin' ain't right.
Well, enjoy it while it lasts.
You working something?
Yeah, I got this one case.
I know who the shooter is
but can't find him.
He'll turn up.
Maybe.
More?
Oh, mercy. No, ma'am.
Dessert?
I was thinking,
we might go out for a little taste.
'Less you got to tuck in the kids.
I don't know.
Oh, it's fine, Jimmy. You go.
I'll tuck 'em in.
She trusts you.
Yeah.
Can't go to dinner
without catching a page?
What now?
Her John jumps in the shower.
She rummages his wallet.
He figures it out
and beats on her
till the people next-door
call the front desk.
Sir, if she doesn't
have the money on her,
I don't know what I can do.
Did you beat that woman in there?
I just want my money back.
Excuse me, Mr. Gergen.
I need a moment with
my director of security.
If she presses charges,
I'm cuffin' that motherfucker.
- Mr. Colvin, this is a delicate matter.
- Delicate? Shit.
Mr. Gergen represents
a national consortium
of convention planners,
and he's been a friend of the hotel--
Mr. Colvin? Mr. Colvin?
Now, you took his cash
and he beat you good, huh?
How much he beat you for?
How much?
Give me the cuffs.
No, Mr. Colvin. I...
What the fuck is this?
She steals my money,
and you're gonna lock me up?
You're gettin' charged with assault.
You wanna charge her with the theft,
I'll put the cuffs on her, too.
- But you in a wagon, shitbird.
- Mr. Colvin, this is not acceptable.
No. He's goin' in a wagon.
Mr. Colvin, I have to insist.
30 years a police officer.
I never took cuffs off a right charge.
Ain't about to start now.
You're not a police officer,
Mr. Colvin.
You work for us.
Naw, I'm good.
You nursin' that thing
like a baby bird.
You know those little
corner joints in the ghetto
that sell subs,
and fried chicken, lake trout?
Lake trout.
Like egg creams in New York.
No eggs, no cream.
Exactly.
No lake, no trout.
They're pogies.
White fish, trash fish.
Exactly. White trash fish.
I mean, "lake trout."
That's all marketing.
It's just all dressed up
like something it ain't.
You know what I'm sayin'?
Sometimes it is what it is.
It really is.
That's deep.
I like the way you think.
Yeah, you, too.
Hold on.
Dang, Bug,
if you can tie one shoe,
you can tie the other one.
You hear me?
Cookies all on your face.
Come on.
What up, shorty?
Ready for the first day?
Yeah, he can't wait to be in
the third grade. Ain't that right, bug?
'Sup?
Dukie.
Cool.
Look at all these big-ass
eighth graders out here.
Look like some sixth-graders
gonna get banked.
Yo, come in here.
I wanna show y'all somethin'.
Go ahead, Bug.
Yo, what up, boy?
That Jersey's crazy, son.
Where you get that at?
Yo, check it.
This dude in the joint
with my father drew these.
I'm about to get one on my arm.
Is this you?
Why would you get yourself on your arm?
In case you forget
what you look like?
Yo, what do these mean, man?
A'ight, this one means "heart,"
like, you know, "he got heart."
- And that means "lion."
- How you know that?
Word, the dude could be playing you.
Like, this one,
instead of "heart,"
it could mean like
"bitch" or something.
And like this one,
it could mean like "pussy" or "clown."
Come on, man.
Fuck y'all motherfuckers.
They probably do, too.
Man, get outta my house.
Understand something about me.
I may be wearing these bars,
but I worked the bricks to earn 'em,
and I am stone cold police first,
last, and always.
Froze my balls off in the winter,
sweated 'em in the summer,
ran, jumped,
rolled in the dirt
with the bad guys 24/7/365.
Now, I'm a great admirer of this unit.
Avon Barksdale?
That was a 14-point buck you bagged.
However,
we are gonna do better.
And if there's a case
to be made out there,
we'll make it together
With good work and good
supervision of that work.
I want to be briefed
every step of the way.
Questions?
No?
Good.
Yo, who you got?
I got... Prez...
Prez... what?
I got Mrs. Scott.
Fuckin' hate that foul bitch, man.
Man, she ain't that bad.
At least you ain't got Sampson.
Yeah, I know.
Yo, Michael, who you got?
Presborowski?
Pres...
yo, he new and white.
We got it made.
Look at this.
Where is your fine take-home car?
Got took home.
We need to talk.
Sixth-grade is on the first floor.
Seventh-grade is on the second.
Eighth-grade homeroom
is on the third floor.
Don't go up the down staircase.
Quickly and quietly, people.
I see you, Quantell.
I see you, too.
School's getting ready to start.
Come on.
Hi, dear.
Good to see you back.
Yo, what up, Turner.
You back for more?
Aw, damn, man.
I love the first day, son.
Everybody all friendly an' shit.
Namond Brice.
Already, we're starting?
Damn, man.
Next time, they stay in my drawer.
Yo, whatever, man.
I know, right? Already, son.
This case is crazy, son.
I know, right?
We're seventh graders.
Yo, dag. You see Neesy?
Yo, them bitches is on steroids, word.
Word, son.
Send them bitches to Iran.
That shit'd be over in a heartbeat.
- OK, check the chart
to see where you're sitting.
Check the chart.
Hi, I'm Randy.
How are you doing, Randy?
Check the chart.
OK. Good morning.
OK, good morning.
Yo! Shut up!
Good morning.
I'm your homeroom teacher,
obviously.
My name is Mr. Pryzbylewski.
But you can call me
Mr. Pryzbylewski.
OK. Let's find out who you are.
This is Mrs. Donnelly.
Teachers,
we had trouble with first bells,
so expect the class change
to ring in one minute.
Students will walk, not run,
to classes in an orderly manner.
OK, we'll, get to
know each other a little later.
Sorry. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Latifah.
Sorry.
Where my bus passes at?
Crystal Judkins, you're not listed.
Crystal?
I look like crystal to you?
I'm Charlene.
Ronald Parker?
Karim Williams.
Ronald over there.
Ah, geez.
Yo, Mr. Prez, I need
a hall pass for the bathroom.
It's an emergency.
Everyone. I need
those bus passes back.
Hold on.
Everyone, stay where you are.
Stay where--
I need those passes back.
It's an emergency.
Mr. Prez...
everyone, I need
those bus passes back.
The kids that need them...
- Mr. Prez...
- What?
- Just take one.
- I need those bus passes...
No one leaves this room
Until Mr. Pryzbylewski
gets those bus passes back.
Do I need to say that twice?
Thank you.
You'll get the hang of it.
Come in.
Are you coming in or what?
I'm coming in, OK?
You asked to see me, sir?
I did.
Seeing as how I like
to know my boys in depth:
why'd you want this unit?
Honestly?
I took the sergeant's test,
scored pretty high,
but not high enough,
and Lieutenant Hoskins,
we went through
the academy together.
He said that this--
This is a good detail
for going up the ladder.
I mean I know you
have to do it for a while,
but maybe next year,
if I do good here,
they'll reach down for me.
Next year?
I mean, for some things,
that's a long time to wait.
Excuse me?
I hear you're a good cop.
I also hear you recognize
who your friends are
and that you're loyal to them.
Did I hear all that right?
Absolutely.
Where are you on the list?
32. They took 15, but--
30-- man, I thought you were
gonna say something like 60,
or, u know, 95.
Let me call my man,
Burrell.
No need in wasting good police like you
chauffeuring around politicians.
I don't even know
what to say, Mr. Mayor.
This-- This is unexpected.
Don't mention it.
Today being the first day,
let's have some fun.
I'm gonna throw you
a little math puzzle,
see if I can get you
thinking on your feet.
Andre is leaving Baltimore...
Mr. Prezbo,
I need to change my seat
'cause this boy here
smells like a garbage can.
All right, you need to work a little
on your compassion skills.
Yeah, he needs to work a little
on his soap and water skills.
All right, like I was saying.
My friend Andre
is leaving Baltimore.
He's going 60 miles an hour...
hey, what side
of Baltimore, east or west?
It doesn't make
any difference.
That's what you think.
OK, east.
West, west, OK?
OK.
And he's going,
to Philadelphia...
man, Philly's ass.
- Yo, you think Allen Iverson is ass?
- OK, stop.
Yo, he only play for them.
He ain't from there.
Hey, I never play for the sixers
no matter how much they pay me.
Nigga, they'd pay yo' ass to go away.
Enough.
OK, Andre's leaving Baltimore,
west Baltimore,
traveling 60 miles per hour.
He's going to Philadelphia
which is 80 miles away.
- What kind of car?
- Hey, he drivin' on I-95,
he need to watch out
for the state police.
They be profilin' niggas.
He ain't say Andre was black, yo.
C'mon, Randy. Andre?
From the westside?
- Hey, he ain't say he was black.
- Yo, you know he black.
OK. OK.
I said OK!
Mr. Prezbo.
You say he travelin' in a car.
Is he driving?
Or is he like in the back seat?
All right, you know what?
Fun is fun...
Take your seats!
Everybody sit down!
Everything OK in here?
Why isn't Officer Massey present?
Working overnight on the wire.
Attendance at all office
meetings is now mandatory.
Inform her.
And this Marlo Stanfield?
This is the best we can do?
- Sir?
- This is the guy,
we're wasting months
chasing with a wiretap?
We could be on the street doing
a dozen other different things.
Stanfield is a comer.
He's got a lot of westside real estate.
How many bodies on him?
He fought a war against
the Barksdales last year
and dropped a few,
but nothing recent.
Nothing recent?
He owns west Baltimore
but with no bodies?
Maybe it's just me,
but in 18 years out there,
I have never seen
a carnivore eat a carrot.
He's been quiet for a time--
For a time?
This city's up to its hips in blood
and you are sitting on
one guy with a history?
OK, here's the new world order, guys.
I want good, quick rips.
6, 10, 12 felony cases a month.
That means no more long-ass wiretaps,
no more subpoenas,
no more mincing around on shit.
We get out on the street
and come back with stats.
The Barksdale case is closed,
and when the Stanfield wire
comes up for another 30 days,
we close out on that
as well. Understood?
You know, to hell with this.
We got a wiretap up,
and a judge decides when it comes down.
Well, Detective,
the deputy ops is gonna
talk to you about that.
Table b. put away
those cards away.
Kareem Myers. Sit down.
Yo, yo, list, listen.
Kit kats a dollar,
Snicker bars a dollar,
Warheads a dollar,
Twizzlers a dollar.
Man, sour patch 50 cent,
and gum 50 cent.
Anything you
can get at the store,
I can get in here for y'all.
- Gummi bears?
Ain't a problem.
I got Snickers, M&Ms.
Check this price and come holla at me.
I'm runnin' a 3 for 2 discount,
and I'm taking personal
orders for tomorrow.
- I'll be here tomorrow.
- So if you want something special,
just come holla at me.
There it is, yo.
Que pena mierda.
Why not give me a water pistol?
Hey, yo, Renaldo, you just
remember about how we gonna do.
It'll play.
Oye, gordo. The package.
Avanza, cabron!
With that raggedy-ass piece?
Nigga, is you crazy?
Loco or something?
Don't you know the shit is bulletproof?
You don't understand--
You heard what the boy said.
A box of newports.
Where my change, yo?
Don't wild me.
Hey, yo, you see the look on his mug?
That's the reason why
we get up every morning.
Now, Andre's friend Yvonne
Is supposed to meet him
in Philadelphia.
- Yeah.
- Andre gonna bone that skank.
Can you please shut up?
Mr. Prezbo is tryin'
to teach us somethin'.
You shut up, bitch.
He ain't teachin' me nothin'.
Yvonne, though,
is coming from New York.
So...
my question for you is--
A, who arrived in Philly
first, Andre or Yvonne?
And B, by how much time?
And C... who gives a rat's ass?
With this grant, the mandate
is not only to rethink
the way we utilize institutions,
but to help us start getting
past having to rely on jail
and drug rehab as our only responses.
We're looking for a specific
target group to inoculate,
epidemiologically speaking...
doctor, pardon me,
I'm not an academic.
Not by a long shot. But,
what exactly are you--
are you saying here?
He's sayin' he's got a lot of
money to come up with some way
to go at those boys out there
bangin' on the corners.
That's what I mean, yes.
So where do I come in?
Well, if the salary
arrangements are suitable,
your duties would be to perform
as a field researcher,
A liaison operating in the,
urban environment.
You go out in the 'hood
and get him some
corner boys to mess with.
See? This is why
I need somebody like you
to be paired up with me.
I go out there on my own--
and they sell
your tenured ass for parts.
In so many words.
Anyway, um, we're looking
for 18 to 21 year olds.
This is where we see the demographic
peak in violent behavior.
You excuse us for a minute?
What happens when
you ain't around to translate?
Don't play ignorant on me, Bunny.
You can back-and-forth
with any of these guys.
I've seen you work.
Besides, it's clear you ain't
cut out for the private sector.
18 to 21?
By that age,
they're deep in the game.
He's fucked on that.
So show him.
50,000, 80-20 health plan,
and a take-home vehicle.
I'd be amazed if they
give you 30, an H.M.O.,
and a bus pass.
YVONNE WINS BY 30 MIN OR HALF HOUR
Peace. See you later.
I go in there now,
you know what that makes me?
Some fucking asshole politician
who's running for office.
Watkins. 40th district.
- You call the reporters?
- All 3 channels and "the sun."
My condolences.
- I'm Thomas--
- I know who you are.
Thanks for your respects.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
We shouldn't be here today
just because...
your son
came forward as a witness...
what do you mean?
I know it's...
I'm just sorry for your loss.
That's all.
A parent's worst nightmare.
I don't know how anybody
can go on after this.
Yeah, me neither.
Ms. Daniels.
Councilman.
How's things going over
in the 11th district?
Harder than I'd hoped for.
Even on the mayor's ticket.
Yeah.
Eunetta's pretty well entrenched.
Good luck with it, though.
The council sure could use you.
Councilman Carcetti,
can you give us a minute?
- Councilman, over here.
- Do you mind doing a standup?
Look, guys,
I'm sorry, you know.
Now's not the time.
I don't really have anything to say.
I'm sorry.
- What, is he kidding?
- What did we come out here for?
You don't want the press coverage?
Are you out of your mind?
We'll get time on the 11:00
from the visual alone.
but I start making speeches
right here? Now?
How's that really gonna look?
Boss, as political theater,
this is pretty fucking lame.
Yeah, well, you know,
that depends on the audience.
This is Shawn Williams.
Lieutenant,
please call shift commander.
Boss, you want me to stay?
No. We're good.
So, Shawn...
you police. He ain't.
Shawn, how old are you?
18. How old are you,
you shinehead motherfucker?
You have a sister, Shawn?
What the fuck you want with my sister?
And what the fuck's this chucky
cheese-lookin' motherfucker writing?
Let's say you hear
that your sister was assaulted.
Who fucked with my sister?
- She wasn't. I'm just saying.
- Sayin' what?
Why you fuckin'
with my head, motherfucker?
And this bitch is writing again.
It's a habit.
Now, what would you do
if you heard your sister
got beat up by some guy?
Which sister?
I don't know. 'Cause it's Cherise,
she probably had it coming.
All right, another sister then.
Danielle?
I'd fuck that guy up.
I'd fuck his ass shut.
With you in jail.
I'd get my boy to do it.
What if you didn't have no boy?
Then I'd get the nigger
myself when I get out.
- What if you had a life sentence?
- Then I'll fuckin' escape.
And put that fuckin' pen down
'fore I shove it up
your motherfuckin' ass.
What if you couldn't escape, Shawn?
Fuck you.
Would you go to the police?
Just a question.
Son, thanks for being you.
Thanks.
Look, I'm ready
to acknowledge that...
18 to 21 might be too seasoned.
How you fixed for juveniles?
Right now? Fresh out.
The van to baby booking just left.
But are you looking
for kids in the system?
Or just kids?
'Cause if it is, you got Douglass
right around the corner,
- and school's in this week.
- High school?
That's what?
15 to 18, right?
Yeah, but I would...
I'd go younger even.
Kima. 'Sup, girl?
Are you sure?
C'mon. I'm the one who
took you out of the eastern,
sent you to the show.
You can't come back here;
you too good for a district.
I need a home, Major.
If you need to make a move,
move up or at leas lateral.
But a district
is you going backwards.
And you don't need to be
under my wing, either.
You're gonna be valued
no matter where you land.
Let me talk to people.
I especially liked the timing
for when you flew your paper.
Shrewd.
I couldn't see
anybody shutting us down,
not with the elections.
What asshole would risk the headline?
But to gut us from the inside out...
Charlie Marimow.
My trojan horse.
And now, let me guess,
to save your wire,
you're prepared to go to judge Davis.
If my memory serves,
this isn't the first time a deputy ops
felt the need to bury you.
You have a gift for martyrdom.
I wonder, though, are your disciples
as keen for the cross?
In your final court report,
it would be prudent to tell the judge
the investigation hit a dead end.
I doubt you'll believe it,
but... I respect the effort.
You're a hell of an investigator.
It would be too much to expect you
to serve under Lieutenant Marimow?
The man's a virus.
Homicide, then.
That's you, right?
Yeah.
I know it's hard
right now, Detective.
but...
try to think on this as a favor.
This seems right.
Yeah.
So I understand my old unit's
gone to Lieutenant Marimow.
Yes, it has.
So that unit is...
yes, it is.
That's a shame.
I need to ask if you could
take care of my girl Greggs.
She's a good cop
looking for a home,
and I think she'd be
a natural homicide.
Well, there was an opening.
Just filled that last night.
Another fugitive
from major crimes,
but...
for you, Major?
Let me see who I don't love no more.
OK, so, if a rocket travels say,
1,000 miles an hour,
how far does it go in an hour?
Darnell.
Chiquan?
As far as it wants. I mean,
it's a rocket ship, right?
Randy?
Is this a trick question?
Nope.
1,000 miles?
On the money.
Mr. Prezbo,
I was gonna say that.
Go 'head, bitch.
Laugh at me now.
What?
You want some?
You on the fucking floor, bitch.
Laugh at me now.
I don't hear shit.
Crystal, have the office call 911,
and get the nurse.
Everybody in your seats.
Just lay still.
Just keep putting pressure on it.
You're going fine.
Chiquan, you're doing fine.
Just hold on
for a few more minutes.
It's gonna be OK.
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
www.thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net