See, to cap a motherfucker,
you put a pistol to his head,
say, "pow," and he tagged.
- But when Chris and them do it--
- It ain't working, nay.
I know you making this up.
Word to my mother, yo.
Lex ain't dead. I seen him creeping in
an alley last night near the playground.
Everybody know Lex is dead.
Nah, there's dead,
and there's special dead.
Yeah,
Chris working that juju shit.
Nah, man.
What I'm saying is they zombies.
Why you think he take them
into vacants?
He need time to change them.
You don't believe me,
yo, it's on you.
Yo, they funnin', ain't they, Michael?
I don't know about
that voodoo shit, man,
but Chris is definitely
doing something.
Get a nigger to walk up in there
knowing he about
to get capped, man.
Chris, he different.
You can tell by them coon-ass
country clothes that nigger be wearing.
9?
Nah, too much bark.
Probably a 40-cal.
Yeah, man,
this is serious business.
So you saying Lex is a zombie?
Pookie, Byron,
all them niggers.
- And Chris?
- Yeah, Chris--
zombie master.
I knew this wasn't going away.
That's what we've been
trying to tell you, yo.
Chris got the power.
He tell them to come,
and they got to come,
like the devil do
with the damned.
What you think
Chris got them doing?
Probably spies, man.
Can't figure any other way
Marlo knows so much.
Yeah, that's what it is.
Like in this movie,
"zombie killer" or something,
they came out at night,
hunting.
- Hunting?
- Yeah, man. They...
yeah, and in that movie,
they was snatching people up,
stealing their warmth.
4x05 - Alliances
St. Jude,
patron of lost causes.
Tell me you ain't
been on bended knee
whispering in his saintly ear
each and every night
before you close those peepers.
I know you have, Tommy,
catch a break like this.
Stan, you're sure about this?
On my mother's soul,
it's a lock.
Assigned a rookie--
a broad, no less--
as lead detective.
Pulled a good man off, too, I heard.
Tom.
Tommy, remember,
anything you need.
He's a piece of work.
Valchek?
Comes with the territory.
You want the first district
council seat,
you make nice with whatever
Polish or Greek Commander
- they dump in the southeast.
- Not Italian.
There ain't enough of us
left down there.
You think he has this right?
- That Royce tampered with the case?
- No way the mayor knows.
You're right. This one has
Ervin Burrell written all over it.
Fuck if the mayor knows or not.
If it's true, we get it out there quick
and bang him hard.
I go public?
They can't spin this.
They sabotaged a criminal case.
No spin on a knuckleball,
you still can't tell
how it's gonna break.
We feed it to Tony Gray.
We keep ourselves out of the line
of fire, sting Royce,
and as an added bonus,
give Gray's campaign a boost
which comes at the expense
of the mayor's base.
I'm a devious motherfucker
once I get going.
So, all told,
we're looking at 13 warrants
and 6 locations.
And given my staffing situation...
not a problem.
I can give you my D.E.U.,
flex, and ops squads.
A sector of uniforms
if you need it.
- Great.
- The problem is,
you're wasting a wiretap
on street-level arrests.
We do these raids right,
we might catch Marlo or one of his
lieutenants at one of these locations,
get them with dope on the table.
Marlo Stanfield.
In a room.
With dope on the table.
I've kicked down doors
and surprised bigger players than him.
Well, let me warn you, Lieutenant,
I am not about to litigate
a wiretap for a handful of street rips.
Well...
that's on you, Counselor.
No, it's not.
Major, see you tomorrow.
Floaters. You had any more?
No more than usual for the season.
What about decomps?
What do you got
in the decomp room?
- 2 or 3 unidentifieds.
- Found in Baltimore?
No, actually, two from Prince George's,
one from Dorchester.
Nah, he wouldn't drive that far.
Let me get this straight.
You're looking for extra bodies,
no one in particular,
other than this one kid you
already put out on the teletype.
Yeah. You on it.
You fellas don't have enough work?
If you do your classwork,
homework,
you earn stickers.
Dag, yo, every day
you be changing it up.
You got us confused, Mr. P.
Behave in class,
that's another sticker.
At the end of the week,
the 4 with the most stickers
get a prize
and are eligible for a grand drawing
at the end of the month.
Don't do your work,
misbehave in class...
your name goes here.
Detention.
A full hour after school,
no exceptions.
So it's up to you:
stickers for prizes
or stay with me after school.
Yo, Mr. P.
Why you do me detention?
You interrupted the class, Namond.
Yo, when you
first came in here,
you was all treating us straight up,
and now you just dog me
before I even know the rules.
That ain't right, man.
When you're right, Namond,
you're right.
Hey, Mr. P.,
I want me some of them stickers.
Zenobia,
you have to do your work.
I want to,
but I ain't got no pencils.
I don't want no damn
welfare pencil!
It seems to me
there are two kinds of kids
walking in this building:
stoop kids, corner kids.
- Excuse me?
- You know, stoop kids.
The ones who stay on their front
steps when their parents tell them.
The others go down
to the corners.
They can't sit still in the class.
The others can and do.
So separate the two.
- That's tracking.
- Excuse me?
Tracking students.
It's a nasty phrase
in educational circles.
It refers to the grouping of children
based on expected performance.
Well, what's wrong with it?
It says you have reduced
expectations for certain students,
that you expect less from them
academically.
So you pretend
to teach all these kids,
and the truth is,
you ain't teaching any of them.
but what if the stoop kids
could be in classrooms
- where there was no disruptions?
- And the corner kids?
They're the ones you're after, right?
That's why you got the grant money.
As long as this doesn't
involve warehousing children,
I'm for anything that
allows me to do my job.
Every teacher here
will tell you the same.
The trick for you
is to come up with a program
that actually addresses itself
to the corner kids.
I don't know. If we pull kids
out of regular classes,
won't they be stigmatized?
There's not a stigma at being
booted out of class every other day?
Question is,
how do we identify the corner kids?
That won't be a problem.
OK.
You understand the work?
Come on, this is easy.
I know you can do it.
You're not giving me a choice.
You have detention.
Yo, nay, Mrs. D. shaking bushes.
Back to your seats.
What the fuck?
She got my blade, yo.
I said, back to your seats.
Yo, Mrs. D. Be stealing shit.
I ain't never gonna
get my blade back.
Yo, you all up on me for?
I do my work.
I'm not your yo.
Show me your work.
Yeah, I see.
Yo, my hand hurting
from all this learning.
You got some tylenol?
What I got for you is detention.
Yo, fuck you, Prezbo.
Fucking gimpy-assed,
big-grill motherfucker.
That's it. You're out of here!
Go!
Get your police stick
out your desk and beat me.
You know you fucking want to.
Everyone back in your seat.
The fuck you looking at, bitch?
Ms. Sampson, I--
Namond Brice, if you weren't
headed to the main office,
you are now.
Yeah, I was just...
one of the corner kids, huh?
Yeah, they do step up
when you need them, don't they?
Look, what? You want me
to say you right, you right.
Should have had protection
at the card game.
Done is done.
Now we need to decide
what we're gonna do about Omar.
You make the price right,
somebody gonna get a whiff
of that bushwhacker's ass.
Now, you take it from there.
You think so?
I ain't saying Omar can't be got.
Any nigger can be got.
But once we put word to ear
and he learn
that we pricing out his head,
he's gonna be trying us
like we're trying him.
You saying
I should let it slide?
Nah.
Nah, we get at him another way.
Get at him without no bounties,
no bullshit like that.
I mean, Barksdale turned this
town upside down hunting him,
and all he ended up
looking was weak.
I ain't no Barksdale.
I'm just saying talk is cheap.
We sit on it, We gonna figure out
a way to get that faggot.
But till then,
we don't say a mumbling word.
I got me 6 now,
and I'll give you the 4 later,
all right? Come on!
Nah. I'm gonna need the whole 10 now.
Sherrod!
You ain't in school?
I'm half a day.
Teachers' meeting.
Come on, I told you
about those lame excuses, man.
I was talking to him first.
Ain't no need for physical--
you got $4.00 for me?
I'm short $4.00.
What the fuck are you talking!
Got a cart full of shit, nigga.
What you got for me?
I know you holding.
Where's it at?
You ain't hear?
It's in my shoe. My shoe.
Don't need the 4 now, son.
Damn, yo, where the shovel at?
Bury that nigger, man.
Here you go, sir. Thank you.
- Tommy Carcetti, running for mayor.
- Good luck, Tommy.
- Mr. Carcetti, you got my vote.
- Thanks.
- Tom Carcetti.
- Hey. Thank you very much.
Good luck, councilman.
How you doing?
Tommy Carcetti, running for mayor.
OK, councilman,
time to hit the west side.
Pretty motherfucker.
Gonna make me
go to my game face.
OK. I'll take 25 of
the honeysuckle incense cones.
Keep me healthy for next week.
Tommy!
Excuse me.
Tony Gray's people
say 20 minutes at their place.
Shit, Clarence.
Look like you did in '98 when you
surprised the hell out of everyone.
Bring 'em on.
Why give it to us?
Why don't you stick it
to Royce yourself?
Because after what Tommy did
at the debate,
it'll seem like more of the same
if it comes from him.
And if we use it to take 4
or 5 points out of Royce's base,
helps him as much as us.
Once bitten, twice shy.
With Tommy Carcetti, I got
to always think a step ahead.
Look, Tony.
You ain't gonna win.
So the only question is
whether you want to lose with
24% of the vote or 28%.
You bring the numbers up,
you look good for the legislature.
Maybe a congressional run.
Albert stokes.
Here. Mr. P., can I go?
My mom's told me to go
straight home after school.
- Mine, too.
You should have thought of that
before you smeared ink all over my desk.
Weren't my fault.
My pen exploded.
Michael. Michael Lee?
Mr. P., please, can I go?
I ain't eat no lunch, and my
stomach making all these noises.
Look. I won't ever disrespect
your pencil again, I promise.
Zenobia, it wasn't
about the pencil.
Please, Mr. P.
OK. OK.
- All right.
Just this one time,
I'll make an exception.
But next time,
expect to stay the full hour.
Why are you here?
Came to say sorry.
I didn't mean to get all
up in your face like that.
I appreciate that, Namond.
It takes courage
to admit when you're wrong.
What I can't understand,
I've seen you in Ms. Sampson's
class doing your work.
Why can't you
do the same in here?
I mean to, I do.
It's just the evil get in me,
and before I know it, I go off.
Well...
tomorrow we'll see
if we can't do better.
Can't tomorrow.
Mrs. D. Put me out.
I got to bump. Later, Mr. P.
If you can wait outside...
it's OK. He can stay.
Thank you.
Mr. P., you know Michael
can't make it to detention.
I know he didn't.
Now it's double.
He's got two days to serve.
Nah. I mean he can't.
He got to go pick up
his little brother from school.
Well, he'll just have to
find somebody else to do that.
It-- It ain't like that.
I mean,
Michael would come if he could,
but wouldn't have nobody else
to pick up his little brother bug.
You know, his mother,
she on that stuff.
We walking home. You coming?
Oh, no. I'm waiting on Alpo.
Ms. Sampson got him
doing detention.
You gonna be here till, like, 5:00.
Yeah. She a hard lady.
She don't ever give
a brother no play.
Well, all right, man.
I'll holla at you later.
All right, yo.
So you're not gonna be
in the NBA?
Then it must be the NFL?
I thought all the boys in class
were gonna join the pros.
Nah, that's just something we say.
So what about you?
What do you want to be
when you grow up?
I'm gonna own my own store.
That's smart.
You're gonna need to know
a lot of math.
You left them in there.
Hey, don't worry, Mr. P.
We got you.
Hey, donut!
Yo, donut's crazy with cars.
He can open anything.
What up, man.
He locked his keys in there.
It's OK. I can call AAA.
Oh, no problem, chief.
Feel the need
to work them corners, huh?
I'm just asking because you don't
need to be doing what you're doing.
I need to learn some shit
on my own.
I'm trying to help you, Sherrod,
but you making it so I can't.
I didn't even know
the man who beat on you, Bubs.
He was short money
on the corner.
I swear he wasn't nothing to me.
Yeah, but when the shit start,
There's nothing to be done, right?
What would I have done
if he started wailing on you?
Same kind of nothing, see?
That's how the corners be.
They gonna use you up, Sherrod.
You welcome to stay tonight,
but you ain't in school
tomorrow morning,
this partnership need to be done.
These two precincts
are the bellwether for the fifth.
If you can take even 18%
out of Carcetti in these,
it's a good guess he won't
have the numbers citywide.
And who are we ticketed
with over here?
The N.D.O., I hope, because...
...this amid allegations
...that high-ranking
police officials intervened
to have a veteran police detective
removed from the controversial case.
the Braddock murder became a
focal point in the mayoral campaign
when councilman
Thomas Carcetti alleged
the west Baltimore man was killed
because he was a witness in the case.
Because they were afraid
the police would prove
what they most fear,
that Fredro Braddock was murdered
because he was a witness
and the city failed to protect him.
It's on all 3 channels.
And the "Sun" and the "Post"
are both calling for comment.
And my sources within the department
say the rank-and-file officers
are simply appalled by
this blatant political manipulation.
Damn. Turn it up.
Hey, Greggs, you're famous.
...is to remove
a highly decorated veteran,
15 years experience
as a murder investigator,
without reason...
- That'd be me.
- Then replaced with a rookie
who has yet to handle
a single homicide investigation.
That'd be you.
- then we need to rethink...
- the fuck I ever do to him?
You gonna make it too heavy, yo.
It might work
if we make it bigger.
It would work if we had balsa wood,
you know. It's really light and strong.
Man, you so full of...
oh, shit.
Zombie master.
Need to take us a little walk.
Nah, I'm good here.
Young'uns need to move along.
Sure, Chris, we'll bump.
Yo, Snoop,
your sister in my class.
What the fuck?
You high or something, nay?
You boys be smoking that shit?
Hearing good things about you.
Say you straight up,
take care of your people,
not begging no handouts.
Motherfucker, you hear
the nigger talking to you,
giving you praises and shit.
You standing here
looking fucking stupid.
Yo, chill.
Sometimes, she get a little hot.
I'm just saying
the boy ain't right!
Yo, we always in the market
for a good soldier.
When we see one we like,
we take care of the situation.
Take him in, school him,
make him family.
And if you're with us,
you're with us,
just like we'd be with you
all the way.
You have a mind, you're in.
Look, man.
I already got a family.
My moms and my little brother--
Yeah. Heard that.
But think on it.
We'll be around
if you need something.
He saw me, yo. I knew it.
I knew Chris was asking Michael
about me.
I knew it, man. I'm dead.
Yo, man, good looking out.
- I thought they was gonna--
- Yeah, I know.
What did he ask about me?
I know he asked about me.
What'd you tell him?
Calm down.
It weren't even about you, man.
For real, man, you need to tell me.
What did he ask you?
Yo, you right, man.
Chris was all up
in your business.
He down on you
for some deep shit, man.
I don't even know what.
Nah, I'm just fucking
with you, man.
He didn't even speak your name.
Oh, man.
So, Erv, what's next?
Your officers gonna shoot
a couple of tourists?
Maybe fly a helicopter
into harbor place?
What can we expect the last week
of my reelection campaign?
Sir, I did what you asked--
no more, no less.
Hamsterdam--
legalized drug zone?
He takes responsibility for that.
- The subpoenas all over town.
- That, too.
The leak about the witness murder.
I mean, that was his shop, too, right?
- Hell, yeah.
- And now, this last thing,
transferring detectives
off the case.
What is that?
Scuttling the investigation.
Yeah, right.
Yeah, that's awful. Jesus.
Mr. Mayor, you asked me
to slow that investigation down.
Subtle, Ervin?
You hold a few facts
for a few weeks.
You put a report or two
in a desk drawer.
But the transferring of people
off a case?
Look. You told me
you specifically
wanted me to not--
Ervin, you may leave.
- Mr. Mayor--
- That will be all, commissioner.
No, I need a word or two
with your deputy, Ervin.
Have a seat.
I tried to warn him.
I mean, if it leaked out of
homicide about the dead witness,
why wouldn't it leak
that we bumped a detective?
Why didn't you
come to us beforehand?
I'm a loyal subordinate, Mr. Mayor,
and Ervin is a good man working
under considerable pressure.
He's a hack.
You're not bothered
by the pressure, deputy?
Not in the least.
I need you to make this go away, Bill.
I won't forget, believe me.
Another thing--
Slim Charles got up with me.
Said the fat man want a sit-down.
Nah. I did that already.
Well, Slim say the fat man knew
the card game was gonna get took.
He did, did he?
Set it up.
Why you always be back here?
Quiet.
And I can see what comes.
But you out in the weather and shit.
I don't like to speak in no rooms.
Yeah.
Yo. You ain't staying long.
So you know,
I almost got that for you.
I just need
a couple of days more.
You can keep my money for now.
I got something
that needs doing.
Anything, Marlo. Your call.
Omar gonna come in your store,
stick it up, rob you.
You gonna call the police,
make a report.
- You feel me?
- Yeah, that'll work, but...
you know when he get out,
he's coming right at me.
I ain't scared or nothing.
I'm just saying, you know?
He ain't gonna get out.
A man make bail on robbery.
Make it no bail.
If you have a problem,
like you can't make it to detention,
you need to tell me.
That's your responsibility.
People will be more than willing
to help you out,
but it's up to you to ask.
You can go back to the cafeteria...
or hang up here.
Duquan.
Could you come here?
I thought maybe you
could help me out.
I packed too much.
Take this down to the cafeteria
and get yourself something
to drink from the machine.
Thank you.
Crystal, you got a second?
What's up with Duquan?
I gave him some new clothes.
I was expecting--
He might have lost them.
That fast?
It weren't that.
His people take his clothes,
sell it on the corners.
You're kidding.
No, sir.
Everybody knows.
Which brings me to
what we're proposing.
Different kids,
different approaches.
You tell us who we need to touch
at north avenue to get the go-ahead.
The puzzle palace?
Look. If y'all still
want to jump in and help,
I'm fine with it.
That's about all the OK
you need in my house.
The Stricker Street situation
is waiting in the office.
Neighborhood squabbles,
and my babies bring it in here.
Two fights yesterday,
all because the mothers
can't get along.
I got to go.
Mrs. Donnelly will work out
the nuts and bolts.
But, just so you hear it,
thank you.
It'll be the only time anyone
in this system will think to say it.
He's a good man.
You need to protect him.
Protect him?
Principal Withers just
went out on a limb for you,
and in this system,
they know how to handle a chainsaw.
Excuse me?
Anyone has a problem
with what we're doing, it's on him.
So, you specified
eighth-graders?
We have 256 on roll.
241 attend on a regular basis.
Of those, 40 or so would fit
your Bill of corner kids.
40?
Pretty workable.
What would you suggest?
Start with 10 or so.
Ms. Sampson has enough
to get you going.
One of them
named Namond Brice?
Pick of the litter.
But you'll have to wait.
He's on a 3-day suspension.
Remember when I was a cadet,
I was up here
on a cadaver search.
Instructor gets
on the radio to say,
we're looking for one body
in particular.
"If you go grabbing
everyone you see,
we'll be here all day," he says.
Leakin Park,
where West Baltimore
brings out its dead.
Not anymore,
from the look of things.
Not by the roadside, anyway.
If he's dumping them here,
he's dumping them
deep in the woods.
Come on.
At each raid site,
we're anticipating
dope or cash or guns.
All warrants are for prime locations
linked to high-level violators.
Weeks-old addresses
linked to low-level corner boys.
We'll also be sweeping drug
corners at these locations.
Wagons will hold
in this location here.
Jump-off time, 1500 hours.
We take our position 10 minutes
before the assault, here.
The go is on my say-so.
Questions?
Excellent.
We'll hold the rec room
till it's time to stage.
Warrants are one thing,
but street sweeps on
Marlo Stanfield's crews?
Are you guys serious?
Carv, you give these
hoodleheads too much credit.
Trust me on this, boy wonder.
Never mind this horseshit.
So what've they got you
doing for your man?
Who, the Lieutenant?
No, Royce.
Herc, the mayor's your meal ticket.
He gets another 4 years,
you're liable to wear the Gold braids.
Shouldn't you be out waving
a campaign sign or some shit?
And so ends the last crusade
of the major crimes unit.
With a whimper.
Lester would cry to see his
wiretap cannibalized for that crap.
Street sweeps
on Marlo Stanfield?
So what else you got cooking?
Narcotics cases?
C.I.D. Has the Burman indictment
coming in.
Nothing past that.
As wars go, this drug thing
seems to rate less and less.
If Demper wins and manages
to forgive my trespasses,
maybe I'll go in
and beg for something new.
I don't know.
Just...
feels like enough's enough.
Crutchfield. Line two. Intake.
- Sergeant, you were looking for me?
- I was, yeah.
Curly fry?
Chicken doohickey?
Sit down.
Norris is back
on the Braddock case.
It's by order of the deputy ops.
In fact, we're gonna go with a story
that says he was never off the case,
that you and he are partnered,
a task force of two,
working it together.
Fuck you, fat man.
Not original, but succinct.
I like your approach.
Y'all humiliate me once
by dropping me into this thing,
and now you're gonna shame me again
by bringing Norris back.
This is homicide, detective.
This is not some
boiler room unit
where no one pays attention to whatever
the fuck it is you call police work.
The bosses?
They know our names up here.
Now, I didn't like it
when they came to me
and told me to dump Norris,
but dump him I did.
And it's not like I want
to carry water for them now
that they're pretending they
never told me to do any such thing,
but carry the water I will.
And in the end,
when everyone else in this unit
is buried and beshitted,
this detective Sergeant
will still be standing.
So...
get the story straight.
Norris was always the primary,
and you are now assisting
on an investigation
which is progressing
even as we speak.
Does the Colonel know about this?
He's in the hospital.
Chemo didn't work.
Press conference is upstairs
in half an hour.
So don't be late.
Press conference?
I ain't mean to laugh at you none.
I know it sound crazy,
but I ain't joking.
For real, Lex a zombie.
I knew it way before
what nay and them was saying.
Listen.
They had me tell Lex
to go up to the playground.
I told him to go up there
and see some girl.
He ain't never come back down.
So what they gonna do to me
when they get mad at me?
It makes sense Chris taking them
into the vacants--
to change them...
and you know what else.
That ain't what he's doing.
Chris and the vacants...
changing them?
He ain't changing them;
he killing them.
That's all.
They're getting killed.
How you know?
Can't tell nobody.
I seen it.
I seen them walk a boy up into
one house over there on Calhoun.
You seen that?
Yeah.
That's just false.
Detective Norris has been
working this case nonstop,
and given her narcotics expertise,
detective Greggs was assigned to
augment rather than to replace him.
But for two days,
sources inside the department
were saying--
I'm inside the department,
and I'm telling you that's not true.
We do not play politics
with a criminal investigation.
And how do you explain
councilman Gray's allegations?
I think you should ask
councilman Gray that question.
Police! Search warrant!
Take the back.
On the ground, now!
Police! Search warrant!
Two upstairs.
- Don't move!
- Check that back room.
I said, get your ass on the ground.
- Get down!
This is the 1300 block, right?
No, this is the 12.
Are we on the right corner?
- We had this as a stash house?
- According to the wiretap.
How long ago?
They move them around, you know.
Zeroes on the warrants.
Minor arrests on
the designated corners, sir.
- They were tipped!
- You think?
For us to come up this empty
at all these locations, It has to be.
This cocksucker Marlo
thinks he's smarter than us?
He is not.
Sergeant, I want to know
where he hangs.
You mean like him personally?
He moves around, Lieutenant.
He floats.
But I have seen him in the
concrete park behind Fulton.
- In a park?
- If the weather's right,
he sits out there in
lawn chairs, holds court.
He's got people covering every approach
so there's no creeping up on him.
My guess is that he likes
to talk outdoors
so no one can drop
a microphone on him.
Sergeant,
what can we do with that?
I admit I've made some mistakes.
Burrell being one of the biggest.
He's got a job
for about 10 more days.
After the primary, he's gone,
believe me.
And that last stunt--
pulling a detective.
What'd you expect?
Not that.
Hey. I had nothing to do
with that nonsense.
Now, that's a straight-up lie.
I was at that damn meeting
when you told him,
"Slow the case down."
I didn't mean--
Who the hell knows
what you mean anymore, Clarence?
Look at this.
Look at it!
You gave me your word on this.
Your word, Clarence.
But here you are ticketed up
with Eunetta in her best precincts
and then ticketed up
with my girl Daniels,
where she's running strong.
Odell, this is the first
I've seen this.
Come on, now! This is probably
Eunetta's people pulling this shit.
With a "citizens for Royce"
authority line?
Look at you, Clarence.
Just look at you.
You've forgotten your agenda.
You've forgotten your base.
You think a shave and some
Marcus Garvey posters
are gonna get you over?
Do you think that's gonna make up
for jumping in bed
with every damn developer?
Shit. You're even on
Clay Davis' tit.
Now, don't you go getting all
self-righteous with me, Odell.
Campaign runs on dollars.
You know it.
Whose dollars?
Those sons of bitches you got
around your card table every month
feeding your kitty?
Oh, yeah.
I know about that, too.
You-- trouble with you--
fuck you, Clarence.
I'm gonna sit what's left
of this one out.
- I'm gonna sit it out.
- Sit it out.
- The primary?
- Sit it out!
Odell!
Who the hell do you
think you are, huh?
Come November, I'm still gonna
be the only game in town!
Odell, turn your back on me now,
I won't forget!
We can't afford this.
We need his organization on Tuesday.
Go after him!
Fuck that holier-than-thou...
motherfucker!
Delegate Watkins.
Delegate Watkins!
Wait sir.
I'm sure we can work this out.
You and the mayor can talk this out.
Deputy Rawls, please.
It's Lieutenant Hoskins at the hall.
You're gonna use
the hole in the wall, right?
Yeah, I'm gonna rub some dog
shit on the front of this thing.
I don't want nobody touching it.
Got it?
You need to raise it a bit.
Yeah, that's good.
Right there, that works.
- Thought I heard something.
- Rats.
- How we doing?
- We need to go.
He ain't nothing but a skanky-ass
bitch to begin with,
and besides, he ex-police,
so you know what that like.
I'm going to the ladies room.
Bey, you need to talk to him.
Yo, daddy,
don't even go there,
with you all the time telling me
how you dropped out in the sixth grade,
went up on the corner
with Avon and Stringer.
Earned cheese for the family,
saying how it made you a man--
all right, all right.
You right.
Can't throw rocks.
But I'm just saying.
You know how your mother be,
with all the fussing.
Maybe you just need
to slow it up.
You know what I'm saying?
Yo, you heard
how Marlo punked Bodie?
Said he either got to work
for him or give up his corner.
Don't you know,
his sorry ass buckled.
You'd have gone about it different?
Yeah, I'd have stood tall, like you.
Got my 9. Fuck Chris and them.
Listen to you,
all spit and fire.
You'd have gone to the mattress
all by your lonesome
and went up against
half of the west side.
You got it where it counts,
and I respect that
more than anything.
But shit out there now?
It ain't like it was
when we was coming up.
Back in the day,
a punk nigger like Marlo steps out,
breaking the rules and shit,
he find himself in the back
of a car trunk
on the way to Leakin Park.
No doubt.
We did that shit right.
Word was your bond.
Man looked out for his own,
knowing he in a family.
Dig where I'm coming from?
But today, it's all fucked up.
These steps.
Thank you, baby.
You're good to go.
Say "Omar."
Omar.
Nothing?
We checked both
sides of the street
from here up to Monroe.
- Nothing?
- Nothing that don't belong in no sewer.
Thanks.
Other ideas?
Blood,
bump me off that nigger up the screen.
Motherfucker in the Buick?
That be him.
I be saying,
No motherfucker gonna run off
with my hair-ron.
Oh, this is fucking great.
Get somebody who reads lips,
this motherfucker's history.
Is this legal? I mean,
intercepting what they're saying?
Don't go Freamon on me.
Shit. I got to run.
Hey, man, what about
some fucking relief?
I been here all morning.
You heard?
They making movies.
Yeah.
How you want to play it?
I ain't sure.
Let's see the fat man.
How'd the other thing turn out?
All good.
Yo.
What up, boy?
- If you want some, I got Reese's.
- Nah, man.
You trying to make some real cheese?
- $5.00?
- What you need?
Me and Paul gonna get it on
with Tiff.
Keep an eye out.
I don't want Mrs. D creeping up.
Feel me?
I feel you, but I got some sixth-graders
waiting on a special order.
Let them wait, man.
It ain't like we gonna be all day.
All right.
No, ma'am, it says right here,
His honor had the bureau of solid waste
conduct a clean sweep along Tivoly.
But it took 6 months
before they showed up.
Well, yeah, OK.
Well, nobody's perfect.
But, listen. I wouldn't be sitting here
If I didn't believe Clarence Royce
wasn't truly committed
to this city and its people.
What about crime
in our neighborhood?
I admit that's another good point.
But, lady, between you and me,
I can tell from your voice
you're black
and you can tell from my voice
I'm white.
So I got to ask you,
when do you think the last time
a white man voted for a black man
when there was
another white man in the race?
I don't know, but you must
really believe in him.
Well, ain't that what I been saying?
He's just the best candidate.
So you'll go with my man?
I'll think about it.
All right, that's great.
Thank you for your time.
- All right.
I have a hall pass.
Yeah, good for you.
Mine's down.
Attaboy.
You need bodies, Lester...
here you go.
We got a warrant and a teletype
for my boy Lex.
So, dead or alive,
he's on file.
And beyond that, it's time for you to
shine that mighty intellect of yours
on some real murders.
Give up the hypotheticals and shit.
Yeah, I suppose.
This is my issue-- crime--
and I understand completely
what you're saying,
and if you give me
the opportunity,
I will be able to do something
to help you out
and, you know, other people
in this neighborhood.
Mr. Ricks, thank you for your
time and for your attention.
- No problem.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Pretty brazen,
shaking hands with the enemy
in broad daylight.
Werner's deli, this isn't.
Definitely not.
Though here you are, councilman,
leaving no door unopened.
Shoe leather--
our secret weapon.
You surprised me.
You've made this a horse race.
So, ah, what makes me think
you didn't just happen by
and find us here?
Watkins is breaking with the mayor.
How do you know?
I know.
I've carried the mayor's water
because I had to, councilman.
I'd love to see
some new blood in this city.
And I'd love the chance
to do the right thing for this
police department for a change.
Wait until he turns the corner.
District office for Watkins.
Gilmor street.
And fuck them red lights, man,
not a place you expect
to find any gangsters.
Police, for that matter.
Heard you knew something I didn't.
Told you before,
I make it my business
to keep an ear to the ground.
to do business.
We doing business,
or are we just talking?
If it's talk, I'm-a walk.
I heard the people pulling
security at the card game
weren't too keen on their wages.
Figured it was only a matter of time
before they found a way
to get their due compensation.
And you didn't think to tell me?
Man learns best
when he get burned.
How do I know
you ain't making this shit up?
You don't.
Things happen on the street.
Proof is hard to come by.
Go ahead, open it.
Off the street,
there's all kind of proof.
They planning
on executing those Friday.
Time it with the election,
I guess,
show they doing their job,
cleaning up the city,
taking down a kingpin.
How did you come by this?
Told you before,
I keep my ear to the ground.
What are you gonna do with it?
Maybe nothing.
Charlie's not part of the co-op.
Or maybe I tip him for a fee.
What do you think a man
with a whole lot of money
would pay for his freedom?
You know, lately,
I come to find out someone
trying to take pictures on me.
Pictures?
Video.
You heard anything about me
through your travels?
Had no incentive to listen.
You do now.
It's one thing
to sit out the primary.
It's another for me
to turn on Clarence Royce.
Granted.
And if I did jump,
why not land behind Tony Gray?
At least he's from
my side of the tracks.
Tony can't win.
I can.
Look. The truth is,
whatever I can do for you,
the mayor can match or double.
I have a pretty good
grass roots organization,
but nothing even close
to his kind of money.
Now, I'll ticket up
with anyone you want me to.
I know you want Daniels in the 11th
and stokes in the 10th.
I'll keep away from any tickets
you think I might harm.
I know I'm not everyone's idea
of a bargain on your side of town.
But right now,
a week from the primary,
the fact is,
Royce and I both need you.
After the election,
the equation changes for him,
but not for me.
I'm a white mayor
in a majority-black city,
and if I'm gonna do anything--
and, delegate, I am so serious
about fixing this city--
I'm gonna have to govern by consensus.
And if you support me, you will have
a voice within my administration
simply because
I'm gonna need it.
Last poll that Clarence showed me,
he was up by 7 points.
Bullshit. I'm within 4.
You won't be needing that.
I know.
- Here?
- Yeah, here.
Dag.
Yo, turn it off.
The bulb might have got too hot.
Or the batteries dying.
We should go back.
Yo, man, it stinks, man.
Ain't like it was.
You see he ain't move.
Yeah.
Blood still stuck to his hair.
He dead?
He dead.
Lex, too.
He dead. They all is.
Feel better?
Donut wrong, yo.
Ain't no special dead.
There's just dead.
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - www.thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net