Hullo...
Hey, what are you doing?
Oh, hi.
Are you sleeping?
No.
What, you're not happy
to hear from me?
No, I'm glad you called.
I want to see you.
Now?
Yes, now.
Where are you?
Same place as before.
Peabody.
Are you sure
you're not sleeping?
No, no, I was up.
You liar.
Come on, get
your ass over here.
Yeah, okay, I mean,
yeah, what the hell.
Room 210.
Fine.
Sean, Seanie...
What?
I have to go out and see
a friend for a little bit.
I'll be gone for
an hour or two, okay?
I put my cell phone number
is on this slip of paper.
I'll put it on that
top shelf, okay?
What did I just say?
You're going out
to see a friend
and your number is
on the top shelf.
Attaboy.
The Kerry camp had
an early opportunity
to capitalize on jobs
and the economy as an issue
and attack
the president with it.
The pre-election polls show
that a significant number
of undecided and persuadable
voters thought Kerry over Bush
offered a better
chance for jobs.
Jobs may have been
a marginal issue, Kate
in some of the rust belt
battle ground states.
But ultimately
this was a referendum
on the leadership of George W. Bush
on the war against terror
and the war in Iraq.
You are so full of shit.
Nothing mattered in the red
states but the economy...
I've been saying that for months.
Hey, I'm not tossing you
so quick tonight.
I got nothing to do tomorrow.
Well, I'm tossing myself.
I gotta get home.
You know what, not that
this wasn't fun
but it might be nice
to have dinner first.
Dinner and a movie.
I got to Baltimore late.
Nah, I'm saying next time.
We talk some, then
we fuck our brains out.
It's different for girls like me.
You need to be cuddled, McNulty?
No, but we make a date
I don't feel like I have
to charge by the hour.
A date, huh?
I'll call you.
In the daytime.
I think we can all agree that
foreign policy and women...
... all the while the United States
was reeling from the attack
on Pearl Harbor...
the wonders of
wood carving...
he wrapped himself
in the american flag
at the convention
and never looked back.
Oh, Kate, that's a little
harsh, don't you think?
No, I don't, I'm serious.
And I think it was great
strategy by his handlers, too.
You don't think when John Kerry
in his acceptance speech
at the Democratic
National Convention said:
"I'm here under old glory"
that he wasn't trying to wrap
himself in a flag, too?
No, I don't think he was trying
to wrap himself in a flag.
I think he was trying
to defend the people
in the battle ground states.
The ones who really...
1942, the U.S. first stormed
the shore at Guadalcanal.
Seizing a nearly complete
airfield at Moga Point
which was renamed
Henderson Field.
And in anchorage
and nearby Tulagy
that would later be known
as "iron bottom sound"
because of the number
of ships sunk there in battle.
The landings of the first day
put nearly 11,000 marines
on the island,
minimal resistance...
Slapstick
Deep into it, I see.
Yeah, gettin' there.
You lookin' correct.
Sunday morning. I'm on my way
to hear the word, you know?
Gracias, amigos.
You payin' those guys
out of pocket?
Boiler in there's working
and the pipes are okay.
I should have it all cleaned
out by tomorrow, I think.
All you gonna need is the permits.
Permits?
Yeah.
Permits.
Whoa, is that him?
S hit.
If it ain't, we'd only
be wasting the bullet.
Only problem is it bein' Sunday
mornin' an all, you know?
Who you callin'?
Slim Charles, man.
You told me you was supposed
to bring our beefin'
before the group, right?
Here it is you go warrin' with the
young boy, Marlo, over corners.
Marlo ain't in the group.
Be that as it may
all this shoot-em-up shit
is bad f business.
We got cops on half
the Westside corners.
And what corners
they ain't holding
I cat have my people
standing on for fear
they gonna be mistaken
as one of Barksdale people
an' catch a bullet.
Look, man, I tried to talk
to the young buck myself, but...
You try talkin' to Avon.
Because that's half
the problem right there.
No doubt, exactly.
Nigger probably sleepin' in.
Fact is, Stringer, your man
needs to reconcile himself
to this new way of thinking.
Now, you could remind him that
like everyone else in this room
he benefiting from my connect
and from the wholesale price
we got by throwin' in together.
I mean, he know that, come on, Joe.
Well, so, now we comin' to him
for help with a little something.
He need to just back the fuck off
and let the youngun keep his corners.
You said yourself it can't
be about territory no more.
Old habits die hard.
Who this?
Yeah, it's me.
We on the house where
the dude who is, you know...
Talk, nigga.
Shit, man, I'm tryin'
not to use names.
This Gerard, man.
We on Omar, he goin'
to come out the house.
As you know, I ain't trying to lose
no niggers on them corners either but
it's a two way street, you know?
Gerard and Sapper
got their sights on omar.
They tried to raise Slim
an' he ain't answering.
So?
It's church day, String.
Sunday morning, you know?
They sure it's him?
Omar, yeah.
Alright, do it.
Do it.
They right there, c'mon.
Oh, my goodness!
This time, I definitely hit him.
District-wide, it's 14%.
A drop like that in the western
felony rate is unheard of.
But God knows what happens
when you let go of your secret.
Hey, what happens, happens.
I mean, if they want to keep
my little experiment going
or they want to go back
to business as usual.
That's on them. But me?
I'm out of here, D., I'm gone.
And... Hopkins came through.
I got the contract offer
on that security job yesterday.
You really gonna retire?
Always planned to.
What?
You started something.
You ain't gonna finish it?
What do you mean?
On a battlefield, you can't do much
to help anybody with anything.
But you managed a truce, Bunny.
And making the game street legal...
takes the heart out of it.
Keep it going, we gonna
reach some of those people
chasing dope and coke
and maybe even
some hoppers, too.
You might at that.
But what happens when you turn
your district over to the next man?
Or people get wind of this thing
and there's no one to defend it?
What then?
How's the contrast on that?
Good for daylight.
Yeah?
On a Sunday,
what the fuck, Lester?
I could say the same of you.
Elena's taking the kids
to her mother's
what the fuck else
am I gonna do?
No life
no marriage, no kids.
No problem.
What's with the video?
Gonna put it up
in one of the windows
across from Stringer's print shop.
Catch him coming and going.
Hey, you need help?
You're a known face.
I figure me and Prez
do it on a Sunday
shop is closed, looking
like working men...
you know something, Lester?
I do believe there
aren't five swingin' dicks
in this entire department
who can do what we do.
I'm not sayin' like
all chest out and shit.
It's just, you think about it
there's maybe, what,
3,000 sworns, right?
100 or so are bosses,
so not a fucking clue there?
A few more hundred is
sergeants and lieutenants
and most of them
wanna be bosses one day
so they're just as fucked...
then there's 600 or 700
fuckin' housecats, you know?
Deskmen...
and in the patrol division?
There's probably a little
bit of talent there, but...
the way the city is right now,
that's 1500 guys...
chasin' calls and clearin' corners...
I mean, nobody's knowing his post,
nobody's building nothing, right?
And C.I.D. is the same.
Catching calls,
chasing quick clearances
keeping everything
in the shallow end...
I mean who is it out there that
can do what we do with a case?
How many are there really?
Don Worden, Ed Burns.
Gary Childs out in the county
John O'Neil and Steve Cleary
over at Woodlawn...
oh, they bring it in,
but there's not many.
There's not many.
We're good at this, Lester.
In this town, we're
as good as it gets.
Natural police.
Fuck yes, natural police.
Tell me something, Jimmy.
How exactly do you
think it all ends?
What do you mean?
A parade?
A gold watch?
A shining Jimmy-McNulty-day moment
when you bring in a case
so sweet that everybody
gets together and says:
"Oh shit, he was right all along.
We shoulda listened to the man. "
The job will not save you, Jimmy.
It won't make you whole,
it won't fill your ass up.
I dunno.
- A good case...
- ends.
They all end.
The handcuffs go
click and it's over
and the next morning it's just
you in the room with yourself.
Until the next case.
Boy, you need something
outside of this here.
Like what?
Dollhouse miniatures?
A life, a life, Jimmy,
you know what that is?
It's the shit that happens
while you're waiting for moments
that never come.
On a Sunday morning...
we called to ask.
Shamrock said to go.
On a Sunday morning
y'all try to hit a nigger
when he takin' his
wrinkled-ass grandmoms to pray.
And you all don't hit
the nigger, neither.
All y'all kill is
grandma's crown?
By the time sham tells us to go,
omar's damn near in the cab...
Ain't enough that y'all violated
the Sunday morning truce.
No!
I'm standin' here holdin'
a torn-up church crown
of a bona-fide colored lady.
Do you know what
a colored lady is?
Not your mamas, for sure.
'Cause if they was that
y'all would have known better
better than that bullshit.
Y'all triflin' with Avon
Barksdale's reputation here.
You know that?
She alright though?
She got cut on her
face from the glass
an' she sore from
where I fell on her.
But other an' that though...
you saved her ass, huh.
I damn near got
that woman kilt, yo.
Y'all shoulda seen me in Sinai
hospital while they stitchin' her up
lyin' about why somebody want
to shoot me down in the street.
That woman thinks
I work in a cafeteria.
Cafeteria?
At the airport, yeah.
Airport, why the airport?
'Cause I know she ain't
never gonna go down there
to go dining that's why.
Yo, Kimmy, this ain't funny, yo.
That woman raised me.
An for as long as I've been
grown, once a month
I been with her on a church Sunday.
Tellin' myself ain't
no need to worry
'cause there's ain't
nobody in this city
that low-down to disrespect
a Sunday morning.
Y'all know I was gonna
walk away, right?
Y'all knew that, right?
I mean, after Tosha, I was
gonna leave them people be, yo.
Avon home now.
Oh, Barksdale's gots to go.
Stringer too.
This thing got to end, man.
I swear to god, yo,
on a Sunday morning
they near shot her
best crown off, yo.
I mean, no shame them
niggers. Y'all feel me?
I'm out.
If you back to dealin' with
Barksdale people, I'm out, yo.
I'm in it for the money.
It's easier out there than that.
Jus' you an' me then.
Like it was.
Naw, yo.
This one about me.
And nobody else.
Hey...
I'm with you.
Not on this one you ain't.
Okay, guys.
We are maybe a step and a half away
from being up on a
wire on these people.
All we need is to firm up the P.C.
showing the disposable phones
are being used in a drug conspiracy.
McNulty and Greggs,
you're on that angle.
You need to walk either
undercover or a wired C.I.
up to one of the Barksdale crews...
Lester, you and Prez
start typing affidavits
because when the probable
cause comes in
we're going to want to get
the application in fast.
Detective, you're the chaser
on our boy Bernard.
When he goes out for cell
phones, we're right behind.
The faster we get a hold
of the new numbers
the faster we're up
on those phones.
Now, when Caroline
comes back off vacation
she's going to be on the mini-cam.
From here on out
we keep a log on any
movement by Stringer
and we keep an eye out
for Mr. Barksdale as well.
Try to get a line on where
he spends his days.
As for me, I'm off to do battle
with the wireless company.
They a problem?
Have been since the damn
things were invented.
Okay, then.
Remember that with this wire
everything is a race
against the clock.
Anything we get up on
is only temporary.
You reach Bubbles?
Yeah. He'll be waiting
at Mount Clare.
Lee, where's the DNR log?
What?
The log.
Never mind, I got it right here.
All Stringer, all the time.
Theresa D'Agostino please.
Hold please.
Yeah, I'll hold.
I'm sorry, she's not
in the office now.
You want to leave a message?
No, I left one already.
A boxing gym?
For kids an' all. An athletic club.
Gyms, reducing salons,
public baths are permitted
only in properties zoned
b- two, b-three, b-four or b-five...
all signed and sealed by a
registered architect and engineer...
floor framing plan,
including the load criteria...
hydronic piping
and equipment layouts...
six copies of your
fire protection plan
with emergency exits
and sprinkler system...
health department, since it's a
physical culture and health service...
a license from the State Athletic
Commission, up on Calvert Street.
Mid-size or full?
Mid-sized.
You should upgrade an' get
one of them escalades.
They got that XM radio an' all...
I'm sayin' if we gonna be
in the damn car all damn day
it's worth it, Bernard.
You ticklish, bubs?
Chills, Kima.
You do that to me.
Here's the buy money, Bubs.
Remember, this is all on tape.
I hear you.
So down there on Vincent Street
they don't even hide
the ground stash anymore.
You watch and wait,
see when they're runnin' low.
Then ask for 30 or so.
Enough so that they have
to call for a quick re-up.
That's the important thing.
We want him to use his burner.
I get to keep the 30?
30 would kill you, Bubs.
You get to keep the money
we hand you once you come back
here with all of that product.
Just asking.
Just telling.
It can't be done.
Excuse me?
The activation information
you're gonna want?
That stuff's not accessible
from the business office
until it goes to billing
and that takes a few days,
sometimes a week or more.
But more than that,
we have dozens of
law enforcement
inquiries every month.
We get to them
in the order received
and currently the
turnaround's 30 days.
30 days.
Let me understand something.
Your company is in business
selling disposable cell phones
to people who don't have to give
any subscriber information
at the time of purchase, correct?
Correct.
They buy these phones
and as far as you're concerned
they use them anonymously,
prepaying for their minutes...
From the retailers, yes.
And while they are using
these phones, anonymously
for whatever purpose
they can't be monitored
by law enforcement
because your company
can't react within a month
to a court order for a wiretap.
We do the best we can.
This is bullshit.
You're selling a phone that you know
is effective for drug trafficking.
Lieutenant, our prepaid inventory
is there for young people
college students and such
people who can't afford
a permanent cell phone plan.
What college student
can't afford a cell phone?
They can afford
the fucking college
they can afford the phone
that goes with it.
I resent the suggestion.
Just so I'm clear:
You're telling me that
even if by some miracle
we are able to get up on a drug
dealer's disposable cell phone
in time to catch him talking
you're gonna take as much
as a month to activate our tap.
Look, if you have
a problem with that
your office can contact
our general counsel.
That's all I can say.
How about this?
How about the state's attorney
for Baltimore city
calls a press conference
on the courthouse steps
to declare that Bay Wireless is
in league with the most violent
drug traffickers in the city
preventing their apprehension
and arrest by law enforcement.
Four to five days turnaround.
Best we can do.
I swear, I felt like a damn balloon
with air rushin' out my ass
goin' from desk to desk.
This our new man, huh?
Frank Reid.
Dennis Wise.
Reverend, our man
Dennis spent all day
down at the Benton building,
trying for permits.
On the new gym?
Yeah.
You use my name?
You use anybody's name?
Hell, man. There was a time
I'da used Smith and Wesson.
Naw, look, man,
I'm just sayin'...
how do regular folk
get it done in this town?
Doreen
ring Delegate Watkins, please?
Yellow tops, yellow tops.
Obliged, man, obliged.
Keep me close, you know?
You tell a friend, okay?
Too hot for them
black tees, right?
Sup, hopper, what you hawkin'?
Body bags.
Alright, let me get 30... 30 pills.
30?
Where the fuck your raggedy-ass
come up with three-hunnert
in motherfucking cash, man?
I've been sellin' them
t- shirts for weeks now.
You know, I might be raggedy,
but I'm in a cash business.
You want my money or no?
Yeah, we out.
A- ight.
Shouldn't be long.
A bulk purchase justify
a discount, right?
250 or so...
275.
And a couple of them whiteys.
That'll work.
Bubs just made another 25.
Theresa D'Agostino, please.
I'm sorry, but she's not in.
Can I take a message?
No, I'll call back.
- So, how's that working?
- What?
Your new hope.
So far, so good.
You got the receipts, man?
Yeah, most of 'em.
A few blew out the damn
window on the interstate.
What, y'all waiting to see Avon?
I heard y'all shot a crown off
an ol' lady's head yesterday.
Good, you all made it.
Yeah...
we puttin' in some work.
C'mon upstairs so we can talk.
Back with numbers.
How many?
24 Trac phones.
Two each from Mondo Marts
in Catonsville and Sykesville
and four from Frederick
and then eight each from two stops
over the river in west Virginia.
Those bumper beepers?
They work great.
He went out I-70 this time.
Can you blame him?
The scenery's better.
24.
We're gonna have
a lot of D.N.R.'s up.
But with any luck
one of these phones leads
to young Mr. Bodie Broadus.
You want to call Pearlman.
A'ight.
Who's hungry?
How 'bout chinese?
Sounds good to me.
You guys call it in and I'll go.
Let me get some of that lo mein.
You take a turn typing
this shit, I'll go with him.
Make mine sweet and sour.
Lo mein for me.
So y'all get with Charles
he gonna get you
all the details on it.
Who they?
Eastside niggas.
Willing to soldier up
for us on retainer.
Milton put me up on them.
Man, we gonna be back
where we was, String.
You know, I can smell it.
We just got to get this boy Marlo
and then we spread out like we do.
Them co-op boys, man, they ain't
happy about this situation, man.
They say they got cops on corners
where they wouldn't have otherwise.
Everybody nervous.
Man, fuck them niggers.
I mean, Prop Joe said he'd mediate.
You know what I mean?
Go to Marlo and talk on it.
Yeah, well, he take a gun
with him, maybe it could work.
Lemme ask you, something though.
Did you tell them
discount ass niggers
they could pop off
at Omar's grandma.
Oh, man.
Sham comes to me
in the middle of the meeting
and talk about they got
their sights on Omar.
They say nothing about no grandma.
No church hat, nothing like that.
I hear the cocksucker's
name, I say, "go. "
On a Sunday morning?
Yo, I don't give a fuck, man.
I hear that cocksucker's name, man
I ain't thinkin'
about a church day.
A Sunday truce been around
long as the game itself, man.
I mean, you know what I'm sayin',
you can do some shit
and be like what the fuck, but hey,
just never on no Sunday, man.
I mean, it's just like people
was talkin' on us and all
and the stories are
getting bigger and bigger.
Like, I swear to god, Fatface Rick
heard that our people went an' shot
Omar granny's in the ass
on purpose, and all that.
And pulled their dicks out and
pissed on her crown an' shit.
I heard the same bullshit.
Prop Joe gave me an earful.
But yo, what can I say, man?
Good help is hard to find.
If it wasn't, you think I'd be
payin' Eastside niggers for shit?
Yo, we still off them corners?
Yeah, got to be.
We be off them corners
till we take care of Marlo.
Yeah, maybe we should
put a couple more crews
on them free zones them cops got.
You know what I mean?
Take the profit where we can.
You trust that shit?
I mean, so far.
An' if they runnin' a game
they ain't gonna get nobody
higher than a crew chief
to take a charge, right?
What you gonna do
with them two niggers
you got waitin' downstairs?
I make 'em buy the lady a new hat.
What're we waiting for?
Sweet-and-sour?
You do the cookie first?
What's the difference?
"A new friend makes himself known. "
Himself?
If it was herself,
then you'd have a fortune.
Shit, I'm married with
lawn furniture, man.
This technology's out
of control no question.
But that's nothing new.
The way these guys are
using disposables nowadays
we cannot get
a working wire up in time.
By the time we get subscriber
information and papers served...
they're dumping phones.
Cellular carrier is telling them
they need nearly a week
to process the paperwork.
They're only half-scared of us,
but a visit from the feds?
You all have profile
enough to push them.
I dunno. If you've got
them down to five days
you're doing about
as well as we can.
Once again, guys:
The bureau's a little busy
with counter terrorism.
Our U.S. attorney here
he only touches himself at the
mention of political corruption.
Ghetto drug stuff
just doesn't rate.
I'm sorry to say.
Shit always smells best
in the car, going home.
Signal 13.
In the alley in the rear,
Eastside, 800 north Montford.
That's five blocks,
up and over.
Go.
What's the cross street?
Shots fired.
Sounded like it was
west of Milton...
I'm police.
He's ten-seven, call it in.
That's a glock.
I saw the gun as he turned.
It's Derrick.
Jesus christ.
You killed Derrick.
It's Waggoner.
You fuckin' killed Waggoner!
Greggs.
Prez shot another cop.
What?
It was an accident in
an alley, a little while ago.
- No.
- I'll call you back.
You here for Barksdale?
I'm here for peace, man.
This some senseless shit goin' on.
But Barksdale ain't sent you?
Naw, Stringer knows I'm here, man.
If I can bring something
respectful back
they most likely to show the same.
Tell the boy he can
come in with the co-op.
If he takes our package,
which by the way
is better than the best
he putting out there now
he'll keep his corners.
Guaranteed.
He might listen.
But the boy got ideas.
And he's thinkin'
Avon weak right now.
You ever know Avon Barksdale
to back down from anything?
A plainclothesman in a dark alley
with his gun out,
and shots fired...
Look, no one wants to burn
anybody, but the fact is
there's a racial
component to consider.
- The appearance of it...
- Has he seen a lawyer?
Lieutenant...
What?
He's in a situation where
you can't compel a statement
out of him until you
read him his rights
and we haven't
done that yet, so...
I'm his commanding officer.
I just want to know if he's alright.
Okay.
Okay, there's just...
it's a legal question
at this point.
Can I get you anything?
You should call the union, Roland.
Talk to a lawyer before
you say anything further.
I'm not saying anyone's gonna
charge anything criminally.
Everyone knows you had
no intention of...
but administratively...
you need to be careful
because of the racial thing.
You see that, right?
There's gonna be people in the
department who see this that way.
You see that, right?
I wasn't scared, I wasn't angry.
I didn't give a shit
he was black or...
whatever...
or, maybe I did.
How the fuck do you know if
that's in your head or if it's not...
But you saw the gun.
Yeah.
Yeah...
He turned toward me and...
'Cause you shouted, right?
You shouted, "police"
and he turned, right?
I don't think so.
I don't think I said anything.
I don't think he did that.
I was a couple steps in the alley...
and he turned and I saw the gun.
That's all.
He have kids?
A wife?
I don't know.
They won't say.
They won't talk to me about him.
Call the F.O.P.
Get a lawyer, Roland.
No, sir.
I'm done.
Let the lawyer talk for you.
Lieutenant...
tell Lester I'm sorry.
Call the union.
He wants a lawyer
in there with him.
Whenever he's done here, you need
to send someone home with him.
For tonight at least,
he's a suicide watch.
Lieutenant
you'll back him.
What I mean is, if this thing
should turn into some kind of
a black-white thing,
you're his unit commander
he can count on you, right?
Are you alright?
Lo mein.
What a clusterfuck.
How many years on for Waggoner?
Six and a half.
Two commendations, 16th
on the current sergeant's list.
Pretty much the exact opposite
of that goof in there...
you know what's
in that guy's jacket?
Motherfucker flaked out,
shot up his own radio car.
They were gonna charge
him with false report
until Valchek weighed in...
You know he married
Valchek's daughter, right?
Fuckin' goof had nine
lives behind that shit...
Eight up, and the rest
still to be activated
whenever the cellular company
gets to our subpoenas.
You did good, detective.
So we're looking for what?
Looking for one of these phones
to give us signature
on our man, Bodie.
Calls to his girlfriend,
his grandmother...
the numbers we pulled
off the burners.
We see that,
we know it's his phone.
We know it's his phone, we
know he uses it to sell drugs.
We know all that.
We get a tap up and pray like hell
he doesn't throw it
away anytime soon.
Prez would love this...
Ain't gonna lie to y'all.
I don't know about nothing
except the boxing part.
That's all I was thinkin'.
Were you a pug?
Yeah, I was.
I got sidetracked, though.
Well, reverend Reid
seems to think you'd
be quite a draw for some of
these corner kids that we got.
They didn't think so downtown?
Well, the fact is
you're looking to put your
gym in the fourth district
so your council person
would be Eunetta Perkins.
Do you know Ms. Perkins?
Well, few of us do anymore.
Few of us do.
Well, since we can't
really rely on Ms. Perkins,
Ms. Daniels here
will go with you.
She's here because
constituent service
is the life of a city
council person.
She needs to get a taste of that.
At least I hope I do.
If you don't mind me
asking, Mr. Watkins.
Why are you doing this?
Do you know who reverend Reid is?
Well, the voters in my district do.
This came today?
Well, I see, this is fucked up.
I give you a quarter million dollars
to have them tell me my paperwork
is insufficient enough to certify
me as a developer
in the empowerment zone?
Yeah...
Yeah, you could call it fucked up.
Look, I know we touched
the right people.
Just lemme get with them,
clear this mess right up.
Get with 'em.
Hey, I'm on it, String.
You got the lightbulb
franchise, right?
That came through...
now...
I'm not talkin' about
30,000 coming back.
I'm talkin' about the quarter
of a mill that you took.
Now, you need to call
Mr. Goose, Mr. Faucet
whoever the fuck you gotta call
because I gave you money to run
remember that?
It ain't like no
drug deal, String.
Hell, man, you don't put
your money on the street
and have it come right back.
It don't work like that.
Oh, it don't, huh?
Patience, my man.
Sometimes with the bureaucracy
the one hand don't know
what the other is all about.
Yeah, well, you know what I see?
I see one hand in my pocket
while the other hand seems
to have grabbed your dick.
Fucking Prez.
I don't even feel like working.
Sanny, baby.
Welcome to the western, guys.
That thing with Pryzbylewski?
Jesus christ.
So fucking sad, man.
So you humpin' a wagon, huh?
Fuck yes.
How's that working out for you?
Jimmy, I love this fucking gig.
Best thing Rawls ever did for me
was to knock me back to a district.
No stress, no struggle.
I work eight-hour shifts.
I take nothing home with me.
Really, I couldn't be happier.
All those years knockin'
my head against a wall
in homicide and for what?
The same fuckin' pension
with twice the heartburn.
Well, I'm glad you landed
on your feet, Mike.
Hello.
You called my office.
Yeah, I did, several times.
Really, why?
Why do you think?
A sleep over.
You want to get dinner first.
How about tonight?
Georgia Browns near 15th Street.
That'll work.
You want me to make a reservation?
No, I can always get a table there.
Alright, whatever.
Let's shoot for 7:30.
I'll see you then.
- Bye.
You in?
What do you think?
Nice colors.
You got a platform?
Schools.
Thought I'd be the education mayor.
Well, good luck, Tony.
I mean it.
Thanks, man.
When do you announce?
Next month, I think.
You know, get out there
early, start raising money.
In fact, I thought I'd make
the rounds of some people
before then, you know?
Feel them out.
What, Watkins?
Hey, he seems to like me.
You really think Odell Watkins
is gonna split from
the mayor's camp?
What you could do is, ah...
feel him out on an issue or two.
You go in that way,
it's more subtle.
You gotta charm the guy first.
Talk to him about the issues
and then down the road
see if he's willing to throw
sunshine on your ass.
I like that.
We should do that.
We?
I was thinking...
maybe you would ticket
your white ass up with me.
Make a run for Council President.
Me at the top of the ticket,
an emerging black leader
handsome, well-spoken...
you the great white hope
the new voice of civic reform.
We'd give Royce a run, man.
And what makes you think I'm
interested in Council President?
What the hell else you got going?
Think about it.
look at 'em. Like roaches
when you turn the lights on.
What's it look like?
Head and torso.
You got two casings over here.
Hold the call.
So much for the no-violence-
- in-hampsterdam theory, huh?
Herc...
Help me move the body.
What?
Just up the block,
just out of the free zone.
Carv, you've lost
your fucking mind.
Before the ambo gets here
to pronounce him, we can do it.
Why?
Because if homicide gets here...
if they do any kinda canvass...
they're gonna get wind of this
shit on the sixth floor downtown.
- Good.
- Herc, c'mon.
No way, man.
No way.
Fuck those stripes.
Fuck 'em.
Hey Toke, Gil...
help me move this guy
outta Hamsterdam.
I'll be first officer at the scene.
It's my responsibility.
Don't forget the casings.
Make sure that you call me.
I will.
Thank you.
Take care. Bye.
7-60 to kga.
Go ahead, 7-60.
Have 70010-11 me on
Vincent Street below Fayette.
10-4, Vincent south of Fayette.
You say you worked with this guy?
Three shots, no warnings.
He scared of black
people or something?
Shit.
The shit's gone too far.
Yeah, you're tellin' me.
Yeah, I need the number
to the newspaper, "The Sun".
Yeah, the number for the reporters.
The newsroom, yeah...
So, you ain't gonna
say nothing on it?
What is there to say?
Avon, this is blood.
- Family.
- I know it.
An' I'm tellin' you that someone
may have done this to us, Avon.
To our family.
The cop's just sayin' that shit.
To mess with your head.
Exactly.
Why?
That cop don't know me for shit.
What the hell am I to him?
He knows you're gonna
want to think this thing.
That Dee, you know,
he wouldn't do what he did.
I do think it.
Was it some beef he had?
Someone on the inside?
That cop said it was someone
who didn't want you to know
and so they made
it look like it did.
Ain't nobody did nothing.
- But the cop said...
- He's lying.
He paid to lie.
Avon...
you are my brother.
I need to know this
more than anything...
Dee did not roll on us.
He came to the edge, but he
turned around and walked away.
And I know he was willing to do
what he had to for his family.
For us...
but I need to know
that you know that
and you saw him that way.
What...
What you tryin' to say?
If something happened...
The fuck are you even thinking?
That I had something to do with it?
I could do that to my own kin?
Is that what you fucking think?
The fuck is in your head?
I ain't do nothing to Dee.
I ain't have shit to do with it.
To do with what?
To do with what?!
Whatever happened.
Whatever it is that
happened, Brianna.
You think I don't
know my business?
Is that what you think?
I can get him to you
tomorrow morning.
Just let me see
if I can find him.
I'll make good on this.
What'd he say?
They found a blood trail
going back up the block.
So maybe...
Smeared, with drag marks.
And they also found a third
casing at the other end.
Shit.
So what's the deal?
Deal is, we turn this into
a dunker by tomorrow morning
or he starts typing a report
for I.S.D. and the Deputy Ops.
Fuck me.
No, fuck me!
Look, you didn't move
that body, Sergeant.
I moved the body.
Do you understand?
Look, I respect that you did
what you did on behalf
of what I'm trying to do down here
but the responsibility is mine.
So what do we do?
He basically said he wasn't
gonna commit any new resources
though he has placed
it on the agenda
of the coordinating council
on criminal justice
for what that's worth...
Poor Clarence.
He's looking tired.
So we're looking for help
from the statehouse.
If the city could
get a couple 100,000
we could afford an overtime
detail to protect these folks.
I know this is an easier sell
with the mayor involved, but...
could you convince him?
Clarence?
He barely listens anymore...
Jesus, tell me about it.
I been a councilman
three years now
that's a long fucking
time to be ignored.
I'm sayin' the rules got broke.
My people kept their promises
they did what they said and they
were as good as their word.
Y'all...
y'all ain't keep up
your end of it.
Wasn't my people.
Look, I ain't makin' those
distinctions right now.
Fact is, somebody brought a gun
up in the free zone and used it
and both those things
against the promises made.
Now, I can't justify this shit if
I've got dead bodies up in there.
So what I'm sayin'
is this: come tomorrow
if I don't have a
shooter in bracelets
this whole Hampsterdam
affair is over, it's finished.
I'm gonna take my people
back up on the corners
and we gonna fuck y'all
every way we can.
You hear me?
Yeah, it was good
while it lasted, huh?
You had cash on the barrel
and you ain't never
need no bail money.
And hell, I had clean corners
everywhere I looked.
But all that gonna be gone tomorrow
unless y'all bring me my shooter.
You think that'll work?
Do you?
That's good food.
How'd you know about this place?
It was big when Clinton was in.
This and the Red Sage.
Now it's all steakhouses
and cigar bars.
So you live here, but you spend
a lot of time in Baltimore, right?
I have work up there.
And the alumni stuff
with St. Mary's on the hill.
I went to U.M. law, so I still
have connections there too.
Actually, I grew up in Homeland.
Yeah?
Lauraville for me.
Where'd you go to college?
Loyola.
Only one year.
My girlfriend got pregnant so...
so...
so you became
a cop in Baltimore.
How's that working for you?
Oh, it's pretty good.
I do a lot of high-end drug stuff.
Wiretaps.
Prolonged investigations of violent
offenders, that kinda stuff...
In fact is, there's not a lot
of guys in the department
that can do that kinda thing.
It takes a certain...
I dunno, you gotta love it.
Thrill of the chase an' all that.
So, you do what in politics?
I do political campaigns.
Like a campaign manager?
More of a strategist really.
Not so much the day-to-day stuff
but the strategy of how
a candidate can win.
A consultant of sorts.
You strategizing for
anyone in Baltimore?
I shouldn't say.
I mean, he hasn't officially
announced anything yet.
He any good?
Hey, if you're for him,
I'll throw the guy a vote.
What the hell.
Who'd you vote for this time?
What? You mean Bush
and whatshisname?
Kerry.
You didn't vote for president?
I thought about it
yeah, and you know
Bush seemed way
over his head, I know
but he wasn't gonna win
in Maryland anyhow.
And besides, these guys...
it doesn't matter who you got.
None of 'em has a clue
what's really going on.
I mean, where I'm
working every day?
The only way any of these guys
would even find west Baltimore
is if, I dunno, Air Force One
crash lands into Monroe Street
on it's way back to Andrews.
It just never connects.
Not to what I see, anyway.
Hey, that's just me though.
The man Colvin say
he want the boy locked up
or the free zone
shuts down tomorrow.
All she wrote for Hampsterdam.
Colvin.
From the Western.
Shame, who is this kid, man?
Some young boy from Tuckie's crew.
He connected? Kin to anybody?
Naw, he only been on
for a couple months or so.
What he use the whistle for?
Some nigger in one a
ghost Kane's crews
laughed at his shoes.
Do it.
I'll be out in a minute...
No, he needs to put those
in departmental mail.
Yeah.
Whaddaya need?
To turn myself in.
For what?
I shot a boy.
Oh, yeah?
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
Transcript par Raceman
Synchronisation: El Uploador
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net