Oh, man!
What's next?
One to the head.
Keep it quick.
Not yet, motherfucker.
You shoot live rounds like paint.
Boy, you be the shit, you hear?
Yo, but these really do
look like Glocks.
Yeah, they make them
look that way.
Yo, why you shoot low?
All right.
If you're close,
aim for the head.
If not, think vest.
That's the way you said it.
A'ight.
Boy's learnin'.
4x12 That's Got His Own
You going inside this one, too?
I'm gonna do the whole block.
It's bad enough you popped the top off
of one house and give us a body.
What the fuck do you think
you're doing now?
An experiment.
An experiment?
Fuck me.
I'm dealing with Madam Curie here.
This nail here
comes from a nail gun,
And it comes from the house
with a dead man inside.
Every other house has screws
that H.C.D. uses.
We find these in the plywood
anywhere in this city,
and there's a body inside.
Gosh, that's good work.
No, I'm very impressed.
Do you see a tool belt on me?
Do I look like
one of those fuckin' jerkoffs
in aisle 5 of the home fuckin' depot?
There's 3 weeks left in the year,
And our unit clearance rate
is under 50%.
We do not go looking for bodies,
Especially moldering
fucking John does.
We do not put red up
on the board voluntarily.
Jay, the bodies are in the houses.
Marlo Stanfield's bodies.
Then they belong to him.
Now, I realize
you're no longer in my squad,
Mr. Major crimes,
But you're still part of C.I.D., right?
And look--
I'm still a Sergeant, right?
And I'm giving you
an order on this, Lester.
Until I feel
chain-of-command down on this
and until you hear otherwise,
you will not--
I repeat not--
pull down any more
Fucking wood!
Let it go, man.
I mean, you know,
I expect a shortfall
when I look at the school budget.
It's a natural.
But how in Christ's name
do you lose $54 million?
One million at a time.
Exactly.
It didn't happen this morning.
This was on Royce's watch.
You didn't get a whiff
of this during council review?
You can't blame the council
or Royce for the school budget.
The fiscal responsibility is
with the school board itself.
But the council does have oversight--
Don't even pretend
to put this shit on me.
Only the city share
shows up on our budget review.
We never see the state money.
You better tell your
pretty new chief of staff
that whatever happens
up on north avenue
is on the school system.
That's a simplistic view,
I think.
How would you complicate it?
As president of the school board,
I'll argue this is a bookkeeping issue.
We've simply been rolling
the system's debt over since '99.
You rolled it and rolled it
until it ran out of cash.
That's not bookkeeping,
that's stupidity.
So what are we talking
about here, waste?
Fraud? Embezzlement?
I would say that although
the system has
some poor accounting practices,
in the end we're going to find
that most of the money
was properly spent on programming.
OK, OK.
We get it.
No one's responsible,
not the school board,
not anybody on north avenue,
not Clarence Royce,
not the city council,
no one at this table.
Fine.
So what's our next move?
Bump the property tax rate?
Scale back our budget.
No pay hikes, hiring freezes,
reduced services,
Tell everyone-- Schools,
police, fire, public works--
they have to hold the line
for a year or 2.
How?
I just ran
a clean up the streets campaign.
I just got done promising the world
to every cop in the city.
Annapolis.
You go beg his republican ass.
The cheese stands alone.
This the drop?
I hope not,
'cause they ain't called yet.
Make me feel bad toward
old Prop Joe.
Yeah, go around
where we can see y'all.
Vamanos, 'Naldo.
Nice hook up.
Private.
Damn, y'all some semper fi
motherfuckers, ain't ya?
Where cheese go to enlist?
That's 25 back to Joe
from what we was short before,
and another 150
to up our order to 6.
We had you down for 4.
I don't know if we got
extras coming off the boat.
Short someone else, then.
I'll see what Joe says.
Yeah.
When we set with the reup,
we'll hit you on that.
The shit will be
where you told us half hour later.
- Yo, we ain't usin' these no more.
- Us neither.
All we do is ring you
from a 958 exchange eastside,
don't need to answer.
Just toss it,
go to the meet.
See you when I see you.
Money on the table,
and Heron to follow.
Stay here on Marlo?
Naw, we gonna stay with Cheese.
Detective,
would you get the door for me?
Sometimes life
just gives you a moment, huh?
He was gonna do me,
and instead he gets done?
I'm dipped in shit here.
I'm the luckiest motherfucker you know.
Gentlemen.
The target is still Mr. Stanfield,
and from the look of things,
we're no closer to him than
when I left here 2 months ago.
Now, they might not
let me go after murders,
but they cannot stop me
from chasin' the drugs.
Leandor, I want you
surveilling his people.
See if they're still up
on cellphones.
How are you with the paper trail?
I want you down
at the city assessment office
pulling paper on all the purchases
on the west side over $100,000.
Then get down to M.V.A. and check for
luxury cars in his name, all right?
Now, this boy has been in
the game for a while now.
He might try to launder money.
Herc, I want you on the paperwork,
rerequisitioning the wire tap equipment
that Marimow shipped
on down to I.S.D.
We're gonna need all of that
to get back up, OK?
If anyone needs me,
I'm down at missing persons, all right?
Let's go.
- Lester?
- Yes?
All this is cool.
But do you think we can do it so that
the direction comes from me?
I mean,
I am the Sergeant here.
Donut,
you think this look right?
Why you knock it down?
So the police
won't scope me so easy.
But now all they gotta do is be like,
"Yeah. Go over there and just grab
that little nigger with the braids."
Damn, boy,
you later than a motherfucker.
Been sitting out here
watching money walk away.
You about to have the day off.
Package was stole, Nay.
What?
Out the back of your basement?
They kicked my motherfuckin' door in.
That's how they do.
Well, look,
how the police know
where you even be keepin' your stash at?
Some snitch-ass bitch,
that's how they know.
I'm gonna find his ass, too.
All right, man, I'm out.
I never did understand
why you stopped eating the pig.
I ain't been in
a Polock Johnny's since 1974,
and if you knew
what was good for you--
Look, I know what's good.
I remember when you did, too.
I never saw you going all Muslim on me.
Ain't that,
but I do believe that other faiths
have got the pig figured better
than us A.M.E.S.
See that?
If you checking out,
I might feel the need
to say a few words.
Naw, I ain't got nothing
to do with that.
I love my pj's,
but they do repeat on me.
As memory serves,
you got to go with the original sauce,
not the kraut and chili like you do.
My pain ain't about no sauerkraut.
The puzzle palace
is ready to clip any program
that ain't tied to the statewide test.
And the thing is,
we just starting to make
a little headway
in what we're doing.
You take it upstairs?
Me and the professor went all the way
to go see the school superintendent.
- And?
- You read the papers?
They're a little busy ducking
that budget mess.
$50 million in the hole,
and they're scared
to take any more problems
to the new Mayor.
Is your thing a problem?
Depends on how you look at it.
A cover your ass
type of person might say
we're tracking any students
that can't hack in regular classes,
giving them work that don't
show up on no statewide test.
City hall says it's OK,
they keep our program.
If not, we on the street.
Odell Watkins.
I was hoping
you'd say that name.
Yeah, he got Carcetti's ear.
If we sell him,
maybe we sell the hall.
Stalk that nigga, man,
that stole yo' shit.
- Yeah.
- Soon as he nod out,
bust 'em in the head
with a brick or some shit.
Nah, nah.
That ain't me.
You can always give 'em
a hotshot then.
Y'all recall junior Bunk?
Cutting his shit with,
uh, what you call it.
Stole it from the funeral home.
Oh, you thinking formaldehyde.
That's the shit.
Nigga's got a taste of that shit,
university started
a 'junior Bunk' ward.
My cousin laid his ignorant ass
up there 2, 3 times.
ain't no guarantee in that, though.
Use some rat poison, then.
No, man, that stuff
don't cook up right.
What you need to use
is that sodium cyanide.
That shit looks and cooks
just like the real thing.
- Where I find that?
- Try...
Minter's over there by the tracks,
or one of those metal shops
where they do plating.
- How much I need?
- It ain't gonna take much.
A vial of that shit'd
kill every horse in this stable.
That's all there is to it?
It ain't no thing to kill a nigga
who's already about the business
of killing himself.
And the police,
they ain't gonna pay no never mind.
You the one's got
to live with it is all.
More young males
than I'd of thought.
I don't suppose they all
went off in search of adventure.
You get a chance to do any
street work on these files?
Shit, no, Lester.
They cut missing persons
to 1 detective 5 years ago.
I barely keep up
with the paperwork.
Feel free.
Just make copies and return
the originals for the files.
For the files...
right.
Damn, son.
Kenard said the police took it?
He said they kicked his door in.
And they ain't lock no one up?
Yo, you see that door?
Were the hinges broke?
I mean, if he said
they put the boot to it,
them hinges gotta be hangin' free.
I sweated him, yo.
He wasn't trying to scheme.
That little motherfucker
took that shit for himself.
Bet it.
And now you gotta step to him,
put something real behind them words.
Where your Spanish boy at?
He stay on point with Cheese
while I round up soldiers.
You got soldiers right here.
Your 2255 must've pleased
some judge, huh?
Enough to get me home, didn't it?
I'm just sayin', Butch,
I know they soldiers,
but I'm thinkin' about being
a little more subtle on this one.
You feel me?
So they don't see me coming.
It ain't like you
to work with strangers.
I'm celebrating diversity.
I'm thinking now the time
to start doing that.
What up, shorty?
What's up, baby?
Damn, girl, you looking good.
- I'm maintaining.
- Shit, I know that's right.
- You doing all right?
- Yeah.
Long time, long time.
I got your word.
Some real money to be made
on this one, huh?
You remember how to do this?
I reckon it'll come back to me.
See that's what
I'm talking about, Butch.
Subtle.
Glasses first so they don't spot.
Yes, ma'am.
- Hello.
- Ho, Mr. Prezbo.
- Come in, please.
- Oh, that's OK.
I just wanted
to stop by on my way home
and drop off Randy's work
for next week.
Hopefully...
this thing will be over soon.
Maybe so,
but we're looking at
the possibility of moving him
to Booker T. Washington
next semester.
I hope that isn't necessary.
I hope so, too.
Anyway, thanks
for bringing this.
I'll try to keep him up to speed.
Hang in there, kiddo.
Thanks.
Long conference call.
About an hour so far,
by my watch.
Got me out here riding the wood.
Unfortunately
the Governor's phone call
has gone longer than anticipated.
Can I get you anything?
Coffee?
Look,
I have other appointments.
It shouldn't be much longer.
Check out
Fisher's column in metro.
He says,
the Governor thinks, quote,
"This latest fiscal emergency
calls into question
"the Baltimore school system's
ability to manage itself
as well as the local
oversight of the system,"
Unquote.
Motherfucker.
He's playing to the D.C. Suburbs.
He sees you coming for him
2 years from now.
He ain't no fool.
There's all your electronic
requisitions right there.
What one's that, a cop?
Nah, security guard.
I don't think he's
one of Marlo's though.
Lieutenant.
Will someone explain to me
what the fuck the brass is doing?
First I get bounced
to telephone reporting,
then I get a call this morning...
How's that beach house coming, huh?
It's almost done,
- I just need a load of lumber--
- That's great, just great.
Welcome. Welcome back.
Who the fuck is that?
That, Sergeant Hauk...
is one of the most effective supervisors
in our police department.
Sorry.
It's just taking a little
longer than we expected.
It shouldn't be much longer, though.
I understand what you're saying.
Some of those kids
are ready for high school,
But not Duquan.
- I've--
- Adopted him?
I've noticed Duquan this semester.
He's more nourished,
wears fresher clothes.
Sometimes he even smells like soap.
You and your wife...
you don't have children, do you?
- Not yet, no.
- Well, have some.
For better or for worse,
they're yours for life.
The kids in this school aren't yours.
You do your piece with them,
and you let them go.
Because there'll be plenty more
coming up behind Duquan,
and they're gonna
need your help, too.
You've got your third period
in 5 minutes, right?
Settle down.
We need to concentrate on these tests.
Ah, fuck this, man.
Talking 'bout,
"if Jane's father
gives Jane 1 week's worth
of allowance."
Shit, I ain't got no allowance
where I stay at. Father, neither.
How many sides a sexagon got?
Why I care about that?
You need to take the test
so you can move on to the next level.
I ain't moving nowhere
but out this motherfucker.
All right, all right.
Let's settle down.
Let's start with question number 1.
Settle down!
All right.
All right, listen up.
Here's the problem.
2 couples go into a restaurant.
- They get the check--
- Yo, when they say couples,
- do it mean they married?
- Why they got to be married?
Mr. Prezbo, why you even get married?
Well, to build a life together for one,
you know, family.
Also to have intimacy.
- What do that mean?
- He mean, like, getting some.
No, no.
It's not just that.
Intimacy can be, um,
a quiet conversation.
Or it can fun, you know?
Like when you tickle your partner.
Yo, tickle my nuts.
All right, all right,
no more of that.
Come on, let's get to the test material.
The statewide exam is next week,
and then we'll get back
to the regular lessons.
Can we talk about intimacy?
If you like, and,
if I don't get too embarrassed.
All right, uh...
so the grand total on the check
is $67.40,
but if they want to leave a tip--
Look at your sample test, please.
I got to say, miss Duquette,
it felt like y'all schemed us.
This class is the same
as the ones down the hall.
Yeah, it's 'cause the test coming up.
OK, class, let's take a look
at the sample math test.
- In sample "a", we start with...
- Kid's right. This is bullshit.
The test material doesn't
exactly speak to their world.
Yeah, don't speak too loud
to mine, either.
An estimate, Detective.
We start opening those houses,
we might turn over
a couple of dozen bodies,
but that's just me guessing.
All of them homicides?
The boy took over half the west side.
We never saw the violence.
This right here is the reason why.
You're asking us to call out
half of public works
and pull the plywood off
thousands of vacant houses
all so we can raise
the city's murder rate by 10%?
What else are we doing on Stanfield?
I'm trying to get backup on his people's
cellphones as fast as I can.
And I started to look for his money.
But if I'm right about this,
they have to be worked.
Is there any evidence at all
that links all these
missing persons reports
to the Stanfield organization?
I'm just starting at that.
The one body that we pulled out of
the Fulton avenue house is Lex.
His case is a direct tie.
And there are 2 other names on
those missing persons reports
that show up in our wire taps
from earlier this year.
So, yes, there are links, counselor.
By any chance, did Landsman
run this up the chain to you guys?
No.
Your call.
My office won't care
until they see case files.
I'll run it upstairs,
and we'll see what comes.
OK, I get it.
He's still tied up,
but it really should only be
a little while longer.
Can you tell the Governor
I have to go back to Baltimore.
I have a little bit
of business today.
I'm the mayor of a major American city,
for Christ's sakes.
How much shit
do I have to eat from this guy?
Wouldn't you play the politics
if you were him?
It's not like the state
had no role in this thing.
The state money for those
schools had no oversight either.
But I'm not telling
the Washington fucking Post,
talking about how
he might be forced
to bail me out because--
What was the quote again?
Because "those are my children
in Baltimore, too."
He's gonna bleed me for that money.
Mayor Carcetti?
The governor's office
says he's ready to see you now.
$54 million's a big number.
We won't go until we get some,
we won't go until we get some--
Did I do something wrong?
I ain't acted up or nothing.
You're ready for this.
You can do the work.
I know you can.
And if you need
to come back here
and use the showers
or give me laundry,
use the computer,
you can do that any time.
Anyway, let me show you.
This here the way to the hard drive.
This isn't necessary, Duquan.
Just in case I'm busy, Mr. P.
So you know how to work it.
- Hey, boy.
- What's up?
Big day for you.
See here?
I got the inventory
divided between us.
You gonna go up one way
towards north avenue...
and I'm gonna stay down
by the highway.
You gonna let me handle
the money alone?
You ready, ain't you?
Yeah, I'm good.
All right.
Let's get on it.
I see you back here tonight.
All right.
You see that foul motherfucker,
you let him have his money, OK?
- I don't need you messing with him.
- All right.
Make sure that count's right!
Yo, I need to talk to
the little motherfucker.
Maybe you can do that with me,
see it don't get out of hand.
Hey! Yo, Mike!
Yo, what up, duke?
I heard Randy's foster mom
gonna take him out of Tilghman, too.
Send him somewhere else.
That's messed up, man.
All right, holla, man.
How many?
As a theory,
Detective Freamon believes
there could be
additional bodies in those vacants,
maybe a dozen or more.
He believes?
Lester Freamon is not
in the habit of selling woof tickets.
I, for one,
would not bet against him.
And what do you suggest I do
with this information?
My feeling is
that city hall should be
brought into the loop.
We pull the bodies now
before New Year's,
and the stats
go to Royce's last year in office.
Matter of fact,
it gives Carcetti an advantage
with regards to
next year's crime rate.
- You mean--
- Tell the major
that now is the time
to empty those houses,
not next year, when it's on his watch
and he has to eat the stats.
Colonel, I see you've
thought this through,
politically, I mean.
I'm learning as I go.
I bet you fuckin' are.
Colonel, keep this conversation close.
That's a direct order.
You seen those girls at Douglass, man?
Yo, you right, duke.
Ain't gonna be like
middle school no more.
You know, I'm just thinking, yo.
Dag, man, not again.
Where your people at now?
Need any of your stuff from the pile?
It ain't no thing.
Yo, man, listen.
Me and bug got our own spot now,
so you could come
crib with us if you want.
What you mean
Kenard took the stash?
And he's still walking around?
I'm gonna talk to him, ma.
Make sure this never happen again.
Look at me, boy.
Kenard got to feel
some pain for what he did.
- He got to.
- I don't--
You don't what, motherfucker?
This how you pay me back
for all the love I showed?
Shit, I been kept you in Nikes
since you were in diapers.
- I'm trying.
- You trying, huh?
That's what you gonna tell your father
the next time you see him,
that you trying?
Or you gonna tell him
what you've done?
What he done got him locked up.
That's right.
Wee-Bey walked in Jessup a man,
and he gonna walk out one.
But you out here,
wearing his name, acting a bitch.
Oh, look at u,
crying now.
Fuck you think you going?
Get your ass back here.
I ain't done talking to you.
I mean, I'm police, right?
Murder police,
and I got bodies.
I'm just supposed
to let them layin' lie?
"We don't throw red up
on that board voluntarily."
That John Goodman off his diet
looking motherfucker was clear on that.
So go over Landsman's head.
Jimmy, that's you.
Send an anonymous fax,
but you see,
Lester here don't fancy boats.
And me?
I get sick just filling the bathtub.
It's just wrong.
Yeah, just like when I seen J-Lo with
that little itty bitty Spanish dude.
Genius.
He hid his mausoleum
right in the neighborhood.
How little pedro gonna
fill that big thing up?
Oh, man, that girl got
a prime cut of ass, boy.
- And a good heart.
- A good inverted heart.
This nail's like their signature.
Find it in any door in the west side,
and right as rain
you're gonna find a body.
Yes, sir.
I'm proud to be chasing
Mr. Marlo Stanfield.
Man, you act like you on the trail
of Pol Pot or some shit.
Motherfucker, I got $10 says
we can leave here right now,
go to any boarded up rowhouse
with a nail like that in the door,
and we will find a body.
- Make it 20.
- There you go.
But first let's have
another little taste.
- Jimmy, you in?
- I'm good.
Oh, come on, man.
Take that skirt off and have a drink,
for Christ's sake.
Drink that.
Man,
don't play like that.
Icicles, get 'em before they melt!
Hey, yo, Kenard.
Why you lie to me?
Fuck you talkin' about?
You said the police
kicked your door in.
I seen the door.
They ain't kicked shit in.
- How you gonna lie?
- Go on, man.
Yo, where the package at, man?
Package up my ass, gump.
- Your mother.
- You about to.
Go on, walk.
Gump ass motherfucker.
Hey-- Nay!
Hey, yo, look at that
little dude getting his ass beat!
Y'all was talking too goddamn much.
Go ahead, Nay.
Get your pack off this bitch
so we can go.
I ain't want it.
I'll take that 20 now, Bunk.
I can't see shit in here.
Ah, man.
I might
pull out my wallet, reach in,
and pull out a $25 by mistake.
I need me some
braille bills, something.
You ladies want to call
the crime lab?
Nah, man.
I'm like Stevie: too high.
You know I can't do no scene.
Well, there's not gonna be one,
on account of there is no body.
Not until the bosses say there is,
and when that happens,
you gonna miss all the fun, junior.
You know Daniels is gonna
keep this alive.
The white shirts will
fuck it up somehow.
You know it, Lester.
Maybe not this time.
Daniels is C.I.D.
It's a new day downtown.
I got it.
World is on its hole
when Jimmy Mcnulty is the most
qualified to drive.
Yeah, up is down,
black is white...
left is right.
What we got here?
Quiet overnight.
Cool.
Relief will be here for you
after roll call.
It's Sergeant Carver.
How you doing, Dawg?
Quiet overnight.
You go to school this morning?
We're gonna wait a little
longer on that to be sure,
but I can't say I'm comfortable going
to work every day and leaving him here.
Blow over in a week or so, you'll see.
Till then we still have
a car on the house,
and you have my cell number
if anything comes up.
We're gonna look out for you on this.
Have you had breakfast, Sergeant?
- No, but I gotta--
- You have time for a plate, I'm sure.
Sure.
I just dreamt something
gave me an idea today.
Hey, Sherrod.
You remember when we turned
that knocked down light pole
at the scales?
Pulled $80?
I been thinking we can
get to topplin' a couple
of those bad boys ourselves,
get all Paul Bunyan and shit, you know?
I mean,
we'll be all discreet and all.
Not take the hacksaw
to no more than a couple
on some quiet streets,
leave more than enough
for some people to
have light and all.
Thing is,
I got this other thing
I still need to take care of today.
Come on, Sherrod.
Wake up.
It's late.
No, no, no!
What you do? What you do?
What you do?
Come on, Sherrod.
Come on, man.
Come on. Come on.
You weren't supposed to do this, man!
Oh, man!
No phones?
Not a one.
And the players that
were using them before,
Chris, Monk, Ray-Ray,
they were out there on those corners.
Now, I would have seen
if someone went to a burner.
Goddamn it.
If we just stayed up
on the wire 2 months ago,
we wouldn't be going through this.
Can I help you?
Which one of you is Sergeant Hauk?
I am.
I'm shea.
This is Thomas. I.I.D.
Let me ask if you remember
pulling a surveillance camera
from I.S.D.,
Serial number AW466J9.
You remember that?
We also need to go over your paperwork
on a couple of informants,
so if you don't mind
coming back downtown with us,
you and...
Detective Sydnor and...
the third guy, what's his name?
Dozerman.
You don't need Sydnor or Doze, either.
Paperwork's all mine--
on the camera,
on the informants,
me alone.
Bodies?
- How many?
- Could be quite a few.
We won't know until
we take down those doors.
And this is 1 drug
organization you think did this?
That's the theory,
but nothing's certain at this point.
What is certain is that
if we're going to do this,
you probably want us to do it now,
before the new year,
while the bump in the murder rate
is still attributable to Mayor Royce.
Thoughtful, deputy,
very thoughtful.
I don't want anymore stat games
from your department.
You need to get your people
into those houses
because if there are bodies
in there, they need to come out.
But do it now.
I don't want to be finding
anymore bodies come January.
Yes, sir, Mr. Mayor, sir.
Choice comes down to this.
We take the state money,
and instead of being
fucked up and broke,
our schools go back to being
merely fucked up.
No teacher layoffs,
no program cuts,
no school closures.
But the price the governor's asking is
more state control over the school board
and changes
in the teachers' union contracts
that would allow them to remove
tenured faculty for cause.
We don't take the money,
looks like we're shorting our own kids.
If we take the money, we're giving up
local control of education,
which is gonna lose us
a lot of middle class black folks.
Not to mention the problem
you might have
2 years from now
running in the DC suburbs
explaining how you needed their money
to bail out your schools.
He sees you coming, Tommy.
That's not important right now.
Take the money.
We need it.
Don't look at me.
If you take it,
you're selling out the teachers,
and that's my base.
If you don't take it,
you're selling out the kids.
Either way, I'll probably rip you
and half the council will, too.
Just glad I'm not the Mayor.
You called?
Word down the chain.
Open 'em up.
And it's my guess this case
is gonna need more manpower.
Yeah, no doubt.
In fact I might have lost Herc
to an I.I.D. File.
Really?
I went light on him for that car stop.
I didn't even think
it would get to a trial board.
This feels like a bigger jacket.
Pick any 2 you want from C.I.D.
For now.
If you get back up on a wire,
we'll detail a few more.
Beautiful.
I don't know what you're talking about,
But she was hot.
I'm going back on Friday
right after work.
Hold on.
What the fuck are you staring at?
How are you liking homicide?
Loving it. Why?
Anyway.
It's on the way, boss.
It's Joe and his message,
but we already know what it is.
All right, girl.
Keep it close.
All right, now,
call your amigos and tell 'em it's on.
That's right.
Yep. That's it.
One, come on.
One, one.
That's right.
What's going on, Mike?
Man, yo, I feel like
I could just pancake
a young'un right now,
you know what I mean?
What about you, duke?
Want some go?
No, I'ma work this rope.
Yeah, you working it.
Like a gump.
They pull around back,
we're gonna come at 'em
from both ways, feel me?
Hey, yo, call your friends,
tell 'em where we at.
Yo, let me get that rope.
I said I'm workin' it.
Man, I said you's a gump,
fucking dog shit and
smelling ass nigger.
Man, fuck this.
Yeah! Go home! Get!
Don't nobody
want you in here, no way!
You see what happened?
That be it.
Hey, daddy.
Kiss the butt of this lyricist.
Blow on my Mike and make a wish.
Get up!
Everybody, get up.
Let me get a 10, daddy.
Let me get a 10. I need a 10.
- Get the fuck out of here, now.
- I'll suck your dick for 15.
Trick-ass bitch, I said get.
Don't you want to see my stuff?
Nah, ain't nobody
want to see that stink box.
- Get your ass gone.
- Come on, let me get a 10, player.
What the fuck is this, the inner harbor?
Yo, what the fuck
y'all think you doing?
- We painters.
- Si, we paint.
Move the van out the way.
You gonna like what I got, soldier.
See? We paint.
We paint.
Which one of y'all
gonna open the truck for me?
- Fucking amateurs.
- Yeah, yeah.
Drink it slow, son.
What am I gonna do?
I'll run you home.
I-- I can't go home.
She expects me
to be my father, but...
I ain't him.
I mean, the way he is and shit...
it just ain't in me.
What's between you and Michael?
Mike ain't Mike no more.
He went hard on his boy last night,
fucked his shit up.
I can't go home.
I can't.
Give us a minute.
Mad at myself, man.
I shouldn't have shut
Michael out like I did.
Namond did push it.
He ain't pushin' nothin' now.
Reckon I'll go mend the fence.
This ain't no motel.
Deacon, how'd you get by my people?
You can't turn away church folk,
ain't done in these parts.
You only come by for a favor,
so what is it?
You know a fella named Bunny Colvin?
Yeah, that rogue police commander,
tried to legalize drugs.
- What's he done now?
- What did they say?
He can tell you best.
You did not bring...
it's something positive, Odell.
Has to do with kids.
Bunny.
Delegate Watkins.
What's this all about?
It's another bright idea.
You Michael Lee's mother?
He got papers on him or something?
I ain't no kind of police.
I'm just looking to get up with him.
You ain't alone.
He booked on out of here,
got his own spot,
- took his little brother with him.
- You know where he stay at?
He ain't tell me nothing.
You find the boy, you let him know
I need some help around here.
I popped him and bug out my ass,
and now they forgot where
they came from.
What my ma said when you called?
She was mad, right?
Not really.
His mother?
Lovely lady.
What she say?
Put that bitch
in baby booking where he belongs,
let him learn something.
She hung up before I could
tell her we didn't have a charge.
Baltimore city 911.
They beatin' a cop
over here on Pennsie and Gold.
- Police officer?
- Yeah, they're beatin' on him bad.
- Pennsylvania and Gold?
- Yo, they firing shots now.
Sign 13, report of shots fired,
Pennsylvania and Gold.
Signal 13--
They cleaned the motherfucker out, Joe.
Put it in the van them
Mexican niggas rolled in.
I ain't hearing about no resistance.
Man, wasn't no time for that.
Omar had one of them commando
squads with him, man.
I mean, he had this one ho
pulling guns out her pussy, Unc.
The shit was unseemly, man.
I got to hand it to Mr. Little.
I ain't see this one coming.
They took the shipment, Joe.
Not no package, man,
the motherfucking shipment,
man, what we gonna tell the co-op?
Where you think my mind at right now?
All I know, it's a lot of gangsters
out a lot of shit, man.
I say we mob up
and go find this faggot, see?
That's what's really hood right there.
That's how you deal with shit.
A lotta gangsters in that room
need to take us at our word first.
Yeah,
first thing they gonna wonder about...
is us.
You need to see my man,
I'll hook you up.
Who is this motherfucker?
Let me get a word with you, Mike.
Listen,
you got to understand
I can't having no physical confrontation
Like the one took place back there.
That kind of thing
got to stay outside my gym.
Yeah. Go ahead, Montel.
I come to tell you I was wrong,
the way I handled it.
Step off, nigga.
Mike...
don't touch me, man.
Look, man,
this here ain't you.
Man don't want you touching on him.
Mike.
I told you, step the fuck off.
Young man, if I was talking to you,
you'd know I was.
Shit!
Tell him to listen next time.
Go ahead, man. Do him.
Nah, man.
I'll hang here for the ambo, all right?
Go with your people.
Go ahead, son.
Dr. Johnson, please call neuro-LCU.
I'm sorry, son.
I'm gonna talk to social services.
We'll get you some help.
Randy...
Would E on call
please return to neuro-LCU.
On call, please return
to neuro-LCU.
You gonna help, huh?
You gonna look out for me?
You gonna look out for me,
Sergeant Carver?
You mean it?
You gonna look out for me?
You promise?
You got my back, huh?
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - www.thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net