W.M.D. Got them W.M.D.
You better move it on down.
It ain't pretty.
It doesn't have to be.
It just needs to pull them
from the places still worth salvaging.
Alright.
I told the other shifts
now I'm telling you:
When I ride my district
at the end of this week
I want to see empty corners.
They bring it here,
or the other two free-zones
or you bang them senseless.
Anything you need to do, you do.
Up to a body that can't walk
itself out of an emergency room
I'll back up you and your men.
You understand me?
Now,'ve detailed our I.I.D. representative
to the range for the entire week.
All citizen complaints will be handled
by Lieutenant Mello here.
Whatever it takes.
Man, I ain't even dirty.
I got rights an' shit.
Go with the one
about staying silent.
Shit like this
don't happen in Hamsterdam.
You gonna humble us
for just standin' somewhere?
Fuck y'all!
We in america.
West Baltimore.
I swear to god, officer Herc
you unhook babycakes
and my peoples be
down where you want us.
Swear to god.
Fuck with a man's ride,
you're gonna get his attention.
Babycakes?
Yo, yo, yo, hold up.
Motherfuckers gonna hear
from my motherfuckin' lawyer.
This right here
is some outrageous shit.
You think?
Fuck y'all lyin' motherfuckers.
Gentlemen.
That is outrageous.
Come on, sweetheart.
Bust your ass out of here.
Still Maryland.
But if y'all don't take that shit
down to Hamsterdam tomorrow
the next time
it's gonna be West Virginia.
That little star right there?
Across from the dipper?
That's north.
You wanna go the other way.
Assholes.
Homecoming
Landfills, got Landfills.
W.M.D. Got that W.M.D.
We'll start the interior
construction within the week.
Which means we need
to readdress the budget.
Readdress how?
Well, for one, the price
of steel has doubled.
It'll triple
if we don't buy it now.
- Ain't the steel bought already?
- Not the bulk of it, no.
And then there are the gutting costs.
They exceeded our original expectations.
He needs to wear
the hat when he's on-site.
Code, you know.
Gutting costs went up, huh?
That was due to your modifications.
The changes you asked for
in those loft units.
Necessitating new permits.
Which means another delay.
Unless we expedite.
Bring the architect and his
people back in over the weekend
and get something
to the city on monday.
Whoa, man, that part
of his original fee?
No, this was unanticipated.
Look, y'all fucked up,
so y'all supposed to take the hit, right?
Excuse me?
I mean, my man here don't know
shit about no gutting costs
he don't know nothing
about no price of no steel.
He just tryin'
to get some shit built
and y'all supposed to have
expertise behind this.
Only what I'm sayin' is
it seem like the expertise
ain't where it supposed to be.
Unfortunately, Mr. Barksdale
cost overruns are
the nature of the business.
We should discuss
this over lunch.
Ah, hell no, man,
I got elsewhere to be.
This is the Marlo kid.
He's fresh blood for the organization.
Bell's given him the best real estate.
The Barksdale people
took what they needed
when the towers
came down, no problem.
Stringer hasn't missed a step.
He's still selling drugs.
Lotta drugs.
He's not dropping bodies.
Nah, he doesn't need to.
He's got all the corners he needs.
And I'm supposed to give a shit?
Lieutenant, two weeks
Bell looked insulated
like he had enough legitimate front
to be able to be just the bank.
What Kima's found out is he's still
directly involved with the drugs.
Otherwise, why the face-to-face
with the Stanfield kid?
He's still connected
to the day-to-day.
We come back six, eight months
you won't even get him
in a room talking drugs
much less handling any.
It's now or never, Lieutenant.
Stringer Bell is quiet.
And if he's quiet
I don't give a fuck
if we come back a year from now
and find out he's on
the greater Baltimore committee.
This unit is about the bodies.
Major Forrester, call two-four-six-two.
Major Forrester.
What the fuck is this?
Ten-page report
on the heroic police work
undertaken to retrieve officer
Dozerman's service weapon.
Send that upstairs, keep the bosses
outta your ass for a while.
You actually did all this?
Would it matter if I had?
Jay
I'm a murder police
I got a double on my plate.
I'm gonna work it.
We ain't got Fayette
and Poppleton neither?
What the fuck?
I'm workin' on it, man.
The avenue corners, too.
What you mean
you workin' on it, man?
Why we ain't at least have
a shop setup down the block?
We did.
There was a setback.
Ran our boys off.
Who?
- Just some player, man.
- Listen.
Let him tell me.
We hire him for muscle.
The boy, Marlo.
Marlo, who the fuck is Marlo?
He tied into one of the mobs?
Young boy.
Runnin' it on his own, too.
Got maybe 15 spots
along here and the avenue.
An independent with
no fuckin' support?
Got all the prime real estate
and we doin' what exactly?
Young boy ran us
off the corner.
I'm losing
my motherfuckin' mind, man.
And I sincerely mean
your girl no disrespect but...
Tosha wasn't killed because
she just happened by that mess.
I think we all know that, right?
She was a player.
We know that much.
We got the science
that says she'd fired a gun
when it all went down.
Gun wasn't there for us to find
but that just means someone
grabbed it up, right?
I mean, your girl she, uh...
definitely had her say
when everybody else
on that street was talking.
Am I wrong?
Well, I got witnesses
on the scene that said
she was there right in
the middle of a drug robbery.
Boy by the name a' Omar
was in on it, too.
Nobody saying Tosha was an angel.
Nobody saying that.
But what are they saying?
The crew Tosha was runnin' with
maybe they didn't throw
the shot that killed her.
But if they don't come to me
early and tell the true story
I guarantee they won't
breathe a free breath
until them cicadas come back.
Y'all get the word
to the right people.
And you've spoken to
the medical examiner, correct?
What's he say?
He says it's lumpy.
Lumpy?
He says if an investigation
can come up with a credible scenario
he's willing to change
the cause of death to homicide.
Do you even have a suspect here?
Look, I don't know
how you city guys do it.
But down here in Annapolis,
we try to duck a punch or two.
Not lean into every last one.
My county doesn't
need another murder.
I'm glad you could came.
Ladies, Reverend Wright
I'd like you to meet
my husband, Cedric Daniels.
Nice to meet you.
Not that I've seen, no.
- She was invited, right?
- Oh, of course.
Eunetta doesn't make it
too much nowadays.
Not even council meetings.
I think Eunetta's gonna have her
hands full come the primary.
Mayor will pull her through.
He still have coattails?
Sheeeeet, boy.
You look up incumbent
in the damn dictionary
and you'll see Clarence
Royce smiling back at you.
He gets his whole ticket through.
Mayor's got a new poll
showing his negatives
they've really jumped
in the last year.
Not that he's gonna be putting
a press release out about that.
I hear you took a swipe
at Hizzoner the other day
on that witness murder.
Not at the mayor directly.
But we had the police brass in
front of the subcommittee and
I dunno, there's just
no excuse for what happened.
You keep on it, Councilman.
A little smack here and there
does this administration
a world of good.
That's why we need
new blood on the Council.
Keep everybody honest.
Don't embarrass yourself.
So...
your murder's never
gonna be a murder
and Daniels's got his head
all up in another case.
You know what the hardest part
of being a police is?
Yeah, explaining to your wife why
she has to take antibiotics
for your kidney infection.
I was gonna say trying to make
the job actually matter.
That too.
Speaking of your ex wife,
what's up there?
Nothing.
She's got her hooks in some lawyer.
Money guy.
Fuck it and fuck her.
So what, you movin' on?
Yeah, I might have some fresh
hope, now that you mention it.
Yeah, there's this woman
at this thing for my kids.
She, like, raises money
for the school and all that.
You know.
She's got a face, a body and
a brain all working together.
And she looks
like the kind who might
tell me when my shit stinks,
which is probably what I need.
She's kinda like Freamon with tits.
So what, you get her number?
No, not exactly.
Hey, what kinda detective
would I be if I couldn't
track a white woman
in Baltimore, right?
There you go.
You were so smooth tonight.
You had them eating
right out of your hand.
It's what you need from me, right?
Anyway, it wasn't too bad.
I'm getting better at it, I guess.
You are.
Cedric. Maybe we could...
I don't know.
Right now
you tell me where you need me
and whether you want the class
"a" or the class "b" uniform.
And I'm there.
More than that, I just don't know.
So.
I'm sayin' what the fuck?
Take a deep breath, man.
I mean take a long deep breath
and know that if you call the shot,
we at war
we at war.
I'm there like I always been.
Thing about turf, man,
it ain't like it was.
I mean you ain't got to pay
no price of buying no corners.
Since when do we buy corners?
We take corners.
Man, you gonna buy
one way or another.
Whether it's the bodies that
we done lost or you gonna lose
time in the joint that's
behind us or ahead of us.
I mean, you gonna
get some shit in this game
but it ain't shit for free.
I mean how many
corners do we need?
How much money can a nigger make?
More than a nigger can spend.
And we ain't gonna be around
to spend what we done made already.
Shit, I didn't think I was
gonna be around this long.
Well, we here now.
The fact is we got
every mob in town:
Eastside, Westside,
ready to pull together
share territory on that good shit
that Prop Joe puttin' out there.
We take the shit downtown
and we get in the money game
that niggers ain't going to jail.
I mean, we past
that run and gun shit, man.
Like we fund us a package
and we ain't got to see
nothing but bank.
Nothing but cash.
No corners, no territory, nothing.
We make so much got-damn
straight money, man.
The government come after us, man
ain't shit they can say.
Businessmen, huh?
Let the younguns
worry about how to retail
we're the wholesale.
I mean, who gives a fuck
who's standing on what corner
if we're taking
that shit off the top
putting that shit to good use
makin' that shit work for us?
We could run more than corners, B.
Period.
We could do like
Little Willie, man
back in the day,
with all that number money.
And run this got-damn city.
Like businessmen.
Man, just lemme talk to the boy, Marlo,
see if I can't smooth this shit out.
I mean it ain't gonna be overnight
cuz the nigger already
knows what he knows.
But I think I could
talk some sense in his head.
Yeah, I ain't no suitman,
businessman, like you.
You know, I'm just
a gangster, I suppose.
And I want my corners.
I've gotta tell ya
I'm having a tough time
wrapping my head around the
reality of you being paroled.
Trust me, I won't fully comprehend it
until I'm sipping my first martini.
Toby, I'm...
Homide police
went to Tosha's people.
Talking about how
they know she was in the mix.
Sayin' they got witnesses an' shit.
They called your name on it, too.
- So what they say?
- They called me.
Hey, yo, I know this cop, man.
Maybe we should help him out.
Tell him who did what.
Yo, stop wallin', Kimmy.
A- ight, now I said I got this.
Tosha's people want to know from me
exactly what happened that day.
That's all I'm saying.
Well tell 'em she caught one tryin'
to take the boys down, man.
Ain't no need to involve
the police in none of this.
Sound to me like
he involved already.
Kimmy, I told you, I got this.
Time!
Asshole.
My husband worked for
Mr. Cooper at the american can.
He made good money.
We saved up and bought this house.
There were some white families
still living in the neighborhood then.
The neighborhood
has changed, Mrs. Hazel.
This is a picture of the house.
City owned, taxes paid and all.
It is very nice.
But I can't afford that.
You don't have
to worry about the money.
It's all taken care of.
This is a special program we have.
It's for people who are living
in really bad situations
with the drug trafficking
you see outside.
And this is a good neighborhood.
It's safe and it's on
the number 19 line.
And it's walkin'
distance from your church.
Officer, this is
the only home I know.
It's all I got.
Now you say you have a program
that can place me somewhere else.
But you ain't got no program
for what's outside my door?
You weren't lying.
I told you.
And I've been all over
these blocks like you said.
I haven't seen any cameras,
nobody peekin'.
And monk man
and his crew been here
for grindin' for days
and knockers ain't even blinked.
Tell you what.
Send my people over.
Not too many.
Just some of the younguns.
Keep the package real small,
in case it's a trap.
I'ma hear directly
from you on this.
I'm on it.
Shit is just bugged out, you know?
String called, said to tell you
he's gonna be late
behind something he needed
to see down the way.
So what you tellin' me we weak?
Boss, I reached out to Black Donnie.
Okay, spit it out, man.
Listen, stop fucking double talkin' me.
Black Donnie said
he ain't having any of it.
Said Brother Mouzone
put a hex on all of us.
What 'bout Peacock?
Peacock when a hired
out some dominicans.
What about Eggy Mule?
Eggy locked up.
Caught a nickel
with the feds for a pistol.
How 'bout Shorty Boyd?
Shorty Boyd went
and cleaned his whole ack' up.
Yeah, I know. Fucked us all up.
What we got?
Soldier you sent at us, Cutty,
he gonna work out
but the rest of them dudes,
I dunno.
A- ight, listen big man,
you about to earn your fuckin'
keep around here right now.
You go out, you get Cutty
and get the best of the rest
and put a hurtin' on Marlo.
I want my corners.
Fuck.
What now?
Problems, Mr. Bell.
Naw, this ain't
the time for problems, man.
I got places to be.
We're being told it
may take weeks before
we can get the city
inspectors back down
here to approve these site changes.
Weeks?
Every day we wait, you lose money.
What the fuck?
How does anybody make
any money in this game?
Every time I think we good,
y'all back in my pockets.
You need to make a call.
Again?
He's the consultant, right?
You're paying him a nice chunk
of change to consult, right?
This is why we have
a politically connected guy
like that on the payroll.
He goes downtown and does for us
what we can't do for ourselves.
Democracy in action, Mr. Bell.
A- ight, look.
Me and Slim, we gonna
work through the alleys
and hit 'em from this side.
I want you, to come through here.
Slow down.
Through the intersection.
Hold, why don't
we just come up this way
then we don't have to worry
'bout crossin' no intersection.
Come that way.
You puttin' your driver
in the line of fire, man.
Think on it.
He gettin' taken out.
Car gonna crash.
Now, where that put you at?
Besides you don't wanna be shooting
cross your driver, do you?
A- ight, so come in easy.
They ain't gonna be lookin' for you
'cause we gonna have their full attention.
Hey, look, pick your targets,
drop 'em and move out quick.
Who drivin'?
I'm under the wheel.
Alright, you make sure
you slow down
at the end of the block
and toss your weapons.
And get rid of any shell casings
that kick back in the car.
Poh-leece can trace them shits.
Toss the gloves too, right?
Naw, hold on to them.
They gonna have
that D.N.A. Shit all on 'em.
Alright, look, it's gonna
take us some time to get set up
soe need ya'll to lay back
'bout four, five blocks.
And when we ready, we're
gonna hit you on the burner.
Which y'all hold t'til I call you.
You got it?
We gonna handle our end.
You just make sure some fuckin'
way left out there for us.
'Cause I don't wanna feel
like I'm just someamn decoy.
Damn right about that.
It's just a relocate, no big deal.
I'm not asking for
round-the-clock protection
or anything like that.
No big deal?
Come on, Bunny, where the fuck
am I gonna find a house
for this old broad?
I got one already.
It's a foreclosure
up off the harford road.
All you gotta do is file
the emergency petition
my boys will move her in.
She's witnessing against
a violent drug crew.
Without her cooperation,
I doubt if it'll go forward.
She's 73 years old.
She's a brave old broad
to be doing this, I guess.
C'mon, Ray.
Look, we just lost
a witness in a drug case.
We don't wanna
lose another one so quick.
If Rawls gets wind of this,
you forged my signature.
Where's she living now, anyway?
She's on Vincent Street, sector two.
Bad location, huh?
You wouldn't believe it.
We should wait for the call.
Man, what if that
crew got lookouts?
Motherfucker, if we wait, it'll
be all over time we get there.
Plus, look I'm sayin'
how's that gonna play with Avon
they takin' all the credit.
Yo, fellas, strap up.
There go that
motherfucker Nay-Nay, man.
I say we take him.
We should wait for the call.
Man, we wait,
he gonna get away, man.
Go, go, go.
Get out, get out!
What the fuck.
Didn't I say something about waiting
for a fucking phone call.
You know how you blow-off
half the invitations
you get to be somewhere?
Ribbon cuttings,
playground clean-ups and shit?
I got to, no choice.
I was gonna cut out
on one the other day,
it was a fundraiser
for the delta phis, you know?
But I drag-ass over to the forum
to show the flag
and who's there in his ironsides
but Odell Watkins.
The rainmaker himself.
Yeah, talking in public about
being kinda disappointed
in the Mayor.
Disappointed, yeah?
Like how?
Like sincerely disappointed...
the way you'd be
with one of your kids.
Like he really wanted to see
the Mayor pressed, you know?
Got me thinking.
Maybe somebody can take a run
at Royce in next year's primary.
Like who?
Madame Council President?
Or Mickey Pepper
would give him a fight.
Mick's already said he doesn't
want to leave the legislature.
He won't risk it.
Well, you gotta
have someone with balls.
And somebody black.
This being Baltimore and all.
How many y'all take?
Two.
Didn't get nary a shot off.
Speak to the quality
of Barksdale's people.
He gonna have to come back at you.
You know it ain't gonna stop at this.
I don't want it to stop.
Barksdale weak today.
They ain't working
with the ammunition I got.
No doubt, you carryin'
a full clip.
But what you gonna do when you sittin'
at the head of the table?
Once you there,
you got to hold it down.
Sound like one
of them good problems.
Prisons and graveyards
full of boys who wore the crown.
Point is, they wore it.
It's my turn to wear it now.
We're gonna do this, right, Chris?
- We gonna do this, son.
- It's ready yesterday, dawg.
White t's, man?
Need to get yourself some white t's.
So you workin'
your plan, huh, Bubs?
Dollar here, dollar there, Kima.
So, what's up? Why you call?
Jus' checkin' in.
You still interested
in the boy Marlo, right?
No?
You wanna keep gettin' paid
you need to get your ass
up to park heights
school yourself on a jamaican
named Kintel got them corners.
Kintel, huh?
My bosses don't
give a fuck about Marlo.
Stringer's people neither.
That's too bad.
Yeah.
'Cause now we got
a whole lot of drama.
What happened?
That young buck, Marlo,
ain't gettin' runned off.
He jus' dropped two Barksdale
soldiers on the corner
of Mount and Fayette
a few hours past.
What?
Corners all jumpin' bad.
I thought Marlo
had them corners for Stringer.
- We saw them meet.
- I don't know what you saw
all I know is Marlo
is flying his own colors.
Westside about
to be all Baghdad an' shit.
But ya'll looking
for jake, what's his name?
Kintel?
Y'all too fickle for Bubs, man.
I swear.
A little gift for you and your boys.
Call me.
Whitey sale! Whitey sale!
Deputy, I am aware of the
incident and my men are on it.
We called in the seven-to-three
flex squad early
and my D.E.U. is canvassing.
And what do we know?
Only that it seems to be rival gangs.
What does homicide have?
Fuck homicide.
I'm asking you
for answers right now, Major.
Sir, my men..
And you damn sure have none.
My men are out there...
What do we know that we
can actually tell the man?
Like you said, rival gangs.
Which gangs?
Gangs.
Assholes who don't like each other.
I'm sorry, Major.
But we got nothin' on it.
Play it. It don't make me
no never mind.
It's all 'bout trumps.
Evenin', omar.
Evenin', Bruiser.
Speakin' 'of them trumps now.
Hey, everybody.
What's for dinner, Jen?
I'm starvin'.
It's working.
Hi, daddy.
How you doin', beautiful?
Daddy, we shared with you.
That's nice.
Hey, Jen, you seen that tape
I was watchin' last night?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You gotta see this.
Videotape from last monday
night's council meeting.
Keiffer tried to block my resolution
but I laid him out good.
I was in rare form, baby.
- You seen that tape?
- Maybe you left it in the VCR.
What... sonofabitch.
Who the hell...
Daddy, Franky shared
his sammitch with you.
We hid it so no one else could
eat it before you came home.
Could I get some chips
and pickles with that too?
I don't want to disrespect you.
String been good to me, you know?
Not just my bills.
Him and Avon probably
think they owe me that much.
And it ain't what people might
be thinking or saying, either.
What they saying, honey?
It ain't like I don't miss Dee.
I do.
Yeah, well, I miss him too
but he's been gone a while now.
More than a year.
Stringer's fine
no denying that.
I feel safe around him.
You asking to get with String
I'm okay with that.
Thought you was gonna be mad.
I mean, everything with Dee
is so messed up, you know?
I mean, every time
I think about it...
and you know this one police
he came by here
and brought it all up again.
Who did?
Police detective from the city.
The one tried to turn Dee on Avon
when he got pulled up in Jersey.
White boy?
- Bushy hair?
- Yeah.
What he say?
He said maybe D'Angelo didn't take
you know... take his own life.
He said maybe
it was something else.
And he came to you with it?
Left his card here one day
but I didn't say
nothing to the man.
Just told Stringer is all.
She's gonna run for Council?
She is.
Probably win, too, if I know her.
And you're the proud husband?
Not sure how that makes me feel.
It's just for show until
the election next year.
A city police lieutenant
looks good on her arm.
Who even cares anymore?
Half the country are separated
the other half are getting
divorced for the second time.
This is a favor.
For her.
It's hard to explain.
Look, I disappointed her.
She lived through me
for a lotta years
telling herself I was tracked
for deputy commissioner
at worst and past the police
department, who knows?
And there we were some things
that happened a long time ago
when I was in Eastern.
I guess she wanted more out of me
and after a lot of years
and a lot of plans
it turns out I have
a better head for police work
than I do for climbing the ladder.
She hung in there
thinking my career
was going to turn
into some kind of big deal
and I probably let her
believe it just to keep peace.
Now she wants
to be the big deal.
What do you want?
I just don't want
to disappoint her anymore
and right now
I'm more help showing up
at some chicken dinner
in my wedding ring and dress blues
then being the
not-even-divorced-yet husband
with the white woman on his arm.
I'm going to do what I can to see
she gets what she
wants this time around.
Nothing more than that.
Last seen Gerard, man
he was racin' bullets
up on Fayette Street.
He appeared to be winnin', too.
Look, man,
until he shows back up
we ain't gonna know
what happened out there.
I damn sure know one
fuckin' thing for sure.
Two our people are chalked
and we ain't got shit to show for it.
Man, police gonna
be real heavy on this, man.
I say we slow down.
Take our time
to build our muscle up...
No, I ain't got no more
motherfuckin' time, man!
When the word comes that this boy,
Marlo, punkin' me
what am I look like?
I'm gonna go do this
shit my damn self.
Naw, man, you just
this minute got home.
Your name come up
in a murder beef, man
they gonna pull your parole.
Let me take care of this.
We was thinkin', man,
me and Cutty, you know
so we could hit
back at 'em ourselves.
That way there
won't be no fuckups.
Look, you two
niggers get on it, man.
And get it right.
You see how shit
had to be handled, man.
The game is the fucking game.
Period.
Same as it ever was.
I dunno though, man.
I mean...
I dunno, I was just down the way
with one of our younguns
on Vincent Street
where they got them
you know, empty houses over there.
And they got crews over there
twirlin' dope and coke like
the shit was candy.
Kids with a lemonade stand.
It's a different world down there.
Like the cops just standing
around like that shit was...
legal.
I mean, every day.
It actually was business.
What you sayin', man.
What's up?
Nothin', man.
Nothin' at all.
Our C.I. tells us those
are Stringer's people.
You want us to be about
the bodies, now we are.
We had this kid, Marlo
working for Stringer
but that might be wrong.
He might be going
to war for those corners.
Let me be clear:
This is no longer
about Stringer Bell.
Or Kintel fucking Williamson.
Or any of them.
What is my rank, Detective Greggs?
My rank!
Lieutenant, sir.
What is my rank,
Detective McNulty?
If you can't
remember that much
then you can go
the hell back to narcotics.
And you can go to whatever the
hell unit will still have you.
Now get the fuck out
of my office.
Your message said you'd be here.
Still, I kinda thought it'd be
one of your minions
showed up in the flesh.
You called on some
of my people's people.
I'm just workin'.
Doin' what a man is supposed to do.
Well, I know you been busy.
Caught some talk from the young men
you rousted over there on the Westside.
That was about a gun,
belonged to a police.
Yeah, caught some
talk about that, too.
This here's about something else.
Girl by the name of Tosha,
got her head blowed off in a firefight.
If you're not here to cooperate,
then why are you here?
Okay, I could just pull up
that other girl from your squad.
She ain't gonna talk to you.
Ain't nobody gonna talk to you.
I just came here
to make that clear, man.
Ain't no thing.
'Cause I already
got me an eyeball wit.
You do?
I dunno 'bout that.
Old Bruiser, he be blind behind
that fortified half the time.
Shit, you gonna have to dry him out
just to get him on the stand.
'Sides, he done had
a change o' heart to that story.
That's what I heard, anyway.
An' past that, you gonna have to call
this one of them
cost-of-doin'- business things
you all police be talkin'
about all the time.
Ya feel me?
No taxpayers.
Shit, way y'all lookin' at things
ain't no victim to even speak of.
Bullshit, boy. No victim?!
I just came from
Tosha's people, remember?
All this death,
you don't think that ripples out?
You don't even know what
the fuck I'm talkin' about.
I was a few years
ahead of you at Emondson.
But I know you remember
the neighborhood, how it was.
We had some bad boys for real.
Wasn't about guns
so much as knowin'
what to do with your hands.
Those boys could real rack it.
My father...
had me on the straight.
But like any young man
I wanted to be hard, too.
So I'd turn up at all the house parties
where the tough boys hung.
Shit, they knew
I wasn't one of them.
Them hardcases would
come up to me and say:
"go home, schoolboy,
you don't belong here. "
Didn't realize at the time
what they were doin' for me.
As rough as that
neighborhood could be
we had us a community.
Nobody, no victim,
who didn't matter.
And now all we got is bodies,
and predatory motherfuckers like you.
And out where that girl fell,
I saw kids actin' like Omar
callin' you by name.
Glorifyin' your ass.
Makes me sick, motherfucker,
how far we done fell.
25,000.
You don't need more
than that to get it done.
The fuck you say?
I'm just tellin' you how they do
down at zoning and permits.
They know you got
a general contractor
and his people out there
sittin' on their ass.
They know you payin'
twice that every week they sit.
25 gets me the permits?
20 gets you the permits.
Five is for me for bribin'
these downtown motherfuckers.
I mean, I'm the one
got to risk walkin' up
to these thievin' bitches
with cash in hand, right?
I'm telling you, String.
The people running
the city nowadays?
They make the last
bunch look sanctified.
I mean, this some shameful shit.
Permits come when?
Monday.
Latest.
Spider bags!
Cutt, that's him.
Fruit.
Yo, I know that nigger, man.
Owe me money, actually.
She ain't say it like that.
She say it like she wanted
to get pregnant an' shit.
A- ight.
Damn, I opened up too early, man.
I stepped on your shot.
Come on, let's book.
Yo, there go
five-oh right there, yo.
Yeah, I know it's nothing.
The cops be lettin'
niggas grind down here.
It all... get the fuck out
of here little hoppers.
Get out of here, son.
Look at these little minis.
Hey, yo, what if he lock us up?
I hope y'all got toothbrushes?
'Cause down in boy's village,
you know what I'm sayin'
if you don't have no toothbrush,
you gonna be usin' some other boy's brush
or rubbin' your teeth
with your damn finger.
If you don't get locked up
y'all can keep an extra
20 each off the pack.
...got that fire, baby?
Come on, Tommy, give it up already.
Look, Terri,
you gotta do this for me.
Tell me why
you wanna be mayor.
Why should I vote
for you over Royce?
'Cause something is wrong in that city
and I think I can fix it.
This guy, he don't give a shit
about tackling the problems.
Crime is outta fucking control.
Last week, a kid witness
in a drug case turns up
shot dead because
of flaws in the system.
I go to the Mayor
who promises action.
And then, "mister reform-is-more-than-
- the-watchword-of-my-administration"
pats me on the ass,
thanks me for my concern
points me out the door. The end.
So, with crime as the issue
the great white father
rides to the rescue.
Against a black incumbent mayor,
in a city that's 65% black?
Black, white, green...
people are pissed off.
What makes you
think this is doable?
One, I hear the mayor's got problems
in his base and with key supporters.
Two, I got
the Police Commissioner
Royce's own man,
telling me all kinds of stuff
about his fucked-up department
and about Royce's inner circle.
And three, Tony Gray,
from the Fifth District
comes pretty close
to telling me he's thinking
about a run for mayor.
That'd split the black vote.
You'd still need a player
who gives the black
middle-class permission
to vote against one of their own.
You got one of those
in your pocket?
Not many of those around.
Elijah?
Congressional black caucus
ain't gonna save your skinny white ass.
What about Odell Watkins?
Well, it's funny you
should mention him
cuz I don't think he's too
happy with the Mayor right now.
I dunno.
I hear a new poll shows Royce's
negatives are pretty high.
You'd have to raise
a load of dough.
He has to see it.
I know he sees it.
It's past that now.
It's about us showing some respect.
Oh, fuck respect.
- He ain't right.
- No, he ain't.
But at this point
with you on the other
side of the argument
he'd rather be wrong.
Maybe if the word
came down from on high
it might change his mind.
I mean, if your friend Bunny Colvin's
up to his ass in bodies
then he'd take all
the help he can get.
Not that you'd ever
go behind anybody's back
or anything like that, right?
No way.
Two more murders yesterday
and another three today...
including a 14-year-old.
We're doing all we can.
You're at 260 for the year
and it's barely october.
You promised me 275 or under, Erv.
I had that as a promise.
Sir...
we see 300 before the new year
and I'm not sure that I can
justify a full term for you.
Now I hate to say it,
but there it is.
Barksdale's people and who?
Marlo Stanfield, the new kid,
we've been on him a couple weeks.
But Daniels' people
are up in the Northwest.
Your war's only
gonna get worse, Major.
The Northwest has been
quiet for weeks.
You willing to back door your
lieutenant like this, huh?
You ain't changed, Jimmy.
Shit.
It's always about your case.
You do what you can.
Keep my name out of it.
How it go?
We got one of the two
of the motherfuckers you know.
You mean, you motherfuckers
come strollin' in here
all walkin' tall and shit...
Yo, B, I, man, I'm sayin', man.
We were blazin' on them dudes.
Man, you know what I'm sayin',
just got in the heat, man.
We were blazin' though.
It was like...
Alright relax, man, I already heard.
Go sit down.
I'm not tweakin'
behind none of this.
That's one less motherfucker
that's breathin' than was yesterday
you know what I'm sayin',
so we all good.
But I'm surprised at you,
though, man.
Shit didn't get by you back when.
Wadn't my man's fault, man.
I unloaded on
the youngun too soon, man.
Gave him enough room
to buck and run, man.
I fucked that shit up
myself, you know...
Hold on.
It's on me.
I had that kid in my sights
close enough to take off his Kangol
and half his dome with it.
I couldn't squeeze the trigger.
Couldn't do it, man.
Why not?
Wadn't in me, I guess.
You know, whatever it is in you
that lets you flow like you flowin'
do that thing
it ain't in me no more.
A- ight.
So you done soldierin'
but you ain't done.
I could use you
for what you got in your head.
We're gonna put you on a corner,
you can be inside...
Aw, man.
I'm ain't makin' myself clear.
The game ain't in me no more.
None of it.
But you ain't done shit else.
You know what I'm sayin',
so what you gonna do?
I don't know.
But it can't be this.
A- ight then.
We straight.
See ya.
B, he was a man
in his time, you know?
He a man today.
He a man.
Any idea what this is about?
Lieutenant.
Here he is, Bunny.
Cedric Daniels to the rescue.
Man of the hour.
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
Transcript par Raceman
Synchronisation: El Uploador
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net