You need another bag?
Yo, Mike, where you at?
Yeah, over here.
Drug war?
Barksdals coming back
on my boy Marlo, hmm?
Shit.
Got it.
Yo man, I don't know where we at.
We are in Baltimore, Lamar.
Baltimore, Maryland.
That's the second crib of mine
them motherfuckers cracked this week.
Stir up a hornet's nest
no tellin' who gonna get stung.
All paranoid an' shit.
Got to be.
They got Latroy.
What the fuck is y'all
on the streets for, man?
Don't you all know there's
a fucking war going on, man?
Get the fuck in the truck, man.
What happened to all them towers?
Slow train comin'.
Reform, Lamar.
Reform.
Reformation
We should be up on
this shit, hearin' voices.
We get a signature number
on Bodie's phone, we will be.
We got enough P.C.
off the burners alone.
Every time these fucking pen
registers click out a call
it screams drug conspiracy.
I'm not the one
takin' the case to court.
Pearlman wants a specific link
to a known drug trafficker.
These drug crews?
They're dumping phones
every couple weeks at best.
So when we do get a wire up,
it's gonna be a limited run.
And dumping phones doesn't
meet the cellular company's
definition of exigent
circumstance, huh?
What's your boss willing to do?
Demper?
He's a bit too focused on next
year's re-election fight.
How about the feds?
They say they can't
do anything for us
and if you look at how they use
the federal communications act
they're not lying.
For national security stuff,
they use the Patriot Act
every thing else gets shorted.
The fact is, the industry
has all of us by the balls.
Pardon my french, Your Honor.
Alright, I'll tell you what.
Best I can do for you is this:
You give me a boilerplate affidavit
with the P.C. from the court report
and then as you get fresh
numbers for new disposables
you call me...
anytime, day or night,
to jump phones.
That helps.
But we're still gonna be getting up
on their phones even
as they're coming down.
Yeah, probably so.
- This is so totally...
- fucked up?
"Je parle français bien,
et tu es très charmant aujourd'hui. "
Judge Phelan has you on his mind.
How long has that been going on?
Started with...
my first jury trial
in his court, I think.
I bet you won all your motions.
You wanted to see me, sir?
Have a seat.
I wanna thank you for
the loyalty you showed
moving that body.
It wasn't the most
sensible thing, but...
I appreciate it nonetheless.
You're a good man, Sergeant
you got good instincts
and as far as I can tell
you're a decent supervisor.
But from where I sit
you ain't shit when
it come to policin'.
Don't take it personal,
ain't just you.
It's all our young police.
A whole generation of y'all.
Now, you think about it:
You been here over
a year now, Carver.
You got nobody looking out for you
nobody willing to talk to you.
That about sum it up?
And that's a problem.
And I didn't think
there was anyway
I was ever gonna
get my head around it.
But then Dozerman
gets shot for some bullshit...
and that's when
I 'bout reach my limit.
And that's when the idea
of the free zone
of Hamsterdam come to me.
Because this drug thing,
this ain't police work.
No, it ain't.
I mean, I can send any fool
with a badge and a gun
up on those corners and
jack a crew and grab vials.
But policing?
You call something a war,
and pretty soon
everybody gonna running
around acting like warriors.
They gonna be runnin'
around on a damn crusade
stormin' corners, slappin' on
cuffs, rackin' up body counts.
And when you at war,
you need a fuckin' enemy.
And pretty soon
damn near everybody on every
corner is your fuckin' enemy
and soon the neighborhood that
you're supposed to be policin'
that's just occupied territory.
You follow this?
I think so.
Look, the point I'm makin',
Carver, is this...
soldierin' and policin',
they ain't the same thing.
And before we went
and took the wrong turn
and started with these war games
the cop walked a beat,
and he learned that post.
And if there were things
that happened up on that post
whether there be a rape,
a robbery, a shooting...
he had people out there helping
him, feeding him information.
But every time I come to you,
my D.E.U. sergeant
for information
to find out what's going
on out there on them streets
all that came back
was some bullshit.
You had your stats, you had
your arrests, you had your seizures.
But don't none of that amount
to shit when you talking about
protecting a neighborhood
now, do it?
You know the worst
thing about this
so called drug war?
To my mind?
It just ruined this job.
Major?
What do you got?
Incoming.
"Sunpapers" reporter.
Been to the free zones,
all three of 'em.
It's begun.
I was thinkin', maybe
we rewrite the affidavit
add some of the stuff we're
gettin' from the pen registers
build the case that way,
take it to the judge.
You have a law degree?
If you did, it would
be your call to make.
Who would pretend to be
a lawyer that wasn't?
I'm just saying.
I think we're being
too cautious on this.
We're going the
extra mile for Phelan.
A short cut now could cost us
later in motions hearings.
We drew Phelan on this wiretap?
That two-faced hack sold
me out the last go-round.
Relax...
he's not running for
a new term. He'll be fine.
He's a piece of shit.
We're all pieces of shit
when we're in your way.
That goes with the territory.
Point taken.
So it's these warehouses
the old Winchester homes and the
dead blocks down by Vincent Street.
All three.
And they're just supposed
to let it go on like this?
Colvin told us to push the
street dealing in these areas
then we would start
locking people up.
But so far, not a single
fucking arrest.
And they know about this downtown?
I don't think they have
a fucking clue about it.
But I'd love to be there
when you pop the question.
This is just...
Tell me about it.
Got the place lookin' good.
Yeah.
Now all needs doin' is to go
out and get you some kids.
Come on, man.
You makin' it sound easy
but to tell you the truth
I ain't got no idea how
to go at these hoppers.
I wouldn't lose
any sleep over that.
Nobody else does neither.
We got one.
His grandmother...
Looking for me?
Look, boy, there's no reason
to leave your clothes in the washer.
How many damn times
do I have to tell you...
Gag, grandma, sorry,
I just forgot, okay?
But I did pick up the laundry
soap, I picked it up...
Laundry soap,
that's definitely code.
Now, let's listen to an intercept
we made of Bodie Broadus
when we were up on the pay
phones a couple years back.
I'm tellin' ya all
I saw the boy he sayin'
he ain't got that thing.
Same voice, no question.
I'll let the judge know.
Reference the voice comparison
in the court report.
We're up.
Major Colvin, Western district.
Banisky, "Sunpapers".
So this your idea?
Mind if we walk?
You got dealers
selling with impunity.
Addicts shooting up on the street.
People down here doing outreach,
giving out needles and all.
I mean, who knows about
this down at headquarters?
Command is well
aware of the situation
and while there were
some initial concern
but they feel the cases
that we're gonna bring in...
Cases?
Yeah, prosecutions, sure.
Your officers say no one's being
locked up in the free zones.
My troops are only involved
in pushing the trafficking
to designated areas.
I mean they're completely ignorant
of the investigative aspect
that's run out of C.I.D. downtown.
Yeah?
Who's the lead detective?
Look...
I already said more than I should.
Bottom line is you start
throwing calls around right now
they gonna shit blue
thinking there's a leak.
They gonna come up
on the case early
and we're not gonna get all
we can out of the good work
we did down here.
You're telling me all this
is an enforcement strategy.
What the hell else could it be?
I mean, you think we'd actually
let this happen otherwise?
Come on, Banisky.
I mean, look, look at this mess.
Any other reporter gets on it...
I give it to you and you
run with it right then.
Absolutely.
A week.
But then I gotta run
something no matter what.
Purple Rain, Purple Rain.
It's understood.
So, Brother, what
brought you back?
It disturbs me to leave
business unfinished.
Heard you was shot before
you even got started down here.
Not like you to get played.
Betrayed, you mean.
I am looking for the man they sent.
From his accent he's homegrown,
raised on the street.
Skilled, intelligent.
Late 20s, dark
but with a scar
across his face like so.
You down with this nigger?
I know him.
Not to speak to
but you can't be
anywhere near the game
and not know
the motherfucker.
He with Barksdale?
He with himself.
'Cept for when he runnin'
with a young boy or two...
10 months to the primary,
and you right now
should be all about money.
I know, I know,
dialing for dollars.
You start this week and you don't
stop until you hit your numbers.
We're gonna need a million
just for television.
You really think this is doable?
The odds aren't great, but yeah...
I think it can be done.
As long as the thousand things
that can go wrong don't go wrong.
Even for a white guy?
Even for a white guy.
Speaking of which
I notice a certain
monochromatic effect here.
One thing we're gonna
need is black faces
and we're gonna need them
in prominent positions.
You're right.
We've gotta start thinking about
endorsements by black leaders.
Ministers, community people,
elected officials.
Here comes the hard part:
Splitting the black vote is the
only way to make the math work.
So Tony Gray's gotta
get in the race
he's gotta stay in the race and
he's gotta stay viable in the race.
Guy's kind of a lightweight,
ain't he?
He's a good guy, all in all.
Great, he's a good guy
but we need him to siphon
votes from Royce.
I dunno.
This thing with Tony...
it's not personal, Tommy.
It's politics.
Live with it or lose.
Hey, yo.
That boy with the sharp nose,
he gonna, you know...
he going to the Apollo.
The Apollo?
Yeah, he gonna need two tickets.
Damn, Tweety Bird
workin' that shit.
Motherfucker, how many times
I gotta tell you not to use no names?
Oh yeah, right.
So I holler at you?
Yeah, a-ight.
Apollo, like the theater?
Like 125th Street.
125 grams, one eighth of a kilo.
Two tickets means twice that.
Only new code so
far is Hamsterdam.
Hamsterdam?
We're thinkin' it might have
something to do with the stash house.
Well, I'm gonna hook up with Kima,
cash the Tweety Bird meet.
You're happy with
what we're getting?
Another week of calls like this
and we'll have their network
fleshed out and plenty
more phones to go up on.
I need a moment with the detectives.
Sure.
I.I.D. picked up Prez's shooting.
It's to be expected.
The racial thing alone is tense
enough that they gotta react.
No luck at all to that boy, huh?
For the supervisor's report
I need to ask if either of you
had any indication that Prez
harbored racial prejudices.
Well, he harbored
some weird shit, no doubt.
But I never got a racial vibe.
Lieutenant, you seriously askin'?
Not to start no shit
but you think Waggoner
gets shot if he's white?
Description called
for a number one male.
I'm just sayin'.
The good lord set sunday
mornin' aside for church-goin'.
Even kenny bird and peanut,
when they was warring,
had the good sense
to respect the truce.
You know them
Barksdales sent a hat?
A church crown?
Walked up, rang the bell,
and set it down on her porch.
'Cause they shamed.
Is Miss Josephine mendin'?
She bruised up still,
but she a-ight though.
But you ain't.
Not until I settle this for good.
Hey, yo, Butch, I want you
to go inside my bank
and spread the word:
Omar payin' cash money to get
at them people, ya feel me?
Save your money.
Come now, Butch,
I got to do this, yo.
I'm sayin' you ain't got to pay.
Thomkins, up on McCulloh.
What the funeral home?
You mean to tell me, all this time,
you had a scope on them clowns
and you ain't let loose
a mumblin' word.
Caught myself lookin' out for you.
Fact of the matter is,
your chances of goin' up
against that mob and comin'
back is as slim as a garter snake.
I can't help that now, Butch.
The fuck?
Where's my people?
Slim Charles pulled 'em.
Hired new muscle.
Slim Charles?
When the fuck did he...
How's the count?
Down bad for the
third straight week.
And the shelf-life
of the shit we got
it ain't gonna last, String.
I know.
Slim said they was to stick
to you for protection.
Nice shot.
Dribble it back out.
Get your dribble on.
Hey, yo, easy, easy.
Y'all just hacking my man up.
Foul machine.
Nice drive.
Kinda unschooled, ain't they?
Is that observation meant as
just a casual curbside fuck-you
or are you lookin' to step up,
maybe help out here?
I'ma give it a try.
I'm lookin' to get some
kids interested in boxin'.
Boxing?
Look here.
This is my time-out corner.
Where I send children
who can't play nice together.
Listen up, this man's
starting a boxing program.
And from the looks of some of you,
signing on might be a good thing.
Gonna need it.
Only thing he know
how to do with his fist
is wrap it around his cock.
Fuck you, man.
I'm gonna kick your ass.
Come on, motherfucker,
you ain't shit.
Yo, sit down, sit down,
come on, ease up.
Sit down, sit down, come on,
man, sit down, man, sit down.
My man...
my man, you droppin' your right.
You see, if the youngun there
was trained, he'd whip you.
Look like he was the one got beat.
Stand up, let me
show you something.
Come on, man.
I ain't gonna hurt you.
Yellow Tops, Yellow Tops,
got them Yellow Tops.
Yellow tops.
See that?
Alright, sit down.
Look, if y'all want to learn more
I got a gym down on Gilmor
in the old tire plant.
You're all welcome.
Alright?
I saw Tweety Bird parked up there.
Now all we got to do
is wait for the re-up.
I hope these fucks don't dick 'round
and make us sit here all day.
What, this eatin' at you?
No, I'm good.
Yeah, I can see that.
Remember that woman
I was talking about?
The politician woman?
How's it going?
It ain't, it turned to shit.
Feel like I don't even belong to any
world that even fucking matters.
'Cause you're a cop?
Naw, it's not just that.
It's like, I went to meet her once.
She was in a hotel
room, the top floor.
I punch the button on the elevator,
it doesn't even go there
because you have to have
some fucking special key
to even get to that
special fucking floor.
So I go to the front desk, some
sneering fuck call upstairs
gimme permission to go get laid.
I listen to the shit she talks about
and for the first time in my life,
I feel like a fucking doormat.
Like anyone with
any smarts would
do something else with
his life, you know?
Earn money or...
get elected.
Like I'm just a breathin'
machine for my fucking dick.
I'm serious.
I'm the smartest asshole
in three districts
and she looks at me like
I'm some stupid fuck
playing some stupid game
for stupid penny-ante stakes.
She fuckin' looks through me, Kima.
Stay in the car, man.
But the tall man said
to stick to you like...
Tall man gonna be there when
I'm stomp on your fucking head?
Stay in the car.
Yo, make it short, man,
I got a meet to make.
Oh, fuck the meet!
You harder to get at than
my fat wife's cunt, nigger.
Yeah, you high and
mighty Barksdales
can afford to sit back
and play low key,
But some of us gotta work
for a got-damn livin'.
What you think this mess
ain't fuckin' up our business?
That mean Avon's willin' to sit
down and talk with Marlo
work this shit out?
Well, if that don't happen,
String, I got you some bad news.
Me and the boys had us a sit down.
Got a quorum an'
took a vote that says...
if y'all don't quit this war
we of a mind to shut you out.
And when I say out, String,
I mean out the package.
The boys don't want
to extend the good shit
if it's gonna keep you and your
peoples out on them corners bangin'.
What about the boy?
What the fuck he say?
Vinson say Marlo willing to talk
if he can keep his corners.
Now, hear me on this,
String, we ain't no ingrates.
We all recognize your
contribute to the co-op.
But the feeling is this:
it ain't right for you to be
at the head of our table
when you can't call off your dog.
Call it a crisis of leadership.
You're gonna tell 'em?
Got to.
Between the health care
workers, the reporter
my own pissed-off troops,
it's gonna come out.
Either tomorrow, or the next day.
Then we should make a few arrests
make it look tactical.
Naw.
You know what happens if we start
lockin' people up in Hamsterdam?
The whole rest of the district
goes back to being a shithole.
Naw.
If Rawls is gonna hand me my ass
at least give me a chance
to tell the man my story first.
Devonne.
It needed doin'.
Somebody just got shot.
What you want I should give the
snitch that clued us to the denali.
I mean we didn't
get Marlo, but still...
No, he kept his end up.
Go it all.
Avon, I need a word, man.
A- ight, get them
things out of here.
Check it out, String.
This shit got a kill range
of like 50 meters.
Slim got this from some soldier
comin' back from wherever.
I spoke to Prop Joe's people.
They think we can work this out.
A sit-down?
It's the perfect time
for it, man, I mean...
you done represented yourself, man.
Your name ringin' out
now that you done
taken Marlo down
a notch or two, man.
So why not quit while we ahead.
Just let me get this
thing right, man
then, you know, we get
back to business as usual.
They gonna cut us out, Avon!
Prop Joe and them niggers,
man, they took a vote.
They gonna cut us out.
We ain't gonna have that dope,
so even if we win, we lose
'cause we ain't gonna have no product
to put on those fucking corners, B.
Avon, look at you.
Fuckin' shooting dope without
a fucking needle right now, man
getting high on a power trip,
playin' fucking soldier.
Yo, you gotta sit back, man,
think about our business.
What the fuck you want?
That motherfucker, he good.
What happened?
You know, Avon, you gotta think about
why we got in this game for, man.
Was it the rep?
Was it so our names could ring out
on some fucking ghetto
street corners, man?
Naw, man, there's games
beyond the fucking game.
Avon, look, you and me,
we brothers, B.
We ain't think we make it
this fucking far, but fuck
if we ain't standing here
right now, with the
whole world at our feet.
The whole world, man,
not these fucking corners.
The whole world, B.
You know what Slim just told me?
Devonne come up dead.
She was shot one in the
mouth, one in each tit.
You still want to
talk truce, String?
You right when you say I need
to learn more discipline.
But this...
you could do this better...
You're the perfect bait, Lamar.
They'll see you as conflicted.
Your homophobia is so visceral.
You see that?
I ain't even stepped
inside the joint yet
and you callin' me
a cocksucker already.
You in the right place?
I'm lookin' for someone name Omar.
No last name.
Scar across his face an' shit.
Scarface named Omar.
Sounds different,
but I can't help you.
You drinking?
Maybe you wait four years.
No, it has to be now.
It's gotta be a three-way
and Tony's gonna go this time.
I'm just...
Tony's my oldest
friend on the council.
Well, couldn't you
go talk to him first?
Put it on the table?
You know, may
the best man win...
Truth is...
he can't win alone
against Royce, either.
He's got the bumper stickers,
but not much else.
Wants to run on education.
I mean...
where do you go with that?
If I level with Tony and he
gets out, then I can't win.
I need him in the race.
I feel like shit.
I really do.
Don't look like much.
This some weak ass
shit right here.
Hells yeah.
Man, we got lockers,
you got gear.
It's all peelin' and shit.
Go long.
Pass it here.
You gettin' me all dirty and shit.
What's wrong with you?
Fuck you, bitch.
We clocked the meet with Tweety Bird,
stayed on him overnight,
tracked him to a possible stash house
and then home to nest in Woodlawn.
Got photos, his tags...
What happened?
They ditched their phones.
The D.N.R.S and the wire all
died around three o'clock.
We were on line just shy 30 hours.
I thought we had them on their
burners for a couple of weeks.
Not anymore, it's a week at best.
We just spent $9,000 and
change for 18 intercepts.
Five of them non-pertinent.
That's close to $700 per drug call.
Until we see which way this goes
shouldn't we get back
on Bernard and his girl?
I mean, get a line on
the new phones at least.
But that'll only give us
what we just had: 30 hours.
Anyway to get ourselves
ahead of the curve?
If there were some way
to pre-wiretap the burners...
What then?
Stick 'em on the rack
at Baba whatever's
and wait for Bernard
to show up that day?
The problem is the wireless people.
They claim it takes
a minimum of four days
to process a court order
and that's only after
I had my office threatened
to go public on them.
Four days to hit
a couple of keystrokes.
Bullshit.
What if...
no way.
I know what you're thinking.
I just thought the
same fucking thing.
Alright, look, man.
You wanna take your
left foot out, man.
Hey, unc's playin'
wit my man's feet.
Yeah, he smellin' up my ass, too.
Stop with the damn clownin', man.
How you gonna learn somethin'
actin' like a damn fool?
Ain't no big mystery why
your face got tattooed.
Shit, that man can't
talk to you like that.
I seen his ragged ass up
the spot, copin' vials.
Yeah, probably pimps his ass, too.
Listen, motherfucker.
Yeah, bitch, touch me.
Touch a juvenile, see what happen.
Let's bounce.
Bitch ass.
Faggot.
Chump ass.
Lester.
First time I seen him smoking.
Tough habit.
And pacing like a motherfuck, too.
Heavy is the head
that wears the crown.
Bay Wireless Connect 411.
What city and state?
Baltimore, Maryland.
How may I help you?
Baltimore police.
Any particular department?
Western District police.
Is this mergency?
Non-emergency.
Man, they just did you
with the bum rush.
That's what they do.
They past expert at pluckin' nerves.
You just gotta remember,
they barely house broke.
I'm tellin' you, man,
you wouldn't believe it.
They was all wild and shit.
Wouldn't listen.
Andre, I want you to crowd him.
Yes, sir, crowd him.
Alright.
Time!
You gotta set your
mind to stick with it.
When those two stumbled in here,
they was wilder than wild.
Now they comin' everyday.
Yes, sir, no, sir.
Still pretty rough
but you know with the right
breaks, they gonna make it.
How?
Try as they might,
I don't let 'em fail.
You do that, it messes
with their mind.
Pretty soon, they run out
of their little bag of tricks.
What you think of that?
Pretty weak.
Ain't weak.
That's the startin' point...
Naw, naw, I can't
put a name on him
but I seen him 'round.
He's off a west side.
He ain't no drug dealer,
less he doin' it on the Q.T.
You can't go at him, game him?
I don't know, Kima,
I mean, it be pressin'.
What about her?
Squeak.
Offa Lanvale.
Yeah, she used to boost
for Turtle Wells', old mob.
She lost a little bit of weight too.
I mean, lookin' a lot
better than I remember
and I remember a lot
about that girl.
Damn, Bubs, is there anybody
westside you don't know?
Jus' citizens an' shit.
My C.I. knows the girl.
He can work her?
If it's smooth, yeah.
Check this.
That's Western District?
Stringer's calling the Western?
Maybe he's surrendering.
After all the work we've done,
I'd never forgive the sonofabitch.
Go down. Go down and out.
Sweet!
I got hands.
What's up?
My knuckleheads didn't post?
They did, but they left.
Over here.
You lookin' for
a discount, old man?
Naw, but I'm lookin' for you.
Why somethin' come up missin'?
Came past to apologize.
I'm new at this coachin' thin'.
An' I got us off on the wrong foot.
I ain't gonna leave it between us,
you thinkin' I gave up on y'all.
Motherfucker's memory weak as shit.
We the ones bailed out on him.
Anyway, I'm here now.
Let me understand:
You want to sell drug traffickers
a series of cell phones
that are pre-approved
for telephonic intercepts.
And you want me
to sign off on court-ordered taps
on a bunch of phones that
at the time I am signing the order
have not been used for any
illegal activity whatsoever.
If you're looking for
precedents, your honor?
There aren't any.
It's circumstantial P.C. at best.
What the hell, let's do it.
Let the court of appeals sort it
out, if it even gets that far.
Quite the legal mind.
Buy you a drink?
Why the fuck
you comin' up behind me?
Sorry.
Bushy Top.
You called, I didn't know if
I'd find you here so late.
Just getting ready
for COMSTAT tomorrow.
So what's up, Major?
Your unit is still working...
a drug war, right?
Working it hard.
Does the name Avon Barksdale
do anythin' for you?
He's a player?
He's the main guy.
We thought he was down,
but he popped up in september.
You add him to the equation,
it goes a long way
to explaining the violence.
So it wouldn't be
a stretch if he got shot?
You heard he got shot?
You know when or where?
I could run it out quick.
Naw, ain't gonna make no difference
he didn't post up at an
emergency room from what I hear.
Major, I'm gonna be straight with you.
We're runnin' wires into his people
but we're barely
above the street.
So far, we haven't even
put an eyeball on him.
Suppose to be layin' his head there.
I need you to check that out,
get back to me as soon as you can.
You got a C.I., huh?
You wanna see if your
man's creds are bonafide.
Don't try to play me, Bushy Top.
I didn't say male,
I didn't say female.
Alright.
I'll get a surveillance
goin' right away.
According to my source,
Barksdale's name is on the paperwork.
No shit.
You get the confirmation on
that, call me back on my cell.
Good luck tomorrow.
Yeah, right.
Sham.
Shamrock.
Run these over to Levy for me.
Tell him I want a read on it.
A read?
Fresh eyes.
Tell him I'll call him tomorrow.
A- ight.
Come on, Mr. Bodyguard.
And so, we're gonna
come at her like that.
So you gonna give me
these phones to sell?
The money comes back, Bubs.
All of it?
- Is that Beadie Russell?
- Looks like.
Whoa, yo, you can't
turn from this lane.
Sweet Beatrice Russ...
I was just gonna say, "hey. "
North and Pulaski.
The photo was taken at four P.M.,
prime time for street-level dealing.
That is Riggs and Calhoun.
Mount and Fayette.
Edmondson and Brice.
It's your old foot post, Deputy.
I know where it is, Major...
what I don't know and
very much want to know is
where is the west
Baltimore drug trade?
I hope, major, these are not staged
photographs you're showing us.
No, sir, they are not.
No, Deputy, I found another approach.
I'm all ears, Bunny.
I moved them off the corners.
Goddamnit, don't be coy
with me, Major. I can see that.
What I want to know is how the
fuck you managed to move them
and where the fuck they are now.
Deputy
I don't know quite
how to put this, but we...
I mean, I...
I began by identifying those
areas of my district where
drug trafficking was least harmful
I proceeded to push all street-level
dealing towards those areas.
Now at first
dealing with the juveniles
on them corners, had little success.
But ultimately
by rounding up all the mid-level
dealers in my district
and making an offer
they couldn't refuse
- I was able to...
- You made them an offer?
Yes, sir.
Either they move their people
to one of three designated areas
where drug enforcement was
not a district priority...
or they face the wrath of every
able-bodied soul in my district.
Major, I don't understand.
The only time we can
hold a drug corner
is when we assign
officers to stand there.
Your slides don't suggest any
concerted deployment on any corners.
How were you able to...
Jesus christ, you nit,
don't you see what he's done.
He's legalized drugs!
Actually, I elected to ignore them.
You lost your fucking mind.
He's lost his fucking mind.
You. In my office. Now!
That's it, gentleman.
She's a go.
Showtime, Bubs.
Oh, shit.
Sister Squeak.
Bottom-end Bubbles.
How you stand, girl?
Been a long time.
T- shirts?
What the hell kinda
money is in t-shirts?
Girl, you just don't know.
But how's your game?
I heard you was locked up.
Shit, I been on paper for a year.
- I got some things going.
- I can see that.
You look good.
How's he doing?
He'd talk a cat off a fish cart.
A-ight, Bubs, I gotta get.
Alright, I see you later on.
Yo, Squeak, Squeak.
I 'bout forgot.
I can sell you one
of these, real cheap.
If you got use for the shits...
I'm fuckin' dead.
You mean, we're fuckin' dead.
We're all dead behind this shit.
Jesus christ.
What I did, I did knowingly
and on my own.
My men had nothin' to do with this.
They thought it was part
of some elaborate trap.
So if you need me to fall on
that sword, I'm good with that.
You're good with it?
Hey, you know I got my vacation time,
my last 30 in a couple months.
So, if you need me
to fall, I'm ready.
But don't let me hear
that you're taking
any punitive action
against my people.
Because I can get on the soapbox
and I can lie as good as
the next man, if I have to.
Are you threatening me?
I believe I am, sir.
My apologies.
Bunny, you cocksucker, I got
give it to you, a brilliant idea.
Insane and illegal, but stone
fuckin' brilliant nonetheless.
After all my puttin' my foot up
people's asses to decrease
the numbers, he comes in
and in one stroke, gets
a fuckin' 14% decrease.
Fuckin' shame it's gonna
end our careers, but still.
You're all probably tired
of hearin' from me, but...
I brought these.
Letters...
from community associations,
ministers, business people, citizens.
And they're all positive.
They're all happy that the
dealers are off the corners.
You think that's
gonna save our asses?
Do you?
No, I guess not, but...
that and my badge is all I got.
I might have your badge,
Major, but not today.
I don't want to draw any attention
to this shit before we're...
ready to speak to it.
So if you have any vacation
time, you're taking it now.
Do not report for
a shift until notified.
Oh...
one more thing, sir.
A "Sun" reporter is
aware of my deployment.
I told him an investigation
was pending
he promised to delay the article.
How long?
About a week, tops.
I was with Superstroke on the
pool circuit in the early days.
But mostly pickpocketin'
and short cons.
I did the long distance access card
heist before cell phones got popular.
You crept numbers?
Yeah, I favored the airports, yeah.
Can you still read numbers?
What's up with this?
Your man thinkin' I brought
him bad merchandise?
'Cause if that what he think,
we can beat feet right now.
Damn, Bernard, why you
actin' all C.I.A. and shit?
We tryin' to make money here.
If you had to answer
to the people I do
your ass would be damn
more sight cautious, too.
That's all I'm sayin'.
I appreciate caution.
'Cause I'm hangin' out here too.
Give it a go.
Use a cell phone.
Marlene, you send
that copy off to Paris?
Thank you, darling.
That will work, I'm at the airport.
The shuttle, yes...
three, one, oh, double four, eight,
sixteen, ninety-one, double seven
eight, three, one, two.
Now that last number might be a seven.
I'm not too sure with
these small keypads and all.
We can do business.
That's it.
One two, one two, one two.
One two, that's it.
One two, there you go.
Alright, there it is.
Now you gettin' it.
Keep that left hand up.
Hey.
Alright.
Watch your balance now.
Don't lean forward.
Don't lean too much, don't
lean too forward, alright?
Alright, let's go. Don't lean
too forward, that's right.
One two, pivot...
You're kidding.
Tell me he's kidding.
You're kidding, right?
He did it without our knowledge.
Without your knowledge.
Well, that's worse.
You're the Commissioner...
Was the Commissioner.
You think the buck's gonna stop
in this office, you're wrong.
If I might, these are letters
from people in his district.
Ministers, business
people, voters...
all glowing reports.
And there's the 14% reduction
in crime, in the Western.
That's not an anomaly.
It's hard data.
Now, we can clean it up,
make it go away.
The press might already
have wind of it
but we can explain that as
some sort of a new initiative.
Trap high-end drug dealers...
14%?
If we handle this right, we
might all get out from underneath.
No mud on anybody.
No, no.
I trusted you, Erv, I really did.
You let me down.
Now, this thing goes wrong,
no tellin' the damage.
On this, you walk point.
That's the way things work, Erv.
You know it as well as I do.
Thank you, Ervin.
I'll be over shortly
to see the detailed plan
on how this shit gets
cleaned up immediately.
If you could call this shit
something other than what it is...
Don't even think it.
Way it works is this:
If you don't re-up the minutes
on your cell phone before 60 days
the wireless company
recycles the phone number.
And that's where I get them.
I put the word out on the street
that I'm buying tossed-off burners.
Payin' two dollars a pop.
Street people bring me hundreds.
I bring 'em in here to my niece
she jiggles the computer
juices them up another 200
minutes on a bogus account.
And that automatically extends the
life of the phone for another 60 days.
She charges me 20
on each phone on her end.
I double it or more
on the street to make mine.
So what you sayin'?
Baby, a standard
Trac phone, with two
maybe 400 minutes on it
gonna run you 150, 200, easy.
I charge you an even 100,
you clear 50 on each phone.
That's if'in you can back
them up with receipts.
I gotta show receipts lookin'
like they from different places
or I can't play.
Can we accommodate the good man?
Damn, Calvin, you know
I got the bingo tonight.
Look, friend, I ain't sure
you want to be around here.
And I'm damn sure we're
gettin' tired of havin' you.
That plain enough?
You should know by now
I don't wanna be 'round no
bunch of cocksucking faggots.
But I ain't gonna stop coming
round till I run up on Omar.
You might want to get the word out.
For the last time,
I don't know him.
Then I'm back tomorrow.
Maybe I can help you?
I don't doubt it for a minute.
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
Transcript par Raceman
Synchronisation: El Uploador
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net