You been nipping
at me all night, son.
Thing I got to figure is,
is you ready to bite the whole ass.
Ain't me with
a mountain by my elbow.
Oh, so you doing all right.
You like the town car?
You young'uns,
you all into them Lexus
and hum-fucking V.S.U.
fucking u-ray or some shit,
I don't know.
See, but me?
I like me a town car.
Man look quiet
and correct in one of them.
So, I tell you what,
you win this,
you be sure pick one
up for yourself, son.
Bye-bye.
Showtime.
Shit, nigga, turn.
Man got clubs.
One day soon,
I'm walking out with a rolls, hear?
Way you been going to school
up in this here room, son,
I suspect you're gonna walk out of here
with Morgan fucking Freeman
to drive it for you, too.
See y'all next time.
I'm up the grocery on Monroe.
A'ight.
Water, one dollar.
The fuck?
You think I dream of coming to work
Up in this shit on a Sunday morning?
Tell all my friends
what a good job I got?
I'm working to support
a family, man.
Pretend I ain't talking to you.
Pretend like
I ain't even on this earth.
I know what you are.
And I ain't stepping to,
but I am a man.
And you just clip that shit and act like
you don't even know I'm there.
I don't.
I'm here.
Look, I told you
I wasn't stepping to you.
I ain't disrespecting you, son.
You want it to be one way.
What?
- You want it to be one way.
- I don't know what you're--
- Man, stop.
Stop saying that.
But it's the other way.
Episode 4x04 - Refugees
I'm saying, man.
The way she was all aah on Chiquan?
Like, like, like, like,
"laugh now, stanky bitch!
"Laugh now!
"How you like this?
How you like I cut your titties off?"
Man, get the fuck away from me.
How you like I carve
your pussy to your chin?
Yo, come on, come on.
He said leave him be.
So, leave him be.
- I'm just saying.
- You're just saying.
That's all you ever do,
just say.
Dude, shit was fucked up.
So, it was fucked up.
Her father...
killed, like, 3 police.
- What?
- Nah, it's true.
Her father kill like 3 police,
and her mama boil cats.
Nigga, please, man.
It's what I heard. She boil cats
and like serve 'em and shit.
Serve 'em to who?
Boiled-cat-eating motherfuckers?
Who want him some boiled cats?
Heard that's how she live.
Maybe you been boiled.
Laetitia live up one of them
group homes off Edmondson.
In them places,
you don't need to eat cats
to make you crazy.
Hey, coach.
Yo, if the boy not coming,
you might as well let me
and Michael go in the ring.
Ain't none of y'all
seen Spider today?
I ain't seen him.
Now how in the hell he gonna fight
next week if he don't show up to train?
I tell you what.
Until the boy shows up for his lesson,
you can lace 'em up
and step on the mat one time.
No, no, no, no.
Not him.
Me.
I'm gonna show you
as gently as I can
how much you don't know,
a'ight?
- A'ight.
- Yeah, nigga, that's yo ass.
You about to get yo ass whipped.
- His ass?
- Hell, yeah.
I don't know who to be taking.
You about to get yo--
Your Sabbath's best?
You hang around, you can see
me preach on some young'uns.
Solemn left
and sanctified right.
Why you down here
on a Sunday, Deacon?
You need to see Ms. Donnelly
at Tilghman Middle.
She's got some custodial work,
you might call it.
Union wage.
Custodial.
See Ms. Donnelly tomorrow.
She can explain it
better than I can.
Tell me something.
How is it you got so much wisdom
About who should be where?
A good church man is always up
in everybody's shit.
That's how we do.
Yo, coach, you ready?
Who's winning?
No one wins.
One side just loses more slowly.
Why don't we
get out of the house?
Take a walk.
It's a nice day.
I got this talk
I got to give to my first period...
about what happened.
An hour.
I got...
I gotta say something
to those kids.
I mean--
OK.
See?
Somebody's winning.
Didn't expect you till tomorrow.
I heard my new squad
had the weekend shift.
And besides,
I figured if I got my shit
out of major crimes on a Sunday,
I wouldn't have to run into
that cocksucker Marimow.
Marimow does not
cast off talent lightly.
He heaves it away with great force.
Freamon got here Friday.
Yeah,
Lester's quick like that.
There's the Colonel's office.
This is my humble abode.
The board.
And over here,
this is your desk.
It's clean.
You'll fix that.
A clean desk is the sign
of a sick mind.
Homicide.
Damn.
I don't know
where your chair went.
Make that your first case.
And put that down, will you?
You live here now.
Look!
Actual po-lice work.
Any of these?
He the one-- right there.
Just put it to Fruit's head,
and the next thing Fruit
on the ground flopping,
and his girl all screaming...
and this pink shit
coming out the side of his head.
The Bunk.
Working weekends.
The man's dedicated.
I'm gonna partner you
with Crutchfield to get started.
You won't catch anything as a primary
for the first few months.
Give you time
to learn the basics.
Our h-files by year,
witness dump,
our coat and necktie mausoleum.
The coffee...
and, the mailboxes,
arranged by shift and squad.
Lester.
I believe you two refugees
know each other well.
Still getting your head around it?
A bit, yeah.
You'll do fine. Just fine.
As tender as this
moment may be, Detective,
you've got mail.
You got Lyon
on your ass already?
Another switch-up
on the methane probes.
I'd call that number.
Get on top of that shit
before you catch a case.
Chair or no chair.
What the hell is
a methane probe?
Hello, Lathleen O'Shea.
Yes, hello?
I need to speak with Mr. Lyon
About the protocols.
I beg your pardon?
Mr. Lyon, please.
You sound a little old for this, hon.
Excuse me?
Who is this?
This is Detective
Greggs with the--
this is the Baltimore city zoo.
Fine, and this
is Detective Greggs.
And you're calling
for a Mr. Lyon.
I'm sorry.
I misdialed.
Methane probe.
Scarred-up faggot.
I need to hunt him down
'cause there ain't no
protection against that shit.
Can't plan against that nigger.
It's like, like,
you know what he's like.
What he like?
He like one of them
terrorist motherfuckers.
Just blowing up shit just to.
Don't care who get hurt,
what kind of sense it makes.
He got a point.
And the government, right?
If they have one of them
terrorist attacks,
they cut delta
or whoever some slack?
The insurance companies,
the banks,
the whole Nasdaq and shit
get some time to pay back
what they owe
'cause the government know
ain't nothing they could do.
Yeah, I know you see it.
You see the big picture.
Problem with niggers today,
they always see the narrow view.
That's nice.
What?
Oh, you like that?
I had it for a long time now.
It's got some
sentimental values.
- Just a thing.
- What's the real value?
Real value?
I ain't much for sentiment.
Oh, you know.
It's been a while
since I checked.
I mean, the fluctuation
in the global economy and all.
I'll find out for you.
- You don't have to.
- I'll find out for you.
- Finger's swelled over the years.
- Need some help?
Yeah, man, you need help?
Nah, I got it, I got it.
Maybe use some spit.
- I don't want the man's spit.
- No, I got it now.
Omar ain't no terrorist.
He just another nigger
with a gun.
And you ain't no
Delta Airlines neither.
You just a nigger
got your shit took.
So, bring me what you owe
and talk that global economy
mess somewhere else.
Feel me?
Yeah.
I got another game.
How much you down already?
Learning their ways
requires some patience.
Some money, too.
How much you need this time out?
Hundred and a half
ought to do.
A hundred and a half?
I take that chicken-nose
fool one day soon.
Take super stick, too.
Take 'em all.
Else, maybe I get bored,
send you to take 'em.
And my point, Colonel Foerster,
is that your man Norris.
He's fucking the dog on this,
way I hear it.
Sir, this is a top priority case,
and Norris knows there's a possibility
- of a murdered state's witness.
- We don't even know yet
if that was the motive for the murder.
This is my point.
Norris is a pro, sir.
His clearance rate this
year says otherwise, Colonel.
Sir, Norris is good police.
Look, ray, we need someone
who can work it hard,
work it around the clock,
work it till it falls.
And I understand we just pumped
some fresh blood into homicide.
Female.
Took one in the line a few years back.
She's never worked homicide.
Fresh eyes, then.
But with all due respect, sir,
if I could guarantee
that no further information
on this case would be
leaked to the press,
certainly not before election day,
would it be possible to keep
veteran investigators working it, sir?
I resent the implication.
My apologies, sir.
You killing my time,
coming up here.
And you ain't notice,
it's costing us money.
How am I gonna trust you
if you keep telling lies,
Saying one thing
and doing another?
I just missed Friday, that's all.
Look, think on it like this.
School is work.
They the same thing right now.
So, you skipping out on school
is like not showing up for work.
And I done heard, made up,
and tested every excuse invented.
So, unless you dead or dying,
there ain't none you can use.
I told you I'm gonna go.
Yeah, OK, I know.
For school
or out the business,
you are gonna go.
Come on.
Falling behind now isn't the way
to start out a school year,
particularly after a 3-year hiatus.
We haven't seen you
since you enrolled.
Is there a reason
you haven't joined us?
Look, I know you
reaching out for Sherrod.
I want to apologize for the boy
'cause he's been working hard
at helping me get a business going.
But he need to be here though.
Ain't no bout a-doubt it.
It's up to him, isn't it?
That's what I been trying to say.
That's it right there.
What about it, young man?
I'm good.
OK.
One thing, though,
been bothering me, ma'am.
If Sherrod already missed
the last 3 years,
should he maybe be back in
the fifth or sixth grade,
instead of up with his age?
I mean, so he can follow the work.
Social promotion.
Excuse me?
We don't have the resources
to repeat grade levels,
and we feel to place the older
children in the younger classes
is unfair to teachers
who are responsible
for maintaining order.
Your nephew has been
socially promoted.
He's an eighth-grader,
headed to high school.
Sorry, but Ms. Johnson's
here about Qadriyyah.
Excuse me for a moment.
...send her daddy up
here to deal with all y'all.
Bill, this is nuts.
I told him that.
You know if this gets out,
who do you think it's gonna land on?
I got two years to make 40
and a pension bump.
Look, I don't agree
with the call either,
but it's his call.
Not yours, not mine.
He's the one over city hall
every day getting his ass chewed.
I don't care about
nothing you say, man,
'cause if you start shit,
you can't complain how
somebody finish that shit.
Man, she was on her
from the beginning
with the mirror
and everything, man.
I wouldn't have waited.
Mr. Pryzbylewski,
this is Sherrod.
He's all yours.
OK.
Take a seat, Sherrod.
OK, listen up.
I'd like to-- everybody?
Everybody, I'd like to talk...
listen up!
Now, we all know something...
unpleasant
happened here Friday,
and, look, I know some
of you are still trying
to get your heads around--
ain't my head
got a big old gash.
And...
I'd like to discuss--
Yo, is it true that you police?
What?
Ms. Carmandy up in the office say
Mr. Prezbo, he police.
Yo, you police, man?
You ever shoot somebody?
- I think we should talk about--
- He ain't shot no one. Look at him.
Yo, you ever bust a man
name Asante Graham?
Sometimes when
something bad happens--
- That your dad?
- Nah, my brother.
Why can't you tell us
if you shot somebody or not?
- What kind of gun you carry?
- You narco?
I used to be police.
Now I'm a teacher.
But being a police isn't
just about carrying a gun.
Yeah, right.
It's about working with the community.
The community.
Y'all ain't been up in
my community
in a long time except
to wail on people.
Yo, Mr. P.,
you ever been shot?
I mean, like, bah.
Namond, that's enough.
Get up.
Get back in your seats.
Thank you,
very entertaining.
Sit down.
Get in your seats.
Sit down, sit down.
Kwaneese, sit down.
Sit down, now.
Yo, Mr. P, you ever
choke somebody dead like...
Yo, you ever get videoed?
Mr. P,
Asante Graham.
You gots to know him.
He was a player, for real.
He work Sunday to Thursday,
7:00 early to 5:00 late.
So, it ain't no
moonlighting thing, then.
Nah, he ain't no real police.
He full-time on this
Mickey Mouse shit here.
What he do again?
Talked back.
Go over Hilltop now?
Yeah, we got that, too.
Looks like we got that.
See ya.
Decision time, son.
Yo, what's your play?
I told Little Kevin right there
to shoot y'all both in the head twice.
But seeing as he
done walked away.
Oh, you funny.
Yeah,
I guess I'm on your package.
Where the boy at-- Michael?
He ain't no regular.
He's just working off a debt.
Why? Why you care?
Never mind you why.
"Why" ain't in your repertoire
no more, nigger.
60-40 split on that.
Do not be messing
with Marlo's money.
Randy Wagstaff.
You aren't a sixth grader,
are you?
Hey, Ms. Reese.
If you were a sixth-grader,
it would mean you and the rest
of the knuckleheads
would still be in my
first period English class.
And that would mean
it was two years ago.
And that would mean time stands
still at Tilghman Middle,
and that would be a catastrophe.
I just forgot
and wore my old shirt today.
Well, if this isn't your lunch,
then where is your hall pass?
Why not just write it in crayon?
Come on.
Deacon says you're a good man.
- Good enough to swing a mop, I guess.
- A mop?
- More like a vacuum cleaner.
- What?
I got a few fellas like you
to help me out every September.
You go out on the street,
you find these kids,
you drag them in.
A truant officer.
The system hasn't been funded
for truant officers in 20 years.
Where the hell you think you are,
Montgomery county?
Nah, I keep a couple custodial positions
unfilled every year just for this.
Those kids?
You haul 'em in,
you cross 'em off the list.
Each kid, one time,
clear the list.
Come October?
You start on the list again.
Job's yours if you want it.
Pays 12 an hour.
Excuse me, hon.
Sit.
Tilghman Middle School,
can I help you?
Will do.
You're welcome.
Why'd you leave class?
I got hungry.
Couldn't concentrate.
Maybe, Randy,
you had another reason
for running the halls, huh?
Tagging walls, maybe?
- You know I don't.
- I don't know anything.
I know it's the second week,
and I got walls covered with tags.
Does that make you feel good,
walking past that?
- I don't know.
- Maybe you don't know
'cause you're the one
doing the marking.
- I'm not.
- Then who is?
- Ms. Thompson?
- Yes, ma'am.
Could you get me the number
for Randy Wagstaff's foster mom?
What you want to call Ms. Anna for?
Because you're skipping class,
running the halls, maybe worse.
She's got a right to know.
- Is this her work number?
- Yes, ma'am.
Hold on.
Wait.
The new girl, Greggs.
Sir, if I may respectfully--
Look, Norris has a full plate, OK?
The Braddock case goes to Greggs.
His plate is fine.
No, it's not.
His plate's a pile of shit, OK?
Listen to me.
Burrell wants this case
stalled until everybody votes.
And Rawls?
What the fuck I know what Rawls wants?
He never said shit,
and let me tell you something,
even he knows this is fucked up.
I have this correct?
Were pulling a veteran off
a pending case and giving it to a rook
so as not to make timely
progress on said case?
The Braddock case to Greggs.
A pilot program.
For one of your
middle schools, yes.
A $200,000 grant is attached.
Free money.
I'm just trying
to help here, Mrs. Conway.
Help how?
You say that your target group
is repeat violent offenders.
Are you in any way suggesting that
the system's lost control of the school?
No, no,
that's not what I'm suggesting at all.
The system's fine.
The system's great.
I mean, this isn't about the system.
We're just gonna try to find a way
to get to some of the troubled kids
who won't be in
the system too much longer.
Well,
look, just make sure there's no fuss.
I mean, nothing that gets
anyone upset, you know?
There's an election going on,
and we don't want to put our schools
in the middle of that mess.
No, indeed.
Humping a radio car
like a young sprite.
I'm a little bit proud
to know you, officer Mcnulty.
Just a little bit?
It ain't like there aren't
better things you could be doing.
- Like what?
- See, I told you, Lester.
The worm has turned for my boy.
So, I heard they
torpedoed your wiretap.
Yeah, they sent us
a new Lieutenant.
Marimow from E-and-T.
The unit killer.
Lester and Kima already
bailed to homicide,
and now Sydnor's looking to jump
at the first good opening.
So, major crimes is dead?
Yeah, Lester killed it good.
I went looking for the money.
Guys like you,
you never learn.
Guys like me?
Yeah, 13 years--
- 4 months.
You guys call
for backup or what?
Yeah.
We got arrest papers on a murder
for one Curtis Anderson,
a.k.a. Lex.
He's been on the wing
for a couple weeks,
so I don't expect him at his mama's,
but you never know.
- What's the address?
- 643 Harlem.
How about you taking the door
with me for old time's sake, Jim?
I'll take the back, gents.
The back?
Damn, junior,
the worm has turned for you.
You know what they say about the man
who volunteers to take the back?
He buys.
B&O Tavern.
Tonight at 9:00, son.
I throw myself out after one.
- Shit.
- You don't believe me, ask Bunk.
True.
The bedroom's clear.
Yeah, basement, too.
Clear.
Yeah.
9:00 tonight, Mcnulty.
B&O Tavern.
He's not here.
I told you.
Is he coming home again?
Ma'am, is your son alive?
Because if he's not,
we can end this right now.
Otherwise, we've got a witness
that gives us a murder warrant,
and that warrant says
that we can come through your door
as many times as necessary.
I don't know where my son is.
It's like them birds of yours.
They go out,
and they fly around the city,
they free to do as they do.
End of the day,
they come back here,
get water, get fed,
'cause they know you got this place
set up regular as the rain.
No surprises,
'cause at the end of the day,
a man don't want no surprises.
You know, birds neither.
Same as what I'm offering.
You part of a co-op,
a whole lot of surprises
you never worry about again.
You just do as you do,
knowing the product
will always be there
and be the finest quality.
Knowing that if one
of yours takes a pinch,
he got a lawyer
and a bondsman
waiting for him before
he even step out the wagon.
I know how to hire lawyers.
It ain't just about the lawyers.
It's having a connection
so that you know
before the bust even go down.
What I got to give up
to get that good dope?
Muscle.
You got muscle.
You stand with us,
we run these New York boys
right out of East Baltimore.
Fuck I care about East Baltimore?
The point of the co-op
is we stand together.
We share information,
And no one fucks
with any of us.
No one fucks with me now.
Well, that don't mean there couldn't be
some unforeseen cir--
No one fucks with me now.
African colors.
Subtle.
Tony Gray is pulling 24% now.
You need new colors
and a new message, Clarence.
You need to rally the base.
You want me to start
wearing dashikis?
Go all Marion Barry and shit?
I'll tell you what I would like.
Another 75 in cash
for walk-around money.
75?
Call another game.
It's a waste of time,
and right now,
time is everything.
They're gonna spit
in your eye and endorse Royce.
They only waited this long out
of respect to Tony Gray.
Otherwise, they gave
it to Royce months ago.
That's not the point.
You go there uninvited,
and you're only gonna piss them off.
Am I?
Or do I piss them off even more
by pretending that they don't exist,
that I don't need them?
I've door-to-doored every
neighborhood in this city
saying I'm ready to be
mayor to all of it.
Not just my base,
but all of it.
What does it say
I don't go see these guys?
He's right.
They endorse Royce, fine.
The hell else they gonna do?
But what they say and don't say
from the pulpit the Sunday
before the primary?
We still got a dog
in that fight.
I do this right,
they'll respect it.
And if they don't,
at least they get to see
a begging-ass white man
on his knees.
Always a feel-good moment
for the folks.
And as to my attendance
at council meetings,
those who know the job
understand there is more
to being a councilperson
than just the meetings.
Yes, Charles.
Yeah, they putting a halfway
house at the end of my block.
Addicts and such.
Not if I have anything
to say about it.
Where you living at, sir?
800 block north Carrollton.
Oh, I'm gonna take
a look into that.
Is there anyone with a question
for any of the other candidates?
Anyone with an issue,
a concern?
Well, I would say
that with regard to
the gentleman's concern
about the halfway house
That while I share your concern,
it's also true that the city has
thousands of drug addicts in recovery,
and those halfway houses and shelters
have to go someplace.
Though not in white neighborhoods.
Ma'am, could I see that?
That Royce flier.
Well, that is
a fair point as well.
But these are people--
our brothers and sisters,
our children, our friends,
and they are trying
to change their lives,
and so it's up to us to
be responsible for them.
Feel good to miss a hand, huh?
What's the point?
Eventually, we all got to ante up.
Yeah, we do.
But I can't believe he
had the balls enough
to call two games in one month.
I mean, please.
He's loading up
on walk-around money.
He wants cash on the street
come election day.
Carcetti got to him.
Call it a war chest, right?
Maybe we got us a war this time.
I wouldn't mind if he wasn't
so fucking ugly with it.
That two pair he bet on--
Right into Roger's trip 9s*.
I folded on a flush.
Full boat.
4 hands ago.
It's immoral, what it is.
So, what's the game, gents?
Clarence's deal.
Texas hold 'em.
I begin to understand
the popularity of this game.
No limit.
Oh, peachy.
I was beginning to think
you'd lost it, son.
That living room shrine of hers
would have shamed
Elvis and Tupac both.
Her son's deader than both of 'em.
She's just too scared to say so.
That shit wasn't there
first time I talked to her.
I'd have seen it.
You being a detective and all.
Hey, look, she got a friend.
She too young for you, boy.
Young?
They get younger, William.
Skinnier, too.
We don't.
Younger, skinnier.
Where's Jimmy?
That's just the nature of things.
Age is age, fat is fat,
and nature is nature.
Pitiful.
Pitiless.
Nature don't care.
Nature just is.
Now my boy, Marlo,
I thought he was skewing that.
Screwing what?
The boy's a young lion.
Hello, is Mr. Lyon home?
And a lion has to have his kill.
Methane probe for Mr. Lyon.
So, then where are my bodies?
Here I am over here on the one hand
without a body in 6 months,
and here you are looking for a suspect
who's most likely dead
and most likely
for dropping one of Marlo's.
And, again, if he's dead,
where's that body?
You know what
the plural of pussy is?
Puss-l.
Jimmy taught me that.
Where's he putting the bodies, Bunk?
In the sewers?
Rogue funeral home, maybe?
Yeah, they teach that fancy-ass Latin
at them catholic schools.
You remember the Eddy Crane case?
Word was they put him
in an acid vat down near Curtis bay.
They're coming up on us now.
Now, for a Westside boy
like Marlo Stanfield,
that would be the traditional
dumping grounds.
- Hey, girl.
- Right?
Hey, girl.
- What?
Jimmy.
Tying to get some of that puss-l.
What the hell you
still sitting here for?
Fucking huxtables and shit, man.
There they go right there.
They still with school.
Shit. Just so they can spring out
that shit pile every day.
Make a good run at that boy,
he'll be on a corner,
no problem, man.
Yeah, we gonna see.
You hung over?
Just saying you look like shit.
Know what you need
at a crime scene?
Rubber gloves.
Soft eyes.
Like I'm supposed
to cry and shit?
You got soft eyes,
you can see the whole thing.
You got hard eyes,
you're staring at the same tree,
missing the forest.
Oh, zen shit.
Soft eyes, grasshopper.
Lividity puts
the time of death at 7:48,
- give or take.
- Noted.
- You're gonna want to get a chem-stat.
- You think?
- Couldn't hurt.
- CDC, too?
- Splatter distance?
- Yeah, definitely.
You know, where the hell
did my q-tips go?
Don't sweat it.
I got mine right here.
Oh, good. It's cool.
You want to take a look?
Won't bite.
Hey, don't forget
the, stippling.
I'm a rookie?
- There's something in his hand.
- Oh, yeah?
Give her some tweezers.
"Tater killed me."
Is it typed? 'Cause that would
hold up a lot better in court.
Phone number in the other hand.
A standard
confidentiality agreement.
And this one?
Oh, that one indemnifies us
should you or any
of your staff be injured.
Who wants to get
some learning today?
I roll up front with you?
You got dibs
in the back, little man.
Let's go.
Come on.
Don't worry about it.
We catch him later.
Yeah, little man's so excited
about what's on that
blackboard, he gonna race us.
What's the line on us so far?
In the teacher's lounge, I mean.
They're saying you're
this year's band-aid.
Is that how you feel?
I was hoping for more than that.
This year's splint?
Hey, Ms. Sampson.
Yo, he police.
I mean, the school
system seems benign.
And I get the sense
north avenue might give us
some latitude, if not support.
You think so?
You sound doubtful.
You can tell the days
by their faces.
The best day is Wednesday.
That's the farthest they get from home,
from whatever's going on in the streets.
You see smiles then.
Monday is angry.
Tuesdays, they're caught
between Monday and Wednesday,
so it could go either way.
Thursdays...
they're feeling
that weekend coming.
Friday, it's bad again.
This is where I leave you.
Your class.
Language arts, huh?
Yes.
Anyway, you should see it without me.
They behave differently
when I'm around.
No doubt.
What do you think this 20 stands for?
No, it's not the number of days
you've been suspended.
It's not the number of years you'll
spend in prison if you don't shape up.
It's 50% below average.
It's 30% below failure even.
But, really, it stands
for the amount of interest
you're taking in your own future.
The next question is worth two points.
Who can tell me
why was Clarence Mitchell Jr.
important to the civil
rights movement?
- I know!
- And I can tell by Shalanta's smile,
she's gonna win for the blue team.
Hey, yo, did you see
that one over there?
Anybody here Deshawn Price?
Never heard of him.
And what's your name?
Herbert Brown.
This the roundup van, right?
Oh, yeah, here you go, my man.
Come on.
Oh, no! Yo, no.
Yeah, see?
Howard Brown,
that's my brother.
He over on McHenry Street
if you want him.
I was just in school on Friday,
so I'm fat until October.
Sorry.
Hold up, my man.
Naw, he's right.
School gets a certain
amount of money
for each kid that shows
up one day in September
and one day in October.
One day?
After that, they don't
lose the government money,
- so we done with it.
- Naw, naw, man.
School is school.
Yeah, well,
I'm just trying to school you, brother.
A'ight.
Which one of y'all still
need your September day?
Get it over with now,
we won't be messing with y'all later.
What up, Butch?
How do we begin?
You the one called the meet.
Why don't we begin by you
respecting my time
and getting to it.
First of all,
I heard you may be
under the impression
I was somehow involved
with the late Mr. Bell
In his play against you
with brother Mouzone.
I was no way involved.
Stringer came at me to set up
the parley with you.
He used me like he used y'all,
I feel the need to say.
It's said then.
Tip out on it.
Businessman such as myself
does not believe in bad blood
with a man such as yourself.
Disturbs the sleep.
Oh, I bet it do.
By way of amends,
a proposition.
I know of a card game
on the West side.
High rollers,
lots of cash money.
Boxcar-sized.
You trying to set me up, Joe?
You ever known me to be stupid?
I'm trying to make things
right here with you.
How much we talking about?
If there ain't at least
a few hundred k in that room,
I wish myself blind.
Serious, Joe.
I say again--
have you ever known me
to be a stupid man?
What are the strings?
No strings.
What's your cut then?
Quarter of the take.
I scope this
and it don't look right,
I'm gonna come back
on you now, Joe.
Where did everybody go?
Which one of you is Sergeant Hauk?
Sir.
And you must be Dozerman.
Yes, sir.
Welcome to major crimes.
I'm Lieutenant Marimow.
I see you just made Sergeant
after driving the mayor around
for less than 3 months.
You must be a hell of a driver.
Anyone here?
- Greggs, Freamon?
- Sydnor and Massey.
And they're on the street,
making rips.
That's what we do here now.
We get on the street
and we rip and run.
Can you get with that, Sergeant?
The Western District way, sir.
Thank you.
Thanks for seeing me.
I understand you've already
heard from mayor Royce
and from councilman Gray,
and I'd like to thank you
for being able to join in this process.
I don't expect to walk out
of this room today with an endorsement
from the interdenominational
ministerial alliance.
I don't.
But the point is
I think I can be a better mayor
for Baltimore than the present one.
I voted for Clarence Royce 8 years ago.
I voted for him 4 years after that.
I felt there was
promise in the man.
But now, I'm disappointed.
I'm disappointed
and I'm angry
at the crime and the waste
and the damage
done to so many neighborhoods.
Not just in my district,
but here on the West side.
Pimlico, Cherry Hill,
Edmondson Village.
Wherever I go, people
want the same things.
They need the same things,
but they're just not getting them.
I'm gonna change that.
I'm not gonna ask
for your vote now.
Maybe I haven't earned it yet.
But I am here to say
that when I am mayor,
my door is open to you,
regardless of who you endorse.
And I want you to remember that I came
here today to say these things.
Thank you.
Councilman.
Thank you for coming.
OK, I'm gonna need a A.P.B.
on a motherfucker named Tater.
"Call Mr. Sweet A.S.A.P."?
Let me guess--
The gay and lesbian alliance.
She's catching on, boys.
Oh, and what do you want?
Another methane probe?
Or some other "CSI"
bullshit that don't exist?
You're the primary
on the Braddock case.
The dead witness.
Norris is back in the rotation.
What?
You caught your first murder.
Kudos.
Come on, man, hell.
Do that to whoever be snitching.
Who snitching?
Don't know,
but kids be snitching.
Rashid got suspended
for tagging walls, yo.
Y'all ain't heard?
How you know he ain't just get
caught with a paint can?
'Cause Ms. Donnelly came
and pulled him out of the classroom.
Yo, I'll see y'all later, man.
Yo, you going past the gym?
- All right, man.
- Peace, peace.
I ain't gonna tell you again.
Give me the remote.
Did y'all learn something today?
Y'all learn something today?
Yeah.
What y'all learn?
I said give me the remote.
Give it.
Math your favorite, right?
Start with it.
I like math.
Yeah, you good at it, too.
Watched this show 5 damn times.
Hey, you good?
All right, man.
So, it turns out the one girl...
200-something stitches
to close her up.
She's looking at a lot of rehab
and maybe more surgery.
The muscles in her face
don't even move right.
How's the class seem?
Like it didn't really happen.
They're still processing.
I know it doesn't seem so,
but they are.
What about Laetitia?
What happens to her?
Nothing worse
than she's already seen.
She'll probably go
to a juvenile facility,
which is only a little worse
than her group home.
She was in a group home?
She grew up in the system.
Monday-to-Friday angry.
Last year, she was suspended twice,
and then expelled.
Chiquan wasn't positive though,
if you're looking for
a silver lining and all.
Excuse me?
She didn't have HIV,
in case you were worrying.
Marcus.
Boy, what are you trying to do?
You trying to get knocked out?
Drop your head, son.
Left up! Get that left up!
Pick your hand up, damn.
Man, that boy listen to anyone?
All right, all right.
Time, time.
Not bad, y'all.
Not bad, Justin.
Marcus, you got
to concentrate, man, think.
All right?
Listen,
I got tickets to the fights tonight.
Pikesville armory.
Now, I was gonna
take Justin and Spider,
but Spider ain't
been hanging out,
and Marcus, I know you
got your mother, right?
So, Michael...
you want to see the fights?
You going?
Yeah, I'm in.
Yeah, all right.
All right.
Come on, get this headgear off.
What the fuck is that?
Souvenir.
What?
Trouble with doing it this way?
Disappearing 'em and shit?
Nobody knows.
I remember when I was a kid,
If you had a map of the world,
the playground over at Baker and
Moreland would be at the center of it.
And as I got older,
the playground just
kept on getting bigger,
went beyond the neighborhood.
Everything changes, you know?
One minute the ice cream truck
be the only thing you want to hear.
Next thing, them touts calling
out the her-on
be the only thing you can hear.
What's that?
Workbook I need to use with this.
So, you read from the small one
and answer questions in the big one?
Yeah, ain't no thing.
Yeah, I see that.
I see that.
All right, you see how
he keeping his hands up?
Look at his feet.
Look at the feet.
See how he's keeping
his feet moving?
See what I'm saying?
See? See how he stay in close?
That's how you take away his power.
Yo, dude is cut.
Yeah, man.
That's discipline.
You take care your body,
your body take care of you.
Yo, I bet his woman is fine, man.
Yeah, I bet she is, too.
Flush to the queen.
Full house.
All right, everybody,
Let me see them hands, y'all.
Hands.
Hey, yo, big man, back up.
I don't know about cards,
but, I think these 45s
beat a full house.
Hey, yo, banker,
cash me out, yo.
Boy, you want a head on
that body, you best hop to.
That's my money.
Man, money ain't got no owners,
only spenders.
I tell you something else--
I like that ring, too.
Boy, you got me confused
with a man repeats himself.
This ain't over.
Oh, that's how you
carrying it, shorty?
'Cause,
I can find your peoples
a whole lot easier
than they can find me.
Wear it in health.
No doubt.
You see what I'm talking about, Justin?
That's what I'm saying.
That's the real deal.
You keep training, I'm telling you, boy,
You can get there.
See, the last fight
was the best.
The Puerto Rican boy
had a good left.
Yeah, shit was tight.
Oh, this is it,
right here on the right.
All right.
- All right now.
- All right, I see you tomorrow, coach.
All right, now,
so you live over on--
Hey, hey, boy, what you doing?
I'm gonna take you home.
No, no, thank you.
Michael, come on now.
Serious.
Nah, no thank you.
I'm good from here.
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - www.thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net