So, Rashad had 82 apples...
and 12 friends...
all of whom are hungry.
And so he looks carefully
at his apples
and sees that 7 have worms.
Another 15 have gone rotten.
But he wants to be fair
and distribute all
the good apples equally.
Distribute?
Give out.
Well, just say that, yo?
OK.
OK, so, how many apples does
each of Rashad's friends get:
A, 4;
B, 5;
C, 6; or d, 7?
or D, 7?
Take your time, but do it fast.
So, my boy said, "oh, yeah?
Well, he's a left go to right."
He was like, pow!
Calvin, you are done already?
Yeah?
B, 5.
How did you work
that out so fast?
Easy.
"B, 5" got the dinks.
The what?
If you want,
I could show you.
Don't show him, show me.
You did just what
the early math class, right.
So, you, like,
got 82 apples...
12 niggers.
And then how many--
then you went, like,
dinking all round this one
and no other one.
So, answer is "B, 5."
Everybody get that?
"B, 5," it got all the dinks.
"B, 5," I'm am Audi 5000.
4x08 Corner Boys
The priority should
be on making sure
the age files are up to date
with all notes transcribed,
the standard office report.
On our day shift today,
you may encounter
councilman and democratic
mayoral nominee Thomas Carcetti,
Who's been fact finding
within the department.
So, if you go leaving your fax
lying around and he finds them,
that shit's on you.
Lastly...
as most of you
are already aware,
our C.I.D. Commander
Raymond Foster,
after a long bout with cancer,
passed away last night
at Johns Hopkins.
Better eulogies are coming.
So, let me just say
that the man served 39 years--
attaining the rank of colonel--
without leaving a trail
of bitterness or betrayal.
In this department, that's
not a career, it's a miracle.
There'll be a detective's
wake this evening
followed by
viewings on Wednesday
and a burial mass on Friday.
The family suggests
donations to the colonel's
favorite charities.
The addresses will be
posted in the coffee room.
All told.
And, Bunk, I just got
your overtime for the week.
Get down to my office
and pull your pants down.
Fuck that.
You've finished your pot,
you make the next one.
I don't see the right one
in here anyway.
Sergeant Hauk.
Yes, sir.
I just got off
with Beauford at I.A.D.
He tells me there's a harassment
complaint been filed.
Some Jamaican woman
says you had her stopped
and searched by Amtrak police.
Well, you've see, in my report,
we had what we thought was liable info.
That she was a drug carrier
for Marlo Stanfield.
I mean, we actually
scoped Stanfield with her.
What was the info?
The C.I.'s been reliable.
Great track record with us.
Long history.
C.I. 238.
Give me his name.
His name?
Sir.
Sir!
I've never been
comfortable with, you know,
tossing around names
of informants in squad rooms.
- I feel that it's--
- Name.
Fuzzie Dunlop, sir.
I might have to set up a meeting
with this character.
He's kind of leery of meets.
He's been reliable,
I promise you.
I mean, this one baffled
the shit out of me, too.
But he's never been off, never.
You jumped out
on bad information, Sergeant.
You brought in another agency,
and you brought
discredit to this unit--
my unit.
In good faith though, sir.
Anything comes of this,
I have your report,
and I will bury you with it.
And in case you haven't been
paying attention to
the election results,
your rabbi has
left the building.
No tantrums today?
What's the point?
They are not even gonna
suspend us, right?
Right.
What's the point?
So, we are here
like it or not.
If it makes you all feel any better,
the word around school is
you're down here because
you beat the system.
You had no interest
in being in a classroom,
and you made the classroom
impossible for everybody else,
and now you are out.
You won.
You feel like winners?
- Always.
- That's how we did.
Who's we?
Us.
No, who are you?
Players.
Kingpins?
Nah, that comes later.
Right now, we are
just corner boys.
So, how long until
you are kingpins?
I am thinking two, three years.
Two, three years.
Let me ask, and I want
everybody to write this down.
Where do you see
yourself in 10 years?
Come on, pencil and paper.
This isn't schoolwork,
this is about y'all.
The young bitch is good.
Dr. Okenna from psych department
of college park.
Thesis work is on social
alienation and analysis.
All right, show of hands,
how many wrote "NBA"?
Yeah, but only
for the Lakers though.
I want to be a pediatric neural surgeon
like that one nigger,
what's his name?
- Len Carson.
- Yeah, that dude.
He's a black surgeon at Hopkins
with a lot of profile.
You want to be a surgeon,
you need to go to medical school.
Whatever.
How many wrote down "dead"?
Shit, you saw that coming, huh?
It's a shame you all have so little time,
and you wasting it here with us.
You know where you're going.
We can't teach you anything
you don't know about. Right?
That's what we've been saying.
Naymond, put away the magazine.
I ain't reading no magazine.
Naymond.
What?
It ain't even mine.
It was laying here
when I came in.
You know, we are giving
them a fine education.
"It ain't even mine.
It was just laying here
when I came in."
You know this right here--
the whole damn school--
the way they carry themselves.
It's training for the street.
The building's the system,
we the cops.
Yeah, you are for sure.
I mean, you'll come in here everyday
and practice getting over.
Try running all
different kinds of games.
You know, it's practice
for the corner, right?
Ain't no real cops.
Ain't no real danger.
But you'll all getting
something out of this.
Bet you didn't even know that.
Still I'd rather be out there.
Can I?
Corner boys, huh?
Let me ask you'll something.
You help us hone in on this,
and maybe we do a little
better job with you in here.
What makes a good corner boy?
- Keep your eyes open.
- Keep the camera's trained--
Don't trust nobody.
If you stupid in the hood, you get killed.
That's the only way.
And I am telling you,
this name in black right here
got stink on it.
Eyeball witness, Bunk.
Vernon, at least go back
to the scene with me
and take a fresh look.
You're out of line here, Bunk.
You are.
A lot of names.
Too many.
No, we're good with it.
Listen, you back seat
driving motherfucker,
the guy picked them out.
Omar fucking Little.
Why he picked him out?
Who the fuck cares?
We got a dead female
taxpayer on our hands,
- and somebody's saying him.
- I don't buy.
And look who you talking about?
This ain't the motherfucker
that came up with
62 ways for the peanut.
His name pops up
on 5 or 6 cases I know of--
including two of yours--
and you want to put him
back on the street?
But this ain't him.
That means someone else
is walking on you all.
Let me tell you something, Bunk:
The next body you catch,
I'm going to be crawling all over it,
second-guessing your ass every step,
pulling on every last
motherfucking thread.
We going to see
how you like it.
Hey, Vernon.
- Just go back on it with me.
- What?
Shit doesn't play out
any differently...
I'll give you a back rub
that you ain't never going to forget.
You guys don't need to do anything
you would normally do
just 'cause I'm here.
I wouldn't know
what we normally do around here.
I'm new and inexperienced.
Oh, you're--
I am.
Seriously, I'm just
trying to get a feel
for the department's
response to the violence.
And not the hall monitor
or anything.
So, this is your day?
We catch a body,
it's different.
- I believe you got my camera?
- I what?
License registration.
You do me one, I'll do you.
You got a card or something?
City, huh?
Video camera gotta come back.
Yeah, well,
I see what I can find out about it.
But you know cameras.
Kind of like pictures in the storm.
You know what I'm saying?
Sometimes they come back.
Sometimes...
but I keep an ear out on it.
Pigeons, he just say pigeons?
He's fucking with you.
Look, you just got to tell Mello
that you used the camera for
the P.C. at the train station.
And then just submit
the camera got took.
I already put it down to the C.I.
I told dickhead the truth.
He takes my stripes on it.
Oh, come on.
Look, I'm just saying
you weren't suspended that long.
Is it because tiff dropped it,
or because you had to do
something for Ms. Donnelly?
Do something?
I don't know,
like promise or something.
No, I just dropped it,
so it's dropped.
ain't nothing past that.
That's good.
You know, the thing with the teachers
and cops and what not,
they always come at you like
think they got you by the ass.
But you keep your mouth shut,
ain't nothing they could do.
So, more times than not,
they go way.
Word on that.
I mean, I don't even matter.
and Ms. Anna--
she got me
on this short leash right now.
Can't go out the house
unless she know right where I'm going.
Shit, at least
you've got a leash.
Dewey!
What the fuck is that?
Club soda...
and line.
Pensive bitch.
Why not just suck a dick
and get it over with?
That will get the bad
taste out of your mouth.
I'm a free-born man of the U.S.A.
Almost new.
Don't wear no dead man's hat.
I'm just fuckin' with you.
Here, let's pray.
Here we lay a couple
of new York boys
who came too far south
for their own fuckin' good.
Fucking Yankee proud of it now,
you fuckin' bitches.
Leave the fucker to rot.
You hungry?
You want some Chinese?
No talking.
Keep your eyes on your paper.
- Yo, Mr. Pryzbo, this say cars.
- So?
All the stuff we did in
practice was about food.
It's OK.
It's just a different object.
Pay attention to the number.
Numbers are messed up, too.
We never did one-thirds.
It's the same operation.
1/4, 1/5, 1/3.
Follow the same steps.
- It's just a different denominator.
- How do you get 1/3 of a car?
It's actually 1/3 of all the cars.
Was I talking to you?!
You get close enough...
you could take a head shot.
Why?
This may be your best step.
Word.
A chest shot maybe
won't do it for you.
Then what? You.
It's his turn.
Thug, you got it.
You gotta shoot from a distance,
you can't risk a headshot.
You go for the belly,
the dick, or the ass area.
Because the vest
don't go down that far.
Bam! Take them out.
Then what?
Walk up,
finish them off.
With a?
Head shot.
Damn, y'all coming
along full effect.
I hear it--
I hear that.
All right,
now say he in a car.
Sergeant Thomas Hauk,
Baltimore city police.
Didn't I say city
would come running?
Did.
I'll checked his joker out for you.
See what's what.
One other thing,
You're are doing OK running them
New York niggers of off east side.
I know that.
But this thing you got
with disappearing the bodies...
my man saying if you just
vanishing the bodies like that,
it do kind of defeats
its own purpose.
Niggers don't know if they went back
to the Bronx or whatever.
You feel me?
Of course.
I'll tell my people.
Hey, no disrespect to your
professionalism or nothing.
We all impressed how you lose
the motherfuckers like that.
We just trying to send a message
to these New York people
in full effect...
you know what I'm saying?
I'll get back to you on this.
So, councilman,
I understand you were
a C.I.D. Yesterday.
See anything vague
with those downtown boys?
Well, they messed
up the lunch order.
I figured I needed to get closer
to the street, so that's why I am here.
Rolling with the mighty
is east of the east.
Now, remember, we had
a shooting incident last week.
So, keep those corner fucks
to one window. Don't get surrounded.
Shit, remember we had
a van full of you guys,
- we'd find the fucking chap.
- What the fuck you say?
Dressed like that, Stevie Wonder
make you as police.
Keep your radio out of sight.
Volume up on those boom box.
10 bucks say we collar up first.
20 makes it worth our while.
Mr. Mayor, you know
what's great about the Easter?
Real hungry motherfuckers--
respectfully, I mean.
So, you're saying,
you don't ever
give anybody a break?
Anybody?
'Cause if you let him
slide for a dollar,
it's a sign that you're weak.
Today's dollar is tomorrow's two.
Yeah, same with your crew.
Your boy come up short
saying spillage
or police or whatever,
you let him be,
and then he gettin' over on you.
Then you a chump.
So, you got to fuck him up.
You gotta, mess him up.
Something for real happen,
you do that.
If you do it over some bullshit,
then all you did
was lose a good worker.
Man, you gotta fuck
that nigger up, man.
Stop talking
on top of each other.
This how you communicating
out on them street?
All right, it's like this:
you boy come back to you, like,
say this happened,
that happened--
Then fuck him up.
In my mind, I'm gonna let him
make it out of his own cut, too.
If you're good worker,
He know what you need to do.
Yeah, he got a point.
He got a point.
That's a good one.
If he thinks about it,
says it ain't his fault,
Then that nigger run a game on you.
And then you fuck that nigger up.
All right, yeah.
But why?
You know it gotta happen, man.
You know what I'm saying!
Wait, wait!
One voice. Y'all, one voice.
Yo, yo, D., you tell him.
There always people watching.
Watching you.
- True.
- Yeah.
What's taking you boys so long?
There he is now.
Hurry up, hurry up, this guy.
This guy right here.
Fuck you, guys.
Yo, man, we need some pills.
Yeah, you in the right place, man.
Get them for us.
Come on, man,
I'm going to work.
Yo, 20 for the pills
and 10 for you.
Leave the bike.
What, you want steal my bike?
What the fuck I want your bike for?
I got a car.
Give me a minute.
$20 might not mean nothing to you.
But I ain't making that much money.
It's hard money.
Y'all some lazy motherfuckers.
This shit is right around the corner.
You have no idea
how much we appreciate this.
I love it when they
come to work pumped like this.
Shit.
Come, man. I'm going to work.
Come, man.
I'm going to work, man!
It's bullshit, man!
This is some bullshit right here.
For real! For real!
I ain't got no drugs,
no shit on me.
I ain't got nothing on me, man.
And you taking my bike, too?!
I need that.
This is bullshit y'all be using!
One down.
We got the money now.
This is fucked up
right here, man.
Andre, how you doing?
This is a friend of mine--
Detective Moreland.
You doing OK there or what?
So, listen, for my friend here,
tell me one more time
how the thing went down, will you?
The boy came in.
Omar?
Omar.
He puts the nine on her.
Says to me, "whatever you got."
A nine, huh?
Where were you?
Where you see me at.
Nine wouldn't go through this.
Why did you come up?
'Cause he said to.
Trying to save her life.
Right, I'm saying...
this is like
vanca annealing glass.
Fort Knox glass.
And who put that up there?
Guy must have had
an elephant gun or some shit.
I don't know.
The boy had a mask on.
A mask?
Like Zorro?
When did that happen?
A few weeks back.
Put in a report?
It got away from me.
We're going to need you
to come down to the office
and straighten out
a couple of things.
I'm running a business here.
I ain't going nowhere.
Give me a bottle of mylanta.
Please.
His whole story
is fucked, and here's why:
first, it don't make any sense.
The shooter took out the woman
and left him breathing to talk to you.
He should be dead, too.
Second,
there's a drug depot in there.
The glass, reinforced steel,
camera, low inventory.
And, third, he's shining us on
about that big-ass .50 cal hole
because I know who put it there,
and he knows who put it there.
And if he were to say,
"Oh, that? That's Omar's previous.
Ripping off a re-Up in here--"
Which is what happened--
he be fucked.
So, what?
A guy comes in the first time
with a .50 caliber because
he knows the glass is thick,
then comes back the next
week with a nine?
The job isn't about
picking the stories we like best.
Motherfucker.
Now you are going to lecture me
about what the job is.
My apologies.
OK. Let's go downtown.
It's a new law, yo--
3 pills, that's felony weight.
And you're on a pre-indicted corner?
You better show some stash.
Oh, it's off the chart now.
Those D.C. Boys down there, too, right.
They love fresh Baltimore ass.
I ain't know no stash.
They say he's got a new pussy.
- Those my pills?
- Yeah.
Have you ever heard
of federal guidelines?
Pre-indicted corners, homeboy.
that's 3 years mandatory.
Unless you mitigate.
Mit-a-what?
Just stash, front boy.
I don't know no stash.
Those my pills, man.
I'm high right now, look.
They gonna love him up in there.
Come on.
I saw him first.
Bitch is mine.
Those are my pills, I swear.
That's two.
Get the fuck in the car.
Damn, fractions?
He's doing fractions.
Shit, you want to know what
we talked about in my new class today?
- What?
- Slinging.
Yo, I'm not playing.
We talked about business.
About putting shit
on the damn street.
- Nigger, please.
- It was that we schooling them.
Yo, my new class is the shit.
You going by the gym today?
No, man. I gotta go vial up
what's left on this package
so I can re-up.
- All right.
- All right, man.
- Peace, man.
- That shit is easy though, right?
I got to leave soon, Duquan.
What level are you on?
12.
I never made it past 10.
Want to see me get to 40?
That's cheating.
Want me to show you how?
Baltimore city police department.
Yes, ma'am, this
is Sydney Handjerker
with Handjerker,
Kernan, and Bronburg.
I'm trying to locate
a sergeant Thomas Hauk
in regards to a client
I am representing.
Hold, please.
Mayor's office, Lieutenant Hoskins.
Yes, hello,
this is Ervin Pepper
of Pepper, Pepper,
and Bayleaf.
I'm calling in regards
to a Sergeant Thomas Hauk
in regards to a--
He's no longer on this detail.
Hold on for a minute.
Major crimes.
May I help you?
This is Dr. J. Calling with
test results for Thomas Hauk.
He's on the street.
You want to leave
a message on it?
Let's do it.
You just got to walk
up on him, all right.
Snap one.
We gotta make sure
he from New York first, right?
Gotta ask.
Ask what?
"You from new York?"
No, ask a Baltimore question,
something New York
nigger won't know.
What's a Baltimore question, yo?
I don't know. Like,
maybe something about club music.
They don't know nothing
about that shit up in New York.
Ask him, like, who Young Leek be.
Shaking it, jiggle it.
OK, swift.
Man! I know nothing
about that 92-cube shit, man.
Man, who gives a fuck, yo?
You don't know Mark Clark?
The b-5 morning show.
You ain't right, girl.
The average Baltimore nigger
know all that shit, all right.
They don't listen
to that shit up in New York.
They listen bullshit in New York.
- Go ahead.
- Whatever.
Got a bet going on, men.
What's up?
Who's your favorite one
on the big-5 morning show, yo?
What, in new York, girl?
- Shawn zee.
- Who? Who?
Saw that show any day.
Snoop! Snoop, yo!
Snoop, yo! Yo!
Chill!
Shawn zee be on the show, too.
So, maybe I ask the questions
from now on, all right?
And then they basically
entrap some poor bastard
on a bet, haul in $20 worth of drugs.
Now they got to process him, feed him,
property voucher his bike--
Next thing,
they are working on some...
14-year-old smoke hound
like he's Bin Laden.
The big haul there's
3 vials of cocaine.
I mean, are you with this?
I've been fighting
this bullshit for years.
The only way to go
is high-end enforcement.
You pick the targets that
will make a dent out there.
Reduce the violence.
So, what's the problem?
Problem is I do what I'm told.
Meaning?
Mr. Mayor, I'm no more
a racist than you are.
Think about affirmative action.
I'm just talking policy here,
no offense intended.
None taken.
It's a numbers game.
And numbers games
breed more numbers games.
In your 20% hike in hiring
a black officer
to keep up with
the city demographic,
that's also got to be reflected
straight up the chain.
Which means fast-tracking
some people past where their--
How do I say this?
Their experienced warrants.
And he who owes his good
fortune to the numbers,
abides in them.
Gotta show arrest
are up 15, 20%.
We'll worry about
the quality later.
So, what you saw out there,
it's a con game.
A band-aid on cancers.
So, no, I'm not with this,
but I do follow orders.
However, if those
orders were to change?
Or if I had the opportunity
to change them myself...
Oh, no, you not!
What's this shit
doing in my house?
I stretching bottles, ma.
You ever see your daddy
bring his work home
with him like that?
That's what you got a Lieutenant for.
Police come to this door
instead of your mother,
they will have
this whole damn house.
This all got to be packed up
and elsewhere right now.
All right, be cool.
Wait till Bell hear about this.
Did you hear that naked-ass
appealed racial solidarity?
I like to kick his pale, entitled ass.
Were you listening?
He's no more a racist than I am.
Might have to kick your ass, too.
What have you heard
about his fellow Daniels?
Major in the western.
Yeah, he's there.
Not much politically.
I don't think he's got
any suction with anybody.
Where's the rice-a-roni?
Ma, where's the rice-a-roni?
There was this boy on the stoop
Looked like he was starving.
So, you cooked it for him?
No, I just gave it to him.
Just gave it to him.
Boy ate a raw box
of rice-a-roni?
How much did you sell
the groceries for?
Don't look at me like that?
I gotta go out.
10?
You have your rice-a-roni profits.
Martin, come on!
Boy, I ain't gonna
let you hold the D.S.S. card
if you ain't gonna do right by me.
You're gonna let me hold that card.
You a hard child.
Next time, don't go selling
the food out of our mouths!
Yeah, like y'all say,
don't lie, don't Bunk,
don't cheat, don't steal
or whatever.
But what about y'all, huh?
What, the government?
What, the Enron?
Steroids?
Liquor business?
Booze the real killer out there.
And cigarettes--
oh, shit.
Hey, you got some
smokes in there?
I'm trying to quit.
And drugs paid your salary, right?
No, not exactly.
But I get your point.
We do the same thing as y'all.
Except when we do it,
it's like, "oh, my God,
these kids is animals."
Like it's the end of the world coming.
Man, that's bullshit, all right?
'Cause this like--
What's it-- hypocrite-- hypocritical.
I mean, yeah, we got our thing,
but this is just part of the big thing.
- Exactly.
- But this corner boy thing, right?
We know how y'all did
all this talking up in here.
You think you could sit down
and write down
the laws to your thing?
Hell yeah.
I'll doing it right now.
Shit.
No, I'm talking about
can you'll do it together?
I give the test on fractions.
Half the kids have breakdowns.
I still have a lot of kids
who can barely handle whole numbers.
Well, if it's any comfort,
I have outside
of my advanced class
maybe half a dozen
reading at grade level.
Try having them on
the periodic table of elements.
The thing is,
it's your curriculum,
and you have to stick to it.
I can't. It's absurd.
You have to.
That test in April
is the difference between
the state taking over
the school or not.
Maybe the state should.
Look, you teach math,
you teach the test.
North avenue is all about The leave
no child behind stuff getting spoon-fed.
And what do they learn?
Find some middle ground.
Every day try to do
a little for the statewide.
And keep a unit problem
on the blackboard for Donnelly.
You know, she comes to visit,
she thinks you are on point.
The rest of the time,
do what you feel like
you need to do.
But be careful.
You're are still on the far
side of your evaluation.
The first year
isn't about the kids,
it's about you surviving.
Get up!
Hands on your head.
- I was eating that.
- Fuck you.
- That's my lunch.
Find a wall, motherfuckers.
Man.
Get your feet up.
- This is harassment.
- What did I say to you?
Fuck you.
That's what you said to me.
There's nothing here, man.
My bad.
Want to play games with me?
Going to be in your people's shit
like this every day
until my camera comes home.
You hear me?
Every day.
You and yours.
Let's go.
Ah, that felt good.
The old western D.E.U. rides again.
Yes?
...All C.I.D. Reports
at the front desk?
Any C.I.D. reports to
the front desk.
Respectfully, sir,
I would feel better if you clear this
through the chain of command.
Yes, sir.
I'll think about that.
Problem with the bosses?
One in particular.
That was our mayor-to-be.
Carcetti?
Seriously?
He wants to meet.
You and him, alone?
He wants to talk about
the police department--
What works, what doesn't.
You have the mayor's ear now.
Look at you.
Here's the thing--
What do I say?
- What do you mean, what do you say?
- How honest should I be?
I mean, it's one thing to talk
technical shit or enforcement strategies,
but the shit that actually goes on.
I start talking about that,
I don't know if I can stop.
Cedric, this is your chance.
This is a career.
And what if I take my shots
at Burrell and Rawls
and he decides not to clean house?
What then?
The new mayor calls you up,
Asks you for your take on things,
and you don't want to be,
what, a politic?
Carcetti, oh.
I don't even know the man.
If he is calling you,
it's because guys like Burrell
and Rawls are on the ropes.
Maybe.
I know there is a risk,
but maybe I'd fire away...
both barrels.
Oh, wait out here, man.
Up top.
Oh, wait, oh, wait.
You got that grub,
you got that pot?
Oh, wait.
"Shake it and jiggle it," yo.
Who made that track?
Yo, who you talking to, Dawg?
I'm asking who Young Big be.
You mean too fat's cousin?
- Who?
- No.
Nigger, how the fuck shit I know?
Yo, who the fuck is you talking--
Oh, shit.
Not bad.
Fuck that nigger.
What up, B?
- Where ma at?
- Upstairs.
Michael, my daddy came home.
Daddy came home?
Look who home?
Michael.
Damn, you grew.
And a pack of cools for Macy.
Still tricking for that clown?
You know, I don't understand
why people talk trash about him.
All I know is he loves me.
Well, when you get tired of him
going upside your head and all,
you'll really know who loves you.
Whatever.
Motherfucker, what?
He had 12 years.
Parole.
It was only a drug charge.
You swore he wasn't coming back.
This is a good thing, Michael.
It's going to be back the way it was.
The way it was?
We family again.
You lied to me.
People change, Michael.
He say you can give him back
the independence card, too.
He gonna take care
of all that for us.
Thanks for coming up from Washington.
The party is happy
for the opportunity.
You got some heat
behind you at this point.
But down to business.
The way we see it,
We got to cobble together
a citywide turnaround--
call it the Baltimore miracle
or some shit.
Which starts with a...
10% drop in crime.
Since that was your campaign cry,
you want the double digits.
No doubt.
Denny's got to do a bricks
and mortar project downtown,
put his name on something.
Well, we flushed with stadiums,
got hotels out of the ass.
You guys got a good convention center?
And a convention center expansion.
Gotta put something up.
Get the sign on it that says:
"Brought to you by Tommy Carcetti
and the citizens of Baltimore."
Well, think on it.
But you don't have too
much time to decide.
- Anything else?
- Education always polls good.
Oh, no, we got to
stay away from schools.
Our last 4 administrations
left us with an inner city system
with inner city problems.
We get involved,
start talking shit,
it becomes our mess.
Gotta respect the depths.
One,
you get the drop in crime.
Two,
you build something downtown.
And 3,
you stay away from schools.
And, 4, you keep
your boyish good looks.
You do all that, you might be
running for governor in 2008.
Maybe take back
that state house for us.
- Can you get him a square corner?
- Easy.
I don't like things
with square corners.
- They look like they have a--
- They don't.
They don't fit certain things.
You OK?
Yeah.
You sure?
- Is it something at home?
- No.
- Come on.
- I said no.
If there's ever anything
you want to talk about...
there's me, but,
if you'd rather, I can write you a...
a pass to see the social worker.
Just say when.
Michael, do you want to
see the social worker?
I have to say,
I've never seen kids
like them
this animated in a classroom.
Focused--
the corner culture kids, at least.
The ones with deeper problems,
they opted out of that.
Deeper problems?
We're not just up against
corner logic in there.
I am seeing
oppositional defiant disorders,
clinical depression,
post traumatic stress,
and with the girl Shaundra,
borderline psychoses maybe.
And with those type of problems,
we are gonna have
a social worker here fulltime.
But the corner kids, yeah,
they really came alive.
When they talk
about what they know,
they talk from here,
and they stay on point.
Shit, they have been even
taking turns in there.
Question is can we get them in that kind
of mindset on stuff they don't know?
Can we have them earn
on faith alone?
In all honesty,
this is uncharted territory.
Where do you go from here?
How about we just let this ride?
See where it takes us.
All right, see,
here's the thing--
once you got it, it's all you.
Anything happen,
I gonna have to fuck you up.
Yeah, but that's nothing.
'Cause the guy trusting
me on this-- Marlo--
he'll kill you
and your whole family.
So, don't go shaking the vials,
'cause Marlo weighs
that shit every time.
I ain't shaking shit.
See that you don't,
'cause if you do fuck with it,
I'm gonna know.
All right, that's good.
All right, it's good.
All right, see,
you under 13 and shit.
So, you safe from everybody--
but me and Marlo.
So, I'm lieutenant now?
Yeah.
You're my lieutenant.
And all's I get an extra $10?
Yeah, you do this good,
and we'll talk.
See this guy here?
That's the grand jury prosecutor.
Now, you lie to us,
it's just good clean fun.
But you tell tales to that
3-piece motherfucker--
Oh, shit!
I ain't telling lies.
Hey, Gary,
let me ask you this hypothetically.
how much time does a witness get
for lying to your grand jury?
You're kidding.
As much as I can get him.
- What's the Max?
- 10 years.
You got people
going away for 10 years?
Oh, hell yeah.
All the time.
10 years.
I thought he was gonna say
like two or 3.
Hey, look, that motherfucker
went upside my head.
I couldn't even see straight.
Which motherfucker
are we talking about?
Then they got me on that medication,
made me groggy as shit.
Then this man starts working at me,
was ahead--
Fuck I did!
I mean-- shit.
I'm still groggy now.
I mean, I got to...
is there a washroom around?
Lying motherfucker.
For real.
Pull over, asshole.
Shit.
Step out of the car, please.
Step out of the car.
Put your hands on the car.
Got anything on you?
Have a seat on the curb.
Have a seat.
Cross your feet.
Put your hands on your head.
Fuck is this powder?
Lime from my mama's garden.
What are you building,
a clubhouse?
Oh, that shoot nails.
Be cool.
Oh, I know what it does.
I want my fucking camera.
I heard what you said
at COMSTAT the other day.
I also hear you are a--
Commander who knows police work.
That's what people are saying.
So, yesterday
I did a ride-along in eastern,
watched street pops,
undercover rips,
so, what am I thinking?
My guess.
You witnessed a waste of time,
money, energy,
and, in few cases, talent.
Rawls says it's Burrell
and his numbers game.
He says if I unleash him,
put him in the driver's seat,
then all of that bullshit goes south.
See a return of high-end police work,
says it'll be the dawning
of a new day.
Rawls said that?
Yeah.
Says he's just following orders,
being a good soldier.
What do you say?
Mr. Mayor, if you want to talk to me
about what happens in the street
or what goes on
under me in the western,
I'll talk your ear off.
But I'm a soldier, too.
I don't go up the chain
with my opinions.
I can respect that.
I will say this though;
we did have one unit
doing high-end stuff,
Major crimes, working out
of an offsite down on Clinton street.
"Did" is past tense.
What wrecked it?
Good question, Mr. Mayor.
With Ray fosters' passing,
I'm going to need a new
C.I.D. Commander right away.
would you object to being
made Colonel working under Rawls?
Under Rawls?
He is deputy ops, is he not?
Is the mayor going to make the changes
or just leave it to the good soldier?
What I'm really asking is
how for real are you?
Well, I guess we're going
to find that out together, aren't we?
Colonel Daniels.
What the fuck do we do?
I don't know.
These guys don't scare.
If we all kick in,
you, me, Sydnor,
maybe we could afford a used camera.
I thought of that.
It ain't gonna match
the serial numbers
from the one from A.S.D.
You gotta get wood on Marlo.
It's the only way.
This Randy kid,
he can give us a murder, right?
Shit, he can't even give us a body.
But he says some little Kevin kid
was the one supposed to tell Lex
to go up in that alley.
Plus, what did fuck-nut
say little Kev said?
Lex went up the alley,
but he ain't coming back.
Maybe he saw the whole thing.
Maybe he's our eyeball witness.
- Little Kevin?
- Little Kevin.
Carry the 4.
80, 100, 10, 20.
420.
Where's the rest?
I'm on a hard strip.
Stuck me with Lafayette.
What the fuck are you doing there?
I got to build it up.
You ain't got to build up shit.
Your father built them corners,
and they owe you--
'cause they owe him.
Bodie got a real short memory
when it comes to giving props.
Ma.
I going to straighten
this shit out right now.
Ma, let me build.
Sir.
Bill...
we need to regroup.
I've come up with something fresh
for the new administration.
I don't mind telling you,
I'm uncomfortable the way
Carcetti is running around in our shop.
He's talked to me--
several times.
You're making your move, huh?
We were a good team,
you and me.
We were.
Ms. Ella, where Bug at?
- He went home, Michael.
- Nah, he waits for me.
The man who came to pick him up
said he was his father.
And Bug said so, too.
Fuck!
The fuck did you do?
And why do you let him do it?
- Hey, listen to me--
- No.
That's how you got him
with his head up his ass.
Unsolving his own fucking murders.
Your job is to turn red to black,
not the other way.
And you,
stand the fuck up for yourself.
You don't get to do the whole thing
on your fingers, little man.
Look, first count,
6 and 6 is...
12.
Put down the two,
you bring over the one.
Bug.
Hey, big man.
Get over to me now.
- We were just going to--
- Now.
Yo, hold on.
Yo, you owe me height hundred
on all that, bitch.
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - www.thewire-france.com|
www.tvsubtitles.net