All that from overnight?
All that from Freamon.
He's out early today
rooting through empties.
You know what he is?
He is a vandal.
He is vandalizing the board.
He is vandalizing this unit.
He is a hun, a Visigoth,
a barbarian at the gate
clamoring for noble roman blood
and what's left of our clearance rate.
And you sit here
doing what exactly?
A hotshot maybe.
We got a sack in the boxes.
He owns one from a couple days ago.
White coat alley.
What the fuck is wrong
with you people?
Is everybody on a crusade
to make more murders out of bullshit?
The mope's confessing, Jay.
He walked up
to the western desk to do it.
Well, at least when you go
to manufacturing a murder, Eddie,
you already have a suspect in hand.
I respect that part of your game.
Oh, that others might learn.
I need a witness for the statement
in box number one.
Yeah. Let me dump my shit.
I'll be there.
Sodium cyanide.
You're telling me
we do a full tox screen on this kid.
He comes back positive for cyanide.
Yeah.
That's what I'm saying, OK.
You need to lock me up
because I killed that boy.
I did.
So just-- Just lock me up
and be done with. Right?
Where'd you get the cyanide?
You getting sick there, Bunky?
When's the last time
you had your medicine?
No.
Naw, I'm not getting high anymore.
OK?
Let me ask you again.
Where'd you get cyanide from?
If you're saying--
Fuck!
Shit.
He got my fucking sleeve.
Just calm down.
We'll get something to clean this up
and maybe a soda or something.
- Get some sugar in you at least.
- Please, lord.
He settles down,
I'll miranda.
Yeah.
Fuck.
Steals like my ex-wife's lawyer.
Jesus.
Get up there.
Come on. Come on.
Come on!
Give me a sec!
Call 911. The muttonbox in one
just tried to hang himself.
4x13 Final Grades
No idea on this one.
Two on this block
and 3 off Lanvale.
They cluster.
And when they found a block they liked,
they came back on it.
One on the next block,
across Gilmore.
That makes 9.
Scary thing is we're only
looking at one district.
Shit. One sector.
How far you think
they might have roamed?
There's only one way to find out.
Excuse me.
Dennis.
How we doing with forensics?
That's the Colonel's domain,
but my understanding is
that we're sending a lab team
to every house.
So far we're finding
9-millimeter casings.
Once they start scoping
at the morgues,
we'll probably have slugs
to go with them.
Trace-wise, we're laser printing
around every body and vacuuming
every crime scene for hair and fiber,
but, of course, these are vacant.
It'll take our lab a year
to sift that many bags of dirt.
Is this all from one drug crew?
Probably.
- Marlo Stanfield's bunch.
- Where are we on them?
Major crimes was working wiretaps
until 3 months ago,
but we came down on those.
Can we get back up?
Trying, but Stanfield's people
may have changed up the pattern.
Well, Colonel,
whatever you need.
Actually, what I need is patrol.
Patrol division?
That was detective Freeman
on the phone.
We found two more at Lafayette
and another on Lanvale.
Jesus Christ.
Now starting at the first scene,
we've been going door to door,
but there's no telling how far
she would have wandered.
And with 15,000 vacants in the city,
It'll take my people weeks
to cover that ground.
He brings this case in,
he'll be closer to the throne.
Look, I wouldn't worry about Daniels.
He's a long way from my chair,
as are you.
You made your move too soon.
I did.
Politics doesn't suit you.
Stick to operations.
And don't you ever cross me
like that again.
Get it out to all the wards.
Leander, go downtown.
Run a flier for every roll call.
Show them the nails and
the screws in detail. All right?
You grab a couple of those nails
and hit all the hardware stores.
Find out exactly what the model
is that we're looking for.
What do you need from me?
Herc.
I'm serious. Get hold of him.
How's he looking?
Pretty good considering.
No worse than before he hung himself.
Where the fuck are you going?
West side.
Freeman found another.
Fucking Freeman.
He a transport?
Borderline.
B.P. And pulse are normal.
We gave him ativan
for withdrawal.
You want to go to a hospital?
Let me ask you something.
What kind of a fellow rigs up a hotshot
then walks into a police station
to talk about it?
What's that?
You want us to wait?
Naw.
What is in your head, fellow?
Hotshot and this other motherfucker,
they were beating on me.
And the boy?
He was dipping.
I knew he was.
I just didn't--
I didn't think...
the child had no one for him.
No mother, no family.
He in the street
like I'm in the street.
I tried to, um...
like I ain't
who I am, right?
Like I'm pretending I ain't been
a dope fiend my whole damn life.
Just lock me up, man.
'Cause I killed that child.
The shot wasn't for the kid.
Let's throw this one back.
This sad-ass motherfucker's carrying
more weight than we'll ever put on him.
What about the clearance?
- Fuck the clearance.
- Cut him loose?
Shit, he'll go off
a roof or some shit.
My luck, I'll catch that call, too.
Maybe he were over at Bayview.
Something with soft balls.
Is you out of your mind, nigger?
You think I'm gonna pay twice for
the same motherfucking package?
Hey, I'm in the same box here.
Faggot took my shit
same as he took y'all's.
Man, but that's on your own people.
Your guys was the ones doing
security on this shit.
Hey, they worked it the same as
we did the last dozen shipments.
Y'all was fine with it
up until this, right?
Ain't no one have a problem with it
till the motherfucker gave us one.
Thing is, Joe,
we called a quorum on this.
Took a vote that says it's your
people need to make this right.
Naw, naw, a co-op means
share and share alike.
You share the good,
and you share the bad.
All right.
I'll dig deep and do the full
shipment if that's what y'all need,
But don't even think about coming
back to me for a re-up after this.
'Cause when that good raw shit
comes straight off the boat,
It's gonna be mine only,
seeing as how y'all can't find
the heart to stand with me now.
You want to quorum up again,
think it over a little?
Yeah. I thought you might.
I'll get word back
that we need a fresh shipment
and right quick,
and you can think about
what we need to do to improve security.
Make sure it only happens the once.
What's up?
Which one of your people was
in charge of the stash?
I want to talk to him.
My nephew.
My sister's boy.
I can't give him up like that.
I can't do it.
My connect had people there
when the shit went down.
If that's what you need
to make you believe,
you can hear it straight from him.
Mi gente.
We are rich.
That's what I'm talking about.
Butch.
My man.
Now, girl, you set that off slow,
you feel me?
'Cause word gonna get around.
They gonna come back on you now.
Naw. None of that.
Yo, anybody ask about me on another job,
tell them, "Kimmy been retired."
All right?
Be easy.
How much you got left after
splitting with the Mexicans?
20 cig roll.
Gracious.
Shit, only problem, man,
I'll spend the rest of my life
trying to put that out on the street.
I ain't no drugdealer, Butch.
You feel me?
Shoot. We done stole
too much this damn time.
So, what am I gonna do, Butch?
You could come give Joe a call.
Offer to sell the shit back to him now
for 20 cents on the dollar.
Joe would have found
some humor in that.
I know you do.
I understand there's a waiting list.
The thing is this kid has
already been in a foster home.
Right. And now his foster
mother's been hospitalized, so--
Right. No.
Is there a supervisor
that I can talk to?
I'm gonna be a little late for rollcall.
- Gotta get this kid settled.
- What's wrong with D.S.S.?
On the phone with them right now.
They're talking about a group home.
So? Either you come up with a
guardian or he goes to social services.
No two ways about it.
Hello? Hello?
Need your help.
Get dressed.
I'm suspended with pay,
pending a full trial board.
Can't do nothing for no one, Kima.
Fuck what they say.
This here's police work,
and I'm asking if you police.
All right.
Listen up, you mutts.
This is complicated.
I mean, it isn't complicated
if you went to college or--
I don't know--
your mothers actually stopped drinking
for a minute while they was pregnant.
For Baltimore city police,
this is complicated.
Anyway, this right here
is for the major crimes
homicide investigation into the bodies
being found in the vacant houses
here in western.
Command now wants all the districts
to check every vacant in the city.
That means you will need to go door to
door to every vacant house in your post
and look at what was used
to board it up.
Most will have the Phillips head screw
that HCD
uses like this here on the flier.
But if you see a house
that's been boarded up
with nail-gun nails
like these shown here,
Call your sector sergeant immediately.
You can enter the house,
but if you find a body,
do not disturb the crime scene.
All told.
But what I don't understand
is why they keep busting
my balls about this.
I mean, Daniels gave me
a slap on the wrist
for the thing with the minister, right?
And Marimow got bounced just before
he could fuck me up on anything else.
You sure we on the right block?
Yeah. Put them on the curb
right here, more or less.
And then you fired the nail gun
into the asphalt right where they sat.
Yeah. Right next to
the little broad's leg.
So who tells these I.I.D. fucks
to start running through
my paperwork looking
for who the fuck cares?
It's not like they caught me stealing
or brutalizing motherfuckers,
right? Right?
Look.
Yeah. It looks like it could be.
Is that about right?
Yeah.
Must have worked himself free.
I took them nails to ballistics.
Preparer said he could match
anything out of that gun
And maybe the nail gun itself
if we could get it.
I mean, I know they're
gonna take my stripes,
But you don't think
they're gonna go past that, right?
Herc, what'd you do exactly?
Lost the camera I took from I.S.D.
without my Lieutenant's approval.
And what evidence I got
from the camera,
I put to a made-up informant.
Son, they're gonna beat on your
white ass like it's a rented mule.
Fuck.
Then make him sign it.
He gets there himself.
That cocksucker.
I hate that bastard.
They called him cocksucker.
Damn.
You're gonna break that call button.
Look, I'm sorry.
I don't mean to bother y'all,
but I don't get but 4 channels.
That's all you get.
What about my man over there?
He has insurance.
And insurance pays
for his cable hookup.
Only reason you're admitted
is that fracture.
Soon as we can discharge you,
we will.
All you gangsters
wash up in our E.R. like it's your due.
You could stand out there
slinging drugs
till you get shot or cut,
have us put you back together
free of charge
So you can do it again.
- Gangster, huh?
- Oh, you're not that?
I pulled your admissions.
You were here in '90
for a gunshot wound,
And 3 years before that, you were
here for chest surgery for a cutting.
Long time back. Yeah.
And I see you're still at it.
Dennis Wise,
I'm Howard Colvin.
Are you police?
I, used to be, but now
I'm a bit of a teacher up at Tillman.
I got a little problem,
and you know Carver
over at the western.
He said that you might
be able to help me.
I went up to your gym.
They told me what happened.
What is it that
I'm supposed to know about?
His name is Brice.
Yeah. What's the problem?
I've just come to care about the kid.
You heard it was Little Kevin.
Seen one of the police step out
the household his neck was...
can't do nothing to me, yo.
This motherfucker just be
killing niggers just to do it.
See? Nigger killing
motherfuckers just 'cause he can,
Not 'cause they snitching,
not 'cause it's business,
But 'cause this shit
just comes natural to him.
- Yo, Bodie, man--
- Little Kevin is gone.
This nigger don't feel nothing.
And all them motherfuckers
in them row houses,
nobody mean a fucking thing to him.
I think you need to calm the fuck down.
Fuck Marlo, man.
Fuck him!
And anybody that think it's
all right to do people this way.
You hear me?
Fuck all y'all motherfuckers.
Get the fuck off me, man.
That's his friend in the bag.
It's like a nigger
ain't fit, man.
You see that shit, yo?
Go on. Lock his dumb ass up.
Attica! Attica! Attica!
The number of victims discovered shot
to death in the boarded-up buildings.
How flattering for us.
Knocks the school deficit
right off the front pages.
There's your silver lining right there.
Those bodies are on Royce.
School deficits should be, too.
Should be, but that's
a problem that's gonna play out
in the next fiscal year.
By then, you're out of Teflon.
So I take
the Governor's money,
and in two years from now when
I shake the hand of any voter
in the D.C. Suburbs,
they say, "all right.
You're the guy who needed my tax
dollars to bail out your school system."
You take his check.
He lives both in Prince Georges
and Montgomery,
and you can't beat him statewide
without the counties.
but two years from now,
if you're Governor,
You can help the city from Annapolis.
He's the Mayor now.
I agree we can't fix
the city schools,
but we can't let them
get any worse either.
Go back to Annapolis.
Heed his shit.
If we lose local control of the schools
and the reason, the teachers
will rip you.
But the rest of the city will see,
you did it for them kids.
Kids don't vote.
Taking a risk
with our supply, ain't you?
I mean, setting up a meeting
with anybody other than us.
Got to.
My boy Cray reassured us.
Boss, you get our boy Marlo
in line on our connect,
he might try to go round the co-op,
go round us.
You know what I'm saying?
Cautious as those Greeks be,
who you think they gonna trust?
They know us.
They don't know him.
Damn.
Look at this nigger coming round.
Easy, son. Easy.
I might have known
I'd find you boys in here
burning that oil after hours.
Nigger, I'm gonna kill you twice.
So you don't want your shipment, huh?
Say your piece.
Well, it just so happens
I got some heroin for sale.
Market-wise,
you fellows look like buyers.
You feel me?
This some shameless shit.
Oh, ain't no shame on my game, dawg.
I'm here about the business.
Ain't that right, Joe?
How much?
20 on the dollar.
10, nigger.
Don't make me say 25, now.
That's 400,000.
How about, we take
your faggot ass in the back room
and get into some diabolical brutality,
Find out shit
the old-fashioned way?
Feel me?
I feel you.
Sounds like a plan.
I don't know though, Joe.
You think old Marlo gonna give it up?
20 on the dollar it is.
Say, how's she ticking, Joe?
Be in touch.
And he thinks,
I'll help the schools,
help the city a lot more
if I'm Governor two years from now.
Thinking that way,
it wouldn't just be about me
if I don't take the money.
Are you asking me what I think?
I think you'll do the right thing.
You sure you want to do this?
I don't want to hurt you.
You're not hurting me.
Detective Crutchfield,
do you have a moment?
Yes, ma'am.
I've got a question in these reports.
Were they all found
in the basement?
No, ma'am. We've been finding
most in the basement,
But some are on the upper floors, too.
Can you be specific in the 24s,
for my sake anyway?
- You got it.
- Thanks.
How many so far?
- 17.
- Christ.
That's a lot of red names.
It's your first red bull.
Yeah. I thought I'd get a nice,
quiet domestic or two to start me off.
We got national press
on this already.
You'll be fine, Rhonnie.
Just don't let any of these guys
see you sweating.
And your case dropped.
Tell Mello to sign off
on your friendly A.S.A.
He kicks out a radio car window,
and you want to give him a walk?
What's the date range for decomp?
The one on mount street
looked about a week.
Some a few days.
Some are skeleton at this stage.
They all head shots?
Most of them.
Black males 15-25?
No, some older.
We got one in a security guard's
uniform around here somewhere.
You laser print?
Vacuum the rooms?
Yes.
Gluco for blood?
What's the geography?
13 on west side.
Baltimore to Winchester.
Schroeder to the Grove.
The eastern boys found 4 more
in the houses on Monument street.
- East side?
- Yeah. That threw us.
We're casting a wider net now
searching the vacants citywide.
My number's 23 in the office pool.
I still have hope.
Hell of a case right here.
You know, if I was police, I don't
think I could lean back on it. You?
Not if I was real police.
Thank you, detective.
Calvin, you done already?
Yeah, I'm done.
Attention, proctors, a reminder.
Answer sheets must be turned into
the office by you and only you
immediately
upon completion of the tests.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Where are we on the nail gun?
A Hill T.D.X. model.
High end but common
among contractors.
Is it what sergeant Hauk saw
in the back of Chris Partlow's truck?
We showed him one,
and he thought so.
Then we dragged his ass back down
to the block where he did the car stop.
Anything?
We found what might be a hole
where he said he fired into the street,
but no nail even after sweeping
the block with metal detectors.
Probably took a ride
in some bastard's radio,
but now it's in a tire pile somewhere.
So our next move is a search
and seizure on that truck.
Along with a court order for hair
and blood from Chris and Snoop both.
With everything we're pulling out
of these houses,
we might get lucky
with some trace work.
What's your P.C.?
Herc sees the nail gun.
Nothing wrong with owning a power tool.
What's the P.C.
on Chris and Snoop specifically?
A witness.
Boy who was told by
a co-conspirator who the murderer was.
The boy is a source.
He's not a witness.
If he's just a source,
you don't have enough.
With the links that we got between
some of these bodies of Stanfield
and his organization,
we have a pattern.
Weak.
Very weak.
Oh, fuck it.
Give me an hour.
You haven't let me alone all week.
Every time I come out of the pool,
want to dry me off without a towel.
- Dennis Wise.
- Hey, man.
Yeah.
Were you able to get some word?
On my say so,
he's willing to sit and hear you out.
What you asking him for,
I don't know.
He'll love it, though.
You see my man Carver again,
you tell him he owe me one now.
All right, man.
Appreciate it.
You got it, bro.
Y'all coming back with a warrant?
The roughneck in room 232.
From what I know,
he runs a gym program for kids.
He got hisself shot for trying
to pull a kid off the corner.
Look, you need to speak up now
or face the fact
that you never spoke at all.
They wouldn't let me see my son,
at marches.
Said there wasn't much left
by the time y'all found him.
We did the best we could
with the information we had.
Word come to me
that a man named Chris
ad a girl named loop or Snoop
or some such took my son and killed him.
Told I would never see my boy again.
Why can't you just make
an exception in this case
and move his name
to the top of the list?
See that he gets another foster parent.
The list is the list.
Some clients have been
in group homes for years.
He was in group homes for years.
- Now he's gotta go back because--
- Please don't raise your voice.
- If you're going to raise your voice--
- Please.
There's gotta be se way
that he doesn't have to go--
Yeah, there is.
There's gotta be.
How about--
How about if I take him
as a foster parent?
The screening process takes 3-4 months.
This child can't be
in your custody, sergeant.
He needs to come back under
our supervision per the juvenile order.
Think you all that
for hassling niggers and shit.
I know I'm all that.
I'm thinking about some pussy.
Yeah. Me, too.
They dumped their tools.
Nothing under the seats.
Nothing in the glove box.
Registered to some
little old lady, no doubt.
These guys know the drill.
Can you see these two riding tail?
Come on.
Aw, shit.
There it is.
It ain't even our truck.
But I need to hear it from you.
From me?
This is not my affair, huh?
It is what Joe Sats said.
I'm only here right now for Joe.
It's who I trust,
who I respect,
Who I worked with for many years.
You I do not know,
and I don't need to know.
But because this thing
go wrong for Joe, then--
Well, how am I supposed to know
this ain't no setup?
How I supposed to know
your people ain't in on it, too?
You know because Joe says
and because I say.
And you trust your people like that?
I talk to my driver.
I looked into his soul.
Chris and Snoop just been found,
with a gun charge found in the truck.
Call the bondsman.
But first,
put a follow on him right there.
Who, white dude with the hat on?
- What, he a problem?
- Naw.
I just need to know more.
All right.
Satisfied?
90,000 to you in the morning.
We'll put a hundred more on later
After the heat on them
empty houses gives way.
What the fuck are you doing here?
You think that charge gets dropped
without somebody
showing you some special love?
You hungry?
Come on.
All right.
Might be surety bond
on this Chris Partlow
given all of his priors.
Pearson woman--
Not so much.
All right?
What's this?
Court order.
We get blood and hair.
14 head hairs, 14 body hairs
two blood samples each.
It's a lot of houses.
A lot of deeds.
Who knows what you left behind?
We still in the city?
Cylburn arboretum.
Pumlico is right up the hill.
This is nice.
I ain't no snitch.
I didn't say you were.
I been doing this a long time.
I ain't never said nothing to no cop.
I feel old.
I been out there since I was 13.
I ain't never fucked up a count,
never stole off a package,
never did some shit
that I wasn't told to do.
I've been straight up.
But what come back?
You think if I get jammed up
on some shit,
they'd be like, "all right.
Yeah. Bodie been there.
"Bodie hang tough.
We got to his pay lawyer.
We got a bail."
They want me to stand
with them, right?
Where the fuck they at when
they supposed to be standing by us?
I mean, when shit goes bad
and there's hell to pay,
where they at?
This game is rigged, man.
Be like the little bitches
on a chessboard.
Pawns.
Yo, I'm not snitching
on none of my boys,
not my corner, and not no Barksdale
people or what's left of them.
But Marlo--
this nigger and his kind, man--
They gotta fall.
They gotta.
Well, for that to happen,
somebody's gotta step up.
I'll do what I gotta.
I don't give a fuck.
Just don't ask me to live
on my fucking knees, you know.
You're a soldier, Bodie.
Hell, yeah.
I remember you.
You used to be
a role-up pitcher and Fremont.
Yeah. It was my old post.
- I came up with C.B.S.
- Calhoun-Baker-Stricker.
Yeah. I used to have
to bang up on y'all all the time.
I remember that, too.
Yeah.
I ain't a cop now, right.
And like I told Cutty,
I'm sort of like a teacher now,
And that's how I come to know Naman.
Only reason I'm even here
is Cutty spoke for you.
He say what I'm asking?
Your boy...
is smart and funny,
and open-hearted,
and he got some flex in him.
And I ain't see it at first
'cause he was always acting out,
always full up of corner talk.
You know,
just talking shit to hide hisself.
But he could go a lot of places,
and do a lot of things in his life,
be out there in the world in a way that,
you know,
didn't happen for you and me.
I mean, you know, our kind?
Shit.
Man, we both know we gonna go
to our grave forever knowing
what block Bentalou dead-ends at or
who got their liquor license
over at the underground
or what corner Tatum man got shot
on when he come out
the musical lounge back in '88.
It's a vision in Gold.
I mean, the westside, we know...
it's dead, man.
You know, people in the game nowadays--
I mean, it's a whole different breed.
No code, no family,
and damn sure no respect.
I mean, you send Naman
out on the corner now,
giving him maybe one, two years
before you down at the morgue
and maybe if you're lucky
up here with you.
Maybe, maybe not.
That's the game.
I'm talking about Naman here, Mr. Brice.
He's a lot of things,
a lot of good things.
I mean, before you know,
he might surprise all of us
given half a chance,
but he ain't made for them corners, man.
I mean, not like we were.
That's why I come down here--
because I gotta believe that you see it.
Being who you are
and all you've been through.
You know your son.
It's in your hands, man.
You asking too much.
Yeah. I'm asking.
You sure it was the boy Bodie?
Man, I seen him
come from out of central bookings
over on Eager street side.
Then he got in some car
with some white dude.
Police?
What kind of car, a caprice?
No. O.T., I think.
They on you like a motherfucker.
They jacking you up, pulling all
your work out of them houses, right?
Man, we can't have nobody
snitching on us now.
We ain't sure it's that.
What, you want to let it go?
Risk it?
Send a message.
Maybe give it to your pup,
get him started.
You and Snoop, y'all lay low
till this shit here blow down.
Boy worked for Bodie.
First time,
must be someone he didn't know.
You hear what Joe said?
Joe's saying this cocksucker
who stole our shit
wants to sell it back to us
for 30 on the dollar.
Joe's saying it's another 90
to buy back our shit.
Dang, yo.
Thought you forgot about me.
Hey, why don't you wait outside?
You spoke to his father?
If it goes the way I think,
he'll be back
with his mom by tomorrow.
Big day all around tomorrow.
Delegate Watkins got us 30
minutes at the Mayor's office.
Yo, spider, what's the count?
I don't even think
we gonna sell out today, man.
Yo, Bodie.
Yo, bode.
Yo, Bodie, you better run, yo.
Yo, this my corner.
I ain't running nowhere.
Bodie, is you crazy?
Shit is on!
Run with it, motherfuckers!
I don't give a fuck!
I'm right here!
You ain't putting me up in one
of them empty-ass houses, neither.
Come on, man.
I don't know about this.
Mayor's office.
Yes. Actually, you want the department
of housing and community development.
Look, I don't know about this, man.
I just...
ma'am, uh--
If...
I'm sorry.
If the mayor prefers not to--
or if he, like, feels more comfortable
with Dr. Perenni alone,
you know, because of the
drug-legalization controversy last year.
I don't ink mayor Carcetti
is in your meeting.
He's in Annapolis.
OK. Thank you.
What up?
Still asleep?
Early bird get that worm.
How you liking the crib?
Fine. Thanks.
Must feel good to be on your own.
Yo, where you get that rent from?
Took it from a nigger.
Why? You want it?
No. No. You keep it, shorty.
I'll go get Bug ready for school.
You ready to put in work?
Two things, then.
First, we' gonna give you
the corner up on Passno,
used to be Bodie's old corner.
Now it's yours.
Crew that up. Run that shit.
You get the points on that shop.
Then we got this other thing.
Yo, if I ain't stepping on nothing,
who was that who dropped for you, yo?
Bug's daddy.
Word?
That's not how you spell
"paraphernalia."
- How the fuck do you spell it?
- Hey, fellows.
- Not like that.
- McNulty. Hey.
You're here 4:00-12:00, right?
- You heard about Bodie?
- What about?
- Bodie from up Passno.
- Yeah, yeah. What?
Shot dead on his corner.
Midnight shift caught it.
Check the read-out.
Sergeant, get your ass in here.
Goddamn it, Norton,
you're on the brink of insubordination.
You call D.S.S. Right now
and ship him out.
- That's an order.
- Lieutenant.
I got $235 if it helps.
How would that help?
Maybe we can get
a foster spot like that.
Pay somebody.
This is tracking, plain and simple.
It's a socialization process.
To any parent who complains,
you're still segregating them.
Look, it's for their benefit,
and for the benefit
of the teachers trying to teach.
And you're proposing to expand
this to every middle school?
With enough grant money
and your support, yes.
By September--
But you wouldn't be teaching
test curriculum here?
These would be the children
left behind, so to speak.
Yeah, but as it, I mean,
We're leaving them all
behind anyway.
We just don't want to admit it.
- What we mean to say is--
- Gentlemen, we'll be in touch.
So, what, that's it?
After a two minute hearing,
they stick a fork in us?
I'm a liability in there, man.
Seems like every time
I open my mouth in this town,
I'm telling people things
they don't want to know.
It's not you. It's the process.
- The process?
- When we get the grant,
We study the problem,
we propose solutions.
If they listen, they listen.
If they don't,
it still makes for great research.
What we publish on this is
gonna get a lot of attention.
- From who?
- From other researchers, academics.
Academics?
What they gonna study your study.
When do this shit change?
And you put him out, huh?
He need to get hard.
Well, if he out, then he out.
Oh, no, you not.
You ain't gonna take my son
away from me.
Remember who the fuck
you talking to right here.
Remember who I am.
My word is still my word.
In here, in Baltimore,
in any place
you can think of calling home,
it'll be my word.
They'll find you.
Man come down here to say my son
can be anything he damn please.
Except a soldier.
Yeah.
Well, look at me up in here.
Who the fuck would want to be that
if they could be anything else, Dalonda?
So, did you cut me off, too?
You still got me.
We'll get by.
But you gonna let go of that boy.
Bet that.
Quien es?
Tu amor, baby.
For your bank?
That's for your pain, Butch.
I be my own bank now.
They ain't follow you?
Naw. Joe paid him my way.
He had to admit my word was
better than his. You feel me?
Let's go, then.
He is in the van, in the garage
in the back of 2249 Polk street.
Key gonna be in the cinderblock.
You stole this much,
and is ain't over.
This ain't over.
Thing about that republican ass--
It's not the flesh of
his political fathers.
- Jesus. You left it
on the table.
Smug son of a bitch.
He was gonna make beg
Then call a press conference
So the world could
see me on my knees.
Don't worry.
Two years,
and we'll make him pay.
Icicle.
Got those icicles.
Shake down.
Corner's indicted.
Go on. Get.
Except you, motherfucker.
On the wall.
Sorry about Bodie.
I ain't jacking you up.
I'm trying to do right
for your boy.
Who dropped him?
- Y'all did.
They took him out 'cause
he was talking to y'all.
Word is they seen him with the
police down at central booking.
So cuff me or kick my ass off this
corner before you do me the same.
Hey, Duquon.
Don't you need
to be at Douglas?
I'm on my way there. Yeah.
Where's your book bag?
- Oh, it's-- I'm gonna stop
past the house and get it.
It's a present
for all you did.
It's for your desk.
- That's great, Duquon.
Thanks.
Stop past anytime.
Let me know how it's
going with you.
OK.
- But I ain't want to go back.
- Program's ending, Zanovia.
- Yeah, boy.
Back to gen. Pop.
- Yes.
Pack my bags.
Shut up.
What about you?
I mean, this was all right.
But maybe it's time.
Why are you up?
You're working 4:00-12:00.
What's the matter?
Something with these bodies.
Lester and them are
getting up on it.
It's under Daniels.
He's got suction there.
He can deliver.
You want in.
- I just feel like
I owe it now.
To who?
To this kid.
Corner kid.
Getting ready to turn him,
you know.
Wrap him up and give him
to Lester as a present.
- He one of the bodies
in the houses?
- No. They dropped him
in the street.
Maybe I'd be different,
you know.
Different?
Yeah.
No more of the drinking and warring
and all that, all that anger.
'Cause I'm better now
here with you.
No more "Jimmy busts
balls world."
Jimmy bust balls?
- I swear to God being that
son of a bitch nearly killed him.
It's OK.
What?
You tried.
You don't need to feel bad.
Thanks.
Hey, yo, look at this.
Got to fucking
talk to you.
- All right, Randy,
this way.
Take that top Bunk over there.
Are you sure?
I'm not asking
'cause I can't use you.
I'm asking for your sake.
I think I can do this
And keep myself away
from myself,
If that makes any sense.
But I gotta tell you.
We're not gonna get Marlo Stanfield
or anyone else above the street
Not on street corners.
- What do you suggest?
Either a wide C.I.
or a title iii.
That's what makes this case.
You sure?
Maybe you do this fast
and clean and simple.
Then you don't do it at all.
Chain of command, colonel.
- How in the hell do we kick up
percentages in math and reading both?
You believe the numbers?
- 38% proficient.
8% advanced. What?
- Proficient means they're at
least two grades below their level.
Advanced can mean they're at
grade level or a year below.
They score them like that, and
they say we're making progress.
OK. I'm still learning.
Naw. You're gonna be fine.
- Albert, Zanovia, Naman,
good to have you back with us.
- Yeah. Your worst nightmare
come right back on you.
Say, naw, I'm just foolin'.
OK. Everyone open to 121.
Who figured out
the first problem?
Kareem?
164.
- Correct.
How'd you get it?
Don't know.
Come. Show us.
- Just when you think
you're done.
What's that one? 20?
22.
Anybody heard from Bunk?
- Ballistics say the guns match
to nothing. Open and closed.
And they cleaned the prints.
- Well, maybe
we'll find a witness.
Maybe trace lab will give us
a hair or splatter or something.
But short of that, we're gonna
have to go pro-Active.
- Where are you on the new body?
- Back to square one.
We're in here for the long haul.
Colonel, how you happen to pick
this place for us to stage?
- Lemille?
- Hmm.
- hey closed it a few years back, and I
knew it was near a lot of our crime scenes.
I went to school here
back in the day.
Got a decent education
now that I think on it.
You try and talk to him?
Didn't know what to say.
Only heard from my sergeant
this morning.
Guess I missed the 24
they wrote on it.
- And he really tried
to do himself?
It wasn't just for show
or nothing?
- He's got some problems, but
insincerity ain't one of them.
- Shame's some
tricky shit, ain't it?
Makes you feel like
you want to change
And then beats you back down
when think you can't.
- When was the last time
y'all talked?
More than a couple of years
Since he last got
on the wagon, I think.
But if he's up in d ward,
He's clearing the motherfucker
right now.
You coming?
Maybe later.
- Can't believe you'd leave
that money on the table.
Why not?
School. Kids.
Shit.
You ain't done enough
of this here, I suppose.
They always disappoint.
Closer you get, more you look.
All of them.
- If he tries...
might stay with Royce.
If not, there's this young buck
out in Salisbury
Thinks he can snatch up
the first district seat.
- You can look him
in the eye now.
No matter who he is
or what he's done,
You look him right in the eye.
I'm still your father.
What you want?
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - www.thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net