All quiet today?
Keepin' it like that, boss.
We rule where we stand.
Police sittin' on all
the corners over these parts.
Likely because
we been droppin' bodies.
Yeah, they do like that.
But you know tomorrow
some other nigger stop a bullet
somewhere else and then they
go stand on a new spot.
Boy Marlo closed up shop.
Word is he wholesaling
his packages for now.
He ain't got no crews
out here at all?
How 'bout his avenue corners?
Nigger give up quick, didn't he?
Damn, I was just beginnin' to respect
the little motherfucker for showin' heart.
A- ight, listen.
When the police roll out,
y'all step in there an' take my corners.
I'm on it, B.
Cheesesteaks from Bill's.
Nah, I did that tuesday, man.
Fuck it then, you pick.
Naw, fuck me.
What?
Mope in the truck.
What about him?
I think I locked him up.
Avon whatshisface.
Big player from the projects.
He was the target on that detail
I worked a couple years back
the one I told you about.
Motherfucker's out already.
Why, what'd he pull?
Six, eight years.
Who the fuck can remember?
An' he's out in two?
Maybe I got the years wrong.
Point is guy's an asshole.
Locked him up is all.
Pit beef, from the market.
See? Now you thinkin' like police.
Back Burners
Change in plan.
Bell you recognize.
Second target is a Marlo Stanfield
who is apparently warring
with Bell for Westside corners.
What about Kintel Williamson?
That case is on hold for now.
On hold?
We just managed to I.D. the cell
phones on two of his people.
Be that as it may...
why not take
a few more weeks
and we can put together what
we got on Kintel, you know?
We send the case to grand jury
and then we start up this Westside case.
Otherwise, we wasted
more than two months...
change of target comes to us from
the Commissioner and the Deputy Ops.
The department is
in a reactive mode
trying to get the murder rate down
by any means necessary.
Kintel was dropping bodies
two months ago.
Today, it's the Westside
that's got the bosses spinning.
Look, I know y'all thought
it was nothin' for me to sit on that roof
day after 90-degree day,
dodgin' swarms of cicadas
and shit, but damn.
This is fucked up.
And all the assets
work I did on Kintel.
His cars, his cash flow...
I just put that in a drawer?
Some day I wanna work
for a real police department.
Just to see how the fuck
they do it, you know?
McNulty.
In my office.
Hey, Prez, can you
run something out for me?
What?
I need to know
who reed this room
in the downtown Hilton,
thursday before last.
Who rented the room?
Address, credit card details,
whatever you can pull.
How's it fit with the case?
Hard to say just yet.
Hey, my man.
I'm done mowin'.
So I figured I'd use this
to edge the weeds around the fence.
- It's gas-powered.
- Means I got to prime it.
You ain't got school me but once.
Get some water
before you go back out there.
You been goin' hard at it.
You keep showin' up at the spot,
I'll keep puttin' you on.
Good, 'cause I ain't
got nothin' else.
You walked back through
them old doors, didn't you?
Tried to.
I took you for gone.
Man, parole officers,
employment agencies...
shit, I just felt like I was
an interruption to their lunch break.
No family?
None besides my grandmother.
She put me up in the basement.
That's plenty to ask
of the old girl right there.
You could use someone to talk
to 'sides your grandmoms.
What about one of them
social worker types?
I hooked up with one dude.
He was cool, but I wasn't ready.
You look like you ready now.
I mean, you found an ear to bend,
you wouldn't have to talk to me.
Shit, I know you gonna get tired
of lookin' at my ugly-ass grill.
Drink that too fast,
you'll cramp up.
- You're asking?
- I am.
Lieutenant, I didn't...
Because I got no problem
changing targets
if that's what the bosses
tell me to do.
Unless it's personal.
Like when Kima got shot...
I don't care where
we spend our time and money.
Bell, Williamson, whoever.
It's all just police work to me.
And I understand that people
above my pay-grade have the right
to make decisions
that are theirs to make.
And if they're wrong?
Then they're wrong
and time will tell, won't it?
Now, I'm asking you for the truth.
You went to Colvin. Behind my back.
I'da gone to the devil himself.
Which way you were standing,
Lieutenant
had not a fucking
thing to do with it.
You piece of shit.
I did it because it had to be done
just like it had to be
done two years ago
when we were first detailed.
Stringer was the target then,
he's still the target now.
Lieutenant, you know,
as bosses go
you're better than most
and I know you went out of your
way to get me off that boat.
I know that.
But now we're back
on the right man.
Detective McNulty.
When the cuffs go on Stringer,
you need to find a new home.
You're done in this unit.
Count right?
Yeah, went almost to Richmond
for this here batch.
Yeah, I'm holdin'...
- You did like we say, right?
- Yeah.
Give him that.
We're gonna need another
60 more in a couple days.
60 more?!
You know how we do.
So don't be cryin', Bernard.
You musta left something out.
Fuck no. I got the part ones
from every sector, every post.
We're down about two percent.
Now where exactly are we down?
Larcenies and burglaries are steady
but shootings and agg
assaults are both down.
Drug arrests, too, but I guess
that won't look so good.
I mean, where geographically
are we down?
In the district?
Well, the posts near the
designated drug zones are up
almost all of them.
That ain't pretty.
But everywhere else is down.
In some places
as much as four percent.
Bosses are gonna love you.
It's too soon to take any credit.
This might be, whatcha call that
statistical aberration.
You ain't gonna let them know
that your little experiment
might be working?
Not yet, no.
But I'll tell you
what we are gonna do:
Starting next week
I want you to pull one car
out of service on
the quiet posts in every sector,
all three shifts.
We'll take those nine guys
gonna use 'em and double up
on the high-crime posts.
If we handle less of it
we ought to do better with
the crime we've got, right?
Can I get two
Trac disposable phones.
They on special. Four for 180?
Just the two.
Last show out at Westview is 8:45.
We could make that if we don't
make the whole damn run today.
Seem to me one phone
is as good as the next.
Only a fool drive all over the
world when there ain't no need.
Keep on with that shit an' I'ma
leave your ass in Baltimore.
I don't trust no man
on the road by hisself, okay?
I'm not stupid.
Stupid ass fucker.
Commissioner!
How goes it?
It went a lot better before
the Mayor's cabinet meeting
I can tell you that.
He rip you?
Says we need to finish under 300
for this year regardless of how it happens.
- I tried to tell...
- Erv, lemme ask you...
where do you guys stand on this
witness assistance thing?
What?
Overhauling the city's
witness assistance program?
Nobody from the Mayor's office
called you regarding
this problem of witnesses
getting killed?
I got a call from the chief
of staff a week ago, yeah.
But all he said was
I should try not to have
any more witnesses get killed.
But overhauling the program?
Unless someone wants
to spend a lot more money
there's not a whole
helluva lot my people can do.
And you haven't talked
to the Mayor directly on this?
You're not gonna fuck me on this?
As it is, I got
the Mayor's teeth in my ass.
Your name does not get mentioned.
Mayor didn't say a word to me.
Thanks.
Where the fuck we at now!?
Just buy four or five, Bernard.
Do it like that
and it'll go twice as quick.
I want a Shrek Slurpee, Bernard.
And some Krispee Kreme.
All this from one disposable
cell phone?
And a dead one, too.
It was used by Marlo's people
and picked up off the ground by Kima's C.I.
Problem is it's just raw data.
We need to firm up what we know
about Marlo's operation
with surveillance and C.I. info.
On the other hand
if we had a burner
that we knew was used
by one of Stringer's players...
we could use what we know
about that origination to make
all kinds of connections.
Get us one good phone,
we'll give you the network.
That's the good news.
What's the bad?
It's all historical.
We can give you
the network no problem
but by then it's a week old
and they've dumped their phones.
And how we get a wire up on that...
I haven't figured out yet.
Well, see that you do, detective.
Oh, yeah. You keep this job.
I'ma gain some serious weight.
- Just the two?
- Just the two.
Nigga, you ain't never
hearda buyin' in bulk?
You could be savin'
them people all kinda money.
Or better still, spendin' it on me.
Why you got a gun, Bernard?
You ain't heard?
Avon's home, so we toolin' up.
You ain't the only one on parole.
Girl, you ridin'
my last good nerve.
That's not the only thing
I can ride.
Just get me back to the Interstate?
Big white bag,
got the big white bag!
Which one is he, again?
Broadus, street name of Bodie.
He used to bein the low-rises.
Had a tower later on.
Big white,
got the big white!
How many more minutes you think
he's got on that phone?
Fuck this, let's hit the bar.
Lester needs a phone, man.
There's an easier way.
I'll show you tomorrow.
C'mon.
Got the big white.
I'm buying.
Big white bag,
got the big white bag!
She just wants
me to be happy, you know?
An' I mean, I do the same for her,
when I can.
Like this thing
with the police detective?
Brianna says she wants me
to go downtown with her, and...
I dunno,
hear the man out about Dee...
and I know there ain't nothing to it,
but she's all upset you know.
And I tried to tell her
what you told me
but she says she wants to go down there
and talk to him herself I guess.
You told her about the cop?
What?
About the detective.
What you told me, you told her?
It's her son, right?
I mean, she got a right
to know what's goin' on.
- Look, I just thought...
- What?!
Why the fuck you gonna get her
all upset over some bullshit?
Here we are, fuckin' year later,
everybody forgot about the shit
you go runnin' your
mouth about nothin' at all.
But, String...
What, an' she gonna
believe that shit, too.
What mom is not gonna believe
her son didn't kill hisself?
String...
How she gonna take to that shit,
go half-crazy with it.
- I just...
- You just what?
Sorry.
When you tell her that?
'Bout a week ago, I guess.
When she gonna go see the cop?
Think she gonna
talk to a lawyer first.
- Ask him how to play it.
- Who Levy?
I guess, whoever.
- The lawyer.
- Levy?
- I guess.
- Oh, you didn't ask that?
And this fucking Royce
just lets it slide.
I mean, I go to him, right?
Not to make points,
just to do the right thing
what does he do
but blow smoke up my ass.
"I'm glad you came
to us with this, Tommy... "
"Oh, I'll light a fire, don't you worry.
We gotta move on this. "
I never thought he'd have the balls
to just fuck the dog on it.
And you were doing the right thing.
Fuck yeah.
What?
You went there hoping
that Royce would disappoint.
You want to know that you're better,
that you deserve his chair.
If I lie down on this couch,
do you charge by the hour?
Thanks.
You're not naive.
Neither am I.
A man doesn't run for office
without being a bit self-righteous first.
Self-righteous?
Me?
So what are you gonna do now?
Call a reporter or two,
rip the Mayor.
Maybe on background,
maybe go on the record. I dunno.
Rip him now?
With the primary next september?
Tommy, no one's gonna remember
a dead witness a year from now?
Better if you go to Royce
confront him, not angrily
give him a chance to explain.
Or maybe take action.
If he does do something,
then a problem got fixed
and you can feel
special for helping.
If he doesn't, you sit tight.
I don't know.
Maybe you document
your meeting in a letter
expressing your concern and regret.
Then you're set
if the next witness gets killed.
Win-win.
Unless you're the witness.
I know, you're right.
But he's taking
on a two-term incumbent.
It's all gonna be ugly from here.
Yeah, it's cool.
Need another 30 by monday, a-ight.
A- ight.
Bitch, everything I say
you hear backwards.
Stupid little fucker.
Got them tees, bright white!
One for three, two for five.
Blue Tops, got them Blue Tops!
I got them tees.
Bright white,
one for three, two for five.
I got this, man, five dollar.
- New.
- No thank you, man.
- It's only five dollars.
- No thank you.
Fuck you, man, fuck you.
Fuck you.
I got them, uh...
I got them tees.
Red Tops, Red Tops,
got them Red Tops!
Rockefeller,
got them Rockefeller here!
Hey, seller man, what you got?
Got the long white tees
for the young ones.
You ain't got candles?
I'm lookin' to buy candles.
And toilet paper
for the shitbucket, too.
You be back here tomorrow?
I can't leave.
I leave, somebody grab my stake.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Yo, Johnny.
Was' up, Bubs.
Shit, Johnny, man.
Just been chasin'
that pipe, you know.
Shit got me all diggin'
and scratchin' in my arms.
You know, it's cool.
Alright, come on, man,
you need a break. Alright?
I'm serious, you need a break.
Come on, man.
Naw, man, look around you.
Soldier's paradise, man.
I'm a viking, Bubs.
You a viking?
Fuck, not again.
You two coming?
Major said to get 'em down here
he didn't say shit
'bout playin' nursemaid
to a bunch of goddamn animals.
Watch your back, watch your back.
Watch your back.
Should we cuff 'em, sarge?
Naw, cut 'em loose.
The fuck we tell you about
fighting down here?
Only rule is no fighting,
no cutting, no shooting!
An' y'all still fuck it up.
Next time you make me come down here,
see if I don't call for a ten-thirty-eight.
So you know, dickhead,
that's an ambulance.
Break it up,
break it up, break it up.
Did I wake the baby?
You would know if you did.
It's 3:00 in the morning.
Nice of you to check in.
I went out after work to unwind.
Yeah, you look unwound.
Well...
I figured you had everything
under control on the homefront.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
What's with the sarcasm?
How come you can talk
to everybody else but me?
You really want to know?
I'm listening.
I miss us.
Do not blame that baby.
Do not do it.
I'm not blamin' anybody.
I didn't do this by myself.
We discussed it, all of it.
We talked about it, yeah.
But...
I didn't have as much
to say about it as you.
And why not?
Because you...
you wanted this.
I didn't want
to disappoint you on it.
I don't think I could be more
disappointed than I am right now.
You need to go.
Quiet overnight?
Midnight shift had to toss a crew
that was casing the place.
But other than that...
Too many damn children.
Whaddaya need lookouts and runners for
if the shit is legal?
A lot of them have been cut
loose by the dealers.
It's like one of those nature shows
where you mess
with the environment
some species gets
fucked out of their habitat.
Did you just use the word
habitat in a sentence?
I did.
You let your lookouts go?
My runners, too.
Shit, what's the point?
So here you are
making money hand over fist
and you're too damn greedy
to take care of your work force.
I don't need 'em.
But they need you, right?
You was all they had
when you couldn't work a corner
except for touts and runners
then it was cool to have them
cut school and work out.
Okay, new tax initiative,
my brother.
Say what?
If you wanna sling
in Hamsterdam after today
you an' every other knucklehead
you each gotta kick in a hunnert a week.
Oh, so you tryin' to get paid, huh.
Not me, not for me.
Get the cash up, I'll be back.
But it ain't something I'm gonna
go to jail for, right?
I mean, it ain't nothing
like that is it?
That one?
No, it was more black than silver.
This one, I think.
I can see y'all got some real
ugly shit planned for me.
I can see it.
You just bumped up against
a clever police is all.
Course he's gonna try
to shame you with the dead girl
or some mess about children lookin' up
to Omar an' his sawed-off.
All he can do
especially since you backed down
what he had for a witness.
He workin' you with guilt, boy.
Yeah, but that fat man gave me
an itch I can't scratch, Butchie.
Everybody in this world does
what they gonna do.
Me, you, that police.
Everybody in this world
got their own place.
An' a man in your line of work
start worryin' about how other
people see you
playin' the other people,
instead of to hisself, he gonna get dead.
I still feel like
I owe somethin', Butch.
I had an uncle down Carolina,
he dead now
but I remember he was
grieving real hard
real hard over chasin'
his lady friend away.
So he put himself to punishment.
Took a knife to his little finger
then his ring finger.
With them all bloody on
the table, he pulled up short.
For the rest of his life
I remember him sayin' the bitch
weren't worth more than a pinkie.
But it was too late then.
You can try that
if you have a mind.
I dunno, Butchie.
A little somethin' less dramatical.
Ya feel me?
You told Brianna she could go
downtown with this?
D'Angelo's her son,
how was I gonna stop her?
Look, look there's no harm done
if she just keeps
her mouth shut and just listens.
Naw, naw.
It's fucked up.
There ain't no call messin'
with Brianna with this bullshit.
What can you do?
I dunno.
File a kinda complaint against
the detective or some shit. I dunno.
Harassment?
This the same motherfucker
that had Avon's case.
Same motherfucker that's comin' at me
in my print shop talkin' shit.
An' now he's comin' up
at Brianna with this bullshit?
A complaint's
not going to do anything.
And the fact is
if the cops are saying
her son might not be a suicide
Brianna's gonna
hear this out regardless.
I suppose Avon
should know about it, though.
Yeah, well, I'll handle that.
Not much slinging going on here.
Western boys are sittin'
on the real estate.
Yeah... a-ight, a-ight.
That'll work, too.
A- ight.
Yo, Shamrock says we should
take some of our people down
to Hamsterdam and sell off there.
At least until these knockos
roll up off some of these corners.
C'mon.
Car stop, maybe?
Why not?
Not yet, you fuckin' rodent.
You all can't do this, man.
We headin' to Hamsterdam.
You come off that car again
an' you goin' to Bon Secours
emergency room. You hear me?
Yo, officer,
we got immunity from y'all.
We goin' to the free zone.
What the fuck's the free zone?
Ho shit.
Packaged for sale.
Hey, straight up.
Why you think we headed
there in the first place?
Headed where?
Hamsterdam.
Suck my dick!
Hey, y'all wanna see a wagon!
Fuck y'all!
You just shut the fuck up
and cut this shit out now!
Like you said.
That's your receipt.
Two-forty-four for
the hoop comes back to me
rounding to two
and a half for my gas money.
This repays me.
The rest of this?
Use it to pay
them hoppers for the week.
Whether you use 'em or not,
you pay this money out.
Shit is like
unemployment insurance.
Every employer got to pay in.
And if I find out anybody holding out
he's out of here and back on the street
gettin' his head busted.
Least y'all can do is look after
your own people a little bit.
What are you a fuckin' communist?
23 o' four. Need a couple of 10-16s,
to Fayette west of Vincent.
That's right around
the corner from here.
Ten-four, units responding.
The fuck happened?
Car stop.
I got a g-pack from beneath
the passenger seat.
Yo, we was on our way to Hamsterdam
an' the man say we don't get hassled
comin' in or goin' out.
Was' up?
What the fuck is Hamsterdam?
Lyin' ass poh-leece!
I can't let you do this.
Carv, they got a g-pack.
On the way to the free zone, they did.
You know the rules.
Yeah, man, and I was tryin'
to tell these people...
Shut the fuck up.
700 to any unit at the scene
at Fayette and Vincent.
Yeah, boss.
You got a situation there?
I can't believe this bullshit.
Yeah, bullshit is right.
I told you to shut the fuck up.
Yo, man, y'all gave your fuckin' word.
You know you did, man.
This is so fuckin' bullshit.
Y'all some fuckin' liar'y man.
Carv, will you please tell me
what the fuck is going on here?
Major said he's on his way.
Carv?
Oh, man.
Sure that's the one?
Reesie say that was the one.
Who am I to say different.
Tell him I ain't gonna pay
'til it proves itself though.
I told him that already.
He say 1500 for his trouble.
Damn.
Conscience do cost.
I seen him, Bernard.
You hadn't even gone past the damn door
and he threw all the papers in the trash.
You lyin' now, I can tell.
You is the only one
who gives a fuck.
An' if you hadn't been
the stupidest mothercker
that I ever gone out with,
you'd just would have bought
a whole bunchaf them
things at once.
Only need like six more.
We be done in, like, half an hour.
How 'bout we make one more
stop you get six of them shits
and I suck your dick
for the next 20 minutes.
Gotcha.
Fuck.
Fuck y'all.
Shit. I worked a double, man.
Bunk, line three.
Detective Moreland.
Heard you lookin' for something.
Lemme get some of them
Trac phones activated.
Eight of 'em bitches.
This one for sector two.
Sector one, I'm using the empty
low-rise housing on Winchester.
Sector three, the old Koppers plant.
And it's legal to sell here?
It's not legal.
We just look the other way is all.
How? How can you?
I know it hurts your heads
to think about it
but before you decide
to lose your minds on this
take a moment, ride around to my corners,
my worst drug corners.
Edmondson and Brice.
North and Pulaski. Hollins and Payson.
They're empty.
All of them.
District-wide, my crime
is down five percent.
But do the bosses know?
No, the bosses
don't know shit about it.
This is just a district commander,
taking an initiative on his own.
Jesus christ!
I knew it was only a matter
of time before I bumped into
somebody from downtown about this.
And I know your natural
impulse is to take what you saw
back downtown with you,
but I gotta ask you...
You legalized drugs?
Look, this is a tactical deployment.
We just wait for everything
to get settled down here
in these three zones
and then we move.
Look, we make a big show
of lockin' everybody up
and then we shut it down.
I'm sorry I had to
fuck you up on that arrest
and I'm sorry you had to see us
give that runt back the g-pack.
That was ugly, I know.
But I'm just tryin' to save
what's left of my district
anyway I can, if I can.
And the longer I have before
I have to brief the bosses
about this deployment...
We got all we needed
from the car stop, major.
Don't sweat it.
Let me get a word
with my old commander.
I dunno, Major.
Whenever you bust this place up,
they'll go back to their same corners.
Besides, you were never
much on making a big show.
If this doesn't work, Jimmy,
we're back to the usual
and I'm out the door
on a pension anyway.
But, Jimmy, I need more time.
I need to be able to rely on you
and your people to keep this close.
The bosses don't know, huh?
Fuck the bosses.
You the man who called?
I did.
You witnessin' or what?
I'm afraid I'm blind.
Legally.
Something you need to see though.
Glock 40, I believe.
I suppose you ain't going to tell me
who brought this here, right?
Like I say
I'm blind.
I thought you might know, though.
You tell him for me
I'm hopin' he might need
this in court some day.
Knockos might come back.
They might.
But until they do,
this your corner to hold.
What about Marlo's crew?
Look, Avon's home,
and you on a Barksdale corner.
Ya feel me?
Avon ain't here now.
You got muscle.
Don't worry about that, little man.
Hey...
the burner of young Bodie Broadus
it still has minutes left.
Speed dial?
Caroline.
You wouldn't have an extra room
at your place, would you?
Jus' for a night or two,
'til I can get my shit together.
Ain't no fixin' it?
It's fixed pretty good, I think.
Thanks.
Credit card was a business account
listed to a Theresa D'Agostino.
Yeah, that's her.
What kinda business?
Democratic Congressional
Campaign Committee.
Billing on the card goes
to a business address
in northwest Washington.
I called the switchboard
and she's listed.
D'Agostino doesn't sound much
like a west Baltimore name to me.
Me either.
Truth is, I don't know what I want.
I'm know I'm lookin' for somethin'
but I can't even
tell you what it is.
I understand you found work.
Ain't no payroll job, but it'll do.
You ain't here for a job.
Or the G.E.D. program.
So you lookin' to join the church?
I, um...
I just...
I've had this feelin'
for a long time
and it's like
I'm standing outside myself
watching me do things
I don't wanna do, you know?
Jus' seein' me like
I'm somebody else
but never ever bein' able
to stop the show.
I'm tired.
It's Cutty, right?
Naw, man.
Dennis.
She's left, huh?
I figured that because, ah,
I'm supposed to meet her actually.
Tonight, yeah...
right, exactly.
I was going to pick her up
and take her to that
but I'm running late...
Yeah, yeah, I know...
Where is that exactly?
I'm not really familiar
with that part of...
Too many damn scheduling
conflicts, unfortunately.
But we have put it
on the agenda for the next meeting
of the coordinating council
on criminal justice.
You're sentencing it to committee?
Mr. Mayor, we're probably only talking,
like, a few hundred thousand to start.
I'm not saying we should create
new identities for these people
and send 'em to New
Mexico like the feds.
We just need to get them
out of harm's way.
Lemme tell you something,
Councilman.
I can't lay my hands on several
hundred thousand dollars
that is not already spoken for.
- Mr. Mayor, I was not...
- What would you have me do, Councilman?
Should I divert the money
that's already been budgeted
for snow removal from
the first district this winter?
How 'bout I reduce trash pickup
to once a week citywide
put the witnesses up
at the Hyatt Inner Harbor?
I'm not trying to be difficult,
Tommy. Come on...
the city in the
financial situation it's in
very few friends in Annapolis
we've done all we can do
with this matter for now.
Okay, then.
Thanks for your time.
Gentlemen.
Nah, what the fuck.
I dunno, boss. If there weren't
so many fucking kids down here
I might be okay with it.
Baltimore police.
Baltimore?
Baltimore, Maryland.
Can I get a Jameson's?
Bushmills, okay?
That's protestant whiskey.
The price is right, ain't it?
Make it neat.
Excuse me.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I was just asking myself
the same thing.
You drive all the way
down here to look at me
from across the room and then leave?
That's kinda creepy.
You looked occupied.
Him?
Honey, that's just business.
This ain't my kind of crowd.
Definitely not.
Yeah, well, I made a mistake,
so I'm gonna go.
Four-twenty-eight.
You live in this town.
Why book the room?
I live across town.
As late as these things go,
that's a D.U.I. away.
Give me two hours, McNulty.
What am I gonna do for two hours?
Dream on it.
Water's fresh?
You keepin' them cool?
You got squeakers nestin' squabs.
Takin' care of the younguns,
I like seein' that.
Yeah, Marlo, he's real loyal.
You can't kick him off that nest.
Good work.
That's really good work.
Police comin' off them corners.
I seen.
I'm gonna keep my name off
the package for a time
keep wholesalin'.
You know, step back a bit.
Barksdale gonna think we weak
not comin' out
to claim what's ours.
The police leave them corners,
he's gonna be back out there.
I know he will.
Your turn, girl.
It's a bout time.
For real.
For starters
its memory holds the last 10 calls
made and received by the user.
That's enough
to give us a signature.
Signature?
The phone numbers
unique to an individual.
That way we can identify the user
when he switches to another phone.
Sorry, I'm late.
Woke up in the wrong town.
Anyway, we ran the tolls
on those numbers
and we came up with
a rather interesting pattern.
Check this out.
This is the pattern of a clod
communication network.
Something you would expect
from a drug organization.
This particular one so far
involves 15 distinct burners.
15.
And none of them list
subscriber information.
You can do that?
With these burners,
with this particular company
you don't need
subscriber information.
Our data shows that over 92% of the calls
are made within this network
with the average call
lasting less than a minute.
Again, suggestive
of drug trafficking.
This user here,
he serves as a clearing house.
He receives calls,
and initiates interactions.
He coordinates the show.
Be nice if that was Stringer.
Now this is the best part,
this is something that Prez discovered
when he was playing with it.
It has a speed dial feature.
Meaning, someone took
the time to program the phone.
Hell, that's probably
the only way these corner boys
can remember all the numbers
what with these phones being
dumped every few days or so.
I'll bet all the other phones
in the network are set up the same way.
Well I've heard enough.
We should start writing for the wire.
When can we get up?
Get up on what?
They're dumping phones
every couple weeks on average.
By the time you get a wire up
on that, the phones are dead.
The whole network
shuts down simultaneously.
Do we have a plan?
Not yet we don't.
But for now, if I could get a couple more
of these dead phones
it'll probably help corroborate
the theory for the affidavit.
Kima, maybe you could ask
those western boys to pick up
what they find on the ground
for the next few days.
Yeah, sure.
Damn boy, you smell like sex.
You didn't take a fucking shower?
Late for work.
You forgot my Newports,
didn't you?
Aw shit, man. I did, yo.
Lemme do up these chips
an' then I'll go get your cigs.
Fuck.
Three one, shooting
at the number one Mayo.
We're gonna need
some suits down here.
For investigation? I'm on my way.
Roger, 10 hundred.
Back so soon.
I thought you guys had enough
of our happy district yesterday.
Just need a favor.
Lester wants you to scoop up
any discarded cell phones
you find on Barksdale corners.
You want Barksdale license plates.
- Tag numbers and all?
- Whatever, sure.
'Cause I saw the big man
riding in a truck the other day.
Missed the tag,
but if I see him again...
Stringer?
- Naw, the other guy.
- What other guy?
Big boy, the one we locked up.
- Avon.
- Avon Barksdale?
Jesus, Herc. He's at Jessup,
down for four or five at least.
What, we all look alike to you?
If you don't believe me fuck it.
No fuckin' way...
but the fact remains
we would not be returning
this service weapon to this officer
without help from the citizens
of Baltimore as well.
And on that note, I think our Mayor
would like to say a few words.
Thank you, Commissioner Burrell.
I just want to take this opportunity
to commend our department
on successfully resolving this case
and to wish officer Dozerman
a speedy return to duty.
Officer Dozerman
the citizens want you
to have this back
and to thank you for your
service in defense of our city.
and I especially want to thank all
of our concerned residents
who called into the hotline.
We would not be here today...
Lester.
Lieutenant, you gotta see this.
Big joke.
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
Transcript par Raceman
Synchronisation: El Uploador
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net