But it's a snail, you see,
and it go--
it go, "meow."
It's a what? What?
It meows.
Then it ooze all up
right up to his belly--
Like it's his pet and shit.
Yo, y'all niggers
watch too many cartoons. I swear.
See, this is what's wrong
with the justice system right here.
Niggers get locked up,
and they don't stay that way.
They make it hard
to take this shit serious.
- What? You snitchin' or something?
- Shit. No, man.
You know they only gave me,
like, 4, right?
Know what I'm saying,
I done 15 months.
So, in good time, I'm like,
"man, what the fuck?"
Shit.
Yeah, man.
So...
It ain't like it was,
but it'll do.
So, who we slinging for?
Marlo Stanfield.
- Come on, come on!
- Yo, man. Yeah.
I was getting this nice
package from Slim Charles, but...
Marlo got the muscle
to hold us down,
so that's where we at.
Shit.
One boss same as the next, man.
Make sure they
ain't slick, all right.
Hey, yo, little Kev,
I told you about
the boy Poot, right?
Pussy hound.
You just home?
- How long in?
- 15 months.
- You got laid yet?
- Shit. I think I already been burnt.
Shit. I might need a ride
to the clinic today.
I see ain't shit changed
around this joint.
On the wall, gents.
Make this easy on all of us.
Which one of you's
is little Kevin?
Come on, fellows.
It ain't no big deal.
We just need some face time
with the motherfucker.
Your name Kevin?
No. This is, uh...
Poot.
- I'm Poot, yo.
- Poot. Right.
Didn't you get locked up
or shot or something?
Society say
I deserve another chance.
Yeah. Let's see. Which one
of these dickheads is Little Kevin?
- Man, I don't know no Kevin.
- Society can bite my dick.
Come on, Bodie.
I know this kid works with you.
- Your name?
- Do I look little to you?
All right. Fuck this. Everyone
under 150 pounds or 5'6" is in the cab.
You, you, and you.
Unless I see birth certificates saying
otherwise, you're my little Kevins.
And if that don't get it,
we're coming the fuck back.
All right?
That's fucked up, yo.
You got any paper on you?
Man, fuck if I know.
These police out here knew how
to flip it even just a little,
my shit would be in handcuffs.
You know?
They don't know shit.
Damn!
4x09 Know Your Place
You my ride?
I'm your motherfucking savior,
is what I am.
Told y'all Andre was lying on me, yo.
I didn't do it for you.
Fact is...
if I could work back on
whatever cases I already caught,
you might be going
right back inside.
I know.
So who did kill that delivery girl?
I don't know.
Know it wasn't Andre.
His blood don't run
that kind of cold.
Who he getting his package from?
Saying I could go back
to the crib and bear up,
find some things for you
if you want me to.
- You owe me, motherfucker.
- I'm saying I know I do, man.
If you want to pay down this debt,
you know what you
gotta do for me?
No more bodies.
No more fucking
bodies from you.
No more comebacks
or get-evens on this.
No more killing.
You owe me your word.
All right, man.
No bodies on me.
Really want to ease my mind,
you'll let me drive you down
to Aberdeen rail station,
put you on a northbound train.
Naw, man.
Baltimore's all I know.
You know what it is like, homey.
Man gotta live what he know, right?
You're absolutely right. There are
many significant factors to consider,
but getting crime under control
is key to sparking investment here,
- jumpstarting growth.
- If you make it safe, they will come.
I hate to begin our beautiful
relationship with my hand out,
but I'm told that two federal grants
to my office dry up this year.
That's right.
Come the first of the year,
those D.O.J. Grants evaporate,
and you're out 12 prosecutors.
I was hoping you'd be able
to absorb that in the general fund,
maybe even throw in a little bit more,
make it competitive with the P.D.
and attorney general's jobs--
Starts the turnover.
It's killing us.
This would be the time to do it.
I mean, we're over the revenue
expected for this point
in the fiscal year
next to the real estate market.
How much past?
'Cause I want to come out of the box
with a big bump in police salaries, in
particular, the commissioner's salary,
which needs to jump, like, 50 grand.
A good guess would be a one-shot surplus
of about 20 million.
But that's rainy-day money
for more than crime.
Around north avenue,
the schools are running a deficit.
Excuse me. Did you say
a 50,000 bump for Ervin Burrell?
Well, no, not for Burrell per se.
For the next police commissioner, then.
- That's what you mean?
- Looking ahead makes sense.
Because firing him would
upset a good-size block
of my constituency, not
to mention the ministers.
And the budget chair
might have a difficult time
allowing a higher salary
to be approved.
In fact, I can guarantee
if that proposal's in the budget--
your first, for the record--
the Bill won't come out
of committee intact.
I'm just saying that in the event
commissioner Burrell were to leave
we'd want to bump that salary
In order to attract the best candidates;
in particular, the best African-American
candidates from across the nation.
With 3 years left in his term,
why would he leave?
Councilman, what may not have
been obvious to you
on the public safety subcommittee
is that the budget process is
a carefully-Orchestrated ballet,
a cooperative effort between
the branches of government.
Well, Madam President,
the nuances of that cooperative effort
are beginning to come into focus for me.
Thank you, Madam President.
Come on in, everyone.
Don't wait by the door.
Duquan, you're here.
Randy, you're here.
No. You two switch.
Calvin, you're here
in the front.
Quenice, you're here.
Mike, you're here.
Destiny, here.
Myesha, here.
Dashonda, here.
Come on. Keep moving.
Don't stop at the door. Come in.
Let's get started.
Mike could be a problem.
How so?
Your boy been assigned to
what they called a major crimes unit.
Meaning what?
They the motherfuckers
that did the last 3 city wiretaps--
One where they bugged
Barksdale's office,
another where they hit
Kentel up in Park Heights.
And the last one-- Shit.
They was all up on
Stringer Bell's cellphone.
You ain't still using
burners, is you?
I'm dumping them every two weeks.
Not good enough.
You read that.
You'll see the Stringer
was changing his number every damn day,
and they still pulled
the motherfucker's voice
off a goddamn cellphone tower.
City police did that?
Where'd you get this?
Courthouse,
clerk's office.
Hey, the shit's open to the public
after they finish prosecuting your ass.
You need to lose
them cellphones, son.
Me-- I ain't as so much
as touched a burner in a year.
5'9" and 3/8?
You got it.
Now, hold the measure
and spread your arms out to the side.
What you got?
I want one.
So, your cat can eat 'em?
Oh, how'd you find them?
I went to the calculators.
Give me that.
Give it here.
The same.
Your height and your arm span--
Identical.
Quenice?
See, look.
You about to get me in trouble.
So, you say you like to box, right?
You must have some kind of reach.
Everything cheap on computers
if you know where to look for it.
Yo, this mean the price
I'm getting from the Koreans.
Yo, they still
marking it up some.
They gotta be.
I can make twice
as much using this here.
Can't.
All this along the lower Patapsco,
Westport area
is ready for a turn.
The proximity to downtown
and the B.W. parkway
make it ideal for Washington commuters.
That's a given.
Anything to speed it up?
A harbor promenade could work
going west from both sides
of the bridge.
The south harbor promenade
brought to you by--
Mayor Thomas Carcetti--
And the citizens of Baltimore.
Doesn't quite have the same ring
as a stadium or an aquarium
expansion, does it?
- It's a start.
- Further east,
you've got the locust point
marine terminal,
which, unfortunately,
is still a working enterprise,
and the further you go
into Brooklyn Curtis bay,
the more the skyline disappears.
We lose the Washington crowd.
For that waterfront,
you're gonna need a different draw.
- Casinos?
- Oh, the urban planning default?
I don't want the kind of crime
that comes with casinos.
Tax base is tax base.
This is where I get off the boat.
It's one thing to sell
waterfront for tax base,
but now you're just sucking
paychecks out of my community.
Well, it was just a thought.
And, anyway,
we're getting ahead of ourselves.
This is just the first
long meeting of many.
So, thanks to everyone,
and we'll continue this later.
Madam President,
a word with you?
Do you have a minute?
You and me got
a problem already.
Just trying to help,
guide you through the process,
Mr. Mayor-Elect.
Felt more like you were dragging me
across a minefield, Narice.
- Why you so pissed off at me?
- Look.
Clarence shouldn't have run again
for any number of reasons.
I was ready to step up,
and the deal was cut long ago
that he'd back me when the time came.
You and Tony--
You guys jumped the line.
It wasn't your turn.
First of all, I'm sorry if Tony
and I ruined your party plans,
but I wasn't privy to whatever
you and Clarence cooked up.
That aside I was...
kind of looking forward
to working closely together.
I think that we could
make things happen.
You're only getting
the one term, Tommy.
I'm not gonna stand down next time.
What makes you think
I'll even be around that long?
Governor's race is in two years,
and plans can change.
You find yourself mayor in 2008
without so much as a campaign speech.
Wasn't easy to track you down.
None of the numbers I got
for you don't work no more.
I see you got a problem.
Looking rough, Bubs.
I been keeping it clean, you know...
pushing my carts and all.
But this one young man--
every time I cross him,
I get tossed
for what I got on me.
Cash, pills.
I mean, he look on me like
an ATM or some shit. I swear.
I'm ready to work, Kima.
Get this motherfucker off me,
I'll do what you need.
Look at me, Bubs.
I ain't a narco.
Yeah, I see.
You look nice.
I'm working homicides.
So, if the bad boy happen to kill me,
you can help me out then, right?
If we drive around a bit, you think
you can put eyes on this motherfucker?
I can try.
So, Narice is bucking already.
Feels like if the mayor's chair
ain't gonna go to Royce,
it should be hers.
Problem is she's gonna see any proposal
to raise the commissioner's salary
as a move against Burrell.
Which it is.
We can't raise the salary, we can't
attract strong minority candidates.
No strong candidates, we can't get rid
of the guy we got.
Fuck if I'm gonna live with
Burrell as my commissioner.
What if he quits?
- Quits?
- Maybe the man can be shamed.
If he leaves on his own account,
that takes us off the hook
with Narice and the ministers.
Right?
No. I mean, we don't want
your credit card number.
I mean, we won't
even know the number.
We just need you
to order the candy.
And you have cash up front?
He pay you back, Mr. P,
when he sell off, man.
He gonna pay you back.
Points on the package, huh?
- No way.
- Aw, come on, Mr. Pryzbo.
I mean, doesn't it teach us
math, addition, subtraction,
a quarter, a 1/4 of a dollar,
a dime, 1/10, you know?
No cash, no card.
All right. Fine.
Cash up front.
No problem.
And if you come in
with a wad of bills tomorrow, Randy,
I want to know where they came from.
I don't want either
of you out on the corner.
All right.
Ms. Decent, you OK?
I, uh...
I think my car's been stolen.
Yeah, man. All right.
So, what I'm saying
is that you got from
Bentlow down there
to Rosewood right here.
All right?
Now, I got the block from Monroe
all the way down to Pacer,
so you're covered that side, but
you gotta put lookouts in Franklintown
to catch anybody coming
from the other way.
- All right, I got you.
- Are you ready to work?
Yeah, just my read up
and go on about the shit for real.
No, are you ready to work?
Ready to work.
- Hey, Donut, go talk to little Kevin.
- All right.
Hey, yo, look.
Man, please do not be having
your mama come talk for you.
Man, I ain't have her do nothing.
She just get on her horse
and come with it.
Look. I done did everything
I can for you and yours,
but from here on, your moms
can't do nothing to help.
All right?
Him?
From Wee-Bey?
Your mom's?
No sign of the motherfucker Andre.
Store been padlocked a week.
Ain't even calling for his re-up.
Check the man at the jail?
People say Omar ain't even been
on the tier for two weeks,
so he either staying someplace
or they got him at county lockup.
Or the charges been dropped.
If this cocksucker's sprung,
my man is backing up on his story.
Mean he could back up on y'all.
I'm on it.
How about the New York boys?
We dropped 5 of them.
Pushed them into the ground.
Drive through east Baltimore,
you don't even see a Baltimore
nigger with a Yankee cap.
Want us to stay on that, too?
I talked to the fat man,
but I think we're done there.
This shit with Andre...
job one.
No. We could try the avenue again.
Keep an eye on the market sometimes.
Look, Bubs, I ain't
got all fucking day.
I'm on shift work now.
I'm working murders.
He banked me 4 times this week, Kima.
I'm having dreams about
this low-bottom motherfucker.
All right.
I tell you what.
You want to work?
I'll call Sydnor or Herc
down at major crimes,
put you with someone
doing drug work.
You work for them,
they'll help you with your problem.
- All right?
- I need this now, Kima.
I'll tell them that.
Woman--
So, show me where you're living,
and I'll tell them where
they can find you.
Make the left.
I don't understand.
You told the man
you not gonna kill no one.
I gave my word on that.
Fuck we doing
back here then, papa?
I can still put a gun
in Andre's face, right?
That man got some explaining to do.
It's dead out here, yo.
Tip on out.
I don't know why he don't
trust us with it, yo.
I mean, we trustworthy, ain't we?
Just gotta get enough
for the first order.
Then we're good.
...I get my money?
All right!
Hard 6!
Come on, treys!
I'm in.
Go away, boy.
- Oh, you in?
- Yeah.
Pass line for me, yo.
Oh, shit!
Yeah. Get that money.
Get that money, shorty.
Get that money.
I heard tell of it,
but I didn't believe it.
All this overtime,
all for two cases as a secondary.
First names are red,
then they're green,
then they're black.
And that doesn't even include the court
pay you make if the soft
case goes to trial.
- Sweet.
- So,
what you gonna do with yours,
detective Greggs, huh?
Pay down some debt.
Why you leaving?
Your luck ain't gonna change.
Don't worry about that now.
Yo, thanks for walking us off.
I thought we was gonna get banked.
You ain't gonna bank us, is you?
Shit, boy.
You think I'm that ungrateful?
I followed you
through 10 shooters
and made more money
that I have in a month.
Nah. I ain't gonna rob you.
I just need to know next
time you fade a dice game.
You feel?
I mean, it's all about the math,
you know, the probabilities and all.
I ain't never seen
you in a game before.
Where you learn your game?
Edward Tillman Middle.
Shit.
All we got is Little Kevin.
Oh, Bodie's boy, huh?
What'd I tell you?
Bubs gets it the first time.
What are you doing?
Y'all meet up with me
in the afternoon tomorrow--
after school lets out--
and I'll give Kevin a new hat.
A hat trick?
Cool.
- Yo, Herc, man?
- What's up?
It's not about the money this time.
He breaking me every day
unless I give him something.
I can't-- I can't
take it anymore, man.
Once we're done with Kevin,
you go find this asshole.
Hit my cellphone.
I'll be on him 5 minutes later.
I promise.
Then you this, yo,
and watch it fizzle.
Not so much.
You gonna make it spill
everywhere, you see?
What are you still doing here?
Ain't nobody want you here.
Your mama want me.
You and the pipe.
Shouldn't talk
about your mama like that.
Hey, daddy, see my volcano?
Bug, go upstairs.
Bug need me, too.
Saturday, right?
- Bug need me.
- My teachers say I gotta need glasses.
I gotta have an adult with me.
Pick 'em up.
Sign for 'em.
Bug, go upstairs to your room.
Ice cold, boy.
Where you be?
Ain't got a forgiveness to your soul.
Man, fuck you.
Watch your mouth.
You're big,
but not big enough.
Now...
where's that D.S.S. Card?
Your mama said that come to me.
Ain't nothing left
on this month's check anyway.
Before the first of the month, then.
Hey.
Uh, come on in.
I see the little man
done took over the living room.
Good for him.
You know how it goes.
Well, I'm just messing with you.
Place looks great.
Even the toys look
like they belong.
B.
This is...
this month
and two going back.
I'm just trying to catch up.
I appreciate you not
coming after me for it.
Knocking over liquor stores now?
Overtime from homicide.
It stays like this, and I won't have
problem coming up with my share.
Kima, this ain't--
Please take me back.
But a deal's a deal.
Right?
Hey, I'm home.
Hey, Elijah.
Hey.
Kima, this is Nancy Owens.
Sorry.
The place is a mess.
You could stay for dinner,
but tonight we have
people coming over.
It's a kind of
a celebration actually.
I passed the bar this week.
Congratulations.
Most of the guys I work
with have a problem with that.
- With what?
- Passing the bar.
Well, guess I better be going.
Thanks for coming past.
- Let's make bed...
- yeah.
Nice meeting you.
Elijah?
Say bye to aunt Kima.
Bye.
- Where's Dre?
- I don't know!
- You believe her?
- No.
One last time.
Where's Andre?
He said if he told me
where he was going,
I'd have to tell you, too.
I don't know.
- I don't know.
- You believe her now?
Dang.
Sure is quiet this early.
Yo, you gonna come
with me to see Mr. P?
No. Go on up.
I'll sit in home room.
All right.
Mr. P.
Randy.
- Randy, how did you--
- 6 beats 4 or 5.
And most times 8 is better than 10.
Right?
You schooled me good.
- You gambled for this?
- I ain't even pick up the dice.
I was all pass, no pass.
Got to the point where some of them
was following me in there.
You shouldn't gamble.
I know, but I'm just saying.
The math be right, Mr. P.,
I'm gonna come back at lunch,
and we can computer up that candy.
All right?
Peace.
Resign?
Either that or the day-to-day
running of the department
falls to the deputy commissioner
for operations.
Erv, I have made no secret
of wanting to make changes.
Oh, so Bill Rawls is now
the voice of reform, is he?
This isn't about Rawls.
I have no faith in you,
given recent events.
And I know you remember the two
of us sitting in this same booth
a year ago, you telling me about
how you respect the chain of command.
Well, respect it now.
Every department head serves
at the pleasure of the mayor.
So, if you're firing me,
Mr. Mayor,
I want you to know
I will go quietly.
You'll tender your
letter of resignation?
Oh, no.
I'm not offering to resign.
If you want me to go,
you're gonna have to shit-can me.
A small distinction,
I know, but...
in the meantime,
since you have Bill Rawls
doing my job for me
and it's such a nice day out,
I think I'll go
to forest park and shoot 9.
Check is yours, I think.
Pick a table, any table.
Eiffel tower, Big Ben,
empire state building.
Your table is your team.
The team that puts its
model together first wins.
You say y'all can work
together out on the corner.
Let's see how you do on this.
- With what?
- Big fat Gold stars and shit.
A dinner downtown.
Any restaurant you can agree on.
Since y'all only seem willing to be
interested in stuff you know,
we look for things
more like Baltimore.
The scale model
of the Fayette street stash house
was all sold out.
So,
y'all just gonna have to make do.
Mr. Colvin, The box say there's supposed
to be some instructions.
We took those out.
Makes it more interesting,
don't you think?
It ain't like we follow
instructions anywhere else, Right?
And I ain't gonna put
no charges on no one.
But see, they made me do that,
and now they're gonna be mad
at me 'cause it ain't stick.
Who be they?
People I'm getting the package from.
I'm asking "who?"
Boy named Marlo.
He's big on the west side.
You heard of him?
Vaguely recall the name.
So, I just need to chill for a while
till they remember how to forget.
So, now you come over east side
and expect me to hide you.
Why is it that every
Baltimore nigger think
that running the fuck away
means crossing downtown?
Shit. You ought to be in New York
or Philly or some shit.
No. See, I know that.
It's just that I don't know
no one outside of B-more,
and I was just hoping, let's say,
trade out my store,
you could maybe, you know,
front me some cash, get me out of town
with people you know.
I mean, I come to the east side to you,
but to me, west-side motherfuckers
are with Marlo.
You know what the problem
with these here machines?
They too cheap to begin with.
Some people would think
for what it's worth to fix it
and make the shit work right,
you might as well dump
them and get another.
2,000 and a free ride north
for the store and its contents.
Store worth way more, Joe.
It depends, don't it?
No, it's goes
on the other side and shit.
Stop fucking fronting me.
I want to do something.
You curse at me again,
I'm gonna cut you.
Get that shit out my face.
I don't even want
to do this shit no more.
That's how you always do it.
What are you doing?
Look at the box.
- Do that look like that's on the box?
- I can't do this.
Nigger, come on, now.
I'm trying to eat.
- Hey, give me that piece, yo.
- Fuck you, yo,
you don't even know what you're doing.
Just sit there and shut up
because you just don't know.
Come over here
and make me shut up, then.
You starting to piss me off,
you don't know what you're doing.
You're too stupid.
Hey, Z, you do the top
while I do the middle.
Darnell, you got the leg parts.
All right?
Then you get it.
Like that. Like that.
Shit!
Done.
Aw, that's bullshit.
Man, you cheat.
Go ahead and touch it, baby.
That shit built to last.
What about the extra pieces?
What extra pieces?
What's in your pocket?
Ain't nothing in my pocket.
So, who cook a good
steak around here?
I got a t-Bone right here.
- Check his ass out.
- I ain't even gonna...
One,
from the day of my inauguration,
Commissioner Burrell is to undertake no
initiative without clearing it with you.
Day-to-day administrative
responsibilities
are to reside with the deputy office
if they don't already.
I like that. No problem.
- Two, I need to elevate Stan Valchek.
- Good man Valchek.
He's a hack,
but he's my hack, and I owe him.
if I make him deputy for adman,
can he cause any real damage?
I'll watch over him.
No problem.
3, I'm bumping Daniels
from western command to Colonel,
Giving him C.I.D. and carte blanche
to fix the investigative units.
- Cedric Daniels?
- Problem?
No, he's good police.
He's just got...
a little independent streak.
Independent from who?
I got no problem making Daniels.
- What else do you need?
- That's it for now.
Mr. Mayor, about Ervin.
If you don't mind my asking,
why keep him as a puppet commissioner
when you can just fire the guy?
We mind you asking.
I'm partial to them cherries.
Yo, Dukie.
You ever called social
services on your mother?
What?
I don't know.
I just want to know what happens
if you call social
services on somebody.
You want to report your mother?
She brung someone home,
and he won't leave.
You don't want to call social services.
They get to looking
at your things,
they gonna put you in a group home,
split you and bug up even.
But I don't want us to leave.
I just want him to leave.
Talking about bug's daddy, ain't you?
Maybe I ought to talk
to a teacher about this.
Mr. Pryzbo is real good about stuff.
Mr. P. Did say I could go talk
to the school social worker.
Mr. Rotten neck?
He an alcoholic.
What about that boxing guy?
Mr. Cutty?
What's wrong with Cutty?
I don't know.
Like, he just
too friendly, you know.
That shit creep me out, man.
Like, he some type
of faggot or something.
Nah, not Cutty, man.
He be all up in the women.
Yo, don't you see how he be doing?
That don't mean shit.
Them faggots
will be just like that, too.
And I don't know.
He just too friendly, you know.
Everybody just too
motherfucking friendly.
Je ne sais quoi right there.
That's my man Poot.
That's his style. Look at that!
He goes right to the dark.
Now, see, this is more me.
It's more me.
Spin around, punch it.
They're fucking me.
So, his name is--
What'd you call him?
Looks like a joke.
Yeah. They flip 'em.
A bunch of fucking clowns.
Last year we had M.S.A.S
in the 22 percentile.
And don't think they
haven't noticed it
down at the puzzle palace.
The word is they're looking
for at least a 10-Point increase
from all city middle
schools this time around.
We're still 6 weeks away
from the M.S.A.S
and you want us to start
teaching the test now?
This year, the preferred term
is curriculum alignment.
There's nothing wrong
with emphasizing the skills
necessary for the M.S.A.
If we can get them
to write a paragraph
without a 4-letter word in it,
it'll have to have better
command of English.
Marcia,
skill sets are one thing,
but this has us teaching
test questions direct.
Test questions that involve skills.
- I don't see your point.
- You don't want to see it.
Were you really expecting
something different than last year?
I don't see the math section.
These are all language-arts questions.
Our greatest failing
on standardized tests last year.
So, for the time being,
all teachers will
devote class time
to teaching language-arts
sample questions.
Now, if you turn to page 11, please,
I have some things
I want to go over with you.
I don't get it.
All this so we score
higher on the state tests?
If we're teaching the kids
the test questions,
what is it assessing in them?
Nothing.
It assesses us.
The test scores go up,
They can say the schools are improving.
The scores stay down,
they can't.
Juking the stats.
Excuse me?
Making robberies into larcenies.
Making rapes disappear.
You juke the stats,
and Majors become Colonels.
I've been here before.
Wherever you go,
there you are.
Raven's got that dude Mike Anderson.
He and Jamal gonna be running...
Look at these runts.
We're gonna go when that
football's in the air on a long pass.
- Slow?
- Yeah.
Big yellow right here.
Yellows, yellows!
Go long. Go. Go.
Throw it high.
Big yellow.
Go.
- Narco!
- Oh, shit.
Po-Po, yo! Po-Po!
- Where you going?
- Put me down!
They're in the alleys.
We get back in there,
we can hunt them up.
No need.
I know 'em all.
- Let me go motherfucker.
- What about this one?
He isn't even bait.
We toss him back--
unless we want to spend half the shift
down at baby booking.
- Me?
- I ain't afraid, motherfucker.
I don't want to spend the
shift on evidence control.
Then why the fuck even do this?
So's I can talk to them.
I like to think that until
the handcuffs actually fit,
there's still talking to be done.
Come here, man.
Let's take a walk.
You shut the fuck up.
Yo, who you listening to?
Miss lady day.
Billie Holliday.
Yeah, she sounds good.
You know, real sad, kind of.
Yeah. I'm like that.
You be thinking I'm all ghetto,
and then I flip it
and mess your mind all up.
The next time we do this, Mr. Colvin,
could you please
make it on the weekend?
I only had, like, 3 hours
between school
and now to get ready.
You look fine, Zenolia.
I could look better.
How long you think it take
to do hair like this?
I'm ordering the biggest
quarter pounder.
- Fries, too.
- Nigger, this ain't Mickey D's.
You better be thinking
t-bone steak medium rare.
The blood all squirting out?
Nah, ain't no blood.
What you think rare is?
It mean rarely cooked, hardly cooked.
Rare.
Get the blood out, stupid.
- See?
- And medium rare, keep the blood in.
All right. Look.
All I want to know which is which
before I order some undone meat.
Hey, Mr. Colvin.
How it work?
Look, we're just gonna ask the waiter.
All right.
Oh, shit. There's a waiter?
Just right down the block.
- Where she at, dawg?
- Ain't seen her.
She owe me.
All that shit I gave her.
How you not know?
I don't know.
She let me find her,
I'm gonna cut her titty off. Watch.
You got something
to say, nigger?
Yo, where Herc at?
I got the asshole, OK.
Tell him Riggs and Calhoun.
He knows. He knows.
Get the fuck back here.
Nigger, I will fuck you up.
You don't know Lex?
I knew the bull.
I mean, I know him.
But he ain't been around though.
You see? Right there.
You just fucked up.
You said you knew him
like you knew he was dead.
No. Now you putting
words in my mouth.
I meant knew him.
When he was around,
I knew him, but he left.
Herc.
Bubbles called.
He sees the guy-- the asshole.
He's on Riggs and Calhoun.
Says he'll hold him there
5 minutes for you to get across town.
I'm in the middle
of an interview here.
What the fuck?
Tell him we'll fix
his problem tomorrow.
All right?
Oh, motherfucker.
He ain't got a phone.
You lied to me out on the street.
Why should I believe you now?
You was there
when Lex got killed.
You part of the fucking setup.
We know 'cause we have a witness
who put you right in there.
Yeah, we do.
You know right
where that body is.
You were there with Snoop,
Chris, whoever else.
Know how to make
an interrogation work?
Leverage.
You don't have leverage?
Motherfucker,
you don't even got a body.
Lex is nothing but a name in there.
Where the fuck
you think you're going?
Home depot here!
What you got for me tonight?
I've been listening
all day long, Dawg.
No. We done with this right here.
Say what? Don't play, man.
I ain't got time for your shit.
My shit's all you're gonna get.
You can kiss my ass all
the fucking trouble you give me.
What you looking for?
It's not there. It's on me, all right.
- It's on you?
- Yeah.
- It's on you?!
- Wait, wait!
Get off me! Get off me!
Hey, wait, wait!
You take him! Take him!
- I got you now!
- No, no!
Like that?!
Fucker!
Easy!
I don't like the orange ones.
Listen to me, fuckhead.
We know you were there.
We know you set him up,
and we know you didn't do it alone.
Say what?
You weren't alone in this.
We know that.
You mean Randy?
I'm asking you questions, remember?
If you don't give us
this murder, Kevin,
somebody else will,
and when they do,
they'll be putting you in.
You hear me?
Colvin, party of 4.
I'll make sure your table's ready.
Colvin, party of 4, huh?
Hi. May I take your coat?
Sure.
You, sir?
Oh, no.
I'm good.
Yeah. Me, too.
OK. Your table's ready.
Follow me, please.
Sir?
That's your chair, right?
No.
You sit there.
The waitress will be here soon
to detail the specials of the day.
- Enjoy.
- Thank you.
Waitress?
Who was that?
That's the, uh, hostess.
Hey, you ain't gotta worry, Mr. C.
I ain't gonna run up your Bill.
I'll just get whatever's on special.
It ain't no k-mart
blue-light special, dumb-ass.
Special just mean
they cook something different.
Yo, what about you,
drinking without a straw,
all ghetto and shit?
You don't drink water with a straw.
And put that on your lap, fool.
You see anybody else up in here
looking all Fred Flintstone and shit?
Shut it down.
Other people be looking at us.
Hello. My name is Ann.
I'd like to tell you about
our specials for the day.
We have king salmon
with sweet corn,
chanterelles, and basil ravioli;
sauted free-range chicken
served with mashed potatoes;
fresh Chesapeake bay blue crab,
roasted garlic, shallot cream,
and hen of the woods mushrooms;
and wood oven-roasted quail
with grilled sapling bread salad.
Dang, I thought y'all had steak.
Oh, we do...
on the second page of your menus.
May I get your drink orders?
We'll take 4 cokes, please.
- Right away.
- Thank you.
Do you mind
if I come tomorrow?
Mind?
I--
You wouldn't be embarrassed?
No, not at all.
I mean...
I'll be proud of you there.
It's funny how it works out.
All those years I'm trying
to climb the ladder,
kissing ass, covering ass,
doing what I'm told.
I finally let some of it out,
tell him what I really think,
and I'm going from
Lieutenant to Colonel
in a little more than a year.
And, you, you're worried sick
about those subpoenas
and worried that Lester
is killing me as a boss.
But the subpoenas
get me promoted.
I know.
You know, Marlo once said to me,
"You cannot lose if you do not play,"
but here we are, right?
Maybe it's changing.
What is?
The city,
the way things work or don't.
Maybe we're turning a corner here
that's not gonna be so
unbelievably fucked up anymore.
To Carcetti.
And us.
Zenolia,
want to take a picture of restaurant?
That's OK. It's late.
No. That's fine.
Come on. Give me the camera.
I'm OK.
Come on, give me the camera.
OK.
Don't want to be in the picture, right?
Yo, Mr. C,
can we stop at McDonald's?
Fuck wrong with you, boy?
Food wasn't right.
Don't like fish.
Why'd you order it, then?
Yo, shut the fuck up.
- Turn it down, Namond.
- What?
Turn it down, Namond.
Turn it up?
All right, you got it.
Seriously, can we get
some fries at least?
Boy, you is pathetic.
Just 'cause you a girl do not mean
I'm gonna fuck you all up.
You hear me?
Nigger, please.
- You keep talking all of that shit.
- No, you keep talking all that shit.
- Must have forgot.
- No, I ain't forget shit.
- What I forget anyway?
- That I'm the man.
So,
what's the first thing we do
when we respond to a prompt?
Randy?
According to the text?
According to the text.
That's good.
And how do we end the answer?
Quenice?
Come on.
I know you know this.
The above stated facts
have led me to conclude that.
Right?
OK. So, let's try to read
the third paragraph.
I'll start it.
Pythias makes a final plea
to the tyrant Dionysius
to return to his home one last--
Calvin, pick it up.
To return to his home one last time
before his punishment.
He denies the request
until Damon inter...
intercedes.
And offers his own life
until Pythias returns.
Good.
Who wants to guess
what "intercedes" means?
What about "plea"?
OK.
What about the story, then?
How would you summarize it?
Duquan, give it a shot.
According to the text.
Everybody's safe in the end, right?
Let's think this through.
According to the text,
Damon offers his own life
on behalf of Pythias
so that he can return home
one last time.
The above-stated facts
have led me to conclude
that Damon values Pythias'
friendship and loyalty.
Any questions?
We got 4 of them raw.
275 large right there.
For 4, it should be 3.
I'm charging 5 a head
on them new York boys--
that about the going rate.
Still want us on that?
Nah.
Seems like they got the message
and went the fuck on.
True that.
Delroy has all of the money
and street corners back.
All right, then.
Holler at us for
the next package in.
You remember when I told
you about the co-op meant
we all stand together,
doing for each other when we can?
You remember that?
Well, the price of 4 raw is 300.
And your work on them
New York boys
already been factored
into the price, you see.
On the other hand,
we got something that you want,
and it's coming back to you...
free of charge.
Someone you looking for.
Co-Op mean
what it sound like, Dawg.
You happy to do for me,
I'm happy to do for you.
Congratulations.
Colonel.
Deputy commissioner.
Congratulations to all
those who were promoted,
their families, and friends.
It's a proud day for them
and a proud day
for the Baltimore police department.
I am so proud of you.
You know, Valchek
we could have guessed.
I mean, he's Carcetti's man, but...
Daniels?
Long time for you to make Major,
but this was quick enough.
Yeah, who's your new rabbi, huh?
Colonel?
So, they didn't know
the salad fork from
whatever the fuck the other fork is for.
So what?
I knew they'd be at a loss,
but the extent of it.
I'm talking about feelings.
Why they feeling this...
this plummet from
Nassau university abject fear
to humiliated fury
and no awareness of it.
Who says they're not aware?
Maybe they just didn't acknowledge.
Either way, but my point is
where do you start with them?
How you get to believe in themselves
if they can't admit their feelings
about who they are
and what they doing in this world?
They not fools.
They know exactly
what we expect them to be.
Y'all missed something else
for real though.
Take your seats.
- It was hot, yo.
- Party of 4, Mr. Colvin.
May I take your coat,
Mr. Brice?
That shit was tight.
I'm dreaming about
that chocolate cake.
Oh, my God.
Shit had like 56 layers, yo!
Try out people like Mr. Colvin...
"D money saves pitman"?
It's bullshit!
Before, at least they were
getting something out of it.
Hell with my evaluation.
To hell with Donnelly,
to hell with the statewide test scores.
I came here to teach.
Right?
Yo, coach, seen Michael?
- Nah.
- All right.
That wasn't you and your runts
I saw down on Bentlow
yesterday slinging?
- Like this.
- Right.
'Cause a gangster like yourself
wouldn't set up such a weak-ass shop
with no real lookouts,
ground stash in plain view.
This is me telling y'all
as plain as I can.
You guys had your one chance.
I see you out there a second time,
everyone takes a beating
and goes to Cheltenham.
Fair warning you just got.
Cheltenham for some drug charges?
- Please, man.
- I'll write you off as a special.
Don't think I won't do it.
Jab, jab! Good.
He don't think I can jail?
Shit! I can jail.
- What's up?
- Man was banging, huh?
He's one of yours, right?
And he hang around the gym,
mostly waiting on his boy Michael.
He don't box or nothing.
He ain't that kind really.
- Not like his father.
- Yeah? Who was his father?
Dude named Wee-Bey.
Stone-Headed.
Used to run with them Barksdales.
I know him.
Shit, I locked him up
in Philadelphia.
Yeah?
Bey was my cut buddy.
We jailed down Jesse.
Anyway, Namond's from him.
Same blood,
but not the same heart.
I've done my warm-ups, coach.
Yeah. We ready for the ring!
Take care, man.
Why we stopping here?
I thought we was going straight out.
Gotta get with your escort out.
Prop Joe said
you was my escort out.
Manner of speaking,
that be true.
Come on over here, man.
Come on.
Chris, no.
You know I keep it quick, Dre.
- Here?
- Here's good.
Not-- Not in a vacant.
What's the difference?
The difference is my people.
They won't know.
They'll know.
But-- But-- But the rats.
I'll be alone with the rats.
You're all right.
I got your back.
Come on, Chris.
Let me do it at my house so my people--
they can give me a home go.
I'll be damned.
Hey, yo, that got to be Marlo, man.
You see?
That's the man we robbed, yo,
from the poker game.
Si. Si. Si.
What the boy don't like me.
Boot you out of la vela.
Thought maybe
I could catch up with Chris.
I got a problem
I can't bring to no one else.
Getting that?
He just a kid.
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - www.thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net