No, Bubs.
I mean, there's gotta be rules
or else things get fucked up.
Ain't no rules
for dope fiends.
When the police got you shackled up,
you make a move, right?
You help yourself out.
But you just start
snitchin' for no reason...
it doesn't make no...
Let me track this.
You hypopulatin' that you can
tattle-tale when you locked up
but you can't do it
straight up for the money?
I mean, no offense, son, but...
that some weak-ass thinkin'.
You equivocatin' like a motherfuck.
- Okay, so a snitch is a snitch, right?
- There you go.
So why be one, man?
I mean, we gettin'
by with our capers.
We gettin' by out here
every damn day
rippin' and runnin' and ain't
got shit to show for it.
It's part of being a soldier?
I mean, that's true, right,
that's what you says.
That was 'fore I put all
this mileage on these feet.
You wait, you wait,
till you ain't a pup no more,
see if you ain't lookin'
for somethin' a little more,
a little more steady
for your ownself.
What the fuck?
You gettin' ill already.
It's not even past morning.
I'm cool, man.
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Look, we hook up with
my girl Kima, we get paid
you gonna be better.
Fuck that, Bubs, alright?
I'm not a fuckin' snitch.
You know...
I could argue the other side.
Say that if you drop dime
to duck a charge, then you a snitch.
You do it as a living,
you a professional.
Hold up, hold up,
hold up, hold up.
You see that, that ladder right there.
Just like old times, man.
I'll be the bad guy,
you be the lone ranger.
Leave that man be.
We get paid more
hooking up to my girl.
But that's cash money
right there.
With the white man,
I best be the bad guy.
That way he ain't confused.
Alright, meet me in the alley.
Fuck.
Yo, Mister.
Yo.
Throw down your wallet, or I'm
a jerk this ladder right out.
What?
No, no!
I'm a poor man
who ain't playin'.
Throw down
the got-damn money.
Please, no.
Leave that man alone.
Thank you.
He's crazy, man.
What's that guy doing?
Oh, shit.
- Here, here.
- I can't, I can't.
No, you saved my ass.
It's appreciated you know.
Yo, Bubs.
You won't fuckin' believe this.
Bubs?
Straight and True
Dennis, you up?
Dennis?
Mee-maw, hey.
Guess you're not
workin' today, huh?
I'm workin' nights now.
At a bar.
Workin' the door.
You know, it's just...
just 'til I find
somethin' a little bit better.
Reminds me.
Your friend called
again this morning.
She said for you
to remember your appointment.
Says there's a job in it,
if you still lookin'.
So, Marlo, right?
He got this one boy
watchin' his back
name be Chris Partlow.
Barlow with a "b"?
Part, like white people
got in their hair.
And low, like
a low-bottom dope fiend.
- Partlow.
- Yeah, what I said.
So, he's Marlo's muscle?
So...
how much is that worth?
Five, if I can
work up a photo id.
The boy, Fruit, he used that.
Fruit who runs
one of Marlo's corners?
Careful, it's got prints.
Prints, huh?
Look at you, gettin' all
C.S.I. on me and shit.
A burner with prints.
That's gotta mean cash money, right?
If I can pull a print, get Fruit id'd,
I can go to ten.
An' if I show you where
Marlo hides his Mercedes.
The Benz would go for 15.
You don't know it, but these
are hard times in a hard land.
You killin' me out here, girl.
A- ight.
25 for the Benz.
You good peoples.
So let's total up
we at 40, right?
Here.
Bank that for me.
Bank it?
For what?
Got me a plan, girl.
The hoppers out here
they only be wearin' them big white shirts
a couple of times 'fore they chuck 'em.
So I'm thinkin' while I'm out
here workin' for y'all
I'ma get my ends up, sell 'em
shirts on the corners.
I'll make my nut
comin' an' goin'.
Truthfully, I don't know
what more you could have done.
Charlie's right, boss.
You tried.
Fuckin' hoodleheads
won't cooperate.
Here you are, giving 'em
their own block or two
offering them a place
to sell drugs in peace
and do they even
fuckin' listen?
It's a damn shame, too,
'cause if it worked
you mighta had a positive
effect on the community.
Shift commander
call the front desk.
You guys are some
lying sacks of shit.
I'm sayin', sir...
I'm guessin' that you
have some thoughts on where
we should go from here.
Well, sir, we were thinkin'
a modified zebra operation.
Jumpouts rotating from sector-to-sector,
combined with a zero tolerance approach.
We detail a couple
of men from each shift
build a flex unit
double up on the head-knocking
and corner-clearing.
More of the same, you mean.
But better.
Better?
Better than nothing.
Ah, fuck this bullshit already!
Man, they gave us 15 cases of legal
but they shorted us
on the colored bonds...
what's going on there?
I got this.
Officer.
Detective, String.
You remember?
Bird trial, detective McNulty.
You want something copied, man?
Search warrant?
Court papers?
Anything I do to help, you know?
I ain't seen you around the way.
I'm not around the way no more.
You wanna find me, I'm right here.
Right here, huh?
This an' some real estate
I'm workin' on is all.
You know?
More than enough
to occupy me, really.
Say where you livin', man?
Where am I living?
Well, if you thinkin'
a comin' downtown
I got some condos about to come
on the line in eight months.
You say the word, I'ma hook you
up something nice down there
by the hippodrome.
Loft apartments.
Real nice.
You disappoint me, String.
I had such fuckin' hopes for us.
Have a nice day, officer.
You see this shit?
Remember that kid
who got shot in the parking lot
at Lake Clifton
a couple months back?
Drug feud, right?
What about it?
Well, last night, they just
found the only eyewitness.
In an alleyway,
buncha holes in him.
And?
What do you mean, "and"?
You're talking about
a state's witness.
You let a witness get killed in
a high-profile case like this
it says the city's
broke and can't be fixed.
Sounds like we found an issue.
Fuck the politics for a minute.
You know, this is something
we all need to be on the same page with.
I'm serious, Tony.
You let shit like this stand,
pretty soon you got nothing left.
You gonna go public
and bang the Mayor with it?
You gonna bang Burrell
and the state's attorney then?
I ain't gonna bang nobody.
Like I said, fuck the politics for once.
But there is a problem here
and I'm gonna do something to fix it.
You want your cape
and the little red underpants?
Or you stash that shit
in the phone booth?
I always wondered about that.
Man, I like a piece of that.
You'd like any piece at all.
I think I'd like
a piece of your mother.
Yo, stop fuckin' around!
He started that shit.
Yo, she got our boy
with his nose wide open.
He's stealing from us,
and she most likely the reason for it.
And y'all stay with the girl,
she'll soon enough show us the money.
Hey, where you goin'?
Yo, I got something I got to do.
You supposed to be here
on this shit with us.
Y'all stay with the girl,
I'll get back with y'all down the way.
Say what?
Yo, I made a date a while back.
Gotta keep it.
Man made a date, gotta keep it.
You find out he pussy-whipped
like this motherfuck over here.
Now, once again, from the data:
When are most cars stolen?
Sir, at night.
And your unit, which I believe is
charged with deterring the theft of autos
when do you work?
The day shift, eight-to-four.
But sir, as I tried to explain...
Your position is clear:
You affect more arrests of car thieves
during the daylight than at night.
You see, our ears work.
We heard you.
But the question becomes:
Why the fuck can't you hear us?
- Sir, I don't...
- The Commissioner is attempting
to move this department
from the dark ages into the 21st century.
That means preventing crime
by relying on computer generated data
not on your
fly-by-your-fucked-up-ass instinct.
Give me the auto theft numbers
for downtown parking lots
on friday nights.
Sir, I have to check that.
Where are we with the gun?
Colonel, I was made to understand
that recovering officer Dozerman's
lost weapon was a priority.
Oh, the gun, yes, we're on it, sir.
Making progress as we speak.
Lieutenant?
Sir, I now understand that
prevention is the way to go
and will immediately change
our hours to reflect the data.
Alright, Lieutenant.
Fecal gravity.
Hey, you beat on the right people
and the shit rolls down the hill.
Dennis is it?
Cutty works for me.
Cutty then.
So, um, it's just
gonna be us here?
You know...
I mean, Grace.
Sister Grace
called on your behalf
but to my knowledge,
she didn't plan to be here.
She's a beautiful woman.
A man might say things he didn't mean
to stand closer to a woman like that.
You're in the job market
though, I understand.
A couple of questions.
You got a high school diploma?
G.E.D.?
Any work experience?
I worked in a warehouse
for a couple of months back in like '86.
How do you see
the church helping you?
Maybe give me some jobs or...
put my name on a list or somethin'.
I dunno.
I should tell you up front,
we don't do like that here.
You want a job, you're gonna
have to work to get it.
We'll help.
But it's gonna be your sweat.
With that said, then, the first thing is to
get you enrolled in a G.E.D. program...
Look, I don't mean to put you out,
but this...
this ain't how I thought
it was gonna play.
Me, Oscar, a bunch of the guys,
we seen it.
Couldn't help it.
They practically ran right past us.
And the victim, the girl...
had a gun?
Whose side was she on?
Couldn't tell, it weren't
doin' slow motion.
Did any of them have a big scar?
Do you think you'd be able to recognize
any of them again if you saw them?
- Just Omar.
- So, you know Omar?
Omar came up 'round here.
That's good, bruiser, very good.
You do know Omar
has a scar, right?
He do?
I think we better go to my
office, put this down on paper.
Come on.
Officer.
Excuse me, officer.
Is this... North and Pulaski?
'Cause I could fucking swear
Dozerman was shot up at North and Pulaski.
Wait, wait, lemme guess
the pursuit of your fellow
officer's service weapon
has led you to this fine citizen.
Tell me, kind sir, do you know
the whereabouts of said officer's weapon?
I didn't think so.
Calls from the detention center.
Some kind souls begging to assist you
in your foundering investigation.
Lemme just grand jury my man here.
Lock in his story.
Now for the gun. Later for his story.
And that's your sergeant talking.
Yo, wipe your nose, yo.
- What the fuck...
- Oh shit!
Motherfucker, you scared the shit
out of us coming up like that.
Shit do make you paranoid, yo.
G'head, nigga, hit this shit.
Naw, man, I gotta
drop urine tomorrow.
Yo, you worried about that?
Go 'head, nigga.
- We got that covered.
- Oh, you got that covered.
What?
You think you're the only
motherfucker on parole?
- Yo, nigger, gimme that shit.
- There you go.
A- ight.
What was her day?
She caught a hack up
to Towsontown mall.
Hit two jewelry stores and
came back with bags from both.
By the time she
caught up with our boy
she was wearin' one of them
shits around her neck.
Gave the other one to him.
You know, his an' hers, like.
Yeah, Cutty.
You was on that shit, man.
It's been a week, McNulty.
Either you got something
on Stringer or you don't.
He tried to sell me a condo.
Cocksucker.
Might as well join the Rotary.
Take up golf or someshit.
He's runnin' with the hounds
though I'll bet his heart
is still with the fox.
Stringer's out of the game?
Mr. Bell has become the bank.
The bank?
The bank plays it legit,
he generates a good bit of honest income.
But at the same time, his money finances
packages that he himself will never touch.
He won't go near the street.
He's insulated from the every day
operations on the corners.
The money that comes back
is then laundered through
enough straight business investments
that there's no way to trace it.
A player gets to that point,
there ain't no way
in hell a working police
is going to tie a can to his tail.
Oh, man.
So, Kintel Williamson,
the prince of Pimlico.
Where we at on this mope?
DNR's on a couple of payphones.
That got it?
Alright.
You gonna help or what, boy?
Might as well not
even take a whistle
if all I'm doin' is
standin' in the fuckin' alley!
Back's where you belong.
That'a way I ain't got to be worryin'
'bout gettin' my damn head blown off
'cause you all scared and shit.
Enough!
You all hear me, I said enough?!
Come over and put some pumpkin
balls in this shotgun, man.
Kimmy!
Both of y'all learn to live
with it or y'all out, man.
Now, this time
we gonna do it right.
Ya all feel me?
Boss, you gotta let this go.
It ain't gonna work.
You said it in comstat:
Shit rolls down.
Now, we tried to talk to all the hoppers,
what the hell can they do about anything?
We need to bring it to the dealers.
Sergeant.
I need a list of names
of all the mid-level dealers
running my corners.
Sir?
You're my D.E.U. Sergeant, right?
I need a list of names.
Maybe narcotics downtown has
something like that, I dunno.
We're knocking heads, taking bodies.
I didn't know I was supposed
to be doin' a census or nothing.
Hey, yo, miss. Miss?
Where the peepot at?
Thanks.
Come on, this way.
Yo, my man you need
to drop a negative.
Five dollars.
Motherfucker, they was just two.
You try findin' clean piss in Baltimore.
Five a go.
Yo, how I know it's clean?
I get mine from day care...
I need you to put the chicken
in the oven at 375.
Yes, and after you've done that
I need you to help me
put your sister down...
Excuse me, miss.
Put your thumb on the scanner.
Hold on a second.
What's your name?
Wise, Dennis Wise.
Take one of those.
Go around the corner to the second door.
No, you can not go outside.
Are you listening
to what I'm saying?
That's all we got
on the Westside dealers.
George...
I'm lookin' at a sprinklin'
of rap sheets here.
You tellin' me nobody
in this department
knows who controls the West
Baltimore corners anymore?
Hey, Rawls has my people
doing street rips.
You want up-to-date info,
you should try the intelligence unit.
- Shit, they sent me to you, George.
- What the fuck can I tell you?
With all the street work
there ain't nobody left
doin' high-end drug stuff.
From what I'm hearing
the guy comes in of his own accord
and he gets betrayed by us.
Protection in this city
amounts to nothing
more than getting dumped
in a fleabag joint on route 40
and calling it a plan.
No monitoring, no assistance.
Nothing just a bundle of
clothes and a toothbrush.
Jesus.
No way to treat a cooperator.
I know someone could get a lot of mileage
out of this with the press.
But fuck that, right?
Because if I go that way
then everyone gets defensive
and nothing gets fixed.
I'm coming to you
with this straight-up.
Agreed.
Where do we stand on this?
You've already called
for a meeting on this
with the State's Attorney
and the Police Commissioner.
It's penciled in
for next wednesday.
No, no, Tommy's right on this,
we need to act quickly.
I'm glad you
came to us with this.
I'll light a fire, believe me.
Thanks.
You will keep me
in the loop on this?
Absolutely, Councilman.
Hey, slow up, girlfriend,
we need to talk for a minute.
Yeah, sweet thin'.
We met before?
No, baby, but that can happen.
- We ain't met, excuse me.
- Hey, it's just talk, baby.
Get the fuck out, boy.
Look, girl, all we need
for you to do is talk...
Is you deaf or just stone stupid?
Hold on, girl...
Now, we gonna talk.
How the fuck
is this little runt of a unit
holding all this
drug intelligence?
I made the rounds
down at headquarters
came up with Jack,
and you're holding all this?
Well, you run a couple wiretaps,
you fill up a file cabinet pretty fast.
This is great, thanks.
Oh, shit!
Goddamnit.
I heard this was where you landed.
This pretty boy?
I broke his ass in.
I wrote more on I.I.D. complaints
on bushy top here
than on the whole
goddamn squad.
That is 'til he scuffed himself up.
Now where you at, McNulty?
1911 South Clinton Street,
first floor.
There you go.
I know you got to keep him close
but still
some good goddamn
police right here.
So what brings you to our shop?
I'm tryin' to find out
who running my corners.
My own D.E.U. is just about street rips
and headquarters wadn't no help neither.
Y'all saved my ass, though.
You tell him about your boy...
Marlo ?
It's in the files
along with every other
mid-level player we know.
You don't mind me asking?
What're you gonna do
with all that, Major?
Well...
round up these young men
and put a little comstat
on they ass.
Gentlemen. Ma'am.
Bushy top.
Bushy top?
Call to order and shit.
Chair recognize the esteemed rep.
of the Veronica Avenue boys.
Alright, look, we done
talked this shit to death. A-ight?
When we gonna vote?
Rick do have a point.
A- ight, then.
All those in favor
of goin' together
so we can get the best
discount on a New York package
raise up.
A- ight then.
There it is.
Look like we gonna
make more money...
together.
Got to say I'm proud
of y'all for puttin' aside
petty grievances an'
puttin' this thing together.
For a cold-ass
crew of gangsters
y'all carried it like
republicans an' shit.
Yo, remember, man,
talk this shit up when you hit them bricks.
Best way to get more
involved is to tell people
about the benefits
of this here thing.
No beefing. No drama.
Just business.
Anybody got a problem
with anybody else here
we bring it to the group.
We ain't gotta take it
to the streets.
A- ight.
Let's do it.
Yo.
Motherfucker, what is that?
Them Robert rules say we gotta have
minutes for a meeting, right?
These the minutes.
Nigga, is you takin' notes on
a criminal fucking conspiracy.
What the fuck
is you thinkin', man?
That's cool.
Dad, he's cheating.
Michael, take it easy
on your brother.
How are you two gettin' along
with mom's new friend?
We call him Dennis,
he's not new.
Okay, how are you
doin' with him?
Mom said we can't talk
to you about family stuff.
Dad, you goin' to the open house?
Yeah, I'll try, but I've been
real busy at work though.
New case an' all.
Mom says you have to go, dad.
Yeah, all the other kids'
fathers are gonna be there.
Get his legs.
Steal from us, motherfucker?
Get the ring, too, yo.
Shit won't come off, yo.
Drop him.
You know the man works for us.
You keep goin' at him like that
ain't gonna be nothing left of
him to make right what he owes.
Bitch got to pay.
Hey, yo, check his pockets, yo.
- That's mine, yo.
- Get the fuck off...
... to security.
Was' up, baby.
Yo, man, I been in here 26 months
an' you come pick me up
in a motherfuckin' Ford?
I'm just fuckin' with you.
Was' up, baby?
What up, man.
Man, I'm feeling real good
to be out of this motherfucker.
You know what?
There's a sign on the other
side of this gate that say "never again".
And that's the only fucking thin'
I'm gonna take with me from this place.
First thin' first,
let's get you lookin' right.
You know what I mean?
Oh, you got my shit.
Good looking, baby.
Start with sector one.
Bring as many as you can
down to the Vincent Street area
by the end of shift.
Don't use your wagons.
Bring as many as
you can in your cars.
The hoppers wouldn't listen.
What makes you think
these guys will?
These are...
the lieutenants running the corners
and I personally feel their pain.
Now, middle-management
means that you have
just enough responsibility
that you got to listen when people talk
and not so much
that you can tell anybody
to go fuck themselves.
Look, my major just wants to talk.
That's all, promise.
We'll bring you right back.
Ain't gonna happen.
The fuck you say?
What the fuck you mean
it ain't going to happen?
Let me tell you something,
motherfucker.
We got orders to bring
your sorry ass down
the way for a sit down
with our boss.
Now we're prepared
to take you with us right now.
We can either do this
the easy way or...
braindead fucks...
Hello.
Prez, it's me.
I think we got
a little situation here.
Stay with me, ten-six...
Major wants the dickhead,
he gotta go.
I think he gets a pass this time.
You sure?
I mean, you want, he goes.
Another time, Herc.
We're on the Major's clock here.
Don't forget the face, cocksucker,
there's gonna be a tomorrow.
You need me to call dispatch?
No, it's okay.
I'll tell you later.
I say we get the troops,
and fuck these assholes up.
Come on, let's go again.
C'mon, Tommy, it's just a game.
Look, sounds like you
got what you want, anyway.
From the Mayor, I mean.
Yeah, well, he's played me before
but so help me
if he farts around on this
I'm going after him. Big time.
For real?
Trust me on this.
He keeps ducking me
I'm going to fuck him good.
That's the good part.
It's what I call the carrot.
Now you move your people
into any designated area
I told you about
and you have immunity from
arrest and prosecution.
You're free to make your drops
collect what needs collectin'
and won't nobody bother you.
You've got my word on it.
What do you get out of this?
That's a fair question.
I want to salvage what's still
worth salvagin' in my district.
And I can't do that with a bunch
of young hoppers runnin' around
scarin' the hell
out of the decent people.
Now, these kids ain't gonna listen to me,
but they will listen to y'all.
Now, you tell them to move
down here and set-up shop
and they will.
So the way I got it figured
I motivate you,
and you motivate them.
Naw, this a trap.
No, you check out the spot.
There ain't no cameras,
ain't no microphones, nothing.
Any cops you see going to be
down right on the perimeter.
Just to make sure
there's no violence.
And you watch
you see if it don't
work out the way I say.
Nothin' personal
against you, chief, but...
what happens if we buck?
You remember the carrot, right?
Well, if you choose
the stick instead
you gonna feel that stick like
you ain't never felt before.
We gonna indict
every corner, every day.
I've got over 200 sworn
personnel and I plan to free up
every one of them to knock every
one of you y'all down they can.
If you're on a corner in my district
it ain't gonna be about no humble
it ain't gonna be about
no loitering charge, nothing like that.
There gonna be some biblical
shit happening to you on the way
to that motherfuckin' jail wagon.
You understand me?
And while you're
buckin' the new system,
the smart ones among you,
gonna be down here
makin' money
hand over fist.
So, think it over.
But I swear to god, come monday
your world and mine
ain't gonna be the same.
I thought you said these
goddamn houses were vacant.
We musta missed her.
There's one more thing
I gotta do then.
Little Man, up on "b" tier,
one of his boys in the dormitory
his brother's tight with the girlfriend
of the boy that shot that poh-leece.
Little Man sayin'
if you sprung the three of us
we could get her talkin',
you know, find the gun.
I'm hearin' the boy, Dink,
got that man's gun.
Now, I ain't sure yet if that
Dink be Dink Dink or Inky Dink
or maybe Fat Dink.
Then again,
it might be Flat Nose Dink.
No, wait
that can't
be him, that Dink dead.
Look, man, I can help you
but first you gotta get me out
from under these murder beefs.
How many murders we talkin'?
Look, man, do it have
to be the cop's gun?
'Cause if it's guns you want,
I can get you guns.
I remember this.
Sixth grade.
Mrs. Holley's science class.
Box lunches. Taste like shit.
You got somethin'
so important, man
you can't go through
the proper channels?
Well, no.
I don't know.
I just figured if
I told anybody but you
you might think
I'm ridin' the rock.
What makes me think you ain't?
Yeah, right.
That's a good point.
Look, today, me,
Tuckie, Little Mikey
man, we all...
A bunch of us got
scooped up by the police.
Well, you shouldn't sell drugs.
Alright, alright.
Nah see, they didn't
take us to the station.
They took us down to the
bottom of Vincent Street
where all the houses is boarded
up, and they let us out.
And then, on top of all of that
like the whole while they
were being all like...
decent and shit,
you know that fucked me up.
And then the police chief,
he come out.
And this is the crazy part
he say that he got it set up
so that we could sell stuff
in certain spots,
and the police won't bother us.
I know, I know. It's fucked up,
but I just thought you should know.
That's it?
Yeah, just that,
and the boy Marlo.
Yeah, I'm on it.
Yep.
2303 to K.G.A.
Have foxtrot meet me
on six, adam.
Foxtrot, ten four.
2303 to foxtrot.
Foxtrot, standing by.
It's a black Mercedes,
pulling out the lot.
Copy that, we got the eyeball.
This here the spot?
'Cause Tuckie says we supposed
to set-up shop here.
Hamsterdam.
Yeah, this is it.
Set-up anywhere inside where
we got the white flags.
- Yo, I'm getting ready to roll out.
- You just got here, what's wrong?
Ain't nobody 'round to buy.
Good point.
Man needs customers.
- I'm sayin'...
- Aw, no.
You can't make me.
I'm a sworn fucking police officer.
Was' up, man.
You got that bodybag still?
Two.
Narco!
Give it up, motherfucker.
Money comes back, right now.
Boss, you fuckin' up, man.
You didn't even let me cop
'fore you snatch me up.
Is that some fuckin' rule?
You call, we haul.
You clean?
Yeah, of course I'm clean
stupid ass rookie didn't
even give me a chance to cop.
This corner's indicted.
You move over to Vincent Street
or we come back with the bracelets.
What you got?
1011 me at Riggs and Calhoun.
Despite unforeseen delays,
we will begin an academy class
this january, which leaves us in
good shape for the coming year.
Thank you, Commissioner.
If the chair pleases,
I have a couple of questions.
Commissioner
I know you are aware
that a state's witness
in a recent city homicide
prosecution was killed.
We are treating that incident
with the highest priority.
Homicide has set-up a task force
and narcotics is working
the informant angle.
We have also asked both the
F.B.I. and D.E.A. for support.
It sounds like a full-court press
but you must admit
it's a bit like closing the barn
door after the horse is out.
I mean, the shooting
of the boy on the lot
at Lake Clifton high school
was a high-profile case
wasn't it, Commissioner?
Yes, it was.
And yet a key witness
in the case was allowed...
one moment...
excuse me, Commissioner,
but the chair was good enough
to remind me that you have
a pressing engagement.
So if it's alright with you,
we can continue this at a later date.
Meeting adjourned.
Did you see Burrell sweat?
The man's collar almost melted.
The hell got into you?
You did, old buddy.
You did.
Nend of the line, all out.
We got that Rockefeller, yo.
We got that Rockefeller
over here, yo.
Over here we got that
Rockefeller, yo.
Whatta fuck?
Yo, yo, we got
the Rockefeller, yo.
We got that W.M.D.
right here, right here.
I hear the W.M.D. is the bomb.
W.M.D. right here.
W.M.D.
Give me two, yo.
W.M.D. right here.
W.M.D. right here, right here.
Right here.
We got that Rockefeller over here.
Yo!
We got that Rockefeller, yo.
What do we got?
There's binoculars on the floor.
Marlo making a move?
Just watch.
Forget everythin'
the boy, Bodie, told you.
Forget the beatin',
it ain't about that.
You smart, man, I can see that.
I wanted you to choose
somewhere safe for us to speak.
But goddamn
only bugs in this
motherfucker gotta have legs.
Now, I appreciate smart
but you gotta know,
in this game, man, it ain't enough.
You a student of history?
You know this town had its
share of smart players, man?
Melvin, Little Wil, Big Head Brother,
Peanut, Warren.
All real smart, man, real smart.
You know, soon as
their names rang out, bam
the feds was on them.
You know what I mean?
The government they want you to be
organized, nah, they want you
scrimpin' and scrapin'
killin' each other on the
corners over some bullshit.
Not me.
That's why me and Prop Joe
we gettin' ready to put
this co-op together.
Different crews, one package.
Best dope, best coke.
Share and share alike.
I've been hearin' 'bout that.
You've been hearin' 'bout that?
That's good,
that's a start, right?
You know that Mercedes you
got ridin' out there, man
you got that titled in your
aunt's name or some shit.
Now, when they come get you
that straw purchase out there
gonna come bite you in the ass, boy.
That's what's they do.
Turn your money against you.
Now, you I'm thinkin'
with the corners you got
you close to a mil, right?
I'm doin' a-ight.
You doing a-ight
but a-ight ain't got you
a name on your crib, right?
Ain't got you a little spot
to wash that dirty money?
That what I'm offerin' you, man.
Come on, who's he in there with?
I told you, keep watchin'.
Did Bunk put you
up to this?
Tell you what, how about
a case of that PBR piss
you drink against a touch of the
Irish that he went out the back
and you're watching
that house for nothing.
Here comes your nothing.
I like my piss in bottles.
Anyway you like, darlin'.
Chris...
tell our people to tool up.
I'm on it.
I got that W.M.D., got that W.M.D.
They got comfortable
with it pretty quick.
Yeah, it's like we ain't
even standing here.
The hoppers call it Hamsterdam.
Like from Amsterdam.
Hamsterdam.
...are the use of integrated
math concepts such as
algebraic reasoning, and number
sines, geometry and probability.
Very impressive.
Now what we try to do is
keep the class size under 10
12 at the very most.
- And there are three levels?
- Yes, so that if...
Sorry, I'm Jim McNulty.
I'm runnin' a little late
because of work.
Mr. McNulty.
I have some concerns about
the integrated math program.
In their previous schools,
Michael took introductory algebra
but I understand that this school
is doing something different.
We are.
The integrated math program...
Excuse me, I'm thirsty
can I get either of you
somethin' to drink?
The integrated math
program here consist...
Not much of a spread, but you
can't go wrong with crudite.
Crudity?
I'm sorry, you know,
I came straight from work
or I'da changed.
No need to call names, right?
What do you do, Mr...
I'm on the board at Legg Mason.
Jim McNulty.
Legg Mason?
Either that or I'm a cop
in the city, I keep forgetting.
Terri d'Agostino.
I'm an alumna and one of
the school's dreaded fundraisers.
The math program offers
tutoring possibilities.
So if Michael finds it
difficult adjusting
we can have classes
on tuesdays and thursdays.
So how do you find the school?
It's good.
My ex and I are thinking
of sending our boys here.
- Any problems, difficulties?
- No, not really.
I mean, there's the math
integration class for my oldest.
He's in sixth, seventh, and...
I'm not sure he's ready,
you know, for all that math.
Careful, I'm only a country boy.
Shut up!
Hey, sweetie, welcome home.
Welcome back.
Hey, sis.
Aw, man.
I just wish I wasn't the only
one comin' home, you know?
I know.
Enjoy tonight, we'll talk later.
Welcome home.
What up, Prop,
how you feelin', man?
Alright.
You lookin' fit.
Hell, yeah, I've been
working out in there.
All you gotta do is work out.
Might be a good place for a fat
man to find his inner-self.
Yo.
I got some downtown suits wanna
hollar with you real quick.
Takin' me to see suits,
I'm tryin' to see some skirts.
So what do you do?
You should get dressed.
I got a lot of work here.
It's a long day for me tomorrow.
I'll be really quiet.
You never know, you might
get bored workin'.
I gotta work.
You gotta go...
What Stringer's done with
all that property downtown
Avon, I cannot tell the kind
of profit you're looking at
once all the federal
redevelopment money lands.
That whole howard street
thing is gonna take off
and you're gonna be right
there to cut the pie yourself.
Any dollar you spend now
is going to come back to you ten times.
And the thing is?
I know you don't wanna
go back to them streets.
Not after what you been through.
I know, because I'm from
those same streets.
And once I had the chance
to play a different game
there wasn't a question
in my mind how to go.
The government is going to be
looking at you hard, too.
No sense in giving them
what they're looking for.
You take what you have,
you build on it.
It's all good.
Just put it up on the calendar.
We should meet.
Yo, Slim.
You see the two niggas right there.
They over here gettin' high
in the middle of all this...
where the fucking
discipline at, yo?
Fuck, toss them niggers.
Talk to me for a second.
don't you know not
to stare at me like that.
Yo. I got to show you something.
Pardon me, sweetie.
Hey, yo, man.
You know I've been locked down.
You gonna love this.
Trust me.
Ah, shit, this ain't
my little place down in jessup.
But you know what I mean,
what the fuck is, right?
This is all you, B.
All you, in your name, too.
You know what I mean?
This piece of paper right
here makes it legit.
Keys to the navigator,
in the basement.
It's just a rental 'til
you pick out somethin' nice.
Damn, all this, huh?
You did good.
Yeah, I mean we're makin'
so much straight money, man
we can carry shit like this out
in the open, in our own names.
Yo, you remember when
we used to sit on the top
of 734 buildin', man?
Lookin' at the city,
talk about what we goin' do?
And you was all heavy into
that black pride bullshit
talkin' about you gonna
get you two grocery stores
make motherfuckers proud.
Sure was, man, you was out
huntin' on a ak-47.
Talkin' about
how I'm gonna get Warren.
Man...
We brothers, B.
Always, baby.
Always.
Hey, just one more thin', man.
I don't mean to be pickin'
with you about this but...
especially not after
you did all this shit for me
but, look, man,
I've been locked down.
You know what I mean?
You know what?
I got take this meet, you know?
I'm gonna get at you,
welcome home, man.
Hey, yo, it's me, man,
I left somethin'.
Aw, shit, my man.
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
Transcript par Raceman
Synchronisation: El Uploador
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net