I gotta hit the head.
I can't take
this shit, Bunny.
Hey
It'll pass.
They're just
riding you now.
Next week it's somebody new.
Can't take away
your E.O.D., Marvin.
Worst they can do is bust
you back to lieutenant.
I don't even
wanna think about
the worst these
motherfuckers can do.
You don't either.
You're still not connecting
the dots, Marvin.
Have a look.
Hoffman and Holbrook, Sir.
Very good.
You had a body drop
there last week
and this is what the fuck
it looked like yesterday.
Bond and Preston
for the record.
Ashland and Wolfe.
Chase and Durham.
Sir, I deployed my resources
per your instructions.
We beefed up foot patrols.
We have our plainclothes
squads on 12-hour shifts.
And the corners stay full?
They move, Sir.
Everyday
they're gonna
sell their drugs somewhere.
Major Taylor.
I look at your numbers, I see
the intel reports, the photos.
It all tells me
that you lack a fucking clue.
If you'll permit me.
Is your Deputy Major present?
Yes, Sir.
You now command
the Eastern District.
Major Taylor,
you are relieved.
Take the podium.
Anyone else having trouble
with the writing on the wall?
Dismissed.
Dead Soldiers
And I'm like "nigger if you want
to sell me a new car
you better really sell it to me
'cause otherwise, I'm sittin'
back and I'm watchin'."
What you want
with a new ride for?
It ain't like you
can't get a new car
anywhere you want,
anytime, this whole city.
- I'm just sayin'.
- Sayin' what?
- In case.
- In case what?
In case I ever want
to buy a new car.
Damn, is that too
much to ask for?
Girl, you crazy.
Shit, shit,
Get down. Get down.
Yeah, they filling it now.
They protectin'
the fuck out of it, too.
You see what you wanted?
Yeah, man.
But they got the whole
second floor boarded up.
Got a little
porch 'round back.
Couple of the boys out there
now smoking on them menthols.
So we slide up from the back?
It barred up, too.
No way through the front?
Not now.
Come tomorrow morning
they gonna scale back down
to a three-man skeleton crew,
ya feel me?
Not sure I like this.
Why we gotta keep hitting up
the Barksdale people?
Ain't like this whole
motherfuckin' city
ain't got stashes all over it.
True that.
So why?
Because.
Because?
Indeed.
So that's a cop shooter?
Yeah, not much to him
but he did the job on
the Dozerman kid last week.
We gave it up
in a full statement.
Before or after you knocked
the shit out of him?
Injuries were sustained while
patrol officers were effecting
pursuit and rest
of aforementioned suspect.
He was caught
Eastside, right?
But the wagon made
a stop at the Western District
for an unscheduled tune-up.
It's dark on that backlot.
Western boys mistook
him for a pinata.
So what do you think?
I think this is a tragic motherfuckin'
miscarriage of justice.
I think it deserves
a special grand jury
and if not, the president
should appoint
an independent prosecutor.
Oh, no, no, no, actually
I think Kofi Bryant
an' the United fucking Nations
should get involved.
It's a murder, Bunk.
The word from upstairs is that
we supposed to be havin'
less murders, not more.
This is Anne Arundel county.
Why should they care about that?
Why should you?
Hey, Bunk.
Hey, how's it going?
Listen, um, Deputy
wants to know.
Have we recovered
Dozerman's service weapon?
No, Sir. The kid says he sold
it on the street.
Gave only the street
name of the buyer.
A certain Peanut,
whereabouts unknown.
They want that gun back.
Sir?
They don't want to have a departmental
weapon on the street.
You know, as a principle.
The great white
deputy has spoken.
This case is not down
until the gun comes home.
Fine, don't get up.
One of the most heavily armed
cities in the gun-loving world,
why should those
ignorant motherfuckers
care about one got-damn
semiauto, more or less?
What'd you bring me downtown
in this shit for, man?
Police don't get whif.
Talk to me, big man.
Thought you should know,
my boy Cheese,
he went into the box
with a couple of police.
He stood tall?
No doubt.
Kept his mouth shut
and waited 'em out.
Way it turned out,
they the ones that fucked up.
How come?
Police let it slip
Cheese played in some talkies.
Tried to pin a hit on him.
Said they had it all over.
Who got hit?
A dog.
What kinda dog?
Kind mistake
your leg for pussy.
So, they had phones tapped?
Don't matter to me
none if they did.
Me and the people I keep close,
we don't talk on the phone none.
You talk on the phone, String?
So we good then.
What we know is they
still looking hard at us.
You wanna know what kills more
police than bullets and liquor?
Boredom.
They jus' can't
handle that shit.
You keep it boring, String.
You keep it dead
fucking boring.
You're serious?
I am.
What's the closest
school to here?
Stuart Hill elementary.
That's at least eight blocks.
Three sevens.
Three sevens?
Five eights.
Bullshit, let's see it.
Read 'em an' weep.
You're cheating.
I just can't catch
your ass is all.
It's just luck, Tony.
It's just luck.
You called my desk
looking for me?
Yes, I did, come on in.
Grab a chair.
But watch your
wallet if you do.
Make it quick, Tommy.
The new city editor wants
a 40-inch weekender
on liquor board reform.
They're going to reform
the liquor board?
Yeah, with a hand grenade.
So what's on your mind?
We're off the record?
There's going to be
no academy class
of police cadets this year.
Mayor's orders.
Homicide rate's climbing,
felonies are up
we got patrol
vacancies out the ass.
Even more coming
at the year-end retirements.
And this is coming
from his honor?
To what end?
Keep some money.
Money's in the budget,
but even a six-month delay
in hiring saves
a couple million.
You think there's some paper,
something the Mayor signed?
Nah, but you call
the personnel office
and they'll confirm that
the class is delayed until next year.
You get that much
you can come back to me
for a couple of quotes.
You want in on this?
No indeed.
I love my mayor.
Councilman, thank you.
Stirring up some shit.
Just a little bit.
For the good of our
fair city by the bay.
Three twos.
Housing authority has this
slated for demolition, right?
But no money to do it yet.
Boss, you sure
it's a good idea
not to tell anyone
about this downtown?
Ignorance is bliss,
Lieutenant.
Anyone ever tell you that?
Once, but I beat the dog-piss
out of the guy with a nightstick.
Anybody seen McNulty?
Catch him up when he posts.
New target.
Kintel Williamson
goes by Prince K.
Has a string of corners from
Park Circle to Woodland Avenue.
And he's dropping bodies, too.
Three in the last four months
or so say our friends
in the Northwestern District.
So we're off
Proposition Joe's people?
We're going to ship the mid-level
arrests downtown to C.I.D.
Let narcotics work
up those prosecutions.
After that, we're
on to new business.
He don't look like much.
He's dropping bodies.
And with everybody pressed
to bring the murder rate down
that's the new mandate
for this unit.
Bell has bodies on him, too.
Not lately.
And Prop Joe hasn't
made much noise either.
They're still running product.
Still got kids
banging out there.
And now, 'cause we blew
a wire over a fucking dog
we have to let
them just walk on
go about their shit
like we were never anything
to take seriously
in the first place?
I want an investigative strategy
mapped out by week's end.
McNulty's here
in spirit anyway.
What?
Right there.
This will work, too.
There's a couple
occupied in the 200 block
and that one over there
but, otherwise...
we're good.
Good shit, right?
Let's go.
Commissioner Burrell, please.
Who's calling, please?
It's Councilman Carcetti.
Hold please.
Hello.
Erv, I'm givin'
you a heads up.
You're gonna get a call
from a Sun papers reporter
about the academy class.
What the fuck, is this a joke?
Calm the hell down, Erv.
You just no-comment the fucker.
You tellin' me my name
will be no where near this
and then send a reporter my way.
Exactly. Then you call
the mayor yourself
and you tell him you
got a reporter nosing around
about the academy
class getting pushed.
You tell him you
have no idea how it leaked.
I know this shit's
coming back to me.
Trust me you're
covered on this.
Goddamn it.
You can't hang me out there
like this with the Mayor.
My ass is flapping
in the breeze.
You want that class, Erv.
You gotta trust me.
Shit!
How you even find me?
Ran into Lukas.
Don't even call his nigger.
Nigger still owes me money.
He just told me
how to find you that's all.
He tell you how I'm doing?
I know what you thinking.
You ain't looking
all that yourself.
You look just fine, girl.
Just tryin' to find
your sister that's all.
She ain't for you no more.
She ain't for none of our kind.
Gone out county-way.
Picked herself up.
County clothes, county car.
County nose to look down
on all us city niggers with.
She a teacher.
Where at?
Don't be rushin' me,
motherfucker.
I know you lookin'
to tip on out of here
get your aftershave on
get yourself correct.
She teach speech.
Make it so every nigger
sound like Condo-Lisa.
Up by the B. Wells.
'Scuse me, Sir.
'Scuse me, have you
seen this little girl?
This my baby.
Can you just take
that picture with you?
Thank you so much, god bless.
'Scuse me, have you
seen this little girl
Lady, you gonna
have to back up.
She's my little girl.
Please, she's only four years old.
I ain't seen your little girl,
you're gonna have to back up.
- Please, just take a look at her!
- I ain't seen your...
How do?
Let's go.
Where it at, man?
Back there.
So, what up, man?
You don't value my time?
Nigga, please.
Hand me that screw gun
and calm the fuck down.
Go! Go!
Clear!
Tosha go!
Dante, go, I got your back!
Oh, I got you, baby.
I got you.
Go! Go!
Yo, y'all ready.
Let's bang out.
Go, go, go!
Go!
Come on, Kimmy,
get in the car!
Get in the car, man.
Your department leaks
like a fucking sieve.
It could be someone
over here at the hall.
Someone on your staff.
Someone on the Council.
Well, it doesn't matter now.
We gotta spin it
the best way we can,
which means,
we need you to step up
and take this one
for the team, Erv.
Me?
Tell the newspaper
that the academy class
has been delayed
for some reason.
Lack of recruits
problems in your
personnel division.
Keep it in your shop.
After which,
the Mayor steps in
announces we'll have
an academy class
in january come hell
or high water.
Do it like that,
it's a one-day story.
Mr. Mayor, this was
a budget question.
I was directed
to delay that class.
And you took the hit then
and you're taking the hit now.
And I thank you
for both, Commissioner.
89.
And that's just the ones
with Westside addresses.
You gotta narrow
that shit down
find some way to work
with all them Peanuts.
Motherfucker, do I look like
George Washington Carver?
Cocksuckers got me chasing one
gun through a city full of 'em.
Homicide, yeah.
Two down, Pall Mall
and Pimlico.
Pall Mall
Got it.
Two down, in the street.
Ray Cole's up.
Cole's in court today.
And I caught that cutting
in Cherry Hill last night.
Don't look at me.
I'm in the haystacks, looking
for Dozerman's prodigal gun.
You gonna make me go
back-to-back as a primary?
That's some
cold shit, Bunk.
Agg assault with
a two-by-four?
I don't think so.
Put that with the part twos.
This one too.
Assault by pointing.
If you don't use a handgun
you don't get credit
for waving it, alright?
Larceny here.
Hump wrote this up
as a daytime b-and-e.
Fuck this.
Do it clean.
Don't massage anything.
Don't sex anything down.
We give 'em the fucking truth.
What about comstat, boss?
They'll rip you.
There's five months
to my 30, right?
Fuck 'em if they
can't take a joke.
The Major no doubt
has some explanation
some excuse if you will,
for a weekly felony
tabulation that's going
in the opposite direction
from the other eight districts.
I have none, Sir.
You are content with this?
No, Deputy, I'm unhappy.
I wish we were making
more of an impact.
But doing what we're doing
it's clear that's not the case.
Major Colvin
I am under the impression crime
is down in the Western.
Perhaps you misfigured
your felony stats this week.
No, Sir.
We were very accurate.
Sometimes the gods are...
uncooperative.
Uncooperative?
This is a cooperative effort,
a cooperative department.
Why in the Eastern District,
Lieutenant Daniels exemplified
this new spirit just the other day.
And because of that
we got two fresh
homicides in the black
and a lot less bodies on
the streets than could have been
had that drug war
been allowed to drag on.
Mayor has me taking the hit in public
for the late academy class.
You're kidding me?
Sacrifice for
the greater good.
Where's the fucking
loyalty, I ask you?
But in the Western, what do
I get from a veteran commander?
You're just having a laugh,
aren't you, Bunny?
You got the real stats
and projections somewhere else.
Someone's just outside
the door with them, right?
A stripper, maybe?
That would be nice.
She comes in,
flashes a little tit
gives us a whiff
of that muff
and delivers
my fucking stat sheets
with a reduction that matches
just what we promised the Mayor.
That would be beautiful.
That would be
creme fucking brulee.
But what I got instead
is some half-assed
"I-wish-we-were-doing-better"
platitude that's
meant to fool maybe
a six-year-old girl into
thinking you're doing your job.
well, she's left the room,
Major Colvin.
She's out there right now
asking the stripper
if she can have her job
when she grows up
because she sure as shit
doesn't want yours.
You know why?
Because there isn't gonna be
a goddamn Western District
in 20 years
if this shit keeps up.
I don't care how many years
you have on this job.
if the felony
rate doesn't fall
you most certainly will.
The gods are fucking you,
you find a way to fuck them back.
It's Baltimore, Gentlemen,
the gods will not save you.
She look like a player?
Bystander?
Right in the middle
of it all if she was.
Yo, my turn to be Omar.
No.
Gimme, please, gimme.
Look, I'm tellin'
you, I was there.
Whitefolks was on the stoop
by the nine-oh-nine club,
an' Apex just
standin' over his ass
pumpin' more holes in the boy
than a motherfucker need.
Shit, I ain't lyin',
Soon as that motherfuckin'
nine stops talkin'
whitefolks looks up
at Apex, says:
"Bitch, that
the best you got"?
Man, I'm jus' sayin'
a boy got that much white blood,
he got to be a punk.
You want me, boss?
Your numbers way down, Fruit.
Way down.
It's Barksdale's people.
They clippin' the dope
fiends comin' up Freemont.
You know, when I ran a shop
an' my numbers dropped
I damn sure did
something 'bout it.
- Yeah, I hear that.
- I just want 'em moved.
Take the younguns with you
give 'em a workout.
Alright.
So, Lieutenant
you got an attaboy
from the deputy today, huh.
Cost me my wire tap though.
Still, it's good work
over in the Eastern.
Knocking down a drug war.
Yeah, he's gonna do the same
thing for me up on Park Heights.
I got this Kintel Williamson
character who needs some fixing
and Rawls promised
me Daniels and his unit
for about a month or so.
You're getting quite
the rep there, kiddo?
So Stan, what's your plan
for the Southeast?
How're you gonna
give Rawls his numbers?
I don't know.
Flex squads on the corners
foot patrols
in the Perkins Homes
overtime out the ass.
And if that don't work,
cheat on the stats.
What say you?
Shit, me?
I'm gonna go to 12-hour
shifts on the weekends.
What about you, Bunny?
I dunno.
I thought I might
legalize drugs.
So they hit
the got-damn alley?
And we on 'em.
That cocksmokin' motherfucker
with the big-bitch gun?
He was runnin' hard
on his ass, but...
I think I hit him.
Nigger, you ain't hit nobody.
I mighta hit him.
Yo, String,
we hit the one girl.
But after that, man, I ain't
see nobody catch no lead, man.
'Cept for Tank.
Yeah, Tank gone.
The other broad dropped him.
So I guess we even now.
So you get one, right?
Yeah.
That's good.
That's like a 40-degree day?
Ain't nobody got nothing
to say about a 40-degree day.
50, bring a smile
to your face.
60?
Shit, niggers is down there
barbecuing on that motherfucker.
Go down to 20, niggers
get their bitch on.
Get their blood complainin'.
But 40?
Nobody give a fuck about 40.
Nobody remember 40
and y'all niggers
is giving me way too
many 40-degree days!?
What the fuck!?
Now, we're gonna cover
that bitch's funeral
her fucking wake.
We're gonna be
all over that motherfucker
till the bitch
hit the ground.
And if the faggot roll up
to pay his respects
we're gonna be
on that motherfucker...
yo, who the fuck you
talking to, man?
It's Donette, String.
She been callin'.
No.
Put the phone down.
Y'all feel me on this?
- Yeah.
He show up
we on him
like a motherfucker...
like a 40-degree day.
So, overall
felonies are down
but murders are still up.
What's our next move?
Let me bump overtime
and court pay for homicide
and district ops.
Cases go into the green
before they go into the black.
Done.
And, of course, if we could get
some help at the courthouse
it would go a long way.
If you're going to try
and dig your way out this
don't make me your shovel.
My department is bringing you
casework that goes nowhere.
The cases are thin.
Most wouldn't make it past
a prelim in the court
of a freshman judge.
Well, maybe if your personnel
weren't so got-damned concerned
for their got-damned
conviction rate
they'd chance
a whodunit or two.
Oh, for chrissake!
Jesus, at least pretend
you're on the same side.
Stephen, you and I are both
going to be counting votes
this time next year.
Do something to help
our sorry asses.
And Erv, if you want
to do more than just
finish out walker's term
show me something more
than a pass of the buck.
I don't think any of us
wants to have to get a real job.
Mr. Mayor.
Alright.
I'll see you both
in here on this next week.
Thank you, Sir.
Like children.
Demper's always
been a hack.
But he's an elected hack,
so we're stuck with him.
But burrell, though?
You're vulnerable
on crime, Clarence.
You need to set some
deadwood adrift.
Burrell's got friends.
The ministers?
He might be their man,
but so are you.
You fire Burrell, you get
some new blood in there
the crime rate drops, huh?
The ministers
will live with it.
So you're tough
on deadwood, huh?
In the new 11th
district too, I hear.
Mr. Mayor
it's time for Eunetta to go.
She's had her time
there are better people
out there for the council.
She's on the team, Odell.
just like my police
commissioner.
I value loyalty.
Don't you?
Bunky Bunk.
Where's my Bunk?
Cole's up, not you.
You're on Dozerman's
gun, remember?
Cole's at the courthouse.
Sue me.
Rawls and Foerster
have crawled up into my backside
and they're gonna stay there
until you find Dozerman's gun.
Now, I would like it
very much if I could
unclench my ample asscheeks
if you don't mind
and rid myself
of that discomfort.
Jay, I just caught one
that pushed it's way
all the way to
the top of my stack.
A victim, Jay.
- On the real side.
- Do tell.
Second body in a double.
Girl in her 20s, caught
in the middle of a firefight
takes one in the dome.
But, she's still dead in a zip code
that does not fucking matter
and you still owe me
a departmental-issue nine.
Find the fucking gun, Bunk.
Fuck me.
Kintel Williamson,
who the fuck?
He has corners
in Park Heights.
But Jesus, who doesn't?
So all day we're
calling you, Jimmy
wonderin' where you were at.
Kima, maybe you
can enlighten us.
Don't look at me.
My runnin' buddy don't even tell
me where he's off to these days.
I was at the library.
Bullshit.
The library at M.C.I. Jessup.
D'angelo barksdale
was not a suicide.
The M.E. tell you that?
He didn't need to.
The physical evidence
didn't match up.
Look, I don't like
coming up off Stringer
and Prop Joe
anymore than you do
but McNulty,
this shit is kinda weak.
Cedric is under
a lot of pressure
to use this unit to get
the murder rate down.
So, for now
Stringer Bell's jacket
belongs in narcotics.
Man took you
off a boat, Jimmy.
He want to peel his unit off,
his unit, Jimmy.
And go after the target of his
choice, maybe it's his call.
Lester, I thought you were
all about the best case possible.
When it's there, I am.
Yo, I need y'all
to hear this, man.
It was my fault.
Ya hear me?
I'm sorry, yo.
That don't do nothin' for me.
How come...
they know you're police
when they hook up with you.
And they know you're
police when they move in.
And they know you're police
when they decide
to start a family with you.
And all that shit is just fine
until one day it ain't.
One day, it's:
"you should have
a regular job. "
"You need to be
home at 5:00".
"You need to call more. "
I'm sayin'.
"You need to stop
fucking waitresses. "
I wanna come down
here tomorrow to Western.
See what's what since
those towers came down.
We're supposed to start
on Kintel tomorrow.
Oh, fuck that chump.
He can wait day or two.
Yeah, okay.
What the fuck.
When you were humpin'
a radio car in the Western?
Was this your hole?
Yeah.
Here and down on Winchester.
Under the bridge.
Bet there were a lot
of nights you didn't
go home to the missus.
Don't tell me
I'm the same kinda asshole.
Pucker up, girlfriend.
Jesus.
I'm turning into McNulty.
Hey, I'm going out.
Nah, grandma,
you know I can't.
Times like these,
honey, you have to shine.
In your face, in your clothes
and in your pocket.
Now, go on.
Make sure you get
something to eat, hear?
Go on, now.
You know 'em?
sNot a clue.
Crew on that corner
looks familiar.
A couple old faces.
Not many.
You go away for a year
and the whole world changes up.
Quiet though.
Barksdale loses the towers
and he's able to stretch out
without bodies falling?
I wonder what the Western
guys have been seeing lately.
Hey, Jay.
What the fuck happened?
When?
How is he?
Aw, shit.
You'll let me know, right?
Okay, yeah.
Thanks.
You know Ray Cole?
Homicide, right?
Collapsed in the gym at the
central district this morning.
On a fucking
stairmaster.
Well, how is he?
A stairmaster.
Hey, Puddin', check it out.
Where they at?
I don't know.
Look out, man.
Break it, motherfuckers.
Man said break, come on.
I was workin' on that bitch.
Yeah, Shorty, you hard.
We outta here.
The Commissioner
acknowledged that money
had been budgeted
for the academy class
but said the department
was awaiting approval
of a federal training
and education grant
before scheduling the program.
Burrell can talk
some shit, can't he?
Downtown in the house.
Hey, Kima, baby.
Hey, Ellis.
Herc.
So, what do we
owe the pleasure?
Cruisin' your district, seeing
what's up since the towers fell.
We see Barksdale crews
on a few corners
but no one seems
to be beefin' with 'em.
What's up with
all this brotherhood?
We keep the lid on tight.
You know, they know
we are not their friends
and they damn well know
we'll take it to 'em
if they don't behave.
What do your C.I.'s tell you?
Fuck C.I.'s.
We don't need
no stinkin' C.I.'s.
We tune 'em up, we beat 'em
down, we lock 'em up.
It's the Western District way.
Sergeant
you're wanted in roll call
for a supervisor's meeting.
Gotta go.
Remember, what I told you?
A police is only
as good as his informants?
Well, we ain't downtown
no more, Kima.
We're in the trenches here.
You want information,
you go get your own C.I.
And shoot the shit.
You're late, Sergeant.
I had a couple downtown
detectives in my shop.
They were confused
and required assistance, Sir.
Well, I'll catch you up.
The new strategic plan
for the district
is to move all
street-level trafficking
to these three areas.
We want to push it.
Push it, boss?
If they don't go easy,
then they go hard.
But...
we let these knuckleheads know
that if they
move to these areas...
away from
the residential streets
away from commercial areas,
away from schools...
if they take their
shit down the road
they go about their business
without any interference from us.
It's going to be hands-off
in the Western District
for the foreseeable future.
Bullshit, man,
no fuckin' way.
Wait, wait.
You're saying you want us
to give them a free pass?
How we going to look
them in the eye?
They'll shit all over us.
Tell their kids
to shit all over us.
Hey, the Major
wasn't finished.
You gotta take
the long view here.
Once
once they're all comfortable
once they're all rounded up
once they've been
down there a bit
and they're used to
putting their feet up
and playing wit the remote
then we move.
Then we go back
and we do police work.
Look at it this way, Gentlemen
would you rather
shoot a fish in the ocean?
Or would you rather
gather 'em up
in a few small barrels
and start emptying
your clips then?
Not to mention, you still get to kick
the shit out of all the mopes
who don't move off our corners.
So, it ain't all bad.
Slow up, girl.
Come on now.
So, this your ride?
It's nice.
Suppose you got a Lex.
Nah, girl.
Got a bus pass.
You out the game, then.
Doing a little
landscaping right now.
But tryin' to figure
things out.
So, what's your boy's name?
Allen.
After Iverson?
After his daddy.
What?
Trying to picture
you mowing a land.
I don't be wearin' the suit.
You look good in it still.
You look good too.
You know they bought
a lot a folks out
with early retirement
in parks and rec.
I could maybe hook you up
with someone to talk to.
A man at my church
is helping the city
fill a lot of those jobs.
That would be...
thank you.
Write your
number there.
He'll call you.
I gotta go.
It was good seeing you.
Grace.
Looking at you.
What?
Hurts.
Shouldn't look then.
Food blast'll
take yer mind off it.
Rather my mind on it, Bubs?
Swear I'm sick
of all this, man.
Wonderin' when
I got so old.
How 'bout some more
mac n' cheese, huh?
Hey, Bubs.
Kima.
Hey, Bub.
McNutty, man, my mainest man.
You ready to put
some work in?
Born ready.
Snitchin'?
Fuck that, Bubs.
Hey, hey, nah, man.
Better than liftin'
500 pound radiators.
I'm up for these two, Johnny.
It's easy money, man.
C'mon
let's grab a burger.
Mind if I bang
outta here early?
I ain't right
with this Cole thing.
Gonna be a detectives'
wake at Kavanagh's tonight.
You gonna come?
Barely knew the guy.
You all layin' him
out at the bar, huh?
Tradition.
Tomorrow night, he goes
the funeral home for family.
Tonight, Ray drinks
with the boys.
C'mon, Bubs,
we ain't got all day.
And he's up for re-election
and he's never had a single one
of his goo-goo bills
pass the committee.
So, he's got one for
all-day kindergarten
I mean who's gonna argue
with more kindergarten?
I mean, this guy
has got a bill which is
the legislative equivalent
of kissing a baby.
So, right, he goes
to his chairman
pleads his case and says:
"You know, this don't
go through, I'm torched. "
"I'm going to be back
in that hardware store, mixing paint. "
So, the chairman
takes pity and agrees
gets the bill to the floor.
But the house speaker?
He hates this bill.
So, it gets loved
to death, you know...
slap on an amendment
for another 150 mil in costs
subsidies, handouts and
the bill goes down in flames.
122 to 10.
The delegate, he can
smell those paint cans.
And the chairman says:
"Hey, sorry brother,
I fought like a tiger for that bill. "
Who wants friends like that?
You want friends
in this racket, get a dog.
What?
I need to talk to him.
Look, just tell
him it's Donette.
Yeah, he know
who the fuck I am.
- YoSstring, she say...
- Not now.
Look, he say not now,
I gotta go.
Marlo.
It's a problem, String.
Club soda and lime.
You'll never
get there that way.
Get where?
Excuse me.
How the hell was I to know
the Mayor was gonna
put the screws to you?
You read the paper?
I look like shit.
Hey, you got your class
and probably scored points
with Royce out
of sheer loyalty, right?
We are police
so no lies between us.
He wasn't
the greatest detective
and he wasn't the worst.
He put down some good cases
and he dogged a few bad ones.
But, the motherfucker
had his moments.
Yes, he fucking did.
You remember
the Mississippi extradition
the Arson murders?
He brought that case home.
And the triple
at the after-hours
over on Hudson Street?
That was Ray Cole at his best.
And Fayette Street...
in '93, the drug wars.
He took a lot of hot
corners and cooled 'em.
Yes, indeed.
He won as much as he lost
much as any of us.
For chrissakes, Hugh, play
the fucking song already.
Did he piss off
a wife or three?
No fucking doubt.
I think the last one
actually kinda got used
to him, thank God.
Did he say the wrong
shit now and then?
Did he bust balls
and cheat on his taxes
and forget to call his mother
and fuck the wrong broad
for the wrong fucking
reason every now and then?
Who fucking doesn't, Christ?
Was he as full of shit
as every other sadsack
motherfucker wearing
a badge of Baltimore City Police?
Abso-fucking-lutely.
His shit was as weak
as ours, no question.
But Ray Cole stood with us,
all of us
in Baltimore
working
sharing a dark corner
of the american experiment.
He was called.
He served.
He is counted.
Old king Cole.
Old king Cole!
I'm sorry, but I gotta
get these guys home.
But all things considered,
I think they did pretty well.
They were great.
And you were great,
really, Jen.
Besides, I think they got
all the family shots they need.
So, you'll be awhile,
though, huh?
Gotta work the crowd,
you know?
Make 'em think
I'm worthy of their faith.
You are.
- Well, thank you...
- Most of the time.
Bitch.
Not too late if you
can help it, okay?
Shit is fucked.
You fucking wake up,
like any other day.
You fucking eat
and think about bills
and dry cleaning and shit
and fucking vacation
and your fucking
retirement plan and what?
Like that.
He checked out of here
with you still owing him
a clearance on that Omar thing.
Oh, I know, I know.
I fucking know.
Like that.
On a fucking stairmaster.
Wake up an' die
right, you cunts.
What's goin' on, man?
That whip is pretty, yo.
I gotta get me one
of them joints someday.
Shit. Yeah.
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
Transcript par Raceman
Synchronisation: El Uploador
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net