That's far enough.
Drop your laundry
and turn slowly.
So, you gonna
rob me now?
I need to remind you
who I am?
Omar, isn't it?
Pull it slowly.
Then toss it.
Oh, I will move slow.
But I ain't tossin' nothin'
bow tie.
So whatever you gonna do
you might as well go ahead
and make it quick.
I knew you'd come back.
I trust you didn't
lose sleep over it.
Worryin' about you would
be like wonderin'
if the sun's gonna come up.
I ain't about to wild out over it.
What I want to know is
how you find me?
Your boy, he didn't
give you up easy.
Ain't sugar-water runnin'
through them veins.
- You kill him?
- He's resting.
I see you favor a 45.
Tonight I do.
And I keeps one in the chamber,
in case you ponderin'.
Nice show piece
you got there.
Walther PPK.
380, double action.
Hear them walthers
like to jump some.
As will you,
with one in your elbow.
That gun ain't got enough firepower
to make my joint useless.
It definitely won't stop me
from emptyin' out half my mag.
- You might not hit me.
- This range?
And this caliber?
Even if I miss,
I can't miss.
I admire a man
with confidence.
I don't see no sweat
your brow neither, bro.
I suppose we could
stand here all night.
S'pose we could.
Or settle this
once and forever.
I want to ask you something... brother.
Omar listenin'.
Middle Ground
A-ight, me, too.
A- ight.
Here we go.
Yo, I need some
face time with the man.
Hold up, I'll holler
back at you, man.
That would be Shamrock.
Assuming Stringer Bell is the man,
now we wait for the return call.
This is beautiful.
Lester, can you actually
believe we fucking sold
the wiretaps to the targets.
For a week at least.
Maybe we duck the bullet.
Maybe we clean this mess quietly,
throw some horseshit at
whatever reporter shows up
and the Mayor
forges and forgets.
We're ready to move on this, right?
As soon as we get the word,
we shut down all three zones
toss everyone into wagons.
There'll be nothing left
of it before midnight shift.
So what the fuck are we
waiting on for a day and half?
Why isn't the Hall calling us?
Commissioner Burrell
for Mayor Royce.
- I've heard enough...
- Hold on, Coleman.
Come on, let the man talk, huh?
Excuse me, Mayor. I have
Commissioner Burrell on the line.
- He says it's urgent.
- I'll bet it is.
He wants to move, Clarence.
He wants to clean this shit up
yesterday, and so do we.
Tell him to hold.
- Go ahead, gene.
- Look
I'm not a politician,
I'm an academic.
All I know is that from a
public health perspective
there are remarkable things
happening in the free zones.
Needle exchanges, on-site blood
testing, condom distribution.
Most of all we're interacting
with an at-risk community
that is largely elusive.
We're even talking some of these
people into drug treatment.
And that's just what U.M. and
Bon Secours have brought to the table.
If this thing were sanctioned
my department could put
public resources into play.
You people can't
see the forest here.
Odell?
When the story breaks, the ministers
will surely be against you.
And most of the City Council
will be walking sideways
away from your administration.
And my guess is the Governor
and the legislature
will use this opportunity to piss on
the city from a great height.
And Washington?
Oh...
Can you imagine how far
the United States
Department of Justice
is gonna crawl up
your ass behind this?
Crime is down, Odell.
Medical people are
telling me this could work.
I mean, a 14% decline
in felonies citywide
I might be untouchable on this.
Now, look, we need to think
see if we can keep
this thing going without
calling it what it really is, huh?
- Jesus.
- Now, there's got to be a way.
I want you to talk this thing out.
Hey, Erv, thanks for holding...
Yes, but...
Yes, I understand.
Then I'll wait
to hear from you.
We're to hold off
on any action in Amsterdam.
No arrests, no movement
until further notice.
He says he wants to regroup.
Determine the most
effective course of action.
Translate that for me, will ya, Erv?
I don't speak his fucked-up lingo.
Royce is figuring a way to put
all of us in the guillotine
and keep the blood from
spraying anywhere near the Hall.
Shit, I'll be goddamned if
I'm gonna go out like that:
Bent over in public.
I can spin the story just as
well as that motherfucker.
- You're gonna go to the press?
- Not me.
But I know a slick little bastard
who will happily
put Hizzoner's shit in the street.
Somethin' funny 'bout that?
'Cause I look in the paper and I see
all these federal grants comin' down
but nothin' for B-and-B.
- You're expecting what?
- Payout.
A big payout for what
we put in, man.
Federal dollars on them
Howard Street rehabs.
- You gave money up front?
- 250,000, yep.
To Clay Davis.
How you know?
What you sayin'?
He's runnin' game?
Naw, hell no, he ain't that brazen.
Lemme guess.
He told you about the faucet.
Or was it the goose
that laid the golden egg?
You ever actually
meet the man?
Did you ever actually see any of
your cash reach anyone in authority?
Yeah, I met the guy
at the federal building.
Yeah, I met him.
Yeah, what office?
He came down to the lobby.
he rainmade you.
A guy says if you pay him,
he can make it rain.
You pay him. If and when it rains,
he takes the credit.
If and when it doesn't, he finds
reasons for you to pay him more.
Clay Davis rainmade you.
Naw, man, he got them building
permits in no time at all, man.
I mean, we bribing
these motherfuckers.
He got the city
contractor's money back.
- How much?
- 35,000 so far.
- On a quarter million you gave him?
- It's for bribing the motherfuckers.
There are no bribes!
You really think
a state senator is going
to risk his salary
and his position
by walking into a federal office with
a briefcase full of drug money?
I seen Chunky... Chunky Coates.
Chunky Coates gets his grant money
same way everyone does.
He fills out applications,
he makes sure the plans meet spec
then he prays like hell.
This is an old game in this
town, and Clay Davis?
That goniff was born with
his hand in someone's pocket.
I just wish you'd have
run it by me sooner.
Now here's Shamrock
returning Bodie's call.
Talk about it.
Yo, the man said he'd see you,
same time as always.
You know the spot.
During the first call, Sydnor had eyes
on Shamrock over in West Baltimore.
Alright? Now look at this.
At the time, Stringer Bell
was at the print shop.
So it couldn't be
a face-to-face meet.
We didn't catch a call between
Stringer and Shamrock.
How can that be?
Stringer's phone isn't on the same
network as everyone below him.
- Right you are, ma'am.
- Bell's not using Bernard's burners?
And Shamrock has a separate
phone for calling Bell.
We can't hear those calls because
the system's compartmentalized.
Some tricky motherfuckers.
A week or so up on Bernard's phones
and we'll have everybody
up to and including Shamrock
tangled up in conspiracy counts.
But Bell or Barksdale?
Not unless we can pluck their
cell numbers out the air.
Where you headed?
Toy store.
He legalized drugs
in special zones?
It's more
than that.
Major Colvin lost
the necessary perspective
that is required for command.
We were all under pressure
to reduce crime before year end
and he responded poorly
to that pressure.
Pressured by who?
Mayor?
I'm just explaining to you
that the pressure was applied
all down the line
from headquarters
to the district commanders
to the shift
and sector supervisors.
So Colvin's 14% decline was bullshit.
And they're selling drugs
with police permission in Western?
The department is ready to shut that
mess down with mass arrests.
- I'm on top of it.
- Why don't you move?
The Mayor says wait.
Why?
I think he's gonna
make some kinda show.
Spin it so that
I take the weight
for something that has
nothing to do with me
and everything to do
with the pressure
that my commanders
are getting from City Hall.
Going public and putting the
responsibility for this
back at City Hall is the only
move I have left, right?
I mean, I spin Royce
before he spins me.
- And you want me to...
- Not you.
Your pal, Tony Gray.
If he's gonna take a run at Royce,
he's gonna need ammunition, right?
I don't have a relationship with Gray.
I do have one with you.
And Councilman?
You owe me.
- What's up, hotshot?
- I got a technical question.
Remember those
analog units we used
to use to pull cell
numbers out of the air?
The C.F. something-something...
Yeah, Cell Frequency
Identification Device.
- The triggerfish, yeah.
- That one, it could flag a number.
Right, but the old analog machines?
We used to have to
follow the guy around
stay close while he used the phone.
New digitals...
bing, we just pull the number
right off the cell towers.
So, you got any down out at
Woodlawn that daddy can borrow?
- What about yours?
- What?
City has three of 'em,
I remember right.
Homeland security
grant sent 'em to you
every big county department
in the state.
No fucking way.
Thanks.
- I doubted you, Tommy.
- I told you it was big.
If we play it right.
He wants me to turn the
information over to Tony Gray...
and let him use it, he figures if
Tony's running against the Mayor
he'll take aim at Royce
and not the department.
We may want to bring
Tony in on it
keep him viable
against the Mayor.
But right now, you need to find
out what this is all about.
Firsthand... do you know
this, Major Colvin?
To shake hands, maybe.
If Burrell's painting
him the villain
Colvin might be anxious to tell
someone his side of the story.
McNulty, Major Crimes.
Sullivan, minor irritations.
You got anything back there that's like
the old C.F.I.D. but digital?
- For catching cell numbers?
- Catching who?
You know, a triggerfish machine.
Triggerfish. For cell numbers.
How 'bout I look around
there on my own?
Yes, this is Councilman
Carcetti over at the Hall.
I'm trying to reach Major Colvin.
I'm sorry, but
he's on vacation.
I'm aware of that, but I'm trying to
reach him on municipal business...
Well, I could put you
through to his voice mail.
No, not his voice mail. I said I have
to reach him immediately...
- Immediately?
- Right...
- How about his cell phone?
- His cell, it'll be fine...
Alright. Four-oh...
Alright, that's enough.
Yeah, I know, it hurts.
But your fists gonna
be like rocks after awhile.
Justin, c'mere.
- Alright.
- I want you to push me on my chest.
You ain't got to do it hard.
That's how you was standin'.
You ain't have no weight
on your back foot.
That's right.
No center of gravity.
Plus, if you get your stance right...
then you got the means
to put your hip into the punch.
Bub-bub, right?
Bub-bub.
That's where your power come from.
Yeah, but what happened
when we get hit?
- Say what?
- We get hit
even with this pad,
you gonna get trucked.
All this stuff fallin' apart.
Yeah, the heavy bag, too.
Yeah, where you get this stuff at?
The Town of Bedrock?
Naw, he said nobody. So you
gonna have to wait right here.
What you mean wait right here?
You know who I am, boy?
Man say he want
to see Avon...
Makin' me wait
to see my own partner?
- He new, String.
- Fuck that.
Lotta new faces round here, man...
Way too many, you ask me.
Get the fuck out of here.
- Where Avon at?
- He'll be along shortly.
That's good 'cause
I came to see you, anyway.
What you need?
I need you to hit somebody.
Who we hittin'?
- Clay Davis.
- The Clay Davis?
Downtown Clay Davis?
That suppose to mean
somethin' to me, man?
- That nigger need to be got.
- Shit, String, murder ain't no thing.
But this here is some
assassination shit...
Look, I tell you you gettin'
somebody, you getting him.
- I ain't askin'.
- Damn, String, I don't know...
Nigger, I got to remind you
who the fuck you work for?!
Hey, yo. I think Slim gonna have
to sit this one out, boss.
So you gonna hit a
state senator now, huh?
Yo, you kill a downtown nigger
like that the whole world
gonna stand up and take notice.
I'm talking about the state police,
federals, all of that.
You need a day-of-the-jackal
type motherfucker
basically to do
some shit like that.
Not a rough and tumble
nigga like Slim.
- That nigger took our money, man.
- I seen it comin'.
Well. He got to go.
Naw, you a fucking businessman.
You'd wanna handle it like that.
You don't wanna get all gangster
wild with it an' shit, right?
What I tell you bout playin'
them fucking away games?
Yeah.
They saw your ghetto ass
comin' from miles away, nigger.
You got a fucking beef with them?
That shit is on you.
So... we aim this
at the nearest celltower
the one that would
be the conduit for calls
coming to and from our boy, Bell.
And...
we let rip.
Fucking hell.
Look's like Baltimore white pages,
without any names.
But the pattern trace
will pull that down.
You know, if we know the approximate
time of Bell's call
we can start just by pulling calls
off that tower, at that time.
That could be thousands.
Yeah, that's the baseline,
but we get a second hit
- and that list comes down to dozens.
- And after a third or fourth...
then we've got his number.
I can't believe that this was just
sitting over at I.S.D. gathering dust.
We're going to be on these
motherfuckers for real now, Lester.
They don't know about
this technology yet.
For once they can't
change and adjust.
It's genius.
Oh, happy day
when jesus washed
oh when he washed
he washed my sins away.
You need something?
How much you make?
What?
On them tees?
How much you make?
A fair profit.
No more than that.
You should probably sell
sweats with hoodys.
Since the seasons changin' an' all.
Where you live at?
Yellow Tops, Yellow Tops,
got them Yellow Tops.
Bodie Broadus.
The man with the hands.
I heard was, um, openin' up
a gym or somethin'.
Yeah, tryin' to.
I'm lookin' to get up with Avon.
- Thought you was out.
- Man, that's why I'm came to you.
I mean, I feel like
the way we left it
I can't just roll up
on the man, you know?
hey, yo, it's me.
Yo, I got that hitter here with me.
Yeah, the soldier
that walked in and out.
Yeah, he want to see the top man.
You slam shit like that
you gonna fall out one day.
I'm good.
I'm tryin' to school you, boy
and you just don't wanna know.
I'm cool, Huck.
I'm good.
Whitey sale,
whitey sale.
One for three,
three for five.
Whitey sale, whitey sale.
Whitey sale, whitey sale!
Alright, so what you
want me to tell the man?
Yo, I'll give word up
and then I'll hit you back.
Shamrock.
4:40 P.M.
B- and-B enterprises...
- We need to have lunch.
- Alright, hold on, I'll call you back.
- Yo.
- It's me.
It's good.
Yeah, it's me.
Yo, tell the hitter, tell him
the tall man pick him up.
- Right.
- 4:47.
A seven minute window.
There's 892 phone numbers.
That's our baseline.
- We're on our way.
- Yep.
Stay the fuck there, man.
Yo.
Jimmy! On the clean phone.
He just hit your friend's number.
The one off the business
card you gave me.
- The Western?
- His cell.
Should we be worried
about this?
Naw.
- A boxing gym, huh?
- It ain't a proper one yet.
Why I asked to see you.
So, what you know about takin'care
of something like that?
Not a damn thing.
But I know that sweet science.
And I got some kids
who are interested.
What I got a need for,
bro, is equipment.
Man, these kids
gonna get rained on.
They need headgear,
they need guards, cups
you know, so they
can take the hit.
Shoot, you know what
I'm sayin', man.
I seen your picture on them
globe posters back in the day.
Undercard shit, maybe, you know.
Yeah, but still,
you was golden gloves.
For a minute.
But I had a physical defect.
What, you had a glass jaw?
- Nah, forehead, nigger.
- Cranium shot'll do you wrong.
Yeah, look here, man.
You seen new heavy bags?
Look, freestandin', man.
All you gotta do is add water.
Then you got speed bags,
right there, right?
You got this headgear
right here. It's new.
Look, protect the cheek
and the chin.
You know.
And I know I can go around and
collect a dollar here, dollar there.
But I'm trying to put together
a select group of people, right?
I call them my,
my gold circle club
and they gonna make
a substantial contribution
and just get
this thing rollin' right.
I mean, I'm gonna put their name and
picture up on the wall in the gym.
What you tryin' to get
me to join a club?
Naw, man, I'm just sayin'.
There's all sorts of levels.
We got the, the silver club,
we got the bronze club.
Man, for motherfuckers who really
don't want to dig that deep.
Come on, man, check it out.
Nah, man, I ain't got no time
for this bullshit, man.
You know I don't want
my fucking name and face
on no damn wall.
You crazy, nigger?
How much money you talkin' about?
$10,000.
I see you go through
all that for 10,000?
Man, slim, go get him $15,000 cash.
Yo.
Shit.
A- ight, then.
Hey, you take care
of them little niggas, hear?
No doubt, bro.
- Yeah. Yo, you talk to him?
- Fat man wanna parlay.
- Alright, you good, hook me up.
- Yeah, a-ight.
You check out what I sent you?
Yeah, your information was good.
So, we can talk on the
real side now, huh?
Tell your man
I'm good for tomorrow.
Yo, I'll hit you back.
- Now we're cooking.
- Cutting butter with a hot knife.
Next time Stringer Bell takes a
call off the baseline he's ours.
Game over.
So, it ain't what
it might seem to you.
That man there
is my brother.
But if it keep on
like it been, then...
You got problems?
I stirred up some shit
with this Hampsterdam mess.
That's 'cause
you was behind that
that made me come
to you with this.
Look like you and me both tryin'
to make sense of this game.
Speak your mind, Russell.
You two good?
Yeah.
We got y'all out front.
Let's go, p-square.
You look healthy.
For a man who was gutshot.
You reached out to a third party
who engaged me in the purpose
of holding your towers.
That third person's word
was your word
as he represented you.
That's right.
And I ran those
East Baltimore gentlemen off.
I held up my end
of the agreement
at least for as long
as I was physically able.
You did.
Your man then set up
a meet at Butchie's bar.
Your man told Omar Little
that I was responsible
for the torture of a young boy
who was close to Mr. Little's heart.
Your man
in effect
sought to have me hit.
Omar told you that?
And you believe that motherfucker?
He doesn't strike me as
a man who would tell stories
even at the point of dying.
Shit.
Proposition Joe package.
The inner workings of your
organization don't concern me.
If there's a way,
I mean, if my man...
if he made
a mistake here
then I'm willing
to pay the cost.
How can we fix it?
You want money?
Money?
Yeah, this is business.
Business is where you are now.
But what got you here is
your word and your reputation.
With that alone, you've still
got an open line to New York.
Without it, you're done.
If my man's still on paper.
I can put him in a spot
that got heavy artillery.
I ain't talkin'about pistols.
I'm talkin' about
mini-tech nines,
shotguns, they even got
grenades in that motherfucker.
That's an automatic fall.
So, I'm hopin' you could
keep that shit to five.
Look, if you hit the joint
his people are gonna try
and take the wrap for it.
They gonna say all
that firepower is theirs.
So all you gotta do is just hit
him with the parole back-up.
Look, I can't make no promises.
- It's gonna be a nickel, at least.
- Come on, man.
- Him and me...
- I'm gonna do my best, alright.
He's always at this place?
Naw, he come and go.
But it's the spot
since the war started.
He musta done
something to you.
Naw, it's just business.
Almost forgot.
This came in for you last night.
Said she called your cell phone,
but you didn't answer.
She had a nice voice.
Like a kitty-cat.
We're on.
He say for you
to be there, half-pint.
Yeah, okay.
Stringer Bell, that's him.
- There it is.
- Yeah, but for how long?
He could toss that
burner at any moment.
I got Rhonda,
you raise Daniels.
Okay.
Ronnie, yeah, we're
on Stringer's phone.
Lieutenant.
- You should go straight to the judge.
- I'll meet you there with an affidavit.
- Lester's raising Daniels.
- McNulty's calling Pearlman.
Watch that footwork, baby.
Alright.
Take it to him now.
I'm a beast, coach.
Alright, boy, don't
be gloatin' on it.
Yo, when we gonna
have some real fights?
You know, one of them
tournament things.
Yeah, we gladiators, son.
Y'all got more fire than skills.
You ain't ready for
no full-blown thing just yet.
But I don't know, maybe it
be good for you all to spar
with some boys you don't know.
A nigga step in my house,
he gettin' dropped.
I met these fellas at that gym
over on Pennsylvania Avenue.
I'll see if
they wanna roll through.
A- ight?
A- ight. A-ight.
You don't return
a councilman's calls?
I'm off this week.
Taking a little
accrued vacation.
Yeah.
And I heard why.
I'm here for your side
of this story.
If I can't get that,
then whatever comes out of
Burrell's mouth is gonna stand.
You good with that?
What did you do, Major?
And why the fuck haven't
they shut it down?
We've seen that law enforcement
steam roller approach
is just spitting in the wind.
I really think that you're
onto something here, Clarence.
But if you keep it up
before you know it,
they'll be calling you the most
dangerous man in america.
Well, I know it may appear that
we're vulnerable here, huh?
But if we enforce the drug laws
everywhere else in the city,
aggressively
how can they say we're not
a law-and-order administration.
Now there's got
to be a middle ground here
that we have yet to find.
There's got to be some way
to accomplish this
without turning
everything upside down.
This used to be one
of my worst corners.
This is the neighborhood
where a cop got shot
last summer, right?
Dozerman.
Looks quiet now.
So do most all my corners.
G- man.
So, what's up?
Shut the door.
In 10 minutes we're gonna
have an affidavit
for a city judge to sign:
It's for Russell Bell's dirty cell.
It's a good pull.
It is if Bay Wireless doesn't
take five days to process it.
You owe me, Fitz.
That whole port case
came down early behind
some ugly shit in your house.
Now, I don't care how you do it,
but I need my wire today.
These guys were in radio cars
two months ago
chasing calls, clearing corners.
I pulled them to do
felony follow-up.
More police work, less bullshit,
and that's why my crime is down.
My numbers are true.
What'd he do?
Church burglaries,
14 of 'em.
Let's go.
Mademoiselle.
Is it aff-ee-ant
or aff-I-ant.
I've never been
clear on that.
You been hunting this guy Bell
for a long time, haven't you, Jimmy?
A while, yeah.
Name's familiar to me.
That the thing that we did
a few years back, was he the...
yeah.
What's done is done, Jimmy.
Now, for your own fucking sake,
just let it go.
Come on.
As the affiant
do you solemnly swear
and attest that the information
contained in this document...
That's the most sign
ificant dropin crime in this district
in recent history.
We still got some hard lookin'
boys out on them streets.
An' Sergeant, them
little mini-motorcycles
they keepin' me up at night.
We're working on that.
I have been livin' in this part
of the city my whole life.
And I can tell you something.
We weren't any angels
when we were kids.
And those are hard boys you
talkin' about, half of 'em
they just playin' gangster.
They no different
from what we were.
Shirts and drawers
a little longer, is all.
The one thing I do miss
about my neighborhood
I'm talking about the
neighborhood I came up in.
See, we knew the police.
See?
We had a white police officer,
our house was on his beat
on his foot beat
and he would be sitting out talking
to my mother damn near every night.
I mean just sittin' out
on her stoop just talking.
And I'm telling you, this man,
his name was Frazier O'Leary.
He even knew
my grandmother by name.
Yes, ma'am.
Now let's move on to the
tip-line information...
I'm so sorry, baby.
I'm real sorry,
but I was not finished.
You see, let me
tell you something.
I have not seen that
face-to-face policein'
in a long while.
In a very long while.
Until last week.
A young officer, black officer,
came by my stoop, I was sitting out
gave me his card.
His name was Reggie Ballard,
is his name, right?
And he said,
and he talked to me.
We just talked.
And see now I know
his name and face
and he knows
my name and face.
You see?
And I'm going to tell you something.
That is how it should be.
My son wants to open up
one of them snowball
stands on the street.
Do he need
a permit for this?
You ever seen a Westside
community meeting like this one?
In fact, folks downtown
at minor privileges
tell me that stands aren't allowed
in the citywide way at all.
Now they do say it is possible
to have a snowball stand
behind the sidewalk...
Why are you really
down here, Councilman?
I mean, this ain't
even your district.
I'm interested.
I have the Public
Safety Subcommittee.
See that buding there?
Was the old Stryker building.
It was a funeral parlor
the last stop before the cemetery
for Westside white folk
back when there were
still some of those around.
Right 'bout the time that...
Jim Crow was breakin' up
back in the early 60s
somebody ask
old man Stryker, they say
"Stryker, you gonna change your
policy and start buryin' black folk. "
And Stryker said
"yeah, on one condition:
If I can do all of them at once. "
That's sick.
You know somethin'?
I had a lot of
respect for that man.
'Cause, unlike most folks
I always knew where he stood.
I'm doing my job.
Look, I done showed
you the good.
Come on, let me show
you the ugly.
Hey, how come so quick?
Stringer Bell's given name?
Russell.
For now.
Achmed.
We're on the top
of the mountain.
Come get 'em,
come get 'em.
This is it?
One of three.
How did you
make this happen?
I just did it.
I got tired of hearin' folks
talk about what needed
to be done or...
what they would do
if it were up to them.
Got them bottle rockets,
bottle rockets.
So, what, this is about
you making a mark?
Nah, I ain't analyzed it
all that deep.
I ain't claimin' no kind
of victory, neither.
I will say,
I'm glad I tried.
Go on, Councilman.
I'll wait for you down here.
You're not comin'?
What you're gonna
see ain't pretty.
But you're safe.
W.M.D'S.,
Got them W.M.D'S.
Think you need to take
this journey your ownself.
Yellow tops.
Yellow tops, right here.
I ordered one for you.
Thanks.
Surprised I called?
A little.
After the way we left it.
I'm a type-a, Jimmy.
People like me break things.
When I slow down, or when I take
a minute to think about it, I...
Is that your idea
of an apology?
I didn't drive an hour
up 95 to apologize.
I missed you.
I missed you,
too, I guess.
Still, seems like a long way
to come just to tell me that
then turn around
and drive back down to D.C.
I'm not driving back tonight.
So what's goin' on?
You working on a case?
It's a good one.
How about you?
Anything interestin'?
I did hear a crazy
Baltimore story
you know through
the rumor of Washington.
Really?
Some...
renegade police commander
takes it on himself to
I dunno, legalize drugs
in the precinct.
Mayor doesn't
even know about it.
Can you believe that?
Crazy story.
Someone...
I think it's Colvin.
You know him?
No, I can't say that I do.
Still, I think
it's funny that some...
water-cooler talker down in D.C.
Knows any Baltimore cop's name.
I was just wondering.
Listen, I'm...
- You're leaving?
- Yeah, I think so.
Goodnight.
Damn, man, I miss
this crib already.
Yeah, well, you spendin' a lot
of time at the other spot
doin' what
you gotta do, huh.
Yeah.
Man, it's a shame we got to deal
with this Marlo bullshit, man.
I mean if I had taken
care of that earlier, man...
There's always gonna
be a Marlo, man.
No Marlo, no game.
But you coulda dealt
with that shit a little sooner.
I mean, yeah, but
you know what I'm sayin'
don't let it lay
on you like that.
Tonight, I mean, I'm gonna kick
back and just enjoy this view.
I mean, look at this shit.
Can you fucking
believe this?
I mean, I got a crib
that's overlooking the harbor.
This is the same place we used
to run through this motherfucker.
We had every security
guard in there...
following us.
As they should have.
True, true.
And then there was
that one time...
Toy store.
Hell yeah, I told your ass
not to steal the badminton set.
What you gonna do
with a fucking net
and a racket and we
ain't got no yard.
Uou like, "yo, that white boy
ain't gonna jump over
that counter
and come chase after me. "
He sure did, though.
And he said, "whschooooo".
I said, "what the fuck... "
He was on your ass
like Carl Lewis.
Fist was rolled up.
Your ass was runnin' too,
fast as you could.
Punching yourself in the chest
looking all mad an' shit.
That shit was crazy, man.
Right here, too, man,
right there.
Goddamn.
Can you imagine, man, if I had
the money that I have now, man
I coulda bought half
this waterfront property.
Goddamnit.
Forget about that
for awhile, man.
Just dream with me.
We ain't got
to dream no more, man.
We got real shit
real estate
we can touch.
I can't get too
fucked up tonight, man.
I got some shit I gotta
do on the site tomorrow.
Plus, the fucking polack
we got working for us, man
I gotta pull his coat.
If he had anything to do with
that Clay Davis bullshit, man
I'm gonna have to cut
his money, little faggot.
What time y'all meetin'?
What time, 12...
I think, why?
You need me to do
something for you?
Naw, just seeing where
you going to be at.
You need to relax
more, man.
All in time, is right.
I will.
You know I don't take
my work... too seriously.
That's right.
It's just business.
Us, motherfucker.
To us, man.
Hit him, Andre,
go get him.
Come on, Spider.
- Alright?
- I'm good, I'm good.
Alright.
Alright, Ditty, you up.
You, Justin.
C'mon, boy, I'm callin' your name.
Alright, listen up, we're gonna
have three two-minute rounds.
Watch the low blows.
Touch gloves.
And...
Let's go, Justin.
Come on.
That's good, that's good.
Come on, man.
Block that.
He leadin' left
and punchin' right, Justin.
Move towards his weak side.
He only come up
to your waist.
Oh, man, bell.
That was a quick two minutes.
Yeah, I know.
Get you some water, boy,
and spit it out.
You alright?
Dizzy.
That's why the hell I keep
tellin' you got to breathe, boy.
So, what?
You had enough?
Nah, I'm good.
Alright, alright.
- Let's go, Justin.
Jab, Justin, jab.
Hey, we're up.
Here it is.
- It's me, man.
- You heard from the fat man?
Yeah.
We low, right?
One mark shy of the mark.
Yeah, it's light.
Cherry says it's light.
Well, tell the man
I'm doin' what needs done.
A-ight, I'll tell him.
- Oh, an' that other thing...
- Huh?
Them two hitters
you asked after.
They good with it.
Not on the phone.
That's it.
We got!
Good work.
I guess this is pertinent.
Ain't no need
to go back out.
You ain't got
to prove nothin'.
Shoot, my momma hit me
harder than that.
I still got a chance,
he gettin' tired.
Drink and spit.
Ready.
You more than ready, boy.
You a game rooster.
Let's go, Justin!
Is there an alley entrance?
Boarded up on both sides.
We gonna have to go
through the front.
That's a change
for you, isn't it?
You just be ready, bow tie.
Know what I'm talkin' about?
Breathe, boy.
Breathe.
Touch gloves.
How I do?
You still got
plenty to learn.
But on the heart side?
You did good.
Go on, soldier.
You done for today.
Oh, I can see it
all clearly now.
Between you and them subcontractors
and that motherfuckin' politician
you all had me
in a spin, right.
- Mr. Bell, I don't know...
- Little man!
We gonna get all
this shit sorted out.
And hey, if the shit
don't come up right
one way or another
you gonna pay for this shit.
Look, I understand you're angry
but at the same time you can see
the progress we've made in here.
Progress.
Now I honestly don't know what
passed between you and Senator Davis.
But if you're unhappy
with Clayton's performance
then you have
to work that out...
Oh, shit.
Oh God.
Oh, God, no.
I ain't strapped.
Look, man, I ain't involved.
I ain't involved in
that gangster bullshit no more.
What you niggas want, man?
Money?
Is that it?!
'Cause if it is, man, I can be
a better friend to y'all alive.
You still don't
get it, do you?
This ain't about
your money, bro.
Your boy gave you up.
That's right.
And we ain't had
to torture his ass, neither.
This seem like...
I can't say nothin'
to change y'all minds.
Well, get on with it,
motherfuckers!
Transcript par Raceman
Sous-titres par la Wired Team:
EZ et El Uploador.
www. thewire-france. com
www. forom. com
www.tvsubtitles.net