On this Sunday
before the primary,
When we will go to the polls
to exercise our blessed franchise,
our lesson comes from
Exodus chapter 18...
"and it came to pass,
on the morrow,
"that Moses sat
to judge the people:
"and the people stood by him
"from the morning
unto the evening.
"And Moses judged the people.
"And he shouldered this
tremendous burden all alone.
"And one day,
his father-in-law said to him,
"Moses,
why do you carry
"this awesome responsibility
by yourself?
'You need other wise men
to help you rule
justly over the people.'
"So Moses harkened to the voice
of his father-In-Law,
and chose able men
to rule over the people."
Can I preach it like I feel it?
This Tuesday,
when we choose the men and women
who will lead our city,
we would do well to keep
those standards in mind.
Men of truth.
Who fear God
and hate covetousness.
God bless you.
Good to see you.
How you doing?
- Just fine.
- How's mama?
Tell her I said hello.
Fellowship committee at 2?
- If I'm late...
- We'll wait.
All right.
Thank you for coming,
young man, young lady.
- Reverend.
- Councilman.
Mrs. Carcetti. How are you?
- Thank you so much for having us.
- Thank you.
Interesting sermon.
Polls seem to think
you have a chance.
Well, we're within
the margin of error.
Margin of error.
That's an interesting phrase.
And I see you've got delegate
Watkins working the crowd.
Well, I'm hoping he's
not going to be the only one.
I'll tell you what, councilman.
I will keep an open mind until
I walk into that booth on Tuesday.
And if you win...
you're holding me to a high standard.
Moses? I mean, Jesus, reverend...
I'm sorry.
I can't believe I said that.
Moses will do for now.
We'll save Jesus
for your second term.
- Have a good one now.
- Thank you.
Thank you all
so much for coming.
4x06 - Margin Of Error
- Signs o' life?
- Not even a lookout.
- Maybe they went to church.
- Our lady of the re-up.
He'll show up sooner or later.
Call me.
All right.
Vote for Carcetti.
Vote for Carcetti on Tuesday.
Tommy Carcetti running
for mayor. Thanks.
- Hello, councilman.
- Good morning.
I've been following your campaign.
- I'm a teacher.
- Excellent.
- High school biology.
- What? Here in the city?
Baltimore county,
and I just wanted say
I think your position
on school board reform
is very encouraging.
- So you'd vote for me?
- If I lived in the city,
I absolutely would.
Good luck on Tuesday.
Thank you.
They're all fucking county people.
We're almost done here anyway.
Thomas, look at this.
What's that?
Check it out.
In your private practice,
you ever represent a Bobby Harrison?
The slumlord? Fuck, no.
I don't remember ever
even meeting this guy.
"Carcetti got the most
serious charges dismissed
"and the others reduced
to small fines.
"The slumlord once again walked
free with a slap on the wrist
"while hundreds of tenants
continue to suffer
substandard living conditions."
Last-minute smear.
They're running scared.
- Royce.
- Who else?
65% of the city rents.
Bobby Harrison's name
is dirt in this town.
2 days before the election
and they smear me?
Courthouse steps.
When the fuck was this taken?
It's a fake.
They photo-shopped me.
We have time to prove that?
- We can try.
- Try, shit.
I'm gonna lose behind this.
Easy, Tommy.
We always figured
they'd pull some last-minute shit.
At least now we know what it is.
Fuck.
I want you to remember,
you representing your daddy.
Yeah, I know.
What she wanna see us for, anyway?
Maybe she got somethin'
special in mind for you, boy.
Cool.
She's a Barksdale.
She know talent
when she sees it.
Besides,
they owe this family a lot.
Your daddy,
he stood tall for them.
I know, I know.
He a soldier.
Like father, like son.
No doubt.
What time you got?
Half-3.
Motherfucker late.
It's for you, Marlo.
Yeah, speak.
You on it.
As long as she hit her mark,
we straight.
What time I gotta pick up
that skinny girl?
A'ight.
So what time they say?
Tomorrow night.
She be on the 8:45
from New York.
We can take care of that.
No.
I'll do it.
Don't want nothin' to go wrong.
You sure about that?
It's a'ight.
You can hang back on this.
Yeah,
I think I got this one, too.
Marlo Stanfield.
He ain't so much.
Using cellphones and shit.
What's he sayin' now?
"What time I gotta pick up
the skinny girl?"
"I do it.
Don't want nothing to go wrong."
Maybe he's picking up a girlfriend?
Skinny girl from New York?
It's code.
Cocaine.
Damn. For Marlo himself
to get near a package...
he's a mope. I told ya.
So what do we do about it?
We work up some counter-lit.
That's why we have
a printer on retainer.
Best if we run-down
the original photograph.
If we can prove
this one's a fake...
I didn't work at "Sun papers"
for 22 damn years not to know somebody.
I'm gonna call Paul McCardle
at the photo library.
And if we still can't find it?
Then we put out
a fake photo of our own.
Show Royce in a motel
with a dead girl and a live boy.
We can't sling mud back.
Not this late.
Relax. I'm kidding.
You get back on your schedule.
Hit all your stops.
Go to that donors' dinner
tonight and make nice.
We'll take care of this.
You can't do this to us.
Bey took the weight for all y'all.
And you've been amply
compensated.
But time moves on.
Not for Bey, it don't.
What I meant to say is
there's no more money coming in.
No more business.
Avon is gone.
So are his people.
Shit.
You seem to still be doin'
all right for yourself.
There's nothing more
I can do for you.
Bey know everything.
You forget that?
And what's he gonna do?
Who's he gonna tell?
And what do I care if he does?
Bey never heard me say
a damn thing about business.
What about your brother?
Avon could be gone longer
if Bey gets to speakin' his mind.
I couldn't care less
about Avon.
The thing is--
I wanted you both
to hear it from me,
so there ain't no lies
from here on in.
She even paid enough
over the last 2 years
that you should have enough
money going forward, son.
Your father has not been
disrespected here.
You both got what was coming.
But ain't nothing lasts forever.
Jailhouse snitch?
Called last overnight.
Worden talked to him.
Says for a deal,
he can give us the case.
No shit.
Gonna write up a writ,
send it over to the state's
attorney's office,
Get them to sign off on it
first thing tomorrow morning.
What's the rush?
We jump on this. We cause a major
shit stink right before the election.
If this guy really knows
why the witness--
- what's-his-name?
- Braddock.
- Was killed.
- Might be bad for the mayor.
If it's not bad for
the white boy, Carcetti.
You care, either way?
Fuck no.
I don't give a shit either way.
I don't even vote.
But it'll be fun to fuck
with them downtown suits.
Maybe get you on the 11:00 news.
Get a little payback for all
that shit they put you through.
With only 2 days left
before the primary,
campaign officials
traded charges today
over a controversial
flyer distributed
in some African-American
neighborhoods.
What seemed to be a secure
lead for the incumbent mayor
has evaporated in recent days.
The latest Sun-WQMD poll
shows the 2 men
in a virtual dead heat
with councilman Tony Gray
trailing.
4% of the likely voters
are still undecided,
and with the prim--
I can't wait for it
to be over.
Yeah, me, either.
Can that flyer hurt you?
You know, we found the original photo
In "the sun's" files.
They grafted my puss
onto some perp-walk
shot on the courthouse steps.
I'm standing where some
sheriff's deputy was.
Oh, my God.
What a nasty business.
Royce is swearing
he had nothing to do with it.
Claims it must've been
somebody freelancing.
Well, Norman and Terri
say not to worry.
It's all in the game.
You know, when I was
15 points behind,
I was resigned, you know?
A landslide,
I could live with that.
I mean, what else did
anyone expect, anyway?
White guy runnin' for mayor
in Baltimore?
But this?
Jen, if I lose this here by 2
points, it's gonna kill me.
It's gonna just fucking kill me.
You gonna have
to step up now, Nay.
A'ight.
Be the man of the family.
You older than your daddy was
when he went out on the corner.
That's what I been sayin'.
Damn.
He quit school.
You ain't quittin' school.
- Not yet.
- Ma...
But you are goin' out
on your own.
You gonna ask Bodie
for a package.
What if he say no?
I ain't take no for an answer.
Just did.
What you mean?
From Brianna.
Hand me the damn phone.
What she say about you already
gettin' paid enough money.
She a lyin' bitch, Namond.
You see?
There's a lot about this world
you just don't know.
What it come down to is
she know you ain't gonna snitch.
No matter what shit she pull.
She got that right.
She takin' advantage of you, Bey.
She takin' advantage of you.
Sound like she got it
all figured.
Bitch got it figured out, all right.
She cuttin' us loose
without notice. Nothin'.
Like comin' home, findin' our
shit in the street, Bey.
She don't give a fuck about you,
Avon, none of it.
She had the nerve
to talk to me on this,
like she gonna
set things straight
so I don't tell no lies.
Jen, I'm sorry.
He said he'd be up.
He's already gone.
To the office.
Well, what's he doing there?
He couldn't sleep.
He's been there for hours.
Aw, shit. See ya.
And given that we still
have a shortage of officers
willing to work secondary
at the polling stations,
we're asking for anyone interested
to contact tactical this afternoon.
Next order of business:
fresh warrants,
beginning with murder
and weapons charges
on one Omar Little.
Anyone know this mutt?
Oh, yeah!
Who'd he kill?
Some lady in a store.
- Reads like a taxpayer.
- A taxpayer?
From what this says, he's
charged with felony homicide,
to wit, murder in
the commission of a robbery.
'Bout fuckin' time someone got
some paper on that motherfucker.
Anyhow, we got no fixed
address, no known abode.
But if apprehended,
contact detectives Holley
and Crutchfield in homicide.
You wanna find Omar Little?
You look for a corner boy
running away from a corner
with shit in his pants.
You ever know Omar
to do a citizen?
Anyway, pass these around.
Jesus, Tommy.
I spent a couple hours
going over the latest data,
rearranged the schedule.
A little bit
of knowledge...
there's a bunch of
middle-class black precincts
which are strong on Tony but
still undecided.
We can pick up some
votes in those neighborhoods...
those people hate the mayor.
You're gonna get them,
- and if you don't, Gray will.
- We go door to door today.
As long as they
don't go to Royce.
I need some black votes
if I'm gonna be mayor.
I need some kind of mandate
from that community.
If I sneak in with
a bare plurality...
We might just win this thing.
What do you think
kept me up all night?
With all due respect
to your early morning analysis,
We got 3 back-to-back
drive-time radio interviews
I wore out my kneepads to get.
The people running your campaign
are professionals, Tommy.
Don't try this shit at home.
You know, there might
just be a job for you
in a Carcetti administration.
Press secretary.
Chief of staff.
Oh, get in the fucking car.
Duquan?
Mr. Prez.
Can you come with me, please?
What'd I do?
Get here early. I'll let you in,
and you can shower.
My dirty clothes?
Put 'em in this bag,
leave 'em in the locker.
I'll bring 'em home
and wash 'em.
Go ahead and get cleaned up.
You'll be late for class.
Hey, Paul. Hey, Monnel.
Skanky ho.
Damn, she good, though.
Yeah, yeah.
You right about that.
Hey, yo, tiff, baby.
I got 50 cent too.
Fuck y'all.
Damn. All 3 at once?
You know she could.
I know you could.
- Sir.
- At ease.
Man, I hate it when the bosses
creep below the eighth floor.
Yeah, well, I need a moment
just to unclench my asshole.
Sir?
The Braddock investigation.
It's coming. Norris and Greggs
are wringing it out.
I fuckin' know it's coming.
Commissioner Burrell had
a visit first thing this morning
from state's attorney
Demper himself,
asking why one day
before the primary,
our detectives were trying
to writ out a jailhouse snitch.
The tip came when it did.
I didn't push it, and I didn't
hold it back either.
Let the chips fall
where they may.
Exactly, sir.
Sergeant?
Fuck your falling chips.
If Braddock was killed
because he was a witness
and we break the case
one day before the primary,
Royce hates us forever--
and Royce might win the election.
If Braddock was killed
for any other reason
and we break it today,
then Carcetti hates our guts--
and Carcetti could win.
I see your point.
Tactical tells me we're
still about 20 bodies short
for manning the polling places.
I want you
to detail 2 detectives
to uniformed election duty
immediately.
Lemme guess:
Norris and Greggs.
Sounds good.
They're to report to tactical
at 13:00 today
for election orientation.
They can pick up their writ
and talk to their snitch
on Wednesday.
American democracy.
Let's show those third-world
fucks how it's done.
Yes, sir.
I have what I think is some
very good news for all of you.
We're going to be implementing
the university of Maryland
pilot program.
You're only taking 3
of my knuckleheads?
A total of 10 children
from the eighth grade
in this first class.
8 boys and 2 girls.
If things go well...
it's a start.
- When?
- This morning.
Hallelujah.
Not a moment too soon.
How was I?
Good on Steiner.
Better on the A.M. talk shows.
I thought you handled that call
about the flyers well.
Fucking Royce.
If I lose because of this
bullshit...
You lose, we can blame it on
10 different things.
Same thing if you win.
Guess who I just
got off the phone with?
State senator Davis.
He wants a meet.
Clay Davis?
Why would I wanna get into bed
with that grasping motherfucker?
He didn't actually say it,
but it sounds like
he's ready to follow Watkins
and jump the mayor's ship.
What's he want in return?
Shit. Same thing
he always wants.
At least 20k to his favorite
campaign committee is my guess.
Maybe even 30, 'cause you know
Clay ain't cheap.
Well, I'm not promising
him anything policy-wise.
You think Clay Davis
gives a fuck about policy?
Naw, this is strictly
for services rendered.
He might be conning us.
Taking the money,
then sitting on his hands.
Maybe. But then all
we have to lose is money.
Could be the extra little push
we need on the westside.
Set it up.
I already did.
- Invert the denominator...
- What invert mean?
The numerator and the
denominator switch places.
- Turn upside down.
- Why you do that?
Because it works.
That's the formula.
Excuse me, Mr. Pryzbylewski.
Namond Brice, Darnell Tyson,
and Zenobia Dawson.
Grab your things
and come with us, please.
Quiet, quiet.
Calm down, please.
What'd we do?
We in trouble?
Just come with me.
Shit.
It's the story of my life.
They ain't coming back.
Yo, Mr. Prezbo,
they gettin' arrested?
No...
Nay, can I have your X-box? 'Cause
you ain't gonna need it where you are.
What'd they do?
Markeith, Kwame, and Latonya.
Bring your things
and come with us.
Again?
You know I can't
publicly endorse you.
Not at this late hour.
Then what are we
talking about?
I lay back and not do what
I usually do on election day.
I see you all get a push
in the seventh
and ninth districts, say,
and maybe that piece of
the eleventh west of Freemont.
I split some of my tickets
for y'all.
I split my walkaround money.
You know, the usual to-and-fro.
Politics is a good thing, partner.
That's a minority opinion.
Let's order.
I'm hungry enough to eat
the horse you rode in on.
If you don't mind,
we're a little busy
for a sit down lunch.
Oh, no doubt.
Just leave enough for the tab.
Naw, she crazy.
She says you were there.
I wasn't. 'Sides, it wasn't even rape.
She wanted to.
How do you know?
You weren't there.
I saw her go in with them.
Go in with who?
This is no time to play, young man.
You are in very serious trouble.
Who did you see her go
in the boys' bathroom with?
Paul and Monnel.
Paul and Monnel?
And what were you doing?
- Lookout.
- So you were involved.
But, I didn't even see
what happened.
You were standing guard.
No, listen, Monnel gave me $5
and just told me to stand by the
door and holler if someone came.
This isn't even fair.
I didn't even do nothing.
You stood lookout
while 2 eighth-grade boys
raped an eighth-grade girl.
- But she wanted to.
- That's not what Tiffanie says.
There'll be an investigation.
You'll be suspended.
You could very well be expelled.
Maybe even face criminal
charges.
Mrs. Donnely, please don't.
Mrs. Donnely, please don't
call my foster mother.
I'll tell you everything
I know about this.
I know all about it already.
No, but I know some other stuff.
Like who been thieving
from the teacher's lounge,
or tagging gym lockers,
or even...
- Miss Jeffries, please.
- Mrs. Donnelly, please...
- this is Mrs. Donnelly calling
from Tilghman middle.
Listen... I know...
remember, the boy who cut
Mr. Philmont's tires?
I know who did that.
I know about a murder.
I do.
We've identified
certain students
we feel will benefit
from the special curriculum
and the smaller class size.
We've chosen 10 students
from the eighth grade
to participate in this program.
You get chose, you got to go?
That's right.
What if you don't wanna?
It's mandatory.
We feel that this program
will benefit everyone.
You'll get the attention
you need.
And we outta
everybody else shit.
My bad. I ain't mean to curse.
Yeah, but you're right, though.
This class get tore up,
it's only on y'all.
So we get put outta class.
This is a classroom, too.
And every one of you has proven
time and again
that you're not ready
for a regular classroom.
But this is a new program
that if you work it
is going to make you ready.
Ready for gen-pop.
This is prison, yo.
And we in solitary an' shit.
- Word.
- Solitary.
That's good, son.
This is solitary.
This is the hole up in here.
He's a good kid.
He really is.
And once you make that call,
his name's gonna be in the system.
What can I do?
He says he knows about a murder.
I have to notify police on this.
At least let me call
someone I trust.
That's him right there.
Stand by.
- You don't wanna be in on the collar?
- Nah.
If you take it, he'll think
it's a straight interdiction,
and I get to surprise him
at the bail review.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Can I have your attention.
Now boarding at
gate letter D, track 4,
the southbound 8:45 acela
express from New York,
making station stops at
BWI rail station
and Union station, Washington.
Sister,
help you with your bag?
No, thank you.
Don't be afraid.
Why should I be afraid?
Who are you?
Just walk you to the door.
My husband is waiting outside.
Like to meet him.
I'll wait with you.
Make sure you're safe.
That really won't be necessary.
Amtrak police, sir.
Excuse me, could you
step over here please?
What is this?
Give me the bag.
What is going on?
I don't know this man.
Where are you taking me?
What'd he say about it?
Nothing much.
Drugs?
I didn't question him too close.
A murder.
I should take it downtown.
Who knows
what he really knows?
I just, I don't want to see him
get chewed up by the system.
Let me try to keep this close,
give it to someone with
a little bit of discretion.
Appreciate it.
- Carver.
- Carver?
Ellis has come a long way.
I think he'd be right for this.
Why do you care?
And what's this kid to you?
I don't know.
He's one of my students.
Sergeant.
Clean. Both of 'em.
Say what?
Nothing in that bag
but ladies clothes.
Nothing dirty on
either one of 'em.
Unless you got another idea,
we gotta cut 'em loose.
From what he says,
he was just a go-between.
He delivered a message.
He told the victim to be at a
certain place at a certain time.
Then how does he know?
He says everyone knows
what happened to Lex.
It's in the streets.
This other thing at the school.
I swear I didn't do it, Miss Anna.
I didn't do it. You'll see.
School's gonna look into that,
we're gonna look into this.
As long as Randy cooperates,
tells everybody the truth...
but if word got out...
understand.
That's why he's gonna go to school,
keep his mouth shut,
his nose clean,
go about his business.
Child's shown such
bad judgment in both instances.
Agreed.
But from what I can tell,
he's not a bad kid.
Dennis?
Where you goin' at so early?
Oh, I'm gonna go run,
and then I got lawn work later.
You comin' back, right?
What you mean
am I comin' back?
It's gonna be like that, huh?
What do you mean? Like what?
- Where to?
- Highlandtown.
Flush out yo' base,
little trooper.
What up, Spider?
Hey, shorty.
Thank you, but I know
how I'm voting.
I'm gonna be late for work.
Miss Anna, is it OK if I stand
out here while you go vote?
- Don't you go nowhere, boy.
- Yes, ma'am.
So, what up, man?
So, how much they
payin' you for this?
They say like 40, but I gotta
work the whole day though.
- Know what I mean?
- Yo, Spider.
- Yo, that was Spider, right?
- Yeah.
Well, where'd he go?
No, thank you, man.
I can't vote.
Conviction?
- Felony?
- Move on, man.
A'ight, man.
You see Spider again, you tell
him he need to come past my gym.
He ain't been 'round in weeks,
an' we need to talk. A'ight?
A'ight.
Where's the older kid?
- Don't know.
- OK. You're hired.
Shove one of those
into every hand you can.
Thank you very much.
Why you ain't at school?
Ain't no school today.
One them Jew holidays?
'Lection.
So what you gonna do?
Dunno. Hang.
What'd I say about steppin' up?
Brianna turn off the faucet.
We gotta make some rain.
I'ma get dressed.
We go see Bodie.
Kid,
I got something else for you.
Put one of these in every door
between the expressway
and Winchester,
and from Freemont to Fulton.
You can do it by yourself
or you can get some friends,
but I'm gonna come past this
afternoon, make sure it's done.
OK. One in each door. Cool.
This is for the day's work.
That's your walk-around.
But don't you fail me.
Took forever.
What's all this, son?
Man said if I put these fliers
in doors, I can get paid.
I come right home after.
You right you will.
You ain't in these streets no more.
No, ma'am.
Sounds like she mean it.
11:00 news, huh?
Shut up.
I'm on this shit detail
because you wanted
to stir the pot.
And tomorrow,
if we bust open the Braddock case,
nobody's gonna give a fuck.
Life is timing.
No shit, fucknuts.
Tommy Carcetti.
How you doing?
- 'S a cute one.
- Thanks.
Hey, Tommy Carcetti.
Hope you're voting today.
I am.
Well, who's it gonna be?
Give me a hint. Come on.
- Don't keep me in suspense.
- You don't have to worry about me.
Appreciate it.
Tommy Carcetti,
running for mayor.
Nice to meet ya.
- How much longer?
- I think we can wrap this up.
We got a lot more places
to be today.
Tommy Carcetti.
I knew your dad.
- First district democratic club.
- No kidding.
Just wanted to say
you got my vote.
Thank you.
They had their chance.
Look what shape the city's in.
I'm hoping to turn things around.
Anyway, thanks for your support.
I mean, you expect
politicians to steal.
I don't, actually...
It's part of the game.
I understand that.
But we took one dollar outta
every 3, not 2 outta 3,
like these moolies.
I mean, leave something
for the city, for Christ sake.
Am I right?
Best of luck, councilman.
Moolies?
Sorry.
'Lection flyers?
Yeah, just run up,
stick 'em in mailboxes,
you know, screen doors,
whatever.
What about the vacants?
- We ain't even got to do the vacants.
- Shit. Some blocks ain't nothing but.
That's what I'm saying.
This be easy money.
- Don't wanna do it?
- I do it.
Me, too.
Yo, this shit'd
be easier if we had a car.
Dag, donut. I'm in enough
trouble with Miss Anna as is.
So, what up, Mike? You in?
All right, then.
I'll holla at you later, boy.
Look, Namond's been--
What's the word?
He been inconsistent.
You know sometimes he be doin' good,
Then other times, he just--
We talked about that.
He gonna do better.
Ain't you?
Election day special, 2 for 2!
- I don't know.
- Oh, I do.
You gonna give this boy
his own package
or there gonna be some Drama.
You want me to talk to Wee-Bey?
Maybe you wanna talk to him.
I give you his number.
He got a cellphone.
All that's not even necessary.
I got all the respect
in the world for Bey.
Then show some for his family.
Make me proud, hear?
Damn, boy.
Your mama's what niggas call
a dragon lady.
She don't blink.
Yeah,
gimme some insight, though.
To what?
Why you is what you is.
Yo. What up?
Where y'all goin'?
Hungry, man. I need to eat.
Nah, come one.
Let's finish this.
- Nah, yo. This shit is boring.
- Fuck it.
Yo, listen, man, I ain't even gonna pay
y'all If you don't finish the job, so...
You already got the money?
Fool, if the motherfucker
paid you out already,
then why the hell are we still here?
'Cause this is the job.
Shit, the man ain't got
nobody to blame but hisself.
It's his fault for payin' up front.
Yo, you need to split
that money up or something
'cause time is a-wastin'.
Didn't even finish the day's work.
Get me something at least.
Lake trout.
- Soda too?
- Yeah. Strawberry.
A'ight. I got ya.
Where the crew at?
Randy got 'em all some job
Handin' out election flyers
or whatever.
You ain't wanna do that?
Hell, no. It's bullshit, man.
- I got a job, too.
- Word?
Yeah, with Bodie.
I'm movin' the package.
You wanna go in on it with me?
You sure?
We could work together.
Nah, man, that's your thing.
Go do what you do.
Yeah, a'ight.
I'm gonna holler at you.
She cute one, ain't she?
Yeah, boy.
You know I love the women.
Hey, you seen Spider
around any?
I mean, he ain't been 'round
the gym in like a month, man.
I leave messages, he don't call.
I don't understand, man.
He was one of my best welterweights.
Now, why would he just
quit like that?
Why don't you ask his moms?
Well, shit.
I was locked up a good while, right.
I mean I ain't no angel.
Naw. You ain't that.
Thanks a lot, folks.
Good job. Keep it up.
We're almost home.
You're the best. The best.
Heavy turnout all around.
Big lines on the westside
might be bad for us.
I dunno but--
We're out here in west Baltimore,
Lafayette square,
The heart of his political base.
This is today?
This is live, right now
in Lafayette square.
Clay Davis just said
his whole organization
was out going door-to-door
for Royce's ticket.
So much for laying back
on the mayor.
We paid $20,000 for this shit?
He probably went to Royce and
shook him down for another 30.
Motherfucker.
Clay Davis must know
something we don't.
He knows just enough
to get paid twice.
Gotta blame ourselves
for payin' this thief up front.
Hey, it was worth a shot.
Aides to the mayor
have told me privately
that they are concerned...
Thanks, yo.
I'ma get me a cold one.
Grab the wall.
Officer walker.
I ain't gonna be
out here strapped.
Aw, you gonna take that
on a humble?
Boy, you don't know there's
rules to this here game.
- Rules?
- Yeah.
Where your shotgun at,
Mr. Omar?
What is wrong with y'all, man?
Y'all ain't got no charges here.
Charge is murder,
motherfucker.
Murder?
Who I kill?
Hey, Omar.
McNulty. What the hell
goin' on here, yo?
You tell me.
We got a warrant for
a robbery murder. In a store.
Wagon's here.
Hey, yo, McNulty,
I need a phone, yo.
Fuck your phone.
If I'm going to booking,
I need to make a call tonight, yo.
4-10-958-6612.
An' let it ring.
Here.
Yo, Butchie.
I'm locked up, yo.
What you need?
I got your bail.
Nah, no bail.
They sayin' it's murder.
Murder? Well,
don't worry. I got ya.
You some kinda democrat or what?
Voter turnout was heavy
all day across the city
with some precincts
reporting lines
as soon as the polls opened
at 7 this morning.
Election officials, however,
reported few problems
throughout the day.
Now the polls have closed,
officials at the board
of elections downtown
have begun the tedious process
of tallying the vote,
prepared for what could be
a long night.
With just over half of the
city's 316 precincts reporting,
councilman Thomas j. Carcetti
has a narrow lead of 2%.
Traditionally, those precincts
that report latest
tend to be from west Baltimore,
which is expected to favor
mayor Royce in the late going.
How it go?
Good. Nothin' to it.
I'm countin' on you, Nay.
Exit polls done earlier
in the day in key precincts
show voters divided over the
challenges facing this city,
such as crime and education.
Be quite an election.
Since this race tightened
in the last couple of weeks,
I've been saying
that this election
would be won on the ground.
And whoever has the best
field operations will take it.
It's all about the turnout,
and this is--
What about bond?
Yeah.
All right. Talk to you in a few.
Bond's running really strong
against Demper.
Looks like we might have
a new state's attorney.
What does that mean for you?
Well, Demper's Royce's boy.
Dare to get
your hopes up, Tommy.
You know what?
Let's get outta here for a while.
Take a walk.
I'll get your ass.
Pretty.
A little ripe.
Well, can't do anything about
the way the harbor smells.
People are gonna expect you to.
I guess.
You sound confident.
I have a feeling.
Could be a great city again.
Pull some jobs in here.
People move back,
fix up the houses.
It's ringing again.
Terri.
Maybe you should answer it.
I don't need an update
every 5 minutes.
- No, we should go, anyway.
- Do we have to?
I'm sure they're frantic.
They don't know where you are.
Yeah?
Taking a walk with my wife.
On our way.
Royce is conceding.
The westside precincts came in
and we pulled 2 outta 5 votes
in some precincts.
We stole his base.
We won.
Are we happy about that?
I think so.
I think we are.
Yeah.
You sure?
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Please.
I want to thank you all for
your hard work and dedication.
Give yourselves a hand. Come on.
I just got off the phone with
mayor Royce and councilman Gray.
They were very gracious.
I asked for their help.
I mean, we still have
a general election to win.
Is there
a republican candidate
for mayor in Baltimore?
I don't know. I'm not sure.
But, assuming
that we win, we still have--
We still have a lot of work
to do to turn this city around,
and we need everyone--
Everyone who's willing to join us
in making a better Baltimore
for our children.
I don't want to make a long speech.
Believe me.
You don't want to hear it.
I don't want to make a long speech,
so I'll thank each of you individually.
But for tonight, let's celebrate.
How you doin'?
Thanks. Hey.
Damond.
I look forward to working
with you, Mr. Mayor.
Likewise.
And congratulations to you, too.
Thank you.
I'm going home.
No, come on. Stay.
I won't be long.
Yeah, you will.
It's your night.
Tommy. Tommy.
Look what washed up
on the beach.
Congratulations, Mr. Mayor.
Just came by to wish you well.
Looking forward to working with you.
Shouldn't you be dead to me?
Shit.
I took it easy on you, son.
I coulda had you
for twice as much.
You got off cheap.
He's right.
Butchie sent us.
What you in for?
I'm here on a 22-55.
I talked back.
- Moolie?
- Moolie.
He said that in front of you?
He made a point of it, in fact.
You're the one said
I oughta Shore up my base.
You didn't call him on it?
The ironies of democracy.
A vote's a vote.
And I never throw one back.
Speaking of ballots,
did you vote for me, Norman?
The sanctity
of the voting booth
is a cornerstone
of American democracy.
I gotta go. You need a ride?
Yeah.
- Come here. You're the best.
- Thanks, Norman.
Yeah, take a break.
- You got it.
- One day.
- Come here, you.
- 2 days.
- Be good.
- I'm gonna call you.
I have a feeling you might.
We are family.
I got my Carcetti and me.
Good night.
I should go, too.
One for the road?
Sure.
- Scotch OK?
- Sure.
You know, I gotta admit,
it feels good.
You deserve it.
You worked hard.
I did. I do...
- Cheers.
You know, when I took this job,
you promised me a win bonus.
Well, you earned it.
I can't do this. Not now.
Oh, come on, Tommy.
You haven't changed.
Hell, from what Norman tells me,
you nearly fell off
the campaign trail for a blonde
at the stonewall dinner
2 months ago.
He had to drag you out of the bar.
It's not that
I don't want to...
You're feeling
a bit mayoral. Right.
You're on stage now.
Well, Tommy,
4 years is a long time
for a fellow like you.
This could be your
last chance for a while.
You sure?
Maybe you have learned something.
Write me a check.
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - www.thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net