Uh, yeah... can I get the
mixed vegetables and white rice?
- OK, mixed vegetables, white rice.
- Damn, dook.
You actin' like this
some fancy ass spot.
It ain't nothing
but a chink joint.
I'm-a order.
Then do it,
I said I got it.
Look at this nigga flashin' his shit
like some big-time gangster.
Yeah, Nay, a righteous hustler.
I'm just treating y'all, that's all.
You know I like to keep it real
with the little people.
Man, fuck you, man.
I was talking about you.
Can I order the yakame
with turkey grease?
Yakame, noodles--
This nigga
ordered turkey grease.
What's wrong, yo?
I mean, my mom, she get it all the time.
Yo, you is really
one of them at risk children.
- You know that, Dukie?
- Yo, man, come on, son.
Yeah, I got it. How much?
- $4.00
- Why is it so funny?
He just goofin' on you.
What's wrong with ordering yakame?
Nothing wrong with ordering yakame.
It's just the turkey grease that
makes the drunks, You know,
throw up all that liquor
they were drinking,
go back to swilling that shit.
Man, this shit is good.
Why don't you buy your own food?
This is all you getting.
Don't ask for no more of that.
That shit tastes good hell.
Yo, y'all heard about
what happened to lil' Kevin?
What?
He be dead.
He up in them vacants.
Why?
Fucked up somewhere,
I suppose.
What the fuck you little hoppers
doing on my avenue?
- Eating.
- Shit you are.
You're probably setting up
to snatch a purse.
Get the fuck back on the reservation
where your black asses belong.
How you feeling, little man?
Need a hand with that food?
I said get.
Yo, y'all hear that shit?
"My avenue."
It's just as much ours as it is his.
Walker be evil, yo.
He be thieving and
smackin' folk down.
We should get him back on
the payback tip for all the dirt he do.
You want to throw down with police?
I don't mean go at him direct,
but, you know, hurt him.
Like, slash his tires
or some shit.
We could stick
condoms on his car.
That'd send a message.
Yeah, but what kind?
We should slap bumper stickers
on his windshield.
I mean,
they is hard to get off.
Hold on, wait, wait.
Do officer walker
go to that club on Stockton,
the one where
the western police party?
I seen his car there.
I got this one.
4x11 A New Day
And as much as I empathize,
I can only tell you
that there is a process
for complaints like this one.
Don't sell us on process, Mr. Mayor.
We've had years of this kind
of treatment from city police.
You need to understand
we do this as an affront to the cloth.
We've asked
for a civilian review board
for decades, now.
Absent that,
how can we trust
any investigation
of any complaint?
Forgive me, gentlemen,
but last I checked,
the department had
a black commissioner
and a black I.I.D. director.
The problem is systemic.
And as to commissioner Burrell,
we understand that
his authority is now limited.
Mr. Mayor, when it comes
to matters like this one,
do you expect us to have
faith in deputy Rawls?
I expect you'll be good enough
not to prejudge
the department's response
before the investigation
even begins,
as I won't prejudge it.
I can only tell you
that I take this incident
very seriously,
and that I will pursue all of the facts.
Well, Mr. Mayor,
you said you would have
an open door,
and so far I credit you
for keeping that promise.
And my door
will always be open to you.
Thank you.
If they couldn't get civilian review
in Royce administration,
how can they think
they'll get it from me?
They're just testing you here,
trying to see how vulnerable
you feel on the racial stuff.
On Burrell, too,
for what it's worth.
Well, civilian review is a nonstarter.
You go now there now,
you'll be bending over
for 4 years for the ministers.
So what? I throw them a bone
and fire some idiot cop?
By pressing that
the average beat cop's
gonna hate my guts,
and I ain't gonna change
anything around without
rank-and-file support.
You don't fire him,
you're going to piss off
most of the black
political infrastructure.
Yummy.
My first bowl of shit.
Circle that right.
And you press that right there.
It's work time.
You guys got work to do?
You write down that data?
- Yeah.
- All right.
Charlene,
what don't you understand?
None of it.
OK, let's see if we can
find a way you can get it, OK?
What's the diameter?
- It's 7.
- Good.
OK, what's half of that?
You can't take half of it.
OK, let's say you have $10
and you gave half of it to Jasmine.
Why I do that?
Well, just pretend, OK?
You give her half,
how much does she have?
- Duh, 5.
- Good.
Now let's say this time
you have $7
and you give her half,
how much does she have?
$3.50.
Good, so...
Yo, Mr. Prez,
check this out.
Why we no pick him up at his casa,
follow him from there?
Why, so we can
lose him here again?
Papa, nothin' say he got to come back
through this way, you know?
What if he take another road...
All right.
We pick him up from his casa tomorrow.
Talk.
- Don't pout.
- Omar,
I'm tired of this, bro.
Lo siento, baby.
Lo siento.
Hey, now.
There she blow.
All right, then.
So we agree staring down
a stick-up boy on a corner
takes courage,
and we agree it takes courage
to go overnight
to Cheltenham or Hickey.
This is a good list,
but are there any examples
we can make
outside of being on a corner?
I need a volunteer.
Not me.
What about you, Albert?
No.
You volunteer
and you don't know what for,
you ain't got brains.
All right, then.
I need a volunteer to stand on this box
blindfolded, fall off,
and let us catch him
before he hits the ground.
- Albert?
- That's fucking stupid.
What about you, Namond?
Wait, wait,
let me get this right.
So you want me to stand up
on that box,
put a blindfold on, fall,
and expect these
weak-ass clowns to catch me?
Hell, no.
Who you talkin' to?
For real.
Yeah, for real.
Hey, yo, y'all drop me,
and we gonna have more than words.
A'ight.
All right, everybody, gather around.
Oh, shit.
You ready? On 3.
1, 2, 3.
Shit!
Oh, that St. was right.
All right, who wants to go next?
Albert?
I ain't doing no
stupid shit like that.
Fuck you, and fuck all
y'all bitches.
We don't like your ass anyway.
Settle down,
settle down.
Yo, today's specials
are those little hershey bars,
3 for a dime, and I got all your
your other favorites, too.
Yo, Deante,
I got your licorice--
red and black both.
Snitchin' Randy.
Well, I' be blessed, yo.
Look it.
This is good?
We put him here?
That tall man with prop Joe?
Yo, for real,
on this caper,
the more we learn,
the less we know.
We can go?
No, we stay.
Papa, I need to go.
I say we stay, Renaldo.
What's wrong, yo?
No, no, I mean go.
We been in the car
too many hours.
Whether you squat in an alley
or sittin' on a porcelain throne,
don't really change
the moment, now do it?
Rough day?
Doesn't help to hold it in.
What the fuck you know?
If you tell me,
maybe we can help.
Ain't nothing.
Look, come on, Albert,
you been doing real good
in this class,
real good till today.
Just give it a try.
I went home yesterday,
my mom's on the couch.
She dead.
Me-Maw said best not come
to school, but...
Yeah, you want to be with your mom.
Of course you did.
Some of you know me
from narcotics work,
some from earlier if you
worked the western district,
and some of you I'm meeting
for the first time,
but the only point I'd
really like to make here today
is that this is a transitional time
for this department
and for the city as a whole.
We have a new mayor
and a new state's attorney,
and they both feel like
they have a mandate for change.
The point is that given
the Mayor's position on crime
and given the outcome of the election,
we can expect certain enhancements.
Oh, really?
Certain improvements...
may be forthcoming
in the near future.
So we're looking
for feedback here,
some input as to what we need
more of or less of
to better work murders.
Better witness protection.
More proactive investigation.
Pay raise.
Better lab work.
- More techs on duty.
- More overtime.
More scotch!
More time for case pp.
Seriously.
More women.
Loose women.
Pay hike, double-Digits.
Mo' better,
mo' better, mo' better.
That's what we need.
Sounds like a new day, don't it?
Department's finally gonna
get what it needs.
State's attorney's office, too.
A new day.
They make a nice couple, anyway.
Looking forward to working with you.
hat's signed by
a now inaugurated Mayor
ordering his police commanders
to avoid mass arrests.
Community based policing,
and high-end enforcements
are to be emphasized.
I take it Burrell got a copy.
In person.
I don't see it.
Why not just fire the fucking asshole?
The mayor is weighing his options.
What the fuck does that mean?
To fire Burrell,
we're going to need more
political capital
than we have right now.
Speaking of which,
it brings us to another
little piece of business.
- The thing with the minister.
- It's a delicate situation.
The ministers are pressing
for a civilian review,
which I know the rank-and-file
don't want to hear,
but it speaks directly
to the situation with Burrell.
If we expend capital
defending this incident--
I get it.
You want the cop fired.
No, we're not saying that at all.
The mayor doesn't want to interfere with
the everyday workings of the department.
But it's a balancing act.
Our response has to be smart
and evenhanded,
in a racial sense especially.
If I'm hearing you,
it's about perception.
Exactly.
I.I.D. Has a black commander,
but he's beholden to Burrell.
He'll stir shit with this if he can.
The sergeant in question
is assigned to C.I.D.
His new commander is Daniels.
He's smart, he's black,
and politically neutral.
That work for you?
Works for us.
Who that?
I said, who's that?
You home, or you just visiting?
Home if I can.
All right.
Get by the fire if you want.
I got a couple of dogs left,
you hungry?
Shit weren't working out with
Jo-Jo and them.
Said I owed him some cheddar or
some shit some other boy did.
I don't want to make no
noise on that, though.
They pressin' you.
You know...
get with me,
and we pay 'em right back, OK?
No, all that shit you been sayin' to me
goin' through my head.
Forget about that.
Forget about all that.
If I wouldn't have pushed you off,
you'd have never
been on that corner.
But everything I do I be fucking up.
Whole time it feel like it
wasn't me on that corner.
I just wanted to get away.
Well, you're here now,
ain't you? Right?
This is you, right here,
right now, OK?
You're burning a hole in
that shirt, man.
Fuck-- You fucked me all up when
I saw you walking through
the door, Sherrod.
Shit!
What you think, huh?
You know, I get
half price for this.
All right,
take your hat off, man.
Don't burn them pimp steaks, huh?
Took long enough.
Yo, Dukie,
you sure about this?
I mean,
I'm with y'all.
Y'all my boys like that.
Y'all there for me,
I'm there for y'all.
I'm really starting to think
this is some fucked-up shit.
I mean, Officer Walker's
a shady motherfucker,
but he's police.
We do it Michael's way,
we send a message.
You ain't got to do what I got to do.
We drew straws, nay.
Let's go.
This is everything?
Sergeant Hauk's statement,
the ministers',
statements of the other officers,
it's all there.
No independent witnesses, huh?
It's a lot of smoke, but
I'm not feeling much in the way of fire.
It was a strong case
for discourtesy.
True, but no indication
of racial or religious overtones.
And the brutality allegation
is a stretch.
I've gone over GOC/7.
I'm up to speed with the matrix,
but since the buck stops
with me on this one,
walk me through my options.
Minor offenses,
you can issue a summary judgme--
A period of extra duty without pay,
guidance and counseling, the like,
or if Sergeant Hauk
fights your decision
or if there's a more
substantive charge,
it goes downstairs to a trial board.
And possible termination?
Let me ask you...
if the minister's connected,
and if all eyes are on this one,
what does command want to see happen?
What does city hall want
to see happen?
City hall just wants
someone to do the right thing,
whatever that is.
You're sitting here, Deputy,
telling me to just do the right thing?
Doesn't happen often, I know.
Hey! What are you doing?
Come here!
You motherfucker,
when I get your little ass...
Come on,
show me hands, bitch.
Back the fuck,
little hopper, I'm police.
Yeah, I know, you the police who like
To fuck with a nigger. Turn around.
You ain't gonna hear the next one.
Get on your knees,
cross them legs,
knit them hand come on.
Ooh, hold on.
Yo, what the fuck you doing?
What the fuck is wrong with you, man?
Give up that ring, man.
Come on.
Yeah.
Payback.
That's right, run, motherfuckers!
Shit!
I'm telling you, right there.
This horse is a winner,
look at it, OK?
How you doing?
Excuse me.
Mr. Mayor.
On my way downtown today
I saw an abandoned car.
Tow it right away.
Where is--
Mr. Mayor, the location.
Fucking Christ.
Call transpo!
Get the fucking trucks moving!
- Mr. Mayor.
- I got a constituent call.
She said the playground
near her house
was a hazard.
Rusted metal.
We'll get right on it.
The location?
Sir, I need a location.
Mr. Mayor, I understand your concern,
but you've got to understand,
we have more than 9,100 hydrants.
And one of them's leaking.
Sensitivity counseling,
2 week's extra duty,
no punishment past that.
They sliced it into the rough.
Does Daniels know the bind
this puts his boy Carcetti in?
Well, Wilson briefed Rawls,
Rawls briefed Daniels.
It's Carcetti doing Pontius Pilate,
putting it on Daniels,
who was a safe choice
as far as the rank-and-file goes.
But that won't be enough
for the ministers,
not by a long shot.
Am I the only one that knows
how to play this game?
Let's go, get that hydrant sealed.
3 of them with shotguns got me
coming outside the club.
I made 'em for bloods.
The paint's supposed to be some
kind of declaration of war.
Sounds like we get to stomp some ass.
The western district way.
Yellow paint
a declaration of war?
That's a new one.
So what I heard was
that this wild-ass boys--
I ain't saying no names--
but they past crazy.
They robbed him.
They threw paint on his ass,
yellow paint.
Shit, I ain't lying.
Well, I don't know about that,
but you showed me something
getting on that box like that.
That wasn't nothing.
No, don't sell yourself short.
Ms. Duquette, Mr. Parenti,
we all thought it took courage.
Especially considering
how y'all do each other.
You think?
Yeah.
Now, look, you're showing
a lot of progress in class.
I mean, you know that, don't you?
You know, you're doing the work.
You're not acting out.
It's getting to the point where
you can go back to regular
class, no problem.
Back to gen-pop?
You want me to go?
Well, if you're ready.
I ain't going back there.
Why not?
Shit they teach there be deadly,
but I know you know that, Bunny.
All right, all right!
We can squeeze a little money
from here and there
but nothing on the scale
for what you're asking.
Maybe free up some operating money
by shifting some of these
pay-go projects
into the capital program.
I can steal a little from
the budget stabilization fund,
but we still got
to absorb 120 grant positions
in the police department,
mostly officers.
- Christ, don't let those go unfunded.
- A lot of balls in the air,
and I still haven't seen
the schools' budget.
What about the revenue surplus?
As I said, that's one-time money.
I'm going to give the police
a 5% raise, that's forever.
If I'm gonna ask the police department
to get up on its hind legs and fight,
I got to throw some money. You're
telling me how I can't do, not how I can.
There's the rainy day fund,
but you really shouldn't draw that down.
The bond rating houses want at least 5%
of the budget in reserve.
Feels like a rainy day to me.
Cloudy like a motherfucker.
Yo, yo, wait up, yo.
Hey, yo.
Check it.
- Fuck is up with y'all?
- Ain't you, Mike.
We wanna have a word
with your boy, here.
Ain't nothing stopping you. Talk.
You know what we mean.
The little bitch been talking to police.
That's a lie.
I ain't do no snitching.
The fuck you ain't.
Peeing hisself right now, man.
You ain't gonna stand by
no rat motherfucker, is you?
Naw, I ain't standing with no rat.
These here be them 18-Hour junks.
Go to bed, wake up,
still be hot.
Man, feel this one from 3 hours ago.
See what I'm saying, two for one?
Each pack come with two pads.
Buy 5, I give you 6.
Gimme 6 then.
$5?
A piece.
Obliged, sir, obliged.
Take this side,
I'll take this side.
Bubbles depot.
Bubbles depot got what you need,
ya'll come see.
Come see me.
Oh, lookie, lookie--
Hey, Sherrod!
What up?
Car must've hit it or some shit.
- How much you think?
- Aluminum?
Aluminum about 30,
40 cents a pound.
We've got a benjamin here easy, baby.
Teamwork payin' off today,
ain't it, baby?
Go get the heavy side.
Let me try it.
Get out of the way!
That's enough!
Get out of here!
That's enough! Break it up!
Hey, Randy, you bitch.
We ain't even done
with your snitchin' ass.
Guess them books
are good for something.
Somebody call the nurse.
Yo, why they banged me?
I ain't no snitch.
Randy, Randy, it's OK.
Thanks a lot.
Health department shut
Chicken George again?
No, I had to duck in here for cover.
Your boys off the hook today.
Not a good day to be
cross-eyed in west Baltimore.
- What, y'all behind on your
quotas or some shit?
What the fuck?
Seems one of my side
got jumped last night.
Yeah, Walker.
I heard about that shit.
Threw paint on him.
Walker's an asshole.
Hey, you play in dirt,
you get dirty.
7-Adam-14, do you copy?
Go ahead, K.G.A.
Report of a burglary 19 north Monroe.
Copy.
We should do this again.
Don't go making any furtive moves.
No doubt.
Don't break a pencil point.
Mr. P., I swear I only told
the police what everybody knows.
Does that make me a snitch, Michael?
Shouldn't oughta told nobody nothing.
But that don't make you a snitch.
Not if you ain't put nobody in.
Jesus.
I should have stopped this.
It ain't your fault, Mr. P.
I mean, all this come up because of what
Tiffany said happened in the bathroom.
What did you tell them, Randy?
What do they know?
I just told them about
Lex going up to the playground
behind Fulton,
and how everybody said he got killed
and put in one of
them boarded up houses.
That's all you told them?
I mean, they wanted me
to say that I was there, but...
I just told them
that Little Kevin told me.
- Little Kevin?
- He killed, too.
I mean, Marlo got him, too.
That's what everybody saying, anyway.
Marlo Stanfield?
I heard Kevin got
locked up just last week.
Now he's supposed to be up
in the house somewhere.
They put him in a vacant, too, huh?
OK, Randy, for now,
I want to say Michael's right.
If anyone tries to talk to you again,
say nothing to anyone, understand?
Will that make it better?
So in sum, gentlemen,
the gods have spoken.
No longer do we live
and die by stats.
From this day forward
we are about quality arrests,
felonies, serious misdemeanors,
the back-to-basics police work
of our sainted fathers.
Still, the truth is it would be easier
to turn an oil tanker around
in a puddle.
Our people were raised on stats.
If you can't bend patrol
to the mission, Eugene,
I'll damn sure find someone who can.
Gentlemen.
Sir.
Along the line of what you propose,
I'd like to reconstitute
the major crimes unit,
bring it under
the umbrella of homicide.
And let me guess, you'd like
to shake up the personnel.
Where appropriate.
Go for it, Colonel.
- What?
- Smart move, accepting any ideas
whatsoever come from
the anointed fella.
Daniels.
The next commissioner.
Any cocksucker that
manages to go from
Lieutenant to full bird in
a little more than a year
is getting groomed.
Wait...
you didn't for a minute think that--
Ah, Jesus, Bill,
it's Baltimore.
You ain't one
of the natives, are ya?
You see where they went?
El gordo and tall man,
they go in a big room.
First floor.
Sign outside say "new day coop".
Coop?
What's a coop?
New day coop.
That's what it say.
Hey, yo, was there like a bar
between the 2 "os"?
Si, exactly.
Yeah, that's co-op.
Prop Joe in a co-op?
Joe go in with the man we robbed.
Remember, he fell down on his knees,
wept like a little baby.
Yeah, fat face Ricky.
Anybody else?
Si, como 8 or 9 others
I never see before,
but all the same to me, you know?
Narcotraficantes.
Prop Joe sat down to the table.
Oh, do tell.
The worm done came full circle.
Marlo.
Que?
If that is what I think it is,
our little clutch of chickens
might be putting
all their eggs up in one basket.
Is good?
Muy bueno, baby.
Know one thing--
I wouldn't walk around with it
on my neck for walker to find.
He ain't gonna find it.
You crazy even taking a chance.
If he catch you with it,
he gonna break more than them fingers.
Man, what up with you?
It's like lately you gone all...
like taking off the mask, yo.
What up with that?
If walker got a look--
He didn't.
What about the thing
with you and Randy?
Everybody now is sayin'
you threw down with him,
busted up the boy, dimples, and them.
You wouldn't have stood tall?
That's not what I'm saying.
It's not that you do shit,
it's how you do it.
Yo, look, I'm not trying to stand around
and let no chump-ass niggers
think I'm shook.
I ain't.
And?
And I want you to sign up.
Colonel,
there's the matter of-
You find yourself incompatible
with a certain Lieutenant?
Detective Freamon,
you have cart blanche
in picking your squad.
In fact, you can pick your
supervisor for all I care.
Motherfucker, as far as I'm concerned,
You are the major crimes unit.
It's morning in Baltimore, Lester.
Wake up and smell the coffee.
Reinforcements?
- Carver.
- Damn, boy,
what brings you back
to the plantation?
I trusted you.
Trusted Daniels.
My fucking mistake, huh?
Hold up.
What's wrong?
The kid you were supposed to protect.
You put his name on the street.
They were beating him in front
of the school today,
stomping on him for snitching.
- He all right?
- It's always the same.
I should have fucking seen this coming.
I swear to you,
I don't know what happened.
I hooked the kid into
Bunk Moreland and Herc.
I can't believe...
where's the kid now?
Home.
Let me go give this
to the night commander.
We'll park a plainclothes unit
on the house.
You think that makes it better?
We'll be discreet,
set up down the block or some shit.
Come on inside. I swear to you--
I'm gonna find out what happened.
- Ed bowers.
- Pleasure to meet you.
You surprised us all.
- Congratulations, Mr. Mayor.
- Thanks.
I'd like to introduce you to Dorothy.
You heard about Ed Nully?
I've heard great things about
what you've been doing, so keep it up.
- I'm delighted you made it, Mr. Mayor.
- Well, it's for a good cause, right?
I am getting the evil eye, however.
I gotta keep him circulating.
- OK.
- This way.
- See you later.
- Take care.
The Washington crowd is driving
the local real estate market now,
and if the harbor promenade
could extend to the south branch--
- We're looking at that.
- Should be.
Everything from here
to Hanover street is money.
Mr. Mayor,
play a little poker?
I'm not very lucky.
Luck can change.
Mr. Mayor, I'd like you
to meet Ray Chandler.
Pleasure to meet you.
Boy, either you gonna do it,
or I'm gonna.
There's a reason the police keep
jumping out on you, Nay.
So, was it the Bunk's cologne, huh?
Pussy.
I'm gonna miss you, too, bitch.
Lester do love listening
to other people's
phone calls, don't you?
A bit of a pervert that way.
You could use a wiretap case or 2.
Broaden your horizons.
Oh, no, no.
The Bunk is strictly
a suit-and-tie motherfucker.
At all hazards,
a man must keep up appearances.
Dignity, I say.
Dignity above all.
Governor, hear, hear!
Bunk, you got a minute?
- What's up?
- The Wagstaff kid I sent your way.
Wagstaff?
He one of mine?
Yeah, you were looking
for the boy Lex,
shot someone outside a nightclub
a couple-- 3 months back.
This kid knew about
Lex getting killed.
Herc brought him to you.
Herc?
This kid is a witness,
and Herc was supposed
- to bring him to me?
- That was the plan.
I'm gonna skin that motherfucker.
Jesus, Herc.
The fuck did you do?
Something happen to that boy?
Well, young man,
your wish has come true.
So this mean I can finally
get out of here?
Yes, Monnel,
paperwork was slow coming in
from north avenue,
but you 5 are at the age
where we feel it's to your advantage
to join your peers in the ninth grade.
Yo, we in high school!
- When we bump?
- The end of this marking period.
Congratulations.
You're excused.
Mr. Johnson, you have
a visitor in the front office.
Mr. Johnson, please come down
to the front office.
Bad news?
Plenty more to go around.
They pulled the pin on your program.
As I've been saying this week
at every roll call
in every damn district,
if I could scrape together
anymore, I would,
but for starters, it's a 5% salary year,
and that's a given.
I know it's not half what you deserve,
but if the revenue estimates stay good,
I promise you'll be seeing more.
Mr. Mayor!
My wife thanks you,
my children thank you,
my dog thanks you.
Hey, Sanny, how you able to
tell your wife from your mutt?
His wife, she's the one
that's got the fleas.
Shit, Bobby, with your old lady,
fleas would be an improvement.
At ease, we got the Mayor here,
gentlemen.
When they sit in one place too long
they get a little feisty.
I'm not going to stand here
and pretend I know how to do your job.
I don't, but what
I can tell you is that
during the past few weeks
I have spoken with many of your peers,
with your union reps,
with the representatives of the F.O.P.,
and the biggest
single complaint I'm hearing
concerns the department's
obsession with stats.
The fucking numbers game.
Well, under my watch
the numbers game is over.
You will no longer be under
the gun to meet monthly quotas
of ineffective, meaningless
arrests and citations.
Excuse me, your worship.
You're not the first person
who stood at the podium making promises.
Jimmy, I'm sure the Mayor
has some pressing business.
No, I'm just saying,
the first community activist
who pitches a bitch about
the corner activity in her neighborhood,
aren't we gonna go right back
to rounding up bodies?
We need to educate
our citizens to the new approach.
They're not the only
ones who need educating.
We got bosses that wouldn't know
police work if it bit 'em in the ass.
They been juking stats for years,
and will do it again once
the neighborhoods complain.
It's all they know.
If the old dogs can't get the job done,
I'll find new ones who can.
Look, for years,
I sat on the back bench of the council
and watched our city deteriorate.
It was business as usual
with the same old ideas
producing the same old results.
Well, I'm here now as you are,
and I'm asking you
to put aside your reservations
and give it a go.
All told.
You did good.
You got 'em pumped.
They love you.
Of course, the wrong decision on
Sergeant Hauk, and who knows?
Carv said the kid had something on it.
I talked to him.
He had nothing,
just a bunch of hearsay
and some shit about zombies.
The boy was to come to me.
You know the goddamn G.O.--
it's homicide's call.
You don't go putting your paws
in my murder, you simpel fuck.
Hey! You're talking to a Sergeant.
Oh, fuck your fucking stripes!
Take it easy, Bunk.
Now, Herc is trying to help us, here.
Man, he messed in my murder, he pays.
Give him a chance.
We can work something out.
That's easy for you to say.
You ain't the primary on this.
Mother fucker...
What got into him?
He's emotional.
He's been working this case
for a long time.
So the thing right now
is for you to remember
everything you did on this case.
From the beginning.
He's out there,
hat in hand, literally.
Well, he can wait till hell freezes over.
A Wise man does not burn his bridges
until he first knows
he can part the waters.
Old Ashanti saying.
Norman, you grew up in Catonsville.
Show the motherfucker in.
Mr. Mayor,
you know, I don't want to take time
out of your busy schedule.
Look, if this is about me
countermanding your orders
- for more arrests--
- No, sir.
You should proceed as you feel
the situation warrants.
Overall policing strategies
may not be my strongest suit.
I'm here about what I do know.
A recommendation from
Sergeant Hauk's Commander
will cross your desk tomorrow.
Colonel Daniels,
with Rawls concurring,
recommends sensitivity training.
It may be a fair decision,
it may even be the right decision.
But we both know
it won't fly with the ministers,
not even with Daniels behind it.
600 pages of rules, regulations,
directives, orders.
You fire a white police
for a bad car stop
on a black minister,
you'll lose the rank-and-file.
It's not cause enough,
but if a Commander can't find
the grounds
for firing a saint in here...
the man has worked narcotics
for 6 years,
and in narcotics
there are no virgins.
And here in lies your expertise?
I've always been comfortable
delegating strategic elements.
It's what the deputy ops is for.
Me, I know what a Mayor needs.
It was a Chevy Tahoe.
License Mike-4-6-0-6-5-4.
And I searched it good,
figuring I'd find some iron,
- but--
- How'd they react?
Chris and Snoop?
They didn't do shit.
Was there anything in the car?
Registration and crap in the glove box,
empty chicken boxes, trash.
They had one of those
plastic milk crates--
In the back with some tools in it.
What kind of tools?
I don't know, carpenter tools.
Did you check the crate for weapons?
- Nail gun.
- Nail gun?
Yeah, one of them bitches
that shoots nails.
They rig it to shoot rounds maybe?
Naw, I shot it.
A nail came out.
Look, Lester, seriously,
is any of this helping?
Naw, you're doing good.
Tell me about jacking Marlo
at the train station.
I'm short 4, right?
Yeah,
I remember your ass.
Here's my 4.
You like that?
- OK!
- I'm gonna beat your ass.
OK, no more!
Stop, stop.
Take the money,
take the money, all right?
Make me work this hard again,
I'm gonna skin one of y'all.
OK. Just go, man.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, man.
You know who got the fattest
asses and the best pussy?
- Who?
- Midgets, nigger.
They're all that,
you know what I'm saying? I got shit--
The fuck happened
to our boy on the door?
Siesta, papa.
You fix this, Joe?
What's the problem?
Ran out of time.
Now, Joe, you've been
so busy being devious,
you done messed around and got
yourself caught up in a web.
Omar, I don't know what
you been hearing, now--
Naw, Joe, ain't no time
for no lies, now.
Now, see, I need you to be straight,
just like you did on that
new day co-op sit down.
Oh, yeah, I know about that.
I knew you the one got Marlo up
in this mess, too.
Hey, Omar, take a deep breath.
A Proposition might fall
kindly on your ear.
Well, tickle my fancy, fat man.
Money, drugs, your call.
Come on, now,
you can do better than that.
Hey, we coming at this all wrong.
See, you the one with the high card.
You should speak your mind.
You going to serve up Marlo.
You gonna take out Marlo Stanfield?
No, no,
but I got a real powerful urge
to take everything he owns,
and I'm quite confident you
the man can make that happen.
That might take some doing.
Naw, naw, see,
we got to have it simple.
See, Omar like it simple.
So how we gonna do this, yo?
My sister's boy.
He do the drop.
We call you and give up the spot.
- That simple enough?
- That's what it is.
Well see now, Joe, I need you to
resist your natural inclination
to do anything twisted up
in this here play.
You feel me?
I even catch a whiff of you
doing something foul, Joe,
I mean, I might got to go
tell Marlo you the one
who put me up on that card game.
We understood?
Now, go ahead and write
my ticket so I can tip on out.
Come on, now.
Gentlemen.
I'll see to Tremaine.
You can't be serious.
Was you listening?
Omar to one side holding a spade,
and maybe Marlo
to the other with a shovel,
and just at this moment,
I manage to crawl out
my own damn grave.
No way do I crawl back in.
What the fuck is you doing, man?
You trust him?
I trust his fear.
Now we go, si?
Not till I teach Prop Joe
a thing or 2 about devious.
We on him, now.
Sorry, guys, that's all I got to say.
Talk to the mom.
I hear you, but we just came from
his foster mother's house,
and she said it was you
that told him not to talk.
- She said you told her to get a lawyer.
- That's right.
All right, look,
something got messed up.
We know that,
but whatever else happened,
we got a murder here.
Even if it's off the record,
it would help us
just to talk to the boy.
If you understand what happened here,
you know I'm not gonna do that.
If you go at it like that,
then you end up
siding with the motherfuckers
doing the dirt.
No. I'm siding with my kids.
You're right.
For you,
the kids come first.
We'll find another road.
Well,
glad this is working out for you.
Oh, man, you two...
makin' me all weepy and shit.
- Be safe, guys.
- All right.
Hey, Roland, man,
you know,
I hate coming all this way
and not getting a little something...
you know,
for old time's sake?
The playground behind
Fulton and Monroe, unit block.
He told this fella Lex
to meet a girl there.
That's all he did.
- What's up, shorty?
Can you give me 3?
Bitch, get the fuck across the street
and plant your ass on a stoop.
Kenard!
How do you think I look
with no tail on my head?
Do I look like a fag?
Yo, Nay.
Big yellow birds!
Yo, Mrs. Lee, you looking for Michael?
Namond, I don't want to be
no trouble to you,
but I got this friend who been ailing,
you know, and she gave me $6,
so I was hoping you could, you know.
Yeah, we cover her.
Go see my man.
The fuck you do that for?
It's Michael's mom, yo.
- Shit, she a fucking dope fiend.
- Namond said I could. Nay?
Naw, it's cool.
Gimme.
All right, but you ain't got
to be all up on me.
I know, I know!
I'm late, you know?
Sometimes it's just too much
damn fun being in charge.
Where you been, boss?
Announcing my presence with authority.
Sorry I'm late,
please sit down. Sit.
Sir, we scarfed up 52 vehicles.
Good.
But you missed my car.
We have new equipment at school 45,
school 52,
and school 58 installed.
Well, I got no calls on those,
but keep at it, though.
You'll get there, I'm sure.
Mr. Mayor, all hydrants
are fully capped as of today,
and solid waste has pulled
32 tons of trash
from the alleys, and, sir,
that's a single day record.
That's what I want to hear.
Thank you, gentlemen,
and keep up the good work.
Finance, of course,
doesn't deal with
the dirt under the nails tangibles,
unless you consider the money
itself to be dirty.
- So what's in your agenda today?
- The school audit.
Well, how bad could that be?
The system is running
a $54 million deficit.
$54 million?
Yes, Mr. Mayor.
Jesus Christ.
Did Royce know this?
How the fuck do we deal with that?
Frankly, I'm not sure just yet.
Our attendance is excellent,
and as to suspensions,
we don't have any.
We intervene immediately,
and we show success
in stabilizing behavior.
Not to mention the world of
good we're doing for the classes
these kids were wrecking
before the program.
In January we could
expand to 4 classes,
cover the whole 8th grade.
Any complaints about the tracking,
- anything from the parents?
- Not a one.
This isn't a group where we see
a lot of parental intervention.
What about test scores?
I can't speak to the program itself,
but it has to help
the rest of the 8th grade.
Next week will tell.
Right now the system
is under a lot of scrutiny.
We have certain fiscal issues
that are of great concern
to the new administration,
and what you're proposing here
is a radical shift in curriculum.
- Meaning?
- If
city hall were to sign off on this,
we could go forward,
but now is not the time
to rock any boats.
Hear that?
That's my joint right there.
So you all got your
work up to date, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I heard you took care of your
puppy's problems.
Oh, he most definitely made
that go away, you hear me?
It's all good.
You know, some of
the young's been saying,
your pup stood tall
with a snitchin' boy.
Michael?
Yeah, that's what they saying.
Yeah.
Lester, you really starting
to scare me, man.
Need a crowbar.
For what?
This is a tomb.
Lex is in there.
Fuck me.
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - www.thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net