I thought he was supposed to have
a breakfast date, right?
I mean,
they told me that last night.
Breakfast?
Is that on the schedge?
It isn't,
but the lieutenant told me
that he'd be doing
breakfast
with someone down at the harbor.
I mean,
if he ain't,
I could go get this gassed up
at the fallsway.
I hate this detail, man.
It's off duty.
Lotsa perks.
All this stand around
and wait,
you know?
Hoskins says I do the 1 year,
and I'll make sergeant
on the next list.
Yeah.
They told me, career wise,
you can't do better
than drive the mayor.
Shit, if you could
make rank the right way,
I'll still be working Western drugs.
All right,
fuck this,
I'm gonna go look
for the lieutenant.
Anyone comes looking,
I'm back up on the second floor.
Sir?
I understood that the mayor
might be going to, uh,
breakfast at the harbor?
With Kweisi.
But, um,
that's up in the air, I thought.
Would you happen to know
where Lieutenant Hoskins is?
Sir?
Lieutenant?
Season 4 - Episode 2
"Soft Eyes"
You don't look happy, detective.
We're about to raise some hell.
Maybe... too much hell.
A state senator,
2 councilmen,
the city
development agency,
All those developers...
princes of the city.
Lester, tell me the thought
hasn't crossed your mind
that some kinda shit
could blow back on us, man.
Do you know what
Theodore Roosevelt said about
hunting grizzly bears?
The thrill is
in overcoming your own fear.
What was the thrill for the bear?
I should've run every one
of these subpoenas by my front office.
That's not procedure.
Fuck procedure, Lester.
My boss is running 2 points behind
in the polls with the mayor's support.
How do you think he's gonna do
if he pisses off Royce
and starts dropping off
incumbent tickets?
Why do you care?
If Demper thinks
I fucked him and he wins,
I will be at central booking
covering bail reviews.
If he loses to bond,
a new front office comes in
and maybe they bounce
the white girl back to a trial team
and give the narcotics division
to one of their own.
It's Baltimore, Lester.
We're missing
a couple of subpoenas.
We are?
Clay Davis
and Andy Krawczyk.
I'm holding those 'til October.
Oh, the hell you are.
Lester, we drop subpoenas
on either of those guys
3 weeks before the primary,
and all hell breaks loose.
That's what I'm sayin'!
Clay Davis is Royce's
deputy campaign chairman,
and the number 2 man at
the city legislative caucus.
And Krawczyk is his
number 1 fundraiser!
You're giving me resumes
and job titles.
I'm just following the money.
And we will follow it...
after the polls close.
We can drop a second batch
of subpoenas.
There is no reason
to do this now and risk...
A year ago,
if we had gone after these records,
City Hall would've stomped on
this unit
and the subpoenas.
And a month from now,
after Royce is reelected,
they'll do us the same way.
But right now,
with the primary coming,
they gotta worry about
how they look,
how they behave.
Right now,
they gotta worry about scandal.
You told me you wanted
to do this a year ago,
but fresh cases got in the way.
You told me that.
Very clever, Lester.
You got it all figured, huh?
Me?
I'm just the police.
I saw the teachers' union
finally endorsed Royce.
You knew they were gonna.
What time's your first appearance?
Today?
I meet up with you guys
at the SoWeBo forum.
And tonight, it's me and the kids
next to Tommy
at the Roland Park fundraiser.
Better speed things along.
A kick in the ass sometimes helps.
B-5?
No, daddy, d-5.
You sure you didn't say b-5?
D-5.
What did I hit?
Submarine.
E-6.
Miss.
Just gimme 10 minutes.
You seen your schedule today?
You ain't got 10 minutes.
Norman, I got this pretty girl's
aircraft carrier boxed in.
D-4.
Hit.
Tommy,
for Christ's sakes.
Is there any way that I can win?
With the numbers what they are,
is there any way at all?
Right, so if it's just a matter
of playing out the string,
then that's what
I'm gonna do.
That game's pretty much
over, Norman.
But this game,
this game right here,
this one
could still go either way.
H-11,
sweetheart.
Miss.
D-3.
So I guess
y'all getting what y'all need?
Brianna keepin' y'all close?
She come up with it.
Money comin' through
every month like she say.
A'ight.
'Cause I'm standin' tall up in here.
They don't need
to worry about me
an' I ain't need
to worry about them.
You a soldier, Bey.
You know it.
Everything all right
with my fishes?
You'd tell me if it wasn't, right?
The fish be fine.
I mean, they fish, right?
How I know how they
feelin' about shit?
De'londa...
they fine, Bey.
Ask Namond.
Cleaned the tank an' all,
like you say.
Cleaned the filter, too.
A'ight, a'ight.
Check you out, though.
Getting some fuzz up there, huh?
Yeah, whatever.
I know when I was a little kid, boy,
I couldn't wait
till I started shaving.
One of the old heads
on the corner say,
"Hey, little man,
you wanna grow a stache?
"Next time you take a piss,
"take some of that piss,
"get it on your fingertips,
do like this, here..."
- You do it?
- You damn right I did it.
Shit.
What's going on with you,
though, son?
Ain't nothing.
School about to start.
So what about Bodie and his boys?
They treatin' you right?
Yeah, he cool.
Boy, don't lie to your father.
He don't even show up
for work half the damn time.
Bodie told me.
I missed a few days.
That's all, dad.
And what money you do make,
you waste on nonsense.
And if you think
I'm gonna give you a dime
for your school clothes,
you better think again.
What Bodie got you doin'?
I'm a runner, most days.
Everybody got to start somewhere.
You better listen to your father.
He ain't tell you 'bout
that hair, though, huh?
Yeah, he said I gotta get it cut.
I like it this way.
Even the white police
lookin' out from
3 blocks away gonna
be able to spot you
from every other nigga out there.
They gonna hop out and say,
"Look at the boy over there
with the pretty ass
pony-tail. Get him."
You think I'm bullshitting.
Either you real out there,
or you ain't, Nay.
You see what I'm sayin'?
Let me get some!
Over here!
Thank you, Mr. Marlo!
Thank you!
That's my money, yo!
Your name gonna ring out, man.
Manuel,
tu empiezas enfrente,
yo hago la parte de atras.
A Cutty le gusta por atras, eh?
Yeah, no tanto
como a ti maricon.
Boy, you talk
that shit better'n me
and I been dealin' with
these Mexicans for years now.
Yeah, I don't think they would call
what I'm speakin' Spanish, man.
Just a dirty word
or 2 here or there.
Yeah, well.
Once you can talk to these cats,
the only thing you need
then is a truck, man.
Could be runnin' your own crew,
pickin' up fresh clients.
I mean,
if we put in together
we could be coverin'
twice the ground,
makin' twice as much.
Nah, man,
I got other obligations.
Oh, right.
You set to be
the new Angelo Dundee.
I near forgot.
Chinga te bendajo.
Chinga a la tuya
hijo de puta.
I thought you already went up
to Mondawmin to get
your school shit, man.
Yeah, but not all of it.
And my boy,
he need to pay for his own shit
and his little brother, too.
The fuck this look like,
a social services office?
You want a check,
go the fuck up Rosemont.
Come on, man,
I'll work for it.
Nay, I took you on
outta respect for your father,
a'ight,
but I can't
go hirin' the whole damn neighborhood.
You can have my job until
you get enough for you an' bug.
Thanks, man.
Yeah, work for y'all,
work for me, yo.
Po-po.
Step the fuck off.
Looking for your man Lex.
I see his broom,
but I don't see him.
Where's your number 2 been at?
I ain't seen him.
Since when?
I thought we were on better terms.
Or do you want me rolling past
lookin' for Lex every 15 minutes?
He come past,
I'll call you.
I will!
If he come past.
Oh, no,
I don't know.
They're spinning their wheels.
You know,
poor Tony Gray,
pulling 20% of the black vote.
It's embarrassing.
Well, who knows what the fuck
Carcetti's trying to prove?
But I tell you,
at the end of this thing,
he's gonna regret getting
on the wrong side of me.
A'ight, now.
I got what you need, boy,
clean tees,
any sizes, huh?
Lookin' for socks,
briefs,
you lookin' for dice,
zippos, cards...
Come on over
to the rollin' emporium.
You ain't gotta walk to rite-aid.
Shit, rite-aid comin' to y'all.
What can I get you, baby?
Fresh dice
an' a pack of Trojans.
All righty.
You got philly blunts, too?
Bubbles got it all, dawg.
I'm the 1-stop shop.
How much is that?
6 an' a bit.
Thank you.
Thank you kindly.
Yes, sir, I see
what you're lookin' at.
2 a deck. Name brand.
You can't beat that price.
Yeah, let me get 2 decks, man,
and a white tee, double-X.
And give me the rest
of them paint cans, too, man.
All right, all right, there you go.
That's it?
Yeah, what's that?
How much the man owe, Sherrod?
13.
He asked for all the cans.
3 cans is 12,
plus the other stuff.
It's 19. 19, sir. Come on,
you still gettin' off with a deal,
now, you didn't have
to move your feet.
We came to you, right?
My bad.
19, like he said.
Thank you very much.
He's an intern, I'm working with him.
But, ma'am,
what I'm asking is
when was the last time
you saw Lex?
Oh, excuse me, Curtis?
2 days ago?
I don't know where he at.
3 days?
You mind if I look around?
I'd rather you leave my house be.
Well, Ms. Anderson...
your son is in trouble,
and I can tell you're upset.
But the best thing
that you can do for him,
the best thing that
he can do for himself,
is talk to me.
I'm gonna tell you the truth:
we know he's selling drugs.
- And I'm gonna tell you...
- I don't know nothin' about that.
But I'm telling you that
I don't care he's selling drugs.
I'm not even gonna bother with that.
I'm here because of a homicide,
and the way it looks right now
your boy is running from the police
behind that killing.
I don't know where he at...
ma'a...
Councilman,
my people got only
cost-of-living bumps for 4 years.
Morale is at rock bottom.
All things being equal,
you'd be our guy.
We like what we hear.
The polls say it's going to be Royce.
We endorse you now,
we're out in the cold.
Bobby...
this might be the chance to get in on
the ground floor of something better.
That may be true, Major.
But for now,
we're gonna play
the cards that we were dealt.
Councilman, if you were me,
I'm sure...
I'd cover my ass
and endorse Royce,
along with the teachers
and the firefighters.
But I'd also tell my membership
not to get carried away,
I mean, it's one thing for
the police union to call out for Royce,
it's another thing entirely
for off duty cops
to be manning
the mayor's phone banks
and polling stations.
I don't think
any of my officers
will be too aggressive
for anybody.
That much I can give you.
Best you could do, Tommy.
Royce has got all those
fucks runnin' scared.
Yeah...
best I could do.
Call it a night, Tommy.
You got a debate
to prepare for tomorrow.
Yeah.
The debate.
Nothing matters more at this point.
Let the truth
set you free, Norman.
Nothing matters at all.
Thanks.
Come on, boy,
come on now.
Man, you better not be getting tired,
'cause you gonna get put to the test
on Saturday night.
I'm ready.
- Hey, Miss Johnson.
- Hey, Justin. Hello, Dennis.
You're Spider's mother, right?
Right, Sharon.
Sharon Johnson.
Your boy left here a while ago.
I ain't looking for him.
He at his grandmother's.
I wanted to ask you something.
You know,
my son is crazy about you.
All he talks about
is boxing, bein' at the gym,
and what his coach
been teachin' him.
Well, Spider's a good kid.
He really studies the sport.
Dennis, I am so grateful
for your interest in Spider,
I want to cook you dinner.
How 'bout tonight?
Well, ah,
that is really nice, Sharon.
But the thing is, I got 4 of my boys
fighting this weekend,
and I got to train 'em really hard
these next few evenings.
You in here every night
of the week.
What you do for fun?
Look here,
you got to eat, right?
And you can look at me and know
I throw down in the kitchen...
among other places.
Yeah, I tell you what.
If you fix me up a plate
and bring it over here,
I would love that.
That I can do.
He said what?
"Me, I'm just the police."
Like butter
wouldn't melt in his mouth.
And the thing
that I resent most
is that he's not just
playing the system,
he's playing me.
Like I'm part of the problem.
You were gonna hold back the paper
for Davis and Krawczyk, right?
Only until the primary was over.
And now you feel guilty about it.
Did he do that thing where he, uh,
stares at you over the top
of his reading glasses?
You know,
that look that says,
"I'm the father you never had,
and I don't want to be
disappointed in you ever again."
It's not funny, Cedric!
Those subpoenas went out today!
The front office is gonna go batshit!
But you did it anyway.
I'm sorry, but shit,
I'm just glad to see
Lester doing it to somebody
other than me.
Hey, you holdin' us back, Sherrod.
I made a mistake, man,
why you trippin'?
If I can cut you loose
to handle the money,
we can cover twice the ground,
selling twice the merchandise.
More... more... what you call it,
market share.
Instead I gotta keep your ass close.
You shoulda been promoted
to your own cart by now.
You keep on hittin' your dome
on the glass ceiling.
Glass what?
I'm sayin' you gotta
step up the math skills
if you wanna advance in
this here enterprise.
You remember last spring when
you tried to take me up to Harlem Park?
They couldn't even find
my records, Bubs.
They didn't want shit to do with me.
They put you in a classroom, right?
The teacher didn't look at me once.
So you rolled out.
An' who got hurt behind that, huh?
The teacher or you?
What's 4 times 5
plus 6 times 7?
See? See?
Fuck that shit, son.
I can't wait until school starts.
- You joking, right?
- Nah, seriously, son.
I can't wait to see all them girls,
you know, see which ones
got phat over the summer, you know?
- Guess who I saw last week?
- Who?
Kwaneese Davis.
Oh, shit, you mean
cute ass Kwaneese?
- She phat?
- Got titties, too.
I'm definitely tappin'
that pussy, now, y'all watch.
I'm be all up
in Kwaneese this year
like this, bangin' that...
Just like you
tried to do last year, right?
Fuck you, nigga,
I only halfway tried.
So, Michael,
who you gettin' with this year?
Stankin' ass, what's her name?
What's her name?
Oh, Tina.
Tina... Tina Jenkins.
Don't talk bad
about Tina, man.
I'm not sayin' that it bad.
I'm sayin' she be
sucking dudes' dicks
in the boys' bathroom and shit,
that's all.
She suck dick even
better than you do, Namond.
What up?
What up, see?
Good jabbin', man.
Chill, chill, chill!
Don't rip this shit.
I just bought this throwback.
Yo, Michael, son,
if I ain't had this shit on,
I'd of fucked you up.
Word up.
You little niggas
ain't up to no good, is you?
Yo, what up, Monk?
Look here, first day
of school coming up, right?
Yeah, next week.
So, y'all need, like,
school clothes and shit?
Here...
Yo, what's this for?
What, you ain't hear me?
For new clothes.
Whatever else you need to get.
Thanks, man!
Damn, 200?
Yo, thanks, Monk.
Oh, you need to thank my man Marlo.
He ain't wanna see
you little motherfuckers
going raggedy on the first day.
That Marlo?
Naw, man,
no thanks.
You ain't gotta do nothing for it.
No, thank you, man.
Hey, yo, mister Monk?
I'll take his if he don't want it.
- I mean, I'll hold his for you...
- Yo, don't press, man.
Don't press.
Fuck is wrong with you, boy?
You too good for my money?
Or is you such a bitch-ass punk
you worried about
where my money come from?
Ain't no thing, shorty.
We cool.
You can't tell nobody.
Swear to me you won't
spread this around.
And he saw you?
Yeah, he saw me.
Carv, I'm fucked in the ass
with a pineapple on this.
What the hell'd you say to him?
I said, "Mr. Mayor, that's a good,
strong dick you got there,
and I see you know how to use it."
I didn't say shit!
And I didn't wait for him
to say anything, either.
Shit, I'm never gonna
make rank now.
I'll end up riding the boat
or some shit like McNulty.
This is way beyond
my pay-grade.
We need to get with someone
who knows politics.
Who do we know like that?
On crime, he knows you're coming,
so he's gonna set some traps
and lean on stats
that say crime is down.
He'll also try to inoculate himself
by making it about you.
Like you're playing
the race card
if you talk about
drugs or violent crime.
He's hoping you'll back down.
But you come on twice as hard:
"Clarence Royce
has not made this city safe."
Hey, Jen, what's up?
You got a second?
No, I got time, what is it?
Oh, no,
you're kidding me.
No, no,
I got the number here, yeah.
No, I'll straighten it out
straight away.
Yeah.
Shit.
I forgot to mail the check
to the fuckin' archdiocese.
My kid's gonna get tossed
outta St. Albans
if I don't get my shit together.
Tommy. Focus.
He comes at me with race
and some bullshit crime stats.
I ignore the race thing
and counter by noting
that homicides are up 15%
even though other
violent crime stats are down 12%.
I point out this
does not make sense
unless Royce is cooking
the crime stats,
making robberies, rapes,
and assaults disappear.
I suggest the mayor is not telling
the truth about crime in the city.
I conclude by declaring that
it is for all of Baltimore...
every neighborhood...
that I'm making public safety
the cornerstone of my campaign.
Tomorrow night,
I will kick his ass.
But the next morning,
I still wake up white
in a city that ain't.
Sister Theresa?
Hey, how you doing?
Yeah, Tommy Carcetti.
Yo, Randy, man,
you crack me up, son.
Running behind him talking about,
"I'll take his, mister Monk.
Give his to me."
Listen, man,
I could've used that extra.
I already spent
all the clothes money
Miss Anna gave me on stuff
to sell at school.
Yo, and plus Marlo
wanted us to have it.
He want to show us
who callin' the shots out here.
Yo, Michael,
why you ain't take it?
- At ain't me, man.
- Say what?
That owin' niggas for shit, man.
That ain't me.
Shit, I'll take any
motherfuckin' money
- if he givin' it away now.
- Why?
Shit, your family got
more money than all of us.
Yeah, but my mom said
she cuttin' me off,
she ain't buyin' me school
clothes and shit.
You already took my job
with Bodie, so...
Gentlemen.
Oh, my God.
Oh, shit!
Donut, you crazy, man.
Yo, Donut. You think you could
steal us one of them camper trucks?
Yo, you steal us a camper truck,
we can all go campin'
out in the woods an' all.
I be scared in the woods.
I don't mean far like that.
I mean like Howard county.
Naw, naw, naw, man.
The Ku Klux Klan
live in Howard county.
I know that for a fact.
Nigga, my aunt live
in Howard county.
There ain't no Ku Klux Klan there.
Nigga, you simple, I swear.
Hey, yo, Donut, drive me away
from these ignorant bitches, man.
You can't tell these niggas nothin'.
Move, motherfucker.
Can you see over the steering wheel?
You think he'll talk to me?
Use my name if you have to.
I had one of his sectors for 8 months.
What's wrong with that picture?
Nigga, if there was
a black one in the parking lot,
I would've took one.
Yo... knockos, knockos!
760 to K-G-A.
I got a bailout at Calhoun and Mosher,
6 to 8 juveniles beating feet North
in the alleys around Calhoun.
I love this.
Just like old times.
I don't need to chase these fucking
knuckleheads. I know half of 'em.
Shit, I know where they hang.
Besides, you're a little overdressed.
Let's just call this in
and go see the man about your thing.
Yo, yo, man,
I ain't do nothin'!
- I ain't do nothin'!
- Then why you runnin'?
- 'Cause you chasin' me.
- Yeah, right. What's your name?
- For real, man, I ain't do nothin'.
- What's your goddamn name?
- Randy.
- Randy what?
- Wagstaff.
- I know you ain't lying.
Wouldn't nobody make that shit up.
Put your hands against
this fucking wall.
Come on...
What do you know
about hoppers bailing
from a stolen car?
Nothin'.
Little motherfucker.
You slingin'.
- No, sir. I swear to God.
- Hell you ain't.
How else you walking
around with 200 in your pocket?
My foster mother gave me that
to buy school clothes with.
- Your foster mother gave you 200 cash?
- Yeah.
Tell her to come down to the Western,
and I'll give it back to her.
Beat feet, motherfucker,
'fore I lock your little ass up.
Don't be fucking lookin' at me, move.
This right here, is fire.
That said,
I'm ready to serve 'em myself
and keep your names off the returns.
I've got my 20.
You two got to live
in this department.
Fuck 'em where they live.
Let's go.
The price of steel being what it is,
that's gonna kill us if we can't
pass along the overage.
Mr. Krawczyk?
- Baltimore city police.
- What's this?
A subpoena for records.
You need these right now,
because, uh,
I'm kinda up to my ass
in stuff today.
Honor it in a timely fashion.
I think that's the legal standard.
No problem, Detective...
Shakima Greggs.
You're with the city?
Which unit?
Major Crimes.
Senator.
What the hell is this?
Subpoena for records.
Sphinx club?
- Man of the year.
- What kinda bullshit is this?
You people must be out your damn mind.
You were in the Sphinx club?
My uncle used to tend bar over there.
Marvin Thompson?
Short guy...
What is your name, Officer?
Detective Sydnor, sir.
Major Crimes?
Shit...
Enjoy your day, sir.
Son, we're gonna see about this.
Yankin' that bitch.
Son, that's too much knuckle.
Why the fuck you keep callin' me?
But what I say, though?
He got the message, fool.
Yo, Monk.
Who that, man?
Andre.
Old-Face Andre.
Here, let me holla at that dude.
Yo, check this out, man.
I'm gonna show you how you do this
right here, man.
Don't rush me on shit.
I'll get at you when I'm at you.
Yo, remember who you're talking to
before you say another fuckin' word.
Andre, man.
Nigga need more maintenance
than both my babies' mama's.
By accident.
It was accidental.
And the mayor doesn't say anything?
I think he's pretty mad.
I mean, Major,
I only took this detail
to try and make sergeant on this list.
Kid, you made sergeant already.
Shit, if Royce gets reelected,
you'll be a lieutenant in
2 years and a major in 4.
You go back down to the hall.
You act like it never happened.
You shut up.
Say nothing to no one.
But the mayor, he's gonna...
He's gonna watch and see
how you carry it.
And kid, you're a fucking rock.
When the mayor looks in your face,
he knows he can trust you with this.
And I'll bet in a couple of weeks,
he comes asking,
real friendly-like,
what are you looking
to do with the department?
With your career?
He's interested in you.
But he doesn't mention no blowjob,
and neither do you.
It just lays there
Like a bad pierogi on the plate.
Both of you pretending it ain't there.
What if he screws me over?
Bounces me to a midnight shift?
He does that, you will talk.
What I wouldn't give to be
in your shoes right now.
Kid, careers have been launched
on a hell of a lot less.
Just,
shut up and play dumb.
I can do that.
No problem.
Thanks, Major.
Thanks for taking the time
to meet me on this.
I mean, it's a weight off
my mind talking to you.
It really is.
Don't mention it.
Maybe you get
a chance to do me a turn
one day after
you make rank, huh?
Oh, boy.
It's all good, Carv.
Because if some federal motherfucker
comes through the door,
I say, hey, it's all in the game.
But a city police?
Baltimore city?
Hell, no.
Can't be happenin',
'cause I know I have raised
too much goddamn money
for the mayor and his ticket.
Hell, no!
Ain't no soul in the world
that fuckin' ungrateful!
- Calm down, Clay, hum?
- Money laundering?
They gonna come talk to me
about money laundering?
In West Baltimore?
Shit...
where do y'all think I'm gonna
raise cash for the whole damn ticket?
From laundromats and shit?
From some tiny ass
Korean groceries?
You think I have time to ask a man
why he givin' me money?
Or where he gets his money from?
I'll take any motherfucker's money
if he givin't away.
I don't wanna know.
I know you don't wanna know.
But I'm scratchin' an' clawin'
to get it done for you, Clarence.
For you and me
and the rest of the team.
And who comes through my door
but a Baltimore city police
lookin' to get up
into my shit about it.
Clay, we didn't know about that.
I'm sorry,
I gots to leave up out of here
before I lose my damn mind.
Nobody knew about that.
You want to run a campaign
with my money pillowed under your ass,
you need your people
to back the fuck up, Clarence.
Krawczyk's on line 1.
I'll jump on Burrell
and Demper both.
- Find out what the hell's going on.
- Wait, wait a minute.
That new driver,
the bald-headed, white kid.
Where did he come here from?
Hoskins brought him in, I think.
Hoskins?
He doesn't have a better rabbi
in the department than that?
Why, you want to lose him?
Let me think about it.
Yeah, man, Officer Walker
be shady like that.
Police be stealin', yo.
Yo, what I really wanna
get is a bubble Caprice.
I seen a nice one, too.
94 Caprice on 22's.
- Shit was tight.
- You better be careful.
They almost caught you today.
Nigga, they ain't almost caught shit.
Be quiet, y'all.
Y'all know who I am, right?
Carver.
You a knockos.
Today I'm auto theft.
Fair warning.
If I see any of y'all little hoppers
even smile at a motor vehicle again,
it ain't gonna be
no juvenile hearing.
No, it's gonna be my people
settlin' up with y'all in the alleys.
- You understand?
- You can't do that, yo.
Try me, Namond.
Yeah, that's right.
I know your name.
I know where you live.
And I know where y'all hang.
Damn, yo!
Nice ride.
Hey, Bunk.
You have any luck
finding your shooter?
Naw.
He's runnin'.
But at least I know
who my shooter is, right?
I just got to find the boy.
- Family won't go for nothin'?
- Nah.
Mother wouldn't say shit.
But it wasn't the usual way
a mama lies.
- What do you mean?
- I don't know.
It was a weird vibe, man.
I can't explain it.
It was like she was off
somewhere else in her head.
Line 4.
Communication.
- Who's up?
- I'm up. I'll take it.
No, wait.
If it's yours, you lucky bitch,
then it's a domestic
in a house with 4 wits.
You want the call?
But I pick up that phone,
do I make it unlucky?
Or is it
still your call?
You want the call, pick it up.
If you don't, don't.
Homicide.
Norris.
Right.
I got it.
1400 Lanvale.
In the street.
Found by the post officer.
No suspects,
no witnesses.
Ah, man.
Better to be lucky than to be good.
You wanna work the heavy bag?
G'head. 4 rounds.
Hey.
- Hey.
- I'm Gail.
I made this for you
and the other men,
to let you know
you're appreciated.
That's real nice.
Peach cobbler.
I'm sorry,
I forgot whose mother you are.
Oh, I don't have any boys.
I just appreciate
what you been doing.
You and the other coaches.
Volunteering and all.
Well, thank you, that's real nice.
I got 3 girls.
Y'all don't teach girls, though, do you?
No, I'm real old-fashioned
about that.
Oh, I agree wit' you.
Men should be men
and women should be women.
That's what I think.
Single wound,
upper back, no casings,
no witnesses,
and nothing on the canvas.
Dead when you got here?
Actually not.
He was still conscious
and coughin' blood when I pulled up.
You ask who shot him?
Yeah, I asked who shot him.
He said it was a guy with a gun.
Yo, why you keep calling?
He got the message, fool.
Yo, Monk, who that, man?
Andre.
Old-face Andre.
Yo, Monk,
who that, man?
Andre.
Old-face Andre.
Lemme key that.
Yo Monk.
Who that, man?
Andre.
Old-face Andre.
Yo, check this out, man.
Don't rush me on shit.
- I'll get at you when I'm at you.
- I'm just saying...
Ol' face Andre.
Tryin' to reup with Monk Metcalf.
Yeah, well, Monk took
the call on his cellphone.
But that second voice ranked him.
Ranked everybody, by the sound of it.
Marlo Stanfield.
On the phone.
The way he shut that call down,
I'd say yeah. That was him.
Yeah, but what was all that
in the background? Fireworks, or?
Naw, it was regular intervals.
Semi-auto from the sound.
Target practice, maybe.
Either that or a firing squad.
There are no bodies
on this guy in months,
but we get him on the phone
and it sounds like a war zone.
Well, at least he gets
on a phone now and then.
That's something.
Sounds arrogant, doesn't he?
Like he's the lil' king of everything.
Ah, youth.
Yo, Bubs.
Thought you asleep.
If you want...
I could go to school some.
I ain't been for a while,
so I don't even know if I can.
But if you
want me to go...
ain't no thing.
His honor was mad?
I can't begin to describe it.
What's he want from us?
To block the subpoenas,
but he knows we can't
once those things go out.
What I could promise him
is no more surprises out of our shop.
- Is this that cocksucker McNulty?
- Not this time.
He's been gone
from that unit a year.
My best guess
would be Lester Freamon.
Freamon?
Lester's got a helluva game.
Well, we need to sit on
the motherfucker.
All that unit needs, Commissioner,
is proper supervision.
Hey, the State of Maryland
just lost another cooperating witness,
and I just found a lot
of fucking overtime.
This case went from
who gives a fuck drug murder
to straight-up red ball.
Fuck,
I should've picked up that phone.
Hey, sarge.
My boy's a witness.
Drug case pending in part 18.
You know for sure
he's killed for that reason?
Don't know shit.
But from the look of the court computer,
This guy's the state's whole case.
Don't put it in the 24
that the guy was a witness.
Trust me, we do not wanna
kick shit in an election year.
Work the case,
take the O.T.,
but bury the witness angle
'til we know for sure.
And close the door.
Yeah.
It's Landsman.
Homicide.
Is the Major in this morning?
Next order of business:
class rules.
It helps if the team
is constant on these.
Less giggle room for the children.
Mrs. Scott?
Same as last year, double space.
Language arts,
we grade a lot of papers.
It doesn't make them write any better
but it saves my eyesight.
Make sure you
demonstrate it for them.
Some of them think double space
means more space between words.
I'd of thought by eighth grade...
Rule of thumb around here,
Mr. Pryzbylewski:
never assume.
Explain what you want them to do,
have them do it,
then explain again.
With time and patience,
they'll get it.
Mrs. Shapiro?
It's easier to keep track of lab work
if we all use the same heading.
Upper right hand corner,
above the first blue line:
name, date, and class number,
in that order?
Mr. Pryzbylewski, do you have anything
you want addressed?
Can we have them not chew gum?
They won't do it in
Ms. Sampson's class,
but in 4 years,
I have not been able to stop them.
You can try, but first year,
it's best to stick with basics.
And team rules, we can only go
with what we can all enforce.
Also, keep your windows closed.
Makes them drowsy,
and drowsy's good.
There's a lot to learn.
But for now,
build in lots of activities
in your lesson plan.
You can't
have enough.
You keep them busy,
you keep them off guard.
You need soft eyes.
Excuse me?
Yeah, but that doesn't prevent you
from giving more
under your wife's name,
your children, if they
got separate accounts... yeah.
Sorry, Richie,
can you hold a moment?
Your buddy from the F.O.P.
and he says it's important.
Hey, Stan.
I'm a little busy
losing an election here.
You remember about 6 months ago,
you told me to keep an eye for
any witnesses gettin' clipped?
You remember that?
Who's better than me, Tommy?
Hey, Richie, can I call you back?
Thanks.
Anything else you want me
to do, Miss Donnelly?
You live near Duquan Weems, correct?
Dukie?
I want you to take this to his house.
Them clothes won't stay clean long.
Make sure you deliver
them just to Duquan.
Not any of the adults in the house.
Just Duquan.
- Want me to do it tonight?
- That would be great.
And, Crystal, thanks for today.
You're welcome, Miss Donnelly.
- Can I help you?
- Yes, ma'am.
This young man has to be
registered for school.
Does he attend here?
He should.
What I mean is,
what grade were you
in last year, dear?
He kinda lost his way some time ago.
He's livin' with me now.
And you are his...
uncle.
I'm his uncle.
Come into my office.
Thank you.
Yo, look at coach workin' it, yo.
A'ight, man, break.
That's what I like to see, baby.
You gotta use that left
a little more, though, a'ight.
Yo, man, you finished?
Got another 2 minutes.
Fuck that, I got a fight coming up.
You can come back later, a'ight?
Yo, man said he got
1 more round, a'ight?
Step aside, young'un.
Naw, man, bag is mine for 4 rounds
and I only did 3.
Fuck that man.
What the fuck u tryin' to prove?
Come on, man,
come on. Come on.
What's going on, boy?
I got a fight Saturday night,
an' the boy won't get off the bag.
What the fuck he on
the bag for anyway?
He don't even fight.
He don't even spar.
Spar with your ass any day.
- Come on, then.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Y'all be cool, you hear me?
I ain't putting up
with this foolishness.
Come here, Michael.
I can work the bag now, right?
Not yet.
Just wait.
- You said 4 rounds.
- Yeah, I know what I said.
You finish up your rounds,
and then Justin gets on.
I don't want hear
no more street talk.
We boxin' up in here,
we ain't fightin'.
He wanna get in the ring with me,
we can go.
Look here,
look here,
let me tell you something.
You can come here, work out,
use the equipment.
But nobody gets in that ring
unless they're being trained.
You wanna be trained?
I've been watching you hit that bag.
You got a natural right hand.
The way you throw it,
the way you land it.
Now, if I was to train you,
we'd have to start with floor work.
'Cause see, if you
don't know how to move,
you ain't got no business
being in that ring.
So what you think?
I'd train you myself, personally.
Nah, really I just wanna keep
doing what I been doing.
All right.
Let's see that right.
Is Dukie here?
What's that?
That's for Duquan, right?
I take it to him.
Gimme.
Hey, Crystal.
Miss Donnelly said to give you these.
OK. I'll be right down.
What?
And for either of
my opponents to suggest
that downtown development
comes at the expense
of our city's neighborhoods,
well, that's just unfair
and, uh, divisive.
For them to suggest
that my administration
has not been responsive, well...
Economic development
cannot be a band-aid.
It is a long-term process
that requires commitment
to retraining our workforce
and, as I said before,
this can only be successful
in a city where people feel safe.
So before we can even
begin to think about
luring new industries to Baltimore,
we need to think
about how we can make
these neighborhoods and
this city safe once again.
Mr. Carcetti may think
it's in his interest
to exploit people's fears.
He's been doing it
throughout this campaign.
I'm offended by it, personally.
But the fact is,
that violent crime
is down citywide,
and our police department
is working hard
to keep it that way...
and will continue to do so
under my administration.
Councilman Carcetti,
you have 2 minutes to respond.
Does anyone in this room really believe
that crime is down in Baltimore?
You calling me a liar, Tommy?
Gentleman, please.
No personal interactions.
Councilman Carcetti.
Can the mayor honestly tell
the people of Rosemont,
of Belair Edison,
of Highlandtown or Cherry Hill
there's less drug-dealing,
less violence?
Any statistics coming from
the police department
cannot be trusted,
because under this mayor,
the police are more concerned with
protecting Clarence Royce politically
than fighting crime.
There's no leadership and morale
has never been lower.
I'll change that.
It's business as usual
down at city hall
and as a result,
our response to crime
has been characterized time
and time again
by wanton indifference.
32 yards!
What do I mean by business as usual?
What do I mean
by wanton indifference?
Well, last night in West Baltimore,
on Lanvale Street,
another citizen was shot and killed.
This time, the victim
was a key witness
in a drug case that had yet
to come to court.
Courageously,
this man had agreed to testify
in 2 weeks time in that case.
The police should have
been protecting him.
They were not,
and he was murdered.
- Oh, shit.
- Why?
You're primetime, Eddie.
would not spend the money
to protect him.
Now I have no doubt
that in a moment or two
Clarence Royce will accuse me
of exploiting
this man's death for
my own political purpose.
But the truth is,
a year ago
I wrote the mayor a letter.
I have copies for
anyone who wants one.
I begged him to spend the money
and make witness protection a priority.
He ignored me.
I even teamed up with our
legislative leaders...
delegate Watkins and others...
to get matching funds for witness
protection approved in Annapolis.
And incredibly
those matching funds
were never claimed by
this administration.
Now to mention this now
may be exploitive,
I don't know,
I only know it's true.
And on such truths,
I ask the voters of our city
to consider a change.
Folks, please, please,
hold your applause until
after the round of questions is over.
Mayor Royce?
No more surprises, huh?
Well, I am unaware of
the specifics of the incident
to which Councilman
Carcetti is referring,
Uh, so I can't answer
that directly...
However, I can say that this city
places the highest priority
on protecting those citizens
who come forward to testify,
and we will continue to do so.
Mr. Carcetti...
states that he wrote a letter
expressing his concerns,
and I'm sure that he did.
I mean it's... it's...
it's easy enough to write letters
when all you have to do
is write letters.
But,
when you are required
to run a city
on limited resources,
and balance priorities,
well, then...
well, then you understand
that writing letters
will not solve the problem.
Oh, no...
Shit, girl.
You know I'm-a roll wit' you.
I need some kinda break...
Oh, shit...
...ain't nothin' worse
than them bitches
with fucked up nails
at the blackjack table...
You know?
Hold on.
You think my son ain't gonna go up
to that school lookin' like himself?
And I don't believe
we can get a handle on crime
until we get a handle on the schools.
Because we need
to be thinking about these kids
before the corners take them,
and this means a renewed focus
on our schools...
Transcript: FRM Team - Synchro: Sixe
The Wired Team - thewire-france.com
www.tvsubtitles.net